<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-1015</num>
  <heading>ASSIGNMENT OF LIEN (§ 19-1015)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1015.1.</num>
    <text>The rights of the holder of an unsatisfied lien shown on a certificate of title may be assigned by an assignment in writing which shall show the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the assignee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The trade name of the vessel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The engine number of the vessel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The serial number or identification number of the vessel; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The Harbor Master’s record number of the instrument or, if none, a brief description sufficient to identify the lien.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1015.2.</num>
    <text>The assignment in writing shall also be signed by the holder of the lien.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1015.3.</num>
    <text>When an assignee of a lien on a vessel presents to the Harbor Master the written assignment of the lien, the certificate of title, and the fee for recording the lien, the Harbor Master shall mark upon the certificate of title and upon the lien card
      the record number of the lien on the vessel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1015.4.</num>
    <text>If the Harbor Master has the lien instrument in the Harbor Master records, he or she shall attach the lien instrument to the written assignment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1015.5.</num>
    <text>If the Harbor Master does not have the lien instrument in the Harbor Master records, he or she shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Briefly describe the lien in a separate memorandum;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Mark on the memorandum the date of the assignment of the lien;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Mark on the memorandum the words “Assigned to” and alongside the words “Assigned to” the name and the address of the assignee; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Mark on the memorandum the date that the Harbor Master recorded the lien.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1015.6.</num>
    <text>If the Harbor Master does not have records of the lien instrument, he or she shall mark the record number of the lien on the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>On the written assignment of the lien;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>On the certificate of title; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>On the lien card in the space next to the information concerning the written assignment of the lien.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1015.7.</num>
    <text>The certificate of title shall be delivered to the record holder of the first unsatisfied lien shown thereon or to his or her representative.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>The Authority for this section is D.C. Law 5-58, the “District of Columbia Boat Titling Act of 1983”.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 2(c) of D.C. Law 5-58, the “District of Columbia Boat Titling Act of 1983”, 31 DCR 1459 (March 30, 1984) incorporating by reference the text of D.C. Act 5-86, 30 DCR 6293, 6307-09 (December 9, 1983).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>