<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-1023</num>
  <heading>IMPOUNDMENT OF VESSELS (§ 19-1023)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1023.1.</num>
    <text>Any unattended vessel found in District waters at any time under the following circumstances may, by or under the direction of the Harbor Master, either by towing or otherwise, be removed or conveyed to and impounded at any place designated by the
      Chief of Police:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Any unattended vessel that is not properly registered or numbered in compliance with § 1004 of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any unattended vessel against which there are two (2) or more outstanding or otherwise unsettled violation notices, or against which there have been issued two (2) or more warrants;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any unattended vessel that is anchored, moored, or tied up in violation of §§ 1028, 1030.16 through 1030.17, or 1041;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any unattended vessel that is sunken, beached, or abandoned, and that is not removed within the time specified by § 1030.9, or that creates an obstruction or other hazardous condition;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any unattended vessel that has been willfully cast adrift;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Any unattended vessel that remains in a restricted area in violation of § 1029;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Any vessel that becomes unattended as a result of the arrest of the operator of that vessel; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Any other unattended vessel that, in the judgment of the Harbor Master, poses an immediate hazard to life or property.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1023.2.</num>
    <text>The Harbor Master, as soon as practicable, shall inform the owner or other person in charge or control of an impounded vessel of the circumstances under which, or on account of which, the vessel was impounded.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1023.3.</num>
    <text>The owner of an impounded vessel, or the owner’s duly authorized representative, shall be permitted to repossess or secure the release of the vessel upon:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Posting of the collateral required for his or her appearance in the D.C. Superior Court to answer for the violation or violations on account of which the vessel was impounded; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Payment of the fees required by this section.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1023.4.</num>
    <text>The owner of an impounded vessel shall be subject to a towing or removal fee of fifty dollars ($50.00) plus a reasonable fee for the cost of storing the impounded vessel. The storage fee shall be established by the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1023.5.</num>
    <text>In lieu of the towing or removal fee, the owner of the sunken, beached, or abandoned vessel which is removed and conveyed by or under the direction of the Harbor Master pursuant to §§ 1030.8 through 1030.14 shall be subject to a fee equivalent to
      the costs of removing and conveying the vessel. This fee shall not be less than fifty dollars ($50.00).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1023.6.</num>
    <text>Impounded vessels that are not repossessed as provided in this section shall be sold or disposed of in accordance with D.C. Code, § 4-160 (1994 Repl.) as it relates to the sale or disposition of motor vehicles.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 29 § 25 of the Police Regulations of the District of Columbia (January 1983).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>