<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-1005</num>
  <heading>CREATION AND RETENTION OF RECORDS (§ 7-1005)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1005.1.</num>
    <text>Each recipient of a District of Columbia government contract or government assistance subject to the Act, and their subcontractors subject to the Act, shall retain payroll records created and maintained in the ordinary course of business pursuant
      to District of Columbia law for a period of three (3) years from the payroll date for affiliated employees eligible for the living wage, as set forth in section 107 of the Act (D.C. Official Code § 2-220.07). Each recipient shall be responsible
      for keeping and maintaining records that differentiate between hours paid from the contract or government assistance and other funding sources.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1005.2.</num>
    <text>The director or the chief official of an agency or other entity of the District of Columbia government which issues contracts or government assistance may request from a contractor, recipient, or subcontractor subject to the Act an affirmative statement
      acknowledging the application of the Act to the contractor, recipient, or subcontractor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1005.3.</num>
    <text>The director or chief official of an agency or entity of the District of Columbia government which issues contracts or government assistance may request from any contractor, recipient, or subcontractor subject to the Act a list of all affiliated employees
      of the contractor, recipient, or subcontractor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1005.4.</num>
    <text>A contractor, recipient, or subcontractor receiving a request under §§ 1005.2 or 1005.3 shall provide the affirmative statement or list of affiliated employees, in writing, utilizing a form specified by the Director.</text>
    <text>The affirmative statement or list of affiliated employees shall be signed by the chief executive officer of the contractor, recipient, or subcontractor, and the signature shall be notarized.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 2831, 2834 (April 1, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>