<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-3600</num>
  <heading>DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA STATEHOOD FUND (ยง 3-3600)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3600.1.</num>
    <text>The D.C. Senator or Representative (Senator or Representative) may establish a District of Columbia Statehood Fund (Statehood Fund) to support the purposes and operations of the public office of a Senator or Representative, which may include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Office expenses; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Staff salaries; provided, that the Senator and Representative shall receive compensation no greater than that of the Chairman of the Council.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3600.2.</num>
    <text>The Senator and Representative shall be prohibited from expending monies from the Statehood fund for:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Promoting or opposing any political party or committee; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Promoting or opposing the nomination, election, or recall of any individual to or from public office.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3600.3.</num>
    <text>To finance the Statehood Fund, each Senator and Representative may solicit and receive the following contributions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Monies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Gifts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Endowments;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Donations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Bequests.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3600.4.</num>
    <text>Except for any monies included in annual Congressional appropriations, all contributions shall be deposited in the respective District of Columbia Statehood Fund for each Senator and Representative.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3600.5.</num>
    <text>Each Senator and Representative shall designate one or more District of Columbia federally chartered depository institutions, including a national bank, which is insured by either:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The National Credit Union Administration.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3600.6.</num>
    <text>Each Senator or Representative may establish more than one (1) account at any depository; provided, that at least one (1) checking account shall be maintained at one (1) depository.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3600.7.</num>
    <text>Each Senator and Representative may designate a financial officer to manage the Statehood fund; provided, that the Senator and Representative shall remain solely responsible for the lawful administration of the Statehood Fund.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3600.8.</num>
    <text>Within ten (10) days of assuming office, each Senator and Representative shall file a Statement of Information (Statement), on a form prescribed by the Director, regarding the Statehood Fund.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3600.9.</num>
    <text>The statement shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name, home, and office address of the respective Senator or Representative;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The names and addresses of all Statehood Fund depositories;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The names and account numbers of all Statehood Fund depository accounts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The names, titles, addresses, and phone numbers of each person authorized to make withdrawals or payments out of Statehood fund accounts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and phone number of the Statehood Fund financial officer, or any designated agent; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and phone number of the custodian of books and records.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 3161, 3201-02 (May 22, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 2171 (March 24, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 1402 (February 8, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 60 DCR 11864 (August 16, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>