<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-305</num>
  <heading>REQUESTS FOR PROPOSALS (ยง 19-305)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>305.1.</num>
    <text>Each request for proposals shall set forth at least the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>proposal submission requirements, including the address where proposals are to be delivered and the time and date set for receipt of proposals, which shall be not less than 30 days from the date of issuance unless the CCO determines that the nature
        of the procurement or the needs of the Authority require a quicker response;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>scope of services, delivery or performance schedule, and any special requirements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>instructions to offerors and all applicable standard contract provisions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>evaluation factors and the relative importance of each factor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>requirement that proposals are irrevocable for 120 days after the closing date for submission of price proposals or of best and final offers, if requested; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>requirement that each prospective offeror receiving a request acknowledge receipt of any subsequent amendment to the request.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.2.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall publish notice of each request for proposals in a newspaper of general circulation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.3.</num>
    <text>The CCO may, in the CCO&amp;#8217;s sole discretion, conduct a pre-proposal conference to discuss procurement requirements. The CCO shall announce the conference to all prospective offerors known to have received the request for proposals.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.4.</num>
    <text>The CCO may amend a request for proposals by sending written notice at a minimum as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>to all prospective offerors known to have received requests for proposals, if the time set for receipt of proposals has not passed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>to all responding offerors, if the time for receipt of proposals has passed but the proposals have not yet been evaluated; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>to those offerors in the competitive range, if the competitive range has been established.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.5.</num>
    <text>An offeror may modify or withdraw a proposal by giving written notice at the office designated in the request for proposals at any time prior to the time set for the submission of proposals.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.6.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall not consider a late proposal, modification or withdrawal, except in two circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>the CCO may consider a late proposal if it is the only one received;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>the CCO may consider a late modification if he determines that it makes more favorable to the Authority the terms of a timely proposal that would have been successful.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.7.</num>
    <text>If the CCO determines in the CCO&amp;#8217;s sole discretion that it is in the best interests of the Authority, the CCO may waive, or allow an offeror to correct, minor irregularities after the time set for submission of proposals. A minor irregularity
      is a matter of form not of substance, and one that can be corrected without prejudice to other offerors, such as: an offeror&amp;#8217;s failure to specify the number of its employees; or a offeror&amp;#8217;s failure to acknowledge receipt of an
      amendment where the proposal is clearly responsive to the amendment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.8.</num>
    <text>The CCO may cancel a request at any time prior to award, if the CCO determines that cancellation is in the best interests of the Authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.9.</num>
    <text>If the CCO so determines, the CCO may hold written or oral discussions with all offerors whose proposals are within the competitive range. All proposals that have a reasonable chance of being selected for award on the basis of the evaluation criteria
      set forth in the request shall be within the competitive range.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.10.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall not disclose technical or pricing information of any offeror to a competitor in any discussions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.11.</num>
    <text>Upon completion of discussions, the CCO shall issue to all offerors in the competitive range a written request setting a cut-off date for submission of best and final offers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.12.</num>
    <text>The CCO may elect to require repeated submission of best and final offers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.13.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall make award to the responsible offeror whose proposal is most advantageous to the Authority, as determined by a written evaluation of proposals on the basis of the criteria set forth in the request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.14.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall give written notice of award to the successful offeror after all required approvals have been obtained.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 4907, 4912-14 (August 22, 1997); and as amended by Final Rulemaking at 49 DCR 10814 (November 29, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>