<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-301</num>
  <heading>GENERAL REQUIREMENTS[COLON] METHODS OF PROCUREMENT (§ 19-301)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>301.1.</num>
    <text>Unless the CCO elects to make a procurement pursuant to a contract of the U.S. General Services Administration or of the Chief Procurement Officer of the District of Columbia government, the CCO shall procure any goods, services or construction by
      one of the methods set forth in these regulations, namely:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>invitation for bids;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>request for proposals;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>small purchase;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>emergency procurement; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>sole source procurement.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.2.</num>
    <text>An invitation for bids or request for proposals shall be the preferred method of procuring all goods, services and construction, unless otherwise provided in these regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.3.</num>
    <text>Where these regulations permit use of a small purchase or emergency procurement, the CCO shall make the procurement by issuing a purchase order (except when section 306 of these rules permit the use of blanket purchase agreement for small purchases).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.4.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall prescribe the form of all purchase orders and blanket purchase agreements, which shall be issued on a fixed or not-to-exceed price basis and shall specify: the quantity of goods, services or construction ordered; any trade or prompt
      payment discounts offered; and the delivery date(s).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.5.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall require offerors to submit and certify cost or pricing data in all procurements, contract modifications, and subcontracts of a value of $ 100,000 or more, unless the CCO makes a written determination that such data are unnecessary in
      accordance with the principles governing procurements by the Federal government set forth in relevant sections of Title 48 Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.6.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall conduct cost or price analyses of all procurements, by whatever method made, in accordance with the principles governing procurements by the Federal government set forth in relevant sections of Title 48 Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.7.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall publish in a newspaper of general circulation notice of all procurement awards of a value of more than $100,000, regardless of the means by which the procurement is made.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 4907, 4908-09 (August 22, 1997); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 2657 (March 12, 1999); and as amended by Final Rulemaking at 49 DCR 10814 (November 29, 2002).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR&amp;#8217;S NOTE</heading>
      <text>Section 301.1 amended the pre-existing provision to clarify that “rules which satisfy the competitive requirements of Federal Regulations satisfy the competitive requirements of these regulations”. See Preamble to Notice of Final Rulemaking, 44
        DCR 4907.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>