<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-309</num>
  <heading>PROTESTS (ยง 19-309)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>309.1.</num>
    <text>An actual or prospective offeror or bidder whose direct economic interests would be affected by the award of, or the failure to award, a procurement, is an interested party with standing to assert a claim that the solicitation or award of, or the
      failure to award, the procurement, is contrary to law or these regulations by filing a written protest with the CCO.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>309.2.</num>
    <text>In order to be timely, a protest shall be filed:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>in the case of an alleged defect in an invitation for bids or request for proposals, before the time set for bid opening or for the receipt of proposals; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>in all other cases, within seven days after the protestor knew or should have known of the alleged defect or other ground for protest.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>309.3.</num>
    <text>Each protest shall be signed by the protestor or the protestor&amp;#8217;s authorized representative, and shall contain: the name, address and telephone number of the protestor; identification of the procurement activity, including the number of any
      solicitation or contract; a concise statement of the facts which are the basis of the protest; and a specific request for action by the CCO.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>309.4.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall not consider any protest that is not filed within the time requirements of section 309.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>309.5.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall issue a written decision on each timely protest within ten days of receipt. Failure to issue a decision within ten days shall be deemed to be a denial of the protest for the purpose of appealing the Authority&amp;#8217;s final decision
      to the District of Columbia Contract Appeals Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>309.6.</num>
    <text>If the CCO determines in the CCO&amp;#8217;s sole discretion that it is in the best interests of the Authority, the CCO may grant an extension of time to accept bids or awards, withhold award of a contract, or seek suspension of performance of an
      awarded contract, if it appears that the protest has merit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>309.7.</num>
    <text>An interested party may appeal the CCO&amp;#8217;s decision to the District of Columbia Contract Appeals Board, which shall have exclusive jurisdiction to review final action of the Authority on any protest.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 4907, 4916-17 (August 22, 1997); and as amended by Final Rulemaking at 49 DCR 10814 (November 29, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>