<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2301</num>
  <heading>GENERAL REQUIREMENTS FOR LICENSURE (§ 17-2301)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2301.1.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a license shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Submit a completed application on a form that the Board supplies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Pay the required fees;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Submit to the Board all required supporting credentials, documents, and materials that the Board requests including the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Transcripts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>References;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Test scores;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Proof of successful completion of prelicensing or precertification coursework; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A completed and notarized affidavit of work experience;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Submit with the application two (2) recent passport-type photographs of the applicant’s face measuring two inches by two inches (2 in. x 2 in.); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>If applicable, the applicant shall submit proof of having passed the examination that the Board requires for the level of licensure desired by the applicant.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2301.2.</num>
    <text>Applicants shall be at least eighteen (18) years of age.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2301.3.</num>
    <text>Applicants may not have been convicted of an offense that bears directly on the fitness of the applicant to be licensed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2301.4.</num>
    <text>Application fees and examination fees are not refundable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2301.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant may not have been convicted of a crime in any jurisdiction or disciplined by any regulatory body in any jurisdiction for any activity that either would be grounds for the Board to discipline the applicant or would impair the applicant&amp;#8217;s
      ability to transact the business of a licensed or certified real property appraiser, or appraiser trainee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2301.6.</num>
    <text>An applicant may not have been convicted, in any jurisdiction, of an offense bearing directly upon the applicant&amp;#8217;s fitness to be licensed under this chapter or the Act. Any plea of nolo contendere shall be considered a conviction for the
      purposes of these regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 8480 (December 10, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 5846 (July 21, 2006); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 10590 (December 16, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>