<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2303</num>
  <heading>ACCREDITATION AND CERTIFICATION OF PRELICENSE EDUCATION PROGRAMS (ยง 17-2303)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2303.1.</num>
    <text>Appraisal organizations shall obtain advance approval from the Board for any changes to be made in Board recognized equivalent courses with regard to program structuring, course content, course completion standards, textbooks or course materials,
      or instructor qualification requirements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.2.</num>
    <text>An organization that has obtained Board recognition of its courses may advertise that such courses are &amp;#8220;recognized&amp;#8221; for equivalent prelicensure education credit toward the requirements for initial District of Columbia real estate
      appraiser licensure or certification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.3.</num>
    <text>Courses offered by real estate appraisal or real estate related organizations deemed acceptable by the Board shall be acceptable for credit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.4.</num>
    <text>Appraisal and appraisal related courses taught by institutions of higher learning recognized by an accrediting body approved by the Secretary of the United States Department of Education shall be acceptable for prelicensure or precertification credit
      if the course has been approved by the AQB.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.5.</num>
    <text>All courses approved by the AQB shall be acceptable for credit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.6.</num>
    <text>All courses submitted for credit shall indicate a passing grade or indicate successful completion of the course and the examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.7.</num>
    <text>The Board may request information from the applicant or the course provider, such as course descriptions, syllabi, or textbook references, in order to evaluate course content.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.8.</num>
    <text>Correspondence courses may be acceptable for prelicensure or precertification credit if the course meets the following conditions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The course is presented by an accredited college or university that offers correspondence programs in other disciplines;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An individual successfully completes a written examination administered by an official approved by the college or university; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The subject matter is appraisal related, and the length of the course is a minimum of fifteen (15) classroom hours for a prelicensure or precertification course.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.9.</num>
    <text>The Board may issue a list of recognized prelicensure or precertification education programs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 8480 (December 10, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 5846 (July 21, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 9991 (September 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>