<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2323</num>
  <heading>APPRAISER TRAINEE (§ 17-2323)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2323.1</num>
    <text>2323.1 The Board may issue an appraiser trainee license to an applicant who hasompleted a prelicensure education program that meets the followingequirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Seventy-five (75) classroom hours of instruction that shall include fifteen15) hours relative to the USPAP:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A classroom hour is equal to fifty (50) minutes of each sixty (60) minuteegment and includes time devoted to tests which are considered to be part ofhe course;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Classroom hours may only be obtained where the minimum length of theducational offering is fifteen (15) hours and the individual successfullyompletes an examination pertinent to that educational offering;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Credit for the classroom hours may be obtained from the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Colleges or universities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Community or junior colleges;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Real estate appraisal or real estate related organizations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>State or federal agencies or commissions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Proprietary schools; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>Other providers approved by the Board or the Educational Licensureommission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Qualifying education shall have been obtained within the five (5)-yeareriod immediately preceding application for licensure; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The core curriculum of the prelicensure education requirements thatppraiser trainees must complete prior to applying for licensure are thirty (30)ours in basic appraisal principles, thirty (30) hours in basic appraisalrocedures, and the fifteen
        (15) hour National USPAP course or its equivalent.he content of the curriculum offered in the courses, seminars, workshops, oronferences used by an appraiser trainee to meet the prelicensure educationequirements shall follow the guidelines established
        by the AQB in theublication, “AQB Guide Note 1 (GN-1).”</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2323.2</num>
    <text>2323.2 There are no examination or experience requirements for the appraiserrainee classification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2323.3</num>
    <text>2323.3 Within four (4) years of submitting his or her initial application foricensure, the appraiser trainee shall pass one (1) of the followingxaminations approved by the Board:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The licensed residential real property appraiser examination;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Certified residential real property appraiser examination; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Certified general real property appraiser examination.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2323.4</num>
    <text>2323.4 The appraiser trainee is subject to direct supervision by a supervisingertified Residential Real Property Appraiser or a Certified General Realroperty Appraiser licensed in the District. The supervising appraiser shall ben good standing, and
      shall not have been subject to any disciplinary actionhat impacted his or her ability to lawfully engage in appraisal practice withinhe last two (2) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2323.5</num>
    <text>2323.5 The supervising appraiser shall be responsible for the training andupervision of the trainee by:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Accepting responsibility for appraisal reports prepared by the appraiserrainee by signing and certifying that the report complies with the USPAP;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Reviewing the appraiser trainee reports; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Personally inspecting each appraised property with the appraiser traineentil the supervising appraiser determines that the appraiser trainee isompetent in accordance with the competency provision of the USPAP for theroperty type.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2323.6</num>
    <text>2323.6 The appraiser trainee may have more than one (1) supervising appraiser,ut a certified appraiser may not have more than three (3) appraisal trainees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2323.7</num>
    <text>2323.7 The appraiser trainee shall maintain an appraiser log and shall includet least the following information for each appraisal record:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Type of property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Date of report;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Client name and address;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Address of appraised property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Description of work performed, scope of review, and supervision of theupervising appraiser;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Number of actual work hours;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Signature and state or jurisdiction license or certification number of theupervising appraiser; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Separate appraisal logs shall be maintained for each supervising appraiser.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2323.8</num>
    <text>2323.8 An applicant for renewal of an appraiser trainee license shall submitroof of having completed all continuing education credits required pursuant to 2310.2 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2323.9</num>
    <text>2323.9 The appraiser trainee shall be entitled to obtain copies of appraisaleports that he or she prepared.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2323.10</num>
    <text>2323.10 The supervising appraiser shall keep copies of appraisal reports for aeriod of at least five (5) years or at least two (2) years after the finalisposition of any judicial proceedings in which testimony was given, whichevereriod expires last.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 8480 (December 10, 1993); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 5846 (July 21, 2006); as amendedy Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 9991 (September 26, 2008); as amended byinal Rulemaking published
        at 58 DCR 10590, 10600 (December 16, 2011); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 9714 (June 28, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>