<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2305</num>
  <heading>LICENSURE BY RECIPROCITY OR ENDORSEMENT (§ 17-2305)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2305.1</num>
    <text>2305.1 An applicant for a license or certificate by reciprocity shall furnish proof satisfactory to the Board that the applicant is licensed or certified and in good standing under the laws of another State or U.S. territory which the Appraisal Subcommittee
      deems to be in compliance with Title XI of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (12 U.S.C. §§ 3331-3351).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2305.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant for licensure by endorsement shall furnish proof of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That the applicant is currently licensed or certified and is in good standing under the laws of another state;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That the original state of licensure or certification has examination requirements which, in the opinion of the Board, were substantially equivalent at the time of licensure or certification to the requirements of the Act, and the examination has
        been approved by the Appraisal Foundation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>That the prelicensure or precertification requirements of the original state of licensure were substantially equivalent, at the time of licensure or certification, to the requirements of the Act.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>That the applicant meets the minimum requirements for licensure in the District of Columbia set forth in § 2301 of this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2305.3.</num>
    <text>The Board may deny an application if the applicant has been convicted in any jurisdiction of any crime involving any offense that bears on the fitness of the individual to be licensed or certified. A plea of nolo contendere shall be considered a conviction
      for purposes of this subsection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2305.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a license or certificate by reciprocity or endorsement shall not have had an application denied by the Board for reasons other than failure to pass the National Uniform Appraiser Examination within 1 year prior to the date on which
      the application is filed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 8480 (December 10, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 5846 (July 21, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 9714 (June 28, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>