<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2322</num>
  <heading>APPRAISAL EDUCATION FUND USE FOR PROGRAMS (§ 17-2322)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2322.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may use the Fund to pay that proportion of the cost of a program that is equal to the percentage of the program that is directly related to establishing or maintaining an educational program to improve the competency of licensees or certificate
      holders.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2322.2.</num>
    <text>The Board may authorize the Fund to be used for expenditures for conferences, workshops, and educational programs for real estate appraisal officials as provided in §§ 2322.3 and 2322.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2322.3.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this subsection, a &amp;#8220;real estate appraisal official&amp;#8221; means an employee of the District of Columbia government whose duties involve the enforcement of real estate appraisal license laws including, but not limited
      to, board members, legal counsel, and other employees as designated by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2322.4.</num>
    <text>The Board may use the Fund to pay the entire permissible cost for a real estate appraisal official, whose duties relate in whole or in part to the enforcement of real estate appraisal license laws, to participate in a conference, workshop, or educational
      program that the Board determines is qualified pursuant to § 2322.5.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2322.5.</num>
    <text>In deciding whether a conference, workshop, or educational program is qualified, the Board shall consider the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The educational objective of the proposed program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The length of the proposed program, the schedule of instruction, location, and anticipated number of participants;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A list of instructors and their credentials; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any other information about the conference, workshop, or program as the Board may require.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 8480 (December 10, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 5846 (July 21, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 9991 (September 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>