<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-501</num>
  <heading>PERSONS INELIGIBLE TO PURCHASE TICKETS (§ 30-501)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>501.1.</num>
    <text>No ticket shall be purchased by, and no prize shall be paid to any of the following persons:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Any member of the Board or employee of the agency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any spouse, child, brother, sister, or parent residing as a member of the same household in the principal place of abode of any member of the Board or employee of the agency; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any contractor, subcontractor or vendor of the agency or its employees who are directly involved in the performance of a contract affecting the conduct, integrity, security, or reliability of the gaming operations of the agency.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.2.</num>
    <text>In addition to the persons identified in § 501.1, none of the following persons shall purchase a POWERBALL®, Hot LottoTM ,Sizzler ticket or win or be paid a POWERBALL® Hot LottoTM or Sizzler prize:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A Multi-State Lottery Association (&amp;#8220;MUSL&amp;#8221;) employee, officer, or director;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A contractor or consultant under agreement with MUSL to review the MUSL audit and security procedures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An employee of an independent accounting firm under contract with MUSL to observe drawings or site operations and actually assigned to the MUSL account and all partners, shareholders, or owners in the office of the firm located at the MUSL draw
        site or in the District of Columbia; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A parent, stepparent, child, stepchild, spouse, or sibling of an individual described in §§ 501.2(a), (b) and (c).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.3.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this title shall be construed to prevent the making of a gift of a lottery ticket to a person under the age of eighteen (18), but no prize shall be paid directly to a minor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 7439, 7440 (October 2, 1992); as amended by notice of Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 295(January 13, 2006) and 55 DCR 6370 (June 6, 2008).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL NOTE</heading>
      <text>Prior to October 2, 1992. the D.C. Lottery and Charitable Games Control Board published Final Rulemaking published at 29 DCR 2202, 2211 (May 28, 1982).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>