<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-5406</num>
  <heading>VERIFICATION OF ANNUAL INCOME (§ 14-5406)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5406.1</num>
    <text>5406.1 All of the below listed sources of income are subject to theerification hierarchy listed previously in this chapter, unless specificallytated otherwise.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Three (3) consecutive paycheck stubs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Tips, commissions and bonuses. If not included in paycheck stubs:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Previous two (2) year official federal and local tax returns;</text>
    <text>Certified Statement from participants of anticipated tips, based on previouswenty-four (24) months; or</text>
    <text>New hire, statement from employer on anticipated amount for the next twelve (12)onths;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Documentation of Self Employment income may include:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>IRS Form 1040, with applicable schedules;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Schedule C (Small Business);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Schedule E (Rental Property Income);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Schedule F (Farm Income);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Audited Financial Statement; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Certified Financial Statement, if Tax Returns or Audited Financial Statements not available;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>If none of the above are available, notarized statement of net incomenticipated to be received within the next twelve (12) months, based on therevious twelve (12) months;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A Social Security/Social Security Insurance Benefits Benefit Award Letterated within sixty (60) days of DCHA’s request is required to verify incomerom the Social Security Administration. The following applies to the proof ofocial Security and Social
        Security Insurance benefits:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>DCHA shall not accept photocopies of social security checks or banktatements.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the participant or applicant is missing the benefit award letter, DCHAhall help the participant or applicant request a benefit verification letterrom SSA&amp;#8217;s website, or by calling 1-800-772-1213. The service is free andhe applicant or
        participant will receive Proof of Income Letter within ten (10)ays;</text>
    </level>
    <text>For child support payments, the following types of documents may be used toerify income:</text>
    <text>Court ordered child support documents;</text>
    <text>Twelve (12) month payment history print out from the enforcement agency;</text>
    <text>Notarized statement from person paying the support stating the amount and therequency of payments made; and</text>
    <text>If the person paying the support refuses to provide the notarized statement,ocumentation of efforts to obtain the statement from the person paying theupport and an affidavit from the person receiving the support stating themount and frequency of payments
      made;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Recipients of unemployment benefits shall provide records from thenemployment agency stating gross amount of pay, frequency of pay, and expectedermination date;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Participants shall provide an affidavit signed by the participant or personssisting the Family attesting to recurring gifts or assistance received.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Examples of regular contributions include:</text>
    <text>Regular payment of a Family’s bills (such as utilities, telephone, rent,redit cards, and car payments);</text>
    <text>Cash or other liquid assets provided to any Family member on a regular basis;nd</text>
    <text>“In-kind” contributions such as groceries and clothing provided to a Familyn a regular basis;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Non-monetary contributions shall be valued at the cost of purchasing thetems, as determined by DCHA. For contributions that may vary from month toonth (such as, utility payments), DCHA shall include an average amount basedpon past history;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Scholarships, Tuitions, Grants and Financial Assistance shall be documentedhrough records from an Institution of Higher Education detailing the cost ofuition anticipated for the next twelve (12) months and verification of allcholarships, grants
        and loans received individually identified;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>DCHA may request third party verification of income, even if the incomeource is excluded from the calculation of annual income; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>If DCHA is able to identify through participant-provided documents that theource is excluded from income, then DCHA shall use participant providedocuments to document the file.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 7916, 7923 (June 29, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>