<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-602</num>
  <heading>INCINERATORS (ยง 20-602)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>602.1.</num>
    <text>The use of single chamber and flue-fed incinerators shall be prohibited. No person shall be permitted to use an incinerator unless it is of multiple chamber design, and is otherwise in compliance with this subtitle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.2.</num>
    <text>Operation of any incinerator built after July 7, 1972, shall be prohibited if the incinerator emits more than three hundredths (0.03) grains of particulate matter per dry standard cubic foot of exhaust gas corrected to twelve percent (12%) carbon
      dioxide, without the contribution of carbon dioxide from auxiliary fuel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.3.</num>
    <text>Use of any incinerator which was in existence on July 7, 1972, is prohibited, if the incinerator has a capacity of more than four hundred (400) pounds per hour, or emits more than eight one hundredths (0.08) grains of particulate matter per dry standard
      cubic foot of exhaust gas corrected to twelve percent (12%) carbon dioxide, without the contribution of carbon dioxide from auxiliary fuel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.4.</num>
    <text>The District facility known as Solid Waste Reduction Center No. 1 shall be operated so as not to discharge into the atmosphere particulate matter which is in excess of eight one hundredths (0.08) grains of particulate matter per dry standard cubic
      foot of exhaust gas corrected to twelve percent (12%) carbon dioxide, without the contribution of carbon dioxide from auxiliary fuel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.5.</num>
    <text>No new incinerator shall commerce operation except for an incinerator to be operated by or for the District of Columbia Government and except where the Mayor shall find that any other system of waste disposal would endanger the public health. These
      incinerators shall be subject to ยง 602.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.6.</num>
    <text>An incinerator shall operate only between the hours of 10 a.m. and 4 p.m. This restriction shall not apply to incinerators with a refuse-burning capacity of five (5) tons per hours or more.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 3 of the District of Columbia Air Pollution Control Act of 1984, D.C. Law 5-165, ยง 602. 32 DCR 565, 608 (February 1, 1985).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>