<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6203</num>
  <heading>STATEMENT OF RESIDENTS&amp;#8217; RIGHTS AND RESPONSIBILITIES (ยง 29-6203)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6203.1.</num>
    <text>The facility shall conspicuously post the &amp;#8220;Statement of Residents&amp;#8217; Rights and Responsibilities&amp;#8221; in the facility. This statement shall include all of the residents&amp;#8217; rights and responsibilities contained in this
      section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6203.2.</num>
    <text>A resident has the right to be treated with fairness, dignity, and respect.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6203.3.</num>
    <text>A resident has the right to receive appropriate and reasonable adult guidance, support, and supervision, consistent with the resident&amp;#8217;s age and level of development.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6203.4.</num>
    <text>A resident shall not be abused, mistreated, threatened, harassed, or subjected to corporal punishment or to other unusual or extreme methods of discipline.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6203.5.</num>
    <text>A resident has the right to have his or her opinion heard and to be included, to the greatest extent possible, and consistent with the resident&amp;#8217;s age and level of development, when any major decisions, including regular case planning meetings,
      are being made affecting his or her life.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6203.6.</num>
    <text>A resident has the right to reasonable and clinically appropriate visitation, mail, and telephone communication with relatives, friends, significant others, attorneys, social workers, therapists, and guardians ad litem.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6203.7.</num>
    <text>A resident has the right to have his or her relatives and designated representatives, who are authorized in writing by the contracting entity, to communicate with the facility, ask questions of the facility, and have their questions answered promptly
      by the facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6203.8.</num>
    <text>A resident has the right to language translation, if necessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6203.9.</num>
    <text>In accordance with the District of Columbia Human Rights Act of 1977, as amended, effective December 13, 1977, D.C. Law 2-38, D.C. Code section 1-2501 et. seq., a resident shall not be discriminated against on the basis of race, color, religion, national
      origin, sex, age, marital status, personal appearance, sexual orientation, familial status, family responsibilities, matriculation, political affiliation, disability, source of income or place of residence or business.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6203.10.</num>
    <text>A resident shall have all other rights specifically set forth in this Chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6203.11.</num>
    <text>A resident shall accept responsibility, consistent with his or her age and level of development, for keeping his or her room(s) and possessions in good order and for completing assigned daily or weekly chores.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6203.12.</num>
    <text>A resident shall comply with the policies and procedures governing his or her conduct.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6203.13.</num>
    <text>A resident shall participate in the facility&amp;#8217;s programs and activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6203.14.</num>
    <text>A resident of school age shall attend school or other alternative education programs, except in extenuating circumstances and such circumstances shall be documented in the resident&amp;#8217;s case record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6203.15.</num>
    <text>A resident shall follow appropriate minimum personal care and hygiene standards established by the facility, consistent with each resident&amp;#8217;s physical and developmental capabilities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 8675, 8678 (September 21, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>