<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6227</num>
  <heading>PRIVACY (ยง 29-6227)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6227.1.</num>
    <text>The facility shall endeavor to provide for a resident&amp;#8217;s reasonable privacy with respect to his or her person, property, and living quarters.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6227.2.</num>
    <text>The facility may limit a resident&amp;#8217;s privacy as reasonably necessary to protect the health, safety, or welfare of the resident or others.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6227.3.</num>
    <text>The facility shall make reasonable efforts to ensure that the resident&amp;#8217;s need for medications is kept confidential.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6227.4.</num>
    <text>The facility shall maintain doors on bedroom areas and bathroom enclosures unless there is a clinical justification for their removal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6227.5.</num>
    <text>The facility shall ensure that a resident has reasonable privacy when using the telephone.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6227.6.</num>
    <text>When the facility limits a resident&amp;#8217;s use of his or her personal property, the facility shall document its decision and rationale and specify how such limitation is consistent with the resident&amp;#8217;s individual service plan. The facility
      shall maintain an inventory of all such personal property, including a description of the condition of the property in its custody as a result of such limitation. The inventory, decision and rationale shall be maintained in the resident&amp;#8217;s
      case record. If appropriate, the facility shall return the personal property to the resident upon discharge. The facility shall return the personal property to the resident prior to discharge only if specifically provided in the resident&amp;#8217;s
      individual service plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6227.7.</num>
    <text>The facility shall prohibit the use of listening devices for routine observation of residents in their rooms, unless otherwise required by court order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6227.8.</num>
    <text>Other than a photograph taken of a resident upon admission into the facility pursuant to ยง 6257.3(g), the facility shall not create or use any photograph, audio-tape, artwork, or writing of or concerning a Resident without the written authority of
      the resident, the resident&amp;#8217;s parent(s) or guardian(s), and the licensing agency or contracting entity, unless otherwise provided by court order. The facility shall not use the photograph taken of a resident upon admission into the facility
      for public relations or fundraising purposes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6227.9.</num>
    <text>A resident shall not participate in a public performance without the written authority of the resident, the resident&amp;#8217;s parent(s) or guardian(s), and the licensing agency or contracting entity, unless otherwise provided by court order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 8675, 8705 (September 21, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>