<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6229</num>
  <heading>STAFF DEVELOPMENT (ยง 29-6229)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6229.1.</num>
    <text>Each facility shall provide a minimum of twenty (20) hours of instructional training and twenty (20) hours of experiential training to each new non-volunteer staff member. Non-volunteer staff members shall complete this training within the first thirty
      (30) calendar days of employment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6229.2.</num>
    <text>For volunteer staff members, the Facility shall provide a minimum of twenty-five (25) hours of experiential and instructional training. Volunteer staff members shall complete this training within the first six (6) months of work at the facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6229.3.</num>
    <text>The training required by ยง 6229.1 shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Familiarization of the staff with emergency and safety procedures of the facility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The principles and practices of resident care, including appropriate training on age-specific and special physical, emotional, and medical needs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Administrative structure, procedures, and overall program goals of the facility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Procedures for maintaining confidential the residents&amp;#8217; case records and information contained therein;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Appropriate techniques of behavior management for staff providing direct care or supervision of residents;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Techniques and methodologies of crisis management for staff providing direct care or supervision of residents;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Methods of considering residents&amp;#8217; diverse cultures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Methods of considering residents&amp;#8217; sensitivities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Manifestation of and techniques for working with abused, neglected, and traumatized residents;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Familiarization of the staff with the discipline policy of the facility and acceptable methods of discipline;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>The techniques and methodologies of passive physical restraint;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Procedures for reporting actual or alleged resident abuse or neglect, and actual or alleged risk to a resident&amp;#8217;s health or safety, including training on mandatory reporting;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Recognition and prevention of abuse and neglect and risks to the resident&amp;#8217;s health or safety;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>Recognition of substance abuse symptoms and treatment resources;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>Universal precautions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(p)</num>
      <text>Identification of, and methods of responding to, suicidal behavior; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(q)</num>
      <text>Intervention with violent residents.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6229.4.</num>
    <text>All staff shall possess current American Red Cross Standard First Aid and CPR certifications or equivalent. Additionally, all staff serving residents five (5) years old or younger shall obtain infant CPR certification. A staff member who does not
      possess current American Red Cross Standard First Aid and CPR certifications or equivalent shall not provide direct care or supervision of residents unless he or she is accompanied by another staff member who does possess current American Red Cross
      Standard First Aid and CPR certifications or equivalent. All staff not so certified shall obtain such certifications within forty-five (45) calendar days of the enactment of this Chapter. All new staff shall obtain such certifications within forty-five
      (45) calendar days of becoming new staff.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6229.5.</num>
    <text>Each facility shall provide at least forty (40) hours of in-service training for each staff member each year covering topics determined jointly by the facility and the licensing agency, including, where appropriate, training in acceptable methods
      of discipline required by ยง 6273.4 and training in acceptable methods of restraint required by ยง 6274.3.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6229.6.</num>
    <text>Each facility shall maintain records of attendance at training.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 8675, 8709 (September 21, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>