<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6236</num>
  <heading>BATHROOMS (ยง 29-6236)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6236.1.</num>
    <text>The facility shall provide bathrooms with a minimum of one (1) sink with hot and cold water, one (1) flush toilet, and one (1) bath or shower with hot and cold water for every six (6) residents. Each bathroom shall contain a mirror secured to the
      wall at a convenient height.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6236.2.</num>
    <text>Bathing and toilet facilities shall be maintained in good repair and in clean condition, in accordance with applicable laws and housing codes, including but not limited to the 1995 BOCA International Plumbing Code, District of Columbia Construction
      Code Supplement, Title 12 DCMR.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6236.3.</num>
    <text>Potty-chairs shall not be located in areas used for food preparation or serving. Potty-chairs shall be emptied and cleaned after each use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6236.4.</num>
    <text>Toilets shall be disinfected at least once daily or more often as needed using an appropriate germicidal agent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6236.5.</num>
    <text>In programs serving teen parents, residents two (2) years old and younger shall not be included in the ratio of bathing and toilet facilities required herein.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6236.6.</num>
    <text>Privacy shall be provided by partitions or doors for toilets (unless inconsistent with a toilet training program), showers and bathtubs, unless there is a clinical justification for their removal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6236.7.</num>
    <text>The facility shall supply each bathroom with toilet paper, soap and a wastebasket.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6236.8.</num>
    <text>Bathrooms shall be located on the same floor as sleeping rooms.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6236.9.</num>
    <text>Bathrooms shall be situated so as to allow direct access to them without the necessity of passing through a bedroom, except when a bedroom has an attached bathroom used only for the residents who reside in that bedroom.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6236.10.</num>
    <text>Bathtubs and showers shall have nonskid surfaces.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 8675, 8714 (September 21, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>