<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6275</num>
  <heading>DISCHARGE AND AFTERCARE PLANNING (ยง 29-6275)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6275.1.</num>
    <text>For each resident, the facility shall prepare a discharge plan, including:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A statement of the reason for the discharge;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A summary of the services that were provided during care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A summary of the resident&amp;#8217;s educational and medical histories;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A description of the supports and resources to be provided to the resident in preparation for discharge;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Recommendations for aftercare and the identity of the person(s) responsible for aftercare;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The resident&amp;#8217;s expected address and telephone number after discharge; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The identity of the person(s) responsible for the resident after discharge, where applicable.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6275.2.</num>
    <text>For residents in emergency care facilities and runaway shelters, discharge planning shall begin commensurately with the resident&amp;#8217;s admission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6275.3.</num>
    <text>The discharge plan shall be developed by a planning team consisting of the administrator, the contracting entity, and staff who will have direct responsibility for implementing the discharge plan. Where feasible, the resident, the resident&amp;#8217;s
      parent(s) or guardian(s), and the resident&amp;#8217;s guardian ad litem shall be involved in the development of the discharge plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6275.4.</num>
    <text>In the case of a planned discharge, the facility shall work with the resident in advance of the date of discharge to assure a smooth transition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6275.5.</num>
    <text>The facility may not discharge a resident without the agreement of the contracting entity and, where applicable, the CSSD.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6275.6.</num>
    <text>Upon the resident&amp;#8217;s discharge from the facility, the facility shall turn over the original or a copy of the resident&amp;#8217;s case record to the contracting entity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 8675, 8739 (September 21, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>