<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6230</num>
  <heading>PERSONNEL POLICIES (§ 29-6230)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6230.1.</num>
    <text>At the commencement of employment of each staff person, the facility shall give the staff person a written description of his or her position which defines the qualifications, duties, and responsibilities of the position and his or her salary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6230.2.</num>
    <text>The facility shall have a written statement of personnel policies which shall be given to staff at the commencement of employment and shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Provisions for paid vacation, sick leave, and policy regarding holidays;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Provisions for periodic evaluations of work performance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A description of employment benefits.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6230.3.</num>
    <text>The facility shall maintain an accurate personnel record on each staff person, including all employees of the facility and any other person (including, without limitation, volunteers, independent contractors, and vendors) regularly providing services
      at the facility. The personnel record shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A written application showing qualifications and experience;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Reports of medical examinations as required by § 6228.6;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Reports of criminal records and child protection register checks as required by § 6228.2 and § 6228.4;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Reports of drug and alcohol testing as required by § 6228.7;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Dates of employment and separation from the facility with reason for separation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Documentation of training received, including the type, duration, and date of training and the person or agency conducting the training;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Annual performance evaluations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Documentation of all certifications and licenses required under this Chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6230.4.</num>
    <text>The facility shall keep confidential staff personnel records.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 8675, 8711 (September 21, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>