<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6272</num>
  <heading>INVOLVEMENT OF FAMILY AND OTHERS (ยง 29-6272)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6272.1.</num>
    <text>The facility shall cooperate with the contracting entity and, where applicable, the CSSD to make reasonable efforts to develop a relationship with each resident&amp;#8217;s family, consistent with any court order, so that the facility is able to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Notify each resident&amp;#8217;s family of the resident&amp;#8217;s whereabouts, if appropriate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Obtain any necessary parental consent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Provide necessary crisis intervention services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Obtain information and documentation necessary to conduct an assessment of each resident;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Assist each resident&amp;#8217;s family to adjust to the resident&amp;#8217;s placement and separation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Develop a visitation plan and encourage each resident&amp;#8217;s family&amp;#8217;s continued interaction with the resident in accordance with the resident&amp;#8217;s ISP;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Inform each resident&amp;#8217;s family of the resident&amp;#8217;s progress; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Mobilize familial strengths and resources to help the family participate in planning for the resident&amp;#8217;s return home or to another community environment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6272.2.</num>
    <text>The facility shall develop and follow written rules for reasonable visitation, mail, and telephone contact between residents and the residents&amp;#8217; family, friends, attorney, and guardian ad litem, which shall be consistent with any court order
      and which shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Regular visiting hours and additional visiting hours for visitors who are unable to visit during regular visiting hours;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Reasonable conditions of privacy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A designated space, separate from the resident&amp;#8217;s bedrooms, for visitation purposes; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Procedures for restricting visitation, mail, or telephone contacts.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6272.3.</num>
    <text>The facility may restrict visitation, mail, or telephone contacts with the resident&amp;#8217;s family, guardian, attorney, or guardian ad litem only for the following reasons:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>To comply with a court order; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>To safeguard against a documented safety or security risk to residents or staff.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6272.4.</num>
    <text>The facility may restrict visitation, mail or telephone contacts with the resident&amp;#8217;s friends only for the reasons detailed in ยง 6272.3 or as a method of behavior management, provided that the restriction is consistent with the resident&amp;#8217;s
      ISP.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6272.5.</num>
    <text>The facility timely shall inform the resident and, to the extent practicable, those affected outside the facility, including but not limited to the resident&amp;#8217;s parent or guardian, attorney, and guardian ad litem, of the nature of the restriction,
      the reasons for the restriction, and the duration of the restriction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6272.6.</num>
    <text>The facility shall document in the resident&amp;#8217;s case record the restriction, the reasons for the restriction, and the duration of the restriction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 8675, 8734 (September 21, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>