<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6257</num>
  <heading>INTAKE SERVICES (ยง 29-6257)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6257.1.</num>
    <text>Immediately upon the admission of a resident, the facility shall identify and provide for the resident&amp;#8217;s basic needs, including, but not limited to, clothing, food, hygiene, and medications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6257.2.</num>
    <text>The facility, together with the contracting entity, shall as soon as possible identify and document all emergency medical and mental health needs, allergies, basic needs, and non-emergency medical and mental health conditions and physical infirmities,
      including all visible signs of illness or injury, and document this information in the resident&amp;#8217;s case record, along with documentation of a pre-admission medical screen.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6257.3.</num>
    <text>As soon as practicable, and, in any event, not more than forty-eight (48) hours after admission, the facility shall complete an admissions record that includes the following information, where available:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The resident&amp;#8217;s name, date and place of birth, social security number, date of admission, and citizenship;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A description of the resident&amp;#8217;s identifying features, including but not limited to sex, race, height, weight, color of hair, color of eyes, and identifying marks;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An accounting of the resident&amp;#8217;s possessions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The primary language or means of communication spoken and understood by the resident and the primary language used by the resident&amp;#8217;s family, if other than English;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and telephone number of the resident&amp;#8217;s parent(s) or other responsible family members, guardian, attorney, guardian ad litem, case worker, therapist, psychologist, psychiatrist, and other medical professionals, and the
        contracting entity and CSSD, as applicable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A description of the resident&amp;#8217;s medical condition, including identification of any allergies, current medications, physical impairments or limitations, and psychological or mental health conditions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A current photograph of the resident;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The resident&amp;#8217;s custody, guardianship and commitment status;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>An assessment of the resident&amp;#8217;s family situation, reasons for needing care and options available as appropriate to the resident&amp;#8217;s situation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>The current and planned school placement for school-aged residents; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Any relevant court orders.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6257.4.</num>
    <text>As soon as practicable, and in any event not more than forty-eight (48) hours after admission, the facility shall explain to the resident, in a manner consistent with the resident&amp;#8217;s age and level of development, the resident&amp;#8217;s
      rights and responsibilities and the facility&amp;#8217;s rules and policies, emergency procedures, and grievance procedures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 8675, 8724 (September 21, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>