<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-104</num>
  <heading>RESPONSIBILITIES OF AGENCY HEADS (§ 4-104)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>104.1.</num>
    <text>Each District agency head shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be personally responsible and accountable for the execution of the EEO program within his or her agency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Establish procedures, consistent with § 103.7, whereby each complaint is reviewed promptly and processed promptly at every subsequent stage and cause agency records to reflect each date of review and the action taken;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Appoint or designate one (1) or more EEO Officers and EEO Counselors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Upon request of the Director, consult with him or her regarding the suitability of persons appointed or designated EEO Officers and EEO Counselors and, upon request, review appointments or designations and advise the Director of the determination.
        Consultation between agency heads and the Director prior to the appointment or designation of EEO Counselors and EEO Officers is encouraged;</text>
    </level>
    <text>The consultation between the Director and agency head shall also include monitoring the EEO Counselors and the EEO Officers to determine whether or not they are executing their responsibilities, including but not limited to:</text>
    <text>Providing the Exit Letter described in § 105.5 to the complainant within thirty (30) days of complainant’s filing date, or within 60 days if both parties determine that the investigation will continue;</text>
    <text>Providing a Position Statement or responding to a request for documents in the time allotted by the investigator;</text>
    <text>Responding to an Order of OHR within the time allotted by the investigator; and</text>
    <text>Informing all employees of their rights and responsibilities under the Act.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Publicize to agency employees by posting on agency bulletin boards, the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name, office address, and telephone number of each agency EEO Counselor and the organizational units served;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Inform employees that they may contact an EEO Counselor outside their organizational unit if desired; and the time limit for contacting an EEO Counselor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The availability of the EEO Counselor to counsel an employee or qualified applicant for employment who believes he or she has been discriminated against because of race, color, religion, national origin, sex, age, marital status, personal appearance,
        sexual orientation, gender identity or expression, family responsibilities, matriculation, political affiliation, genetic information, and disability in connection with respect to any aspect of District government employment; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Inform employees and applicants of the requirement of consulting with an EEO Counselor within one hundred eighty (180) days of an alleged unlawful employment practice.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.2.</num>
    <text>Each District government agency head shall also publicize to all agency employees, and post permanently on official bulletin boards, the name, address, and telephone number of the Office of Human Rights, each agency EEO Officer, and the agency EEO
      Counselors.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.3.</num>
    <text>Each District government agency head shall make reasonable accommodation for the religious needs of applicants and employees, including the needs of those who observe the Sabbath on a day other than Sunday, when that accommodation can be made without
      undue disruption to the business of the agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 56, 60-62 (January 6, 1984); amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 9162, 9165-9167 (October 1, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>