<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-122</num>
  <heading>THE COMPLAINT FILE (§ 4-122)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>122.1.</num>
    <text>The Director shall establish and maintain a complaint file containing all documents pertinent to each complaint.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>122.2.</num>
    <text>The complaint file shall not contain any document that has not been made available to the complainant. The complaint file shall include, as a minimum, copies of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The complaint;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The written report of the EEO Counselor to the agency EEO Officer on all pre-complaint counseling efforts made with regard to the complainant’s case;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The investigative file;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A signed written statement of the complainant or the complainant’s representative, if the complaint is withdrawn by the complainant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The written record of adjustment, if the complaint is adjusted informally under the provisions of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A copy of the letter from the Director notifying the complainant of the proposed disposition of the complaint and of the right to a hearing, or a decision by the Director without a hearing if no adjustment of the complaint is reached;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A copy of the letter to the complainant transmitting the decision of the Director when the decision is made without a hearing under the provisions of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The record of the hearing, including the Hearing Examiner’s findings, analysis, and recommended decision on the merits of the complaint if a hearing was held; and</text>
    </level>
    <text>A copy of the letter to the complainant transmitting the decision of the Director if the decision is made after a hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 56, 79 (January 6, 1984); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 9162, 9183-9184 (October 1, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>