<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-1201</num>
  <heading>COMMUNITY RELEASE AGREEMENTS (§ 29-1201)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1201.1.</num>
    <text>Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services (DYRS) shall place youth in a community status after a determination that he or she will benefit most from the least restrictive environment consistent with public safety, and with D.C. Official Code § 2-1515.01
      et seq., and § 16-2301.02.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.2.</num>
    <text>Social service workers shall work closely with juveniles and their families to provide those services necessary for rehabilitation to take place.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.3.</num>
    <text>Each youth shall adhere to the specific terms of Community Release Agreements. The terms include, but are not limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Attending school or work regularly;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Meeting curfews;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Refraining from the illegal use of controlled substances;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Complying with all federal, state and local laws, rules and regulations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Abiding by all court orders and directives of DYRS case management staff.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.4.</num>
    <text>The DYRS Case Worker shall thoroughly explain the terms of the agreement with the youth and the youth shall sign the Community Release Agreement as a condition of DYRS placing the youth in the community.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.5.</num>
    <text>The Case Worker shall make reasonable efforts to discuss the agreement with the youth’s family and/or counsel of record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.6.</num>
    <text>Counsel of record or alternate counsel may sign the Community Release Agreement after consultation with the youth if the guardian is unavailable.</text>
    <text>Counsel shall not be called as a witness against the youth if the youth is later alleged to have violated the agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.7.</num>
    <text>Where the youth’s community placement is a private residence, the DYRS Case Worker shall thoroughly explain the terms of the agreement with the youth and his or her guardian.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.8.</num>
    <text>The youth and a guardian shall sign the Community Release Agreement as a condition of DYRS placing the youth in a private residence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.9.</num>
    <text>DYRS shall not place a youth in a private residence unless both the youth and a guardian sign the agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.10.</num>
    <text>The youth shall sign a Community Release Agreement when the level of restrictiveness is lowered.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.11.</num>
    <text>Failure to comply with terms of the Community Release Agreement may result in the youth being placed in an alternative community placement and/or youth’s community placement being rescinded.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>56 DCR 4756 (August 28, 2009).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>56 DCR 4756 (August 28, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>