<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-1212</num>
  <heading>ENFORCEMENT OF THIS CHAPTER (§ 31-1212)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1212.1.</num>
    <text>The enforcement of this chapter shall be governed by the procedures set forth in Chapter 7 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1212.2.</num>
    <text>Complaints shall be in writing, signed by the complainant, and contain the complainant&amp;#8217;s address and telephone number.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1212.3.</num>
    <text>Written complaints shall be delivered or mailed to the Office of Taxicabs, District of Columbia Taxicab Commission, 2041 Martin Luther King Jr., Avenue, S.E., Washington, D.C. 20020.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1212.4.</num>
    <text>Within ten (10) days of receipt of a complaint the Office shall notify the limousine operator or owner, or both, by first class mail, postage prepaid, or certified mail, return receipt requested, of the nature of the complaint.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1212.5.</num>
    <text>The notification shall direct the operator or owner, or both, to file an answer with the Office within ten (10) days of receipt.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1212.6.</num>
    <text>If the answer shows a violation of the Commission&amp;#8217;s Rules and Regulations, the Office, within ten (10) days, shall notify the limousine owner or operator, or both, of the violation and the proposed sanction. The Office shall also inform
      the complainant of the proposed sanction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1212.7.</num>
    <text>If the answer does not show a violation of the Commission&amp;#8217;s Rules and Regulations, the Office shall notify the complainant of the answer and provide an explanation of why there is no violation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1212.8.</num>
    <text>When the Office does not determine whether action under §§ 1212.6 or 1212.7 should be taken, the Office shall attempt to resolve the complaint.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1212.9.</num>
    <text>If the Office does not resolve the complaint, the matter shall be referred to the Panel on Adjudication (Panel) for disposition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1212.10.</num>
    <text>If the facts alleged in a complaint do not constitute a violation of the Commission&amp;#8217;s Rules and Regulations, the Chief of the Office shall dismiss the matter and notify the complainant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 2812, 2821 (May 20, 1994); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 12394 (August 30, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>