<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-1201</num>
  <heading>GENERAL REQUIREMENTS (§ 31-1201)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1201.1.</num>
    <text>Operators may be licensed by the Office of Taxicabs (Office) pursuant to § 1209 to provide limousine service, sedan service, or both, and luxury class service (LCS) vehicles may be licensed by the Office pursuant to § 1204 for use as limousines, as
      sedans, or both. All LCS vehicles may be used as limousines, but only LCS vehicles meeting the definition of “sedan” in § 1299.1 may be operated as sedans.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.2.</num>
    <text>The Office may issue Office orders approving certain vehicles as meeting the definition of “sedan” under § 1299.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.3.</num>
    <text>Operator requirements. An individual shall be authorized to provide luxury class services if he or she:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Has a valid and current driver’s license from the Department of Motor Vehicles (DMV);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Has a valid and current District of Columbia Taxicab Commission (DCTC) operator’s license authorizing the person to provide luxury class service under § 1209; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Is in compliance with Chapter 9 (Insurance Requirements) of this title.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.4.</num>
    <text>Vehicle requirements. A vehicle shall be authorized to provide luxury class services if it:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Has been approved and licensed by the Office pursuant to § 1204 for use as a sedan, a limousine, or both;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Is registered and displays valid and current livery tags (also called “L-tags”) from DMV;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Has a valid and current inspection from DMV pursuant to § 1215 and applicable DMV regulations, including inspection for current compliance with the definition of a sedan under § 1299.1, where applicable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Is operated in compliance with § 1201.5; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Is in compliance with Chapter 9 (Insurance Requirements) of this title.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.5.</num>
    <text>Operating requirements. Luxury class service shall not be provided unless, from the time each trip is booked, through the conclusion of the trip, all of the following requirements are met:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The operator is in compliance with § 1201.3;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The vehicle is in compliance with § 1201.4;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The owner is in compliance with § 1202.1;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The operator is maintaining at the Office current contact information, including his or her full legal name, residence address, cellular telephone number, and, if associated with an LCS organization, contact information for such organization or
        for the owner for which he or she drives, and informs the Office of any change in the foregoing information within five (5) business days through U.S. Mail with delivery confirmation, by hand delivery, or in such other manner as the Office may
        establish in an Office order;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The operator is maintaining in the vehicle a manifest that:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Is either:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>In writing, compiled by the operator not later than the end of each shift using documents stored safely and securely in the vehicle; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Electronic, compiled automatically and in real time throughout each shift;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Is in a reasonable, legible, and reliable format that safely and securely maintains the information;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Reflects all trips made by the vehicle during the current shift;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Includes the date, the time of pick up, the address or location of the pickup, the final destination, and the time of discharge;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Does not include terms such as “as directed” in lieu of any information required by this paragraph; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Is kept in the vehicle readily available for immediate inspection by a District enforcement official (including a public vehicle enforcement inspector (hack inspector)).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Where limousine service is provided, the trip is booked by contract reservation based on an hourly rate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Beginning November 1, 2013, where sedan service is provided, the trip is conducted in accordance with the operating requirements of Chapter 14 (Operation of Sedans) of this title;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The trip is not booked in response to a street hail solicited or accepted by the operator or by any other person acting on the operator’s behalf; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>There is no individual present in the vehicle who is not the operator or a passenger for whom a trip is booked or payment is made.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.6.</num>
    <text>The penalty for a violation of § 1201.4(i) by an operator providing LCS service shall be a civil fine of five hundred dollars ($500), or any other penalty or combination of penalties authorized by § 1218.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.7.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, an LCS vehicle, for which valid and current livery tags have been issued by both DMV and by the motor vehicle licensing agency of another jurisdiction, may operate in the District during such times
      when:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>It displays valid and current tags from such other jurisdiction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>It displays on its windshield a valid and current vehicle registration sticker from DMV; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The luxury tags issued by DMV are maintained in the vehicle available for inspection upon demand by a District enforcement official and such vehicle is otherwise in full compliance with this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 2812 (May 20, 1994); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 855 (February 10, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 5605 (June 8, 2007); as amended by Final Rulemaking published
        at 54 DCR 6069 (June 22, 2007); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 12394 (August 30, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>