<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-1299</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 31-1299)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1299.1</num>
    <text>1299.1 When used in this chapter, the following words and phrases shall havehe meaning ascribed.</text>
    <text>Associates – is a voluntary relationship of employment, contract, ownership,r other legal affiliation. An association not in writing shall be ineffectiveor purposes of this title.</text>
    <text>Contract reservation – an advance booking for limousine service that includeshe start time and the hourly rate.</text>
    <text>Customer – a person that requests public vehicle-for-hire service on behalf ofny person.</text>
    <text>DCTC public vehicle-for-hire license – a vehicle license issued pursuant to.C. Official Code § 47-2829(h) (2012 Supp.).</text>
    <text>District enforcement official – a public vehicle enforcement inspector (hacknspector) or other authorized official, employee, or general counsel of theffice, or a law enforcement official authorized to enforce a provision of thisitle.</text>
    <text>DMV – D.C. Department of Motor Vehicles.</text>
    <text>EPA – U.S. Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
    <text>DCTC identification card (face card) – the licensing document for anperator’s license issued under D.C. Official Code § 47-2829(i) (2012 Supp.).</text>
    <text>Impoundment – impoundment that occurs pursuant to the Taxicab and Passengerehicle for Hire Impoundment Act of 1992, effective March 16, 1993, (D.C. Law-199, D.C. Official Code § 50-331 (2012 Supp.)).</text>
    <text>Independently Operated Vehicle – an LCS vehicle not associated with an LCSrganization.</text>
    <text>Limousine – any LCS vehicle.</text>
    <text>LCS organization – an owner of two (2) or more LCS vehicles.</text>
    <text>Licensing document &amp;#8211; a physical or electronic document issued to a persons evidence that such person has been issued a license under this title.</text>
    <text>Livery tags – vehicle tags issued by a motor vehicle licensing agency for aublic vehicle-for-hire used to provide luxury class services, including theL” tags issued by DMV.</text>
    <text>Luxury class service or LCS service – limousine and sedan service.</text>
    <text>Luxury class vehicle or LCS vehicle – a public vehicle-for-hire that:</text>
    <text>Is a “Luxury Sedan”, an “Upscale Sedan”, or a “Sport Utilityehicle” (“SUV”), as defined by the EPA (available at:</text>
    <text>http://www.fueleconomy.gov/feg/powerSearch.jsp), or the Chrysler 300, provided,owever, that if it is an SUV, it has a passenger volume of at least one hundredwenty (120) cubic feet;</text>
    <text>Does not have a manufacturer’s rated seating capacity of ten (10) or moreersons, and;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Is not a salvaged vehicle or a vehicle rented from an entity whoseredominant business is that of renting motor vehicles on a time basis.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Operator – an individual who operates an LCS vehicle.</text>
    <text>Owner – a person, corporation, partnership, or association, including an LCSrganization or independent owner, that holds the legal title to an LCS vehicle,he registration of which is required in the District of Columbia. If a vehicles the subject
      of an agreement for the conditional sale or lease with the rightf purchase upon performance of the condition stated in the agreement and withn immediate right of possession vested in the conditional vendee or lessee, orf a mortgagor of a vehicle
      is entitled to possession, then the conditionalendee, lessee, or mortgagor shall be considered the owner.</text>
    <text>Sedan – a public vehicle-for-hire that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Meets the requirements for a luxury class vehicle;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Is not stretched;</text>
    </level>
    <text>Is any “dark” color other than 15-1150 TCX, 15-1150 TPX, 16-035 TCX, or6-035 TPX, or any “black” color, as defined by Pantone LLC (available at:ttp://www.pantone.com/pages/pantone/colorfinder.aspx); and</text>
    <text>Has a passenger volume of at least ninety five (95) cubic feet, according to thePA (available at:</text>
    <text>http://www.fueleconomy.gov/feg/powerSearch.jsp).</text>
    <text>Washington Metropolitan Area – has the same meaning ascribed in § 499.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 2812, 2828 (May 20, 1994); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 3831 (April 11, 2008); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 12394 (August 30, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>