<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-1207</num>
  <heading>LICENSING OF LCS VEHICLE OPERATORS &amp;#8211; HEALTH REQUIREMENTS (§ 31-1207)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1207.1</num>
    <text>1207.1 Each application for a new or renewal operator&amp;#8217;s license shall be accompanied by a certificate from a licensed physician who resides in the Washington Metropolitan Area.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1207.2.</num>
    <text>The certificate shall be on a form provided by the Office executed under penalty of perjury.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1207.3</num>
    <text>1207.3 The certificate shall be executed no earlier than thirty (30) days before the date on which the application is filed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1207.4.</num>
    <text>The certificate shall not be considered sufficient to support an application unless it contains all of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A statement that the applicant is not afflicted with any disease or infirmity, such as a contagious disease, epilepsy, vertigo, fainting spells, blackouts, attacks of dizziness, or another medical condition that, in the discretion of the Office,
        may render the applicant unsafe or unsatisfactory as a vehicle operator;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A statement that the applicant has central visual acuity of at least twenty/forty (20/40) in one (1) eye, either unassisted or assisted by glasses or contact lenses, and hearing of at least ten/twenty (10/20) in one (1) ear; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Such additional information or documentation relating to the applicant’s past or present medical history as the Office deems appropriate.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 2812, 2819 (May 20, 1994); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 12394 (August 30, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>