<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-1218</num>
  <heading>PENALTIES (§ 31-1218)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1218.1.</num>
    <text>Each violation of this chapter by an operator shall subject the violator to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Except where otherwise provided in this chapter, a civil fine not to exceed two hundred fifty dollars ($250), provided, however, that the applicable fine for a violation of this chapter shall be doubled for the second offense within any twenty four
        (24) month period and tripled for the third and any subsequent offense within such period;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The suspension, revocation, or non-renewal of the violator’s DCTC operator’s license issued under this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Impoundment of a vehicle found to be operating in violation of this chapter; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A combination of the sanctions listed in Paragraphs (a)-(c) of this subsection.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1218.2.</num>
    <text>Each violation of this chapter by an LCS organization shall subject the violator to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A civil fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500); provided, however, that the applicable fine for a violation of this chapter shall be doubled for the second offense within any twenty four (24) month period and tripled for the third and any
        subsequent offense within such period;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The suspension, revocation, or non-renewal of the LCS organization’s operating authority issued under this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Impoundment of each vehicle owned by the organization found to be operating in violation of this chapter; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A combination of the sanctions listed in Paragraphs (a)-(c) of this subsection.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 2812, 2828 (May 20, 1994); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 12394 (August 30, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>