<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-6701</num>
  <heading>FINANCIAL RESPONSIBILITY MECHANISMS (§ 20-6701)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6701.1.</num>
    <text>Subject to the limitations of §§ 6701.2 and 6701.3 of this section, the owner of a petroleum UST system may use any single mechanism or combination of mechanisms listed in §§ 6703 through 6711 to demonstrate financial responsibility under this chapter
      for one (1) or more UST&amp;#8217;s.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6701.2.</num>
    <text>An owner may use a guarantee or surety bond to establish financial responsibility only if the Corporation Counsel of the District of Columbia has submitted a written statement to the Director that the guarantee or surety bond executed as described
      in this section is a legally valid and enforceable obligation in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6701.3.</num>
    <text>An owner may use self-insurance in combination with a guarantee only if, for the purpose of meeting the requirements of the financial test under §§ 6703 through 6705, the financial statements of the owner or operator are not consolidated with the
      financial statements of the guarantor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6701.4.</num>
    <text>Subject to the requirements of §§ 6701.5 and 6701.6, an owner may substitute any alternate financial assurance mechanism or combination of mechanisms specified in §§ 6703 through 6710 for a financial assurance mechanism currently in place.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6701.5.</num>
    <text>If an owner substitutes an alternate financial mechanism, the owner shall maintain the existing financial assurance mechanism or combination of mechanisms in effect, in compliance with the requirements of § 6700, at all times until the transition
      to the alternative mechanism or mechanisms is completed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6701.6.</num>
    <text>After obtaining alternate financial assurance that complies with the requirements of § 6700, an owner may cancel an existing financial assurance mechanism by providing notice to the provider of financial assurance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6701.7.</num>
    <text>An owner shall obtain alternate assurance of financial responsibility within thirty (30) days after the owner receives notice of any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Commencement of a voluntary or involuntary proceeding under Title 11 of the United States Code (Bankruptcy), naming a provider of financial assurance as a debtor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Suspension or revocation of the authority of a provider of financial assurance to issue a financial assurance mechanism;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Failure of a guarantor to meet the requirements of the financial test required under this chapter; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any other incapacity of a provider of financial assurance.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 43 DCR 2799 (May 24, 1996), incorporating text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 42 DCR 5765, 5770 (October 20, 1995); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7699 (October 1, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>