<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-6705</num>
  <heading>FINANCIAL TEST OF SELF-INSURANCE[COLON] TEST B (ยง 20-6705)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6705.1.</num>
    <text>In order to meet financial Test B, the owner/guarantor shall meet the federal financial test requirements set forth in Title 40 of the Code of Federal Regulations (40 CFR ยง 264.147(f)(1)), substituting the appropriate amount specified in ยง 6700.12(a)
      or (b) for the &amp;#8220;amount of liability coverage&amp;#8221; each time specified in that section of the federal regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6705.2.</num>
    <text>Under Test B, the fiscal year-end financial statements of the owner/guarantor shall be examined by an independent certified public accountant and be accompanied by the accountant&amp;#8217;s report of the examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6705.3.</num>
    <text>Under Test B, the owner/guarantor&amp;#8217;s year-end financial statements may not include an adverse auditor&amp;#8217;s opinion, a disclaimer of opinion, or a &amp;#8220;going concern&amp;#8221; qualification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6705.4.</num>
    <text>Under Test B, the owner/guarantor shall have a letter of assurance signed by the chief financial officer in the form specified in Appendix 67-2 (Alternative II) to this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6705.5.</num>
    <text>Under Test B, if the financial statements of the owner/guarantor are not submitted annually to the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission, the Energy Information Administration, or the Rural Electrification Administration, the owner/operator/guarantor
      shall obtain a special report by an independent certified public accountant (&amp;#8220;CPA&amp;#8221;) stating the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The CPA has compared the data that the letter from the chief financial officer specifies as having been derived from the latest year-end financial statements of the owner/guarantor, with the amounts in the financial statements; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>In connection with that comparison, no matters came to the attention of the CPA which caused him or her to believe that the specified data should be adjusted.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 43 DCR 2799 (May 24, 1996), incorporating text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 42 DCR 5765, 5774 (October 20, 1995); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7699 (October 1, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>