<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2699</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 24-2699)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2699.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed below:</text>
    <text>Act &amp;#8211; the Terrorism Prevention in Hazardous Materials Transportation Temporary Act of 2005, effective May 14, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-2), or any substantially identical successor legislation.</text>
    <text>Capitol Exclusion Zone &amp;#8211; all points within 2.2 miles of the United States Capitol building, except for land located beyond the geographic boundaries of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Carrier &amp;#8211; the person who owns the locomotive or motor vehicle (excluding the trailer) used in providing transportation of ultra-hazardous materials.</text>
    <text>C.F.R. &amp;#8211; Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
    <text>Department &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia Department of Transportation.</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; the Director of the District of Columbia Department of Transportation.</text>
    <text>District &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Emergency &amp;#8211; an unanticipated, temporary situation that threatens the immediate safety of individuals or property.</text>
    <text>Empty Rail Car or Motor Vehicle &amp;#8211; A rail car or motor vehicle that is capable of containing ultra-hazardous material, has exterior placarding or other markings indicating that it contains such material, and contains less than one percent
      (1%) by capacity or volume of any ultra-hazardous material.</text>
    <text>Motor Vehicle &amp;#8211; any vehicle propelled by internal-combustion engine, electricity, or steam, other than a vehicle designed to run only on rails or tracks, that is intended or used for moving freight, merchandise, or other commercial loads
      or property. A motor vehicle shall include any trailer attached to the motor vehicle.</text>
    <text>Person &amp;#8211; an individual, corporation, company, firm, agency, association, partnership, organization, or commercial entity. The term also includes a trustee, receiver, assignee, personal representative, or authorized agent thereof</text>
    <text>Practical Alternative Route &amp;#8211; a route that lies entirely outside of the Capitol Exclusion Zone and whose use would not make movement of ultra-hazardous material cost-prohibitive.</text>
    <text>Public Space Management Administration &amp;#8211; an administration within the Department that is responsible for the issuance of public space permits, or any successor District government entity.</text>
    <text>Rail Car &amp;#8211; any vehicle without motor power that is intended or used for moving freight, merchandise, or other commercial loads or property on rails or tracks and is drawn by locomotive.</text>
    <text>Trailer &amp;#8211; a vehicle without motor power intended or used for carrying freight, merchandise, or other commercial loads or property and drawn or intended to be drawn by a motor vehicle, whether such vehicle without motor power carries the
      weight of the property wholly on its own structure or whether a part of such weight rests upon or is carried by a motor vehicle.</text>
    <text>Transportation &amp;#8211; movement of a rail car or motor vehicle within the Capitol Exclusion Zone.</text>
    <text>Ultra-Hazardous Material &amp;#8211; explosives of Class 1, Division 1.1, or Class 1, Division 1.2, as designated in 49 C.F.R. § 173.2, in a quantity greater than 500 kilograms; flammable gasses of Class 2, Division 2.1, as designated in 49 C.F.R.
      § 173.2, in a quantity greater than 10,000 liters; poisonous gasses of Class 2, Division 2.3, as designated in 49 C.F.R. § 173.2, in a quantity greater than 500 liters, and belonging to Hazard Zones A or B, as defined in 49 C.F.R. § 173.116; or
      poisonous materials, other than gasses, of Class 6, Division 6.1, in a quantity greater than 1,000 kilograms, and belonging to Hazard Zones A or B, as defined in 49 C.F.R. § 173.133.</text>
    <text>U.S.C. &amp;#8211; United States Code.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking Published at 52 DCR 10700 (December 9, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>