<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2601</num>
  <heading>ULTRA-HAZARDOUS MATERIALS TRANSPORT PERMIT APPLICATION PROCEDURES (ยง 24-2601)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2601.1.</num>
    <text>The carrier shall complete a permit application for an Ultra-Hazardous Materials Transport Permit provided by the Public Space Management Administration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.2.</num>
    <text>In addition to such other information as the Public Space Management Administration may request, the permit application for an Ultra-Hazardous Materials Transport Permit shall include the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Type of ultra-hazardous material to be moved within the Capitol Exclusion Zone;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Whether a rail car or motor vehicle will move the ultra-hazardous material within the Capitol Exclusion Zone;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Route of the rail car or motor vehicle moving the ultra-hazardous material, including points of origination and termination;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Statement and supporting documentation explaining why there is no practical alternative route that can be used to move the ultra- hazardous material;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Emergency contact information; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Statement establishing that by signing the application, the carrier attests that the information provided on the application is true and complete.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.3.</num>
    <text>The carrier shall submit the completed Ultra-Hazardous Materials Transport Permit application to the Public Space Management Administration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.4.</num>
    <text>After review and analysis of the information provided on the completed Ultra-Hazardous Materials Transport Permit application and upon receipt of the appropriate permit fee, the Director may:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Issue a permit upon a demonstration that there is no practical alternative route; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Deny the permit.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.5.</num>
    <text>If the Director denies the permit application, the carrier may appeal the Director&amp;#8217;s denial by filing a request for a hearing with the Office of Administrative Hearings within fifteen (15) days after the Director&amp;#8217;s denial was issued.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.6.</num>
    <text>If the Ultra-Hazardous Materials Transport Permit is denied by the Director, the carrier may request that the Director reconsider the permit application. A request for reconsideration shall not act to stay the time for filing a request for hearing
      under ยง 2601.5.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.7.</num>
    <text>The Ultra-Hazardous Materials Transport Permit shall expire:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Single-trip permit: Seven (7) days after the designated date of movement of the ultra-hazardous material;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Annual permit: Three hundred sixty-five (365) days after the date of issuance.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.8.</num>
    <text>The Ultra-Hazardous Materials Transport Permit fee shall be:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Single-trip permit: Three hundred dollars ($300);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Annual permit: One thousand dollars ($1,000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking Published at 52 DCR 10700 (December 9, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>