<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-1102</num>
  <heading>REPRESENTATIONS AND ADVERTISING (ยง 16-1102)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1102.1.</num>
    <text>A copy of the permit application under ยง 2 of the Act approved Sept. 9, 1916 (D.C. Code ยง 47-2702 (2001 Ed.)), shall be posted in a conspicuous place in the premises in which the authorized sale is conducted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1102.2.</num>
    <text>Any person or corporation selling or offering for sale any personal property at public action shall, in describing the property, be truthful with respect to the description, character, quality, and kind of property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1102.3.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this chapter, the representations made under ยง 1102.1 shall be considered as warranties, and any breach of those warranties shall be punishable by prosecution in the Criminal Division, Superior Court, as set forth in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1102.4.</num>
    <text>No one shall offer for sale any personal property unless that property is shown before or at the time of the sale.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1102.5.</num>
    <text>All advertisements of auction sales in the District of Columbia shall contain only true statements of fact in relation to the sale, and the statements when so made shall be considered as warranties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1102.6.</num>
    <text>A person, firm, or corporation desiring to sell property (either real or personal) at public action may, for the purpose of attracting attention to the prospective sale of that property, ring a bell once a day for a period of time not to exceed five
      (5) minutes, in front of the premises to be sold or the place where the personal property to be offered for sale is stored. The bell shall not to exceed six inches (6 in.) in diameter at the bottom and five inches (5 in.) in height perpendicular
      from the level to the crown.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>