<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-115</num>
  <heading>IMMINENTLY DANGEROUS RESIDENTIAL PREMISES (§ 14-115)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>115.1.</num>
    <text>If any residential premises, or part thereof, presents an imminent danger to the inhabitants or the surrounding community because it has been determined that it is an unsafe structure, a structure unfit for human occupancy, an unlawful structure,
      or a structure in which there is unsafe equipment, the Director may order the structure closed and barricaded. If the owner fails to carry out the Director’s order within forty-eight (48) hours after service of notice, the Director may order the
      structure barricaded and may assess all reasonable costs of barricading the structure and all expenses incident thereto, including, but not limited to, administrative costs, occupant relocation costs including temporary housing, security deposits
      and the first month’s rent if required, costs associated with cleaning the premises as defined by this subtitle, utility removal costs, court costs, fines, and penalties, as an assessment against the property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>115.2.</num>
    <text>All assessments authorized to be levied by the District to reimburse it for money expended to remove imminently dangerous premises pursuant to this section shall bear interest at the rate of one and one-half percent (1½ %) per month or part of a month
      from the date the assessment was levied. If any part of the assessment remains unpaid after the expiration of sixty (60) days from the date the assessment was levied, the property against which the assessment was levied may be sold for the outstanding
      assessment, plus interest and penalties, at the next ensuing tax sale, but no later than six (6) months from the expiration of sixty (60) days from the date of the assessment in the same manner and under the same conditions as property sold for
      delinquent property taxes, if the assessment plus interest is not paid in full prior to the sale.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>115.3.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of any property sold pursuant to subsection 115.2, the redemption period shall be six (6) months.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>115.4.</num>
    <text>Monies in the revolving fund established by section 1(b)(1) of An Act to provide for the abatement of nuisances in the District of Columbia, and by the Commissioners of the District, and for other purposes, approved April 14, 1906, 34 Stat. 114; D.C.
      Official Code § 6-711.01(b)(1) (2001), shall be available to cover the costs incidental to carrying out the actions authorized by this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>115.5.</num>
    <text>All monies payable to the District pursuant to this section shall be deposited in the revolving fund referenced in subsection 115.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 2 of the Imminently Dangerous Premises Amendment Act of 1994, D.C. Law 10-157, 41 DCR 4878 (July 22, 1994).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>