<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-902</num>
  <heading>INVENTORY CONTROL (ยง 27-902)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>902.1</num>
    <text>902.1 Each District agency is responsible for all personal property in its custody whether purchased from appropriations or other authorized funds, or acquired by transfer, donation, or other authorized means. Each District agency shall ensure that
      the personal property is properly utilized and managed in the best interest of the District government.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>902.2.</num>
    <text>Each District agency director shall designate in writing to the CPDO:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An administrative employee who shall serve as an Accountable Property Officer (APO); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An administrative employee who shall serve as an alternate APO.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>902.3.</num>
    <text>The APO shall be responsible for:</text>
    <text>Maintaining records that reflect accountability of property assigned to the agency;</text>
    <text>Ensuring the proper utilization and care of all property assigned to the agency;</text>
    <text>Reconciling physical inventories with property records and inventory databases; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Approving transfers of, accounting for, and reporting dispositions of agency personal property to SPD by utilizing the property disposal action form.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>902.4.</num>
    <text>The D.C. SASP and the SPD shall maintain a shared electronic inventory control system to monitor all federal and District surplus personal property in their possession. The system shall contain the following information for each item of surplus personal
      property:</text>
    <text>The date of receipt of property;</text>
    <text>The agency from which the property was received;</text>
    <text>A description of the property, including quantity and condition;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A photograph of the property; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The estimated value of the property.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 9345 (June 21, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>