<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-7121</num>
  <heading>PERSONAL LEAVE INCENTIVE (§ 14-7121)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7121.1.</num>
    <text>A full-time employee in a pay status for the Leave Year shall accrue:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Three (3) Personal Leave Days and one (1) day of Annual leave for utilizing a total of less than two (2) days of accrued sick leave.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Three (3) Personal Leave Days for utilizing a total of two (2) days of accrued sick leave.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Two (2) Personal Leave Days for utilizing a total of more than two (2)</text>
    </level>
    <text>but not more than four (4) days of accrued sick leave.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>One (1) Personal Leave Day for utilizing a total of more than four (4) but no more than five (5) days of accrued sick leave.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7121.2.</num>
    <text>Employees in a non-pay status for no more than two (2) pay periods for the leave year shall remain eligible for Personal Leave under this policy. Sick leave usage for maternity and catastrophic illness/injury, as defined in the Family Medical Leave
      Act of 1990 (D.C. Law 8-181) not to exceed two (2) consecutive pay periods, shall not be counted against sick leave for calculating eligibility for Personal Leave under this policy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7121.3.</num>
    <text>Personal Leave Days shall be selected by the employee and requested at least three (3) full workdays in advance of the leave date. The employee’s supervisor shall approve the Personal Leave requests unless staffing needs or workload considerations
      dictate otherwise. If the request is denied, the employee may request and be granted an alternative day off of the employee’s choice within one (1) month of the requested date.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7121.4.</num>
    <text>All Personal Leave Days must be used in full-day increments within the leave year following the leave year in which earned and may not be substituted for any other type of absence from duty. There shall be no carryover or payment for any unused Personal
      Leave Days. Annual Leave days earned under this policy are subject to carryover or payment provisions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7121.5.</num>
    <text>Part-time employees are not eligible for Personal Leave Days as provided in this policy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 42 DCR 6914, 6927-6928 (December 8, 1995).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>