<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-7100</num>
  <heading>SCOPE AND AUTHORITY (§ 14-7100)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7100.1.</num>
    <text>This personnel policy and procedure manual supersedes all current District of Columbia personnel regulations which applied to the former Department of Public and Assisted Housing except when District of Columbia personnel regulations apply to employees
      covered by any collective bargaining agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7100.2.</num>
    <text>This personnel policy is not intended to be, and it shall not constitute, a contract of employment between the housing authority and any of its employees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7100.3.</num>
    <text>In order to retain necessary flexibility in the administration of policies and procedures, the Executive Director may alter or completely abolish this personnel policy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is the District of Columbia Alley Dwelling Act, as amended, Public, No. 307, 48 Stat. 930 (1934).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 42 DCR 6914, 6916 (December 8, 1995).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR’S NOTES</heading>
      <text>At the time of the adoption of the regulations in this chapter, the DCHA was under the direction and control of a court-appointed receiver. By court order dated July 14, 2000, the receivership was terminated, effective September 15, 2000. See Pearson
        v. Kelly, Civil Action No. 92-CA-14030 (D.C. Superior Court)(Graae, J.). Subsequently, the receiver was succeeded by an Executive Director appointed by the Mayor of the District of Columbia who serves as the head of the DCHA. Accordingly, the
        word “Executive Director” has been substituted for “Receiver” wherever it appeared previously in this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>