<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-7140</num>
  <heading>CORRECTIVE ACTIONS (§ 14-7140)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7140.1.</num>
    <text>A corrective action is intended to correct and improve an employee’s job performance or behavior in a formal systematic manner. Corrective actions do not adversely affect the current base pay, status, or tenure of the employee. The following provisions
      shall apply to corrective actions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Corrective actions must be in writing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Corrective actions may be administered for the causes listed in this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>When the reason for a corrective action is a performance problem, the supervisor can use either the written corrective action format or the Performance Appraisal (PA);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Corrective actions may be administered concurrently with disciplinary actions.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7140.2.</num>
    <text>A corrective action shall be in writing and shall contain the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The area(s) of needed improvement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The corrective actions the employee must take;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The time allotted to the employee to make the correction shall be reasonable and in accordance with the nature of the problem;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The consequences the employee will face if he or she fails to make the necessary corrections;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A statement that the employee may submit a written explanation to the supervisor. The statement shall be attached to, and kept with, each copy of the corrective action in the employee’s file.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7140.3.</num>
    <text>A corrective action may contain a statement that the action will be removed from the employee’s file after a specified period of time if the employee satisfactorily complies with the terms of the corrective action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 42 DCR 6914, 6935 (December 8, 1995).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>