<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-7106</num>
  <heading>HOURS OF WORK AND OVERTIME (§ 14-7106)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7106.1.</num>
    <text>The Authority shall have sole discretion in establishing hours of work and overtime procedures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7106.2.</num>
    <text>Normal working hours for all full-time personnel are between the hours of 8:15 a.m. and 4:45 p.m., Monday through Friday. Part-time personnel will work an established written schedule at the time of employment with the Authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7106.3.</num>
    <text>Lunch periods will be one-half (½) hour and scheduled by the supervisor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7106.4.</num>
    <text>Employees are entitled to take one fifteen (15) minute break in the morning and one fifteen (15) minute break in the afternoon.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7106.5.</num>
    <text>Eight (8) hours, exclusive of the lunch period, constitute a full workday.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7106.6.</num>
    <text>Forty (40) hours per week constitute a full work week.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7106.7.</num>
    <text>The Authority reserves the right to alter the work schedule of employees in selected classifications at all grade levels.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7106.8.</num>
    <text>An employee may not work overtime without his or her Department Director’s written authorization.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7106.9.</num>
    <text>An employee may be entitled to overtime compensation for work performed in excess of eight (8) hours a day or forty (40) hours a week if in an authorized pay status, i.e., active duty, annual, sick, or other authorized leave with pay.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7106.10.</num>
    <text>Overtime will be paid at the rate of time and one-half (1½) the employee’s base hourly rate of pay.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7106.11.</num>
    <text>An employee is paid for overtime work performed on a Saturday, Sunday or holiday at the same rate as for overtime work performed on any other day.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7106.12.</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise mandated by the Fair Labor Standards Act (FLSA), overtime is prohibited for employees at the Department Director level, members of the Executive Director’s personal staff, and employees classified as DS-14 and above.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7106.13.</num>
    <text>An employee may not work compensatory time without his/her Department Director’s written authorization.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7106.14.</num>
    <text>Compensatory time shall be accrued in accordance with Fair Labor Standards Act (FLSA) regulations. All eligible employees covered under FLSA shall accrue one and one half (1½) hours of compensatory time for every hour worked; provided, that the employee
      was in a pay status for forty (40) hours.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7106.15.</num>
    <text>All employees exempt under FLSA shall accrue one hour of compensatory time for every hour worked.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7106.16.</num>
    <text>All overtime and compensatory time worked and all compensatory time used must be documented on each employee’s Official Time and Attendance Record in order to assure proper credit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7106.17.</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise mandated by FLSA, compensatory time is prohibited for employees at the Department Director level, members of the Executive Director’s personal staff, and exempt employees classified as DS-14 and above.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 42 DCR 6914, 6919-690 (December 8, 1995).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>