<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-2800</num>
  <heading>MUSICAL INSTRUMENTS, LOUD SPEAKERS, AMPLIFIERS, AND UNAMPLIFIED VOICES (§0-2800)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2800.1.</num>
    <text>Noise resulting from musical instruments, loud speakers, sound amplifier, radio, tape recorder, television, compact disc player, stero system, including those installed in motor vehicles, and unamplified voices shall not exceed the maximum noise levels
      contained in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2800.2.</num>
    <text>It shall be unlawful for any person to make, continue, or cause to be continued any noise disturbance by the operation, use, or playing of any musical instrument or device, loud speaker, sound amplifier, or other similar device, or unamplified voice,
      for the production or reproduction of sound on private property or public space.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2800.3.</num>
    <text>Parades and public gatherings conducted pursuant to a permit issued by the Metropolitan Police Department (as provided for in 24 DCMR, Chapter 7) are exempt from the noise disturbance limitation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is An Act approved January 26, 1887, 24 Stat. 368, ch. 49, as amended; D.C. Code § 1-315 (1992 (Repl. Vol.); the §§ 422(6) and 422(11) of the District of Columbia. Self-Government and Governmental
        Reorganization Act; the District of Columbia Noise Control Act of 1977, D.C. Law 2-53, as amended; Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 79-28 dated February 5, 1979.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 5 of the District of Columbia Noise Control Act of 1977, D.C. Law 2-53, 24 DCR 5293, 5308 (December 30, 1977); as amended by § 4 of the D.C. Noise Control Act of 1977 Amendment Act of 1986, D.C. Law 6-180, 33 DCR 7660, 7661 (December 21,
        1986); and by § 2 of the Noise Control Amendment Act of 1996, D.C. Law 11-161 43 DCR 3727, 3729 (July 19, 1996);as amended by final rulemaking published at 48 DCR 11747(December 28, 2001).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR&amp;#8217;S NOTE</heading>
      <text>Chapter 31 Maximum Noise Levels was renumbered Chapter 28.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>