<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-3206</num>
  <heading>FEES (ยง 19-3206)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3206.1.</num>
    <text>Charges for services rendered in response to information requests shall be as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Searching for records, per quarter hour, by clerical personnel</text>
    </level>
    <text>$1.50</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Searching for records, per quarter hour, by supervisory personnel</text>
    </level>
    <text>$3.00</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Photocopying $.25 per page</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3206.2.</num>
    <text>In no instance shall the total fee for searching exceed ten dollars ($10.00) for each request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3206.3.</num>
    <text>When a response to a request requires services or materials for which no fee has been established, the direct cost of the services or materials to the Commission may be charged, but only if the requestor has been notified of the cost before it is
      incurred.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3206.4.</num>
    <text>Search costs, not to exceed ten dollars ($10.00) for each request, may be imposed even if the requested record cannot be located. No fees shall be charged for examination and review to determine whether the record is subject to disclosure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3206.5.</num>
    <text>Fees shall be paid in full prior to disclosure of the requested record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3206.6.</num>
    <text>Where an extensive number of documents are identified and collected in response to a request and the requestor has not indicated his/her willingness to pay fees as high as are anticipated for copies of the documents, the requestor shall be notified,
      in writing, that the documents are available for inspection and for subsequent copying at the established rate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3206.7.</num>
    <text>Remittances shall be in the form of cash, a personal check, a bank draft on a bank in the United States, or a postal money order, payable to the order of the D.C. Sports Commission, and mailed or otherwise delivered to the executive director. The
      Commission assumes no responsibility for cash which is lost in the mail.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3206.8.</num>
    <text>A receipt for fees paid shall be given only upon request. No refund shall be made for services rendered.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3206.9.</num>
    <text>Records may be furnished without charge or at a reduced charge where the general manager determines that waiver or reduction of the fee is in the public interest because furnishing the information can be considered as primarily benefiting the general
      public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 42 DCR 5232, 5240 (September 15, 1995).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>