<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-3600</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (ยง 27-3600)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3600.1.</num>
    <text>Only a contracting officer acting within the scope of the contracting officer&amp;#8217;s delegated contract authority is authorized to execute a contract modification on behalf of the District. Other District personnel shall not:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Execute contract modifications;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Act in a manner that causes a contractor to believe that they have authority to bind the District; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Direct or encourage a contractor to perform work that should be the subject of a contract modification.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3600.2.</num>
    <text>A contract modification, including a change issued unilaterally by the District, shall be priced and a government estimate shall be prepared before signature by the parties, unless the interest of the District would be adversely affected. If a significant
      cost increase could result from a contract modification and time does not permit negotiation of a price, the contracting officer shall negotiate a maximum contract price increase and include that price in the modification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3600.3.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall not execute a contract modification, including a change order, which causes or will cause an increase in the funding level of the contract without having first obtained a certification of the availability of funds. The
      certification shall be based on the negotiated price or the negotiated maximum price.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3600.4.</num>
    <text>A modification to a contract may be executed without having first obtained the certification required under ยง 3600.3 if the modification includes a clause, approved by the Director, which conditions payment upon the availability of funds.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1684 (February 26, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 14956 (December 21, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>