<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-2609</num>
  <heading>PETITIONS FOR ARBITRATION PURSUANT TO 47 U.S.C. § 252(B) (§ 15-2609)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2609.1.</num>
    <text>Any telecommunications carrier, including the incumbent local exchange carrier, participating in voluntary negotiation pursuant to 47 U.S.C. § 252(a)(1) may, during the period between the 135th day and the 160th day (inclusive) after the date on which
      the incumbent local exchange carrier received the telecommunications carrier&amp;#8217;s request for negotiation, file with the Commission a petition requesting arbitration of any open issues.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2609.2.</num>
    <text>An original and fifteen (15) copies of the arbitration petition shall be filed with the Office of the Commission Secretary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2609.3.</num>
    <text>All arbitration petitions filed with the Commission pursuant to 47 U.S.C. § 252(b)(1) shall be signed by a duly authorized representative of the petitioning carrier and shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and main telephone number of the petitioning carrier;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name, title, business address, telephone number, fax number, and e-mail address (if available) of the person(s) who will be representing the petitioning carrier during the arbitration proceeding;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A complete list of all telecommunications carriers that participated in the negotiation that is the subject of the arbitration petition;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A statement of any issues that have been resolved by the negotiating parties;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A statement of any issues that have not been resolved by the negotiating parties;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A statement outlining the positions of each negotiating party regarding the unresolved issues;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>All relevant documentation that supports the petitioning carrier&amp;#8217;s position concerning the unresolved issues;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Any request for an order for the production of information pursuant to 47 U.S.C. § 252(b)(4)(B); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>A statement as to whether the petitioning carrier requests an evidentiary hearing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2609.4.</num>
    <text>The only parties to the arbitration shall be the petitioning carrier, the responding carrier, and any other carrier that participated in the voluntary negotiation that is the subject of the petition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2609.5.</num>
    <text>Any petitioning carrier shall serve a copy of the arbitration petition and any supporting documentation on all other parties to the arbitration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2609.6.</num>
    <text>The Commission may reject any arbitration petition that is not filed within the time period prescribed by subsection 2609.1. Rejected arbitration petitions shall be returned to the petitioning carrier.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 5242 (June 23, 2000) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8315 (October 20, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51DCR 2905 (March 19, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>