<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-2622</num>
  <heading>PETITIONS FOR INTERPRETATION OR ENFORCEMENT OF AGREEMENTS APPROVED PURSUANT TO7 U.S.C. ยง 252(E) (ยง 15-2622)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2622.1.</num>
    <text>Any telecommunications carrier, including the incumbent local exchange carrier, may file with the Commission a petition requesting interpretation or enforcement of an agreement approved pursuant to 47 U.S.C. ยง 252(e) of the Telecommunications Act,
      D.C. Code, 2001 Ed. ยง 34-2002(h), and these rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2622.2.</num>
    <text>An original and fifteen (15) copies of the interpretation or enforcement petition shall be filed with the Office of the Commission Secretary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2622.3.</num>
    <text>All interpretation or enforcement petitions filed with the Commission shall be signed by a duly authorized representative of the petitioning carrier and shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and main telephone number of the petitioning carrier;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name, title, business address, telephone number, fax number, and e-mail address (if available) of the person(s) who will be representing the petitioning carrier during the interpretation or enforcement proceeding;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A complete list of all telecommunications carriers that are parties to the approved agreement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A statement of the disputed issues that give rise to the interpretation or enforcement petition;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A statement outlining the positions of each party to the approved agreement regarding the disputed issues;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>All relevant documentation that supports the petitioning carrier&amp;#8217;s position concerning the disputed issues; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A statement as to whether the petitioning carrier requests an evidentiary hearing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2622.4.</num>
    <text>The only parties to the interpretation or enforcement proceeding shall be the parties to the approved agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2622.5.</num>
    <text>Any petitioning carrier shall serve a copy of the interpretation or enforcement petition and any supporting documentation on all other parties to the approved agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 5242 (June 23, 2000) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8315 (October 20, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 140 (January 5, 2001); as amended by Final
        Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 2905 (March 19, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>