<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-810</num>
  <heading>BEHAVIOR RULES GOVERNING THE USE OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA PUBLIC LIBRARY (§9-810)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>810.1</num>
    <text>810.1 Introduction</text>
    <text>The District of Columbia Public Library’s behavior rules have a threefoldurpose: to protect the rights and safety of library customers, to protect theights and safety of staff members, and to preserve the library’s materials,acilities, and property.</text>
    <text>The DC Public Library supports the rights of all individuals to free and equalccess to information and use of the library without discrimination,ntimidation, threat of harm or invasion of privacy. The DC Public Library isedicated to providing friendly,
      courteous and respectful service, and annjoyable, clean, and comfortable environment for all Library users.</text>
    <text>For everyone’s safety and protection, the DC Public Library reserves the righto inspect an individual’s belongings to include purses, backpacks, bags,arcels, shopping bags, briefcases, and other items to prevent unauthorizedemoval of library materials
      and equipment or for the health and safety of staffnd other customers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>810.2</num>
    <text>810.2 Definitions and Scope</text>
    <text>These behavior rules shall apply to all buildings, interior and exterior, andll grounds controlled and operated by the DC Public Library (such buildings androunds are hereafter referred to as the “premises”) and to all personsntering in or on the
      premises.</text>
    <text>Listed below are the library’s behavior rules. Persons who violate these rulesay be removed from the premises and excluded from all library premises for theeriod of time listed below, by authority of the District of Columbia Publicibrary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>810.3</num>
    <text>810.3 Enforcement</text>
    <text>Authorized library staff, Library Police, security guards and/or theetropolitan Police Department officers may intervene to stop prohibitedctivities and behaviors. Failure to comply with these rules may result in: 1)ithdrawal of a person’s permission
      to remain on Library premises; and/or 2)ssuance of a Notice of Barring from Library property for a period of one day toive (5) years, as provided in policies and procedures issued by the Chiefibrarian. A violation of law may also result in arrest
      and prosecution.iolations of law and/or these rules may also result in the restriction and/orermination of Library privileges, including the use of Library computers andther equipment, and facilities. Authorized personnel may base a Notice ofarring
      on personal observation or investigation. Barred parties may have theirhotographs or video captured by DC Public Library staff to enforce the bar.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>810.4</num>
    <text>810.4 ADMINSTRATIVE REVIEW OF NOTICES OF BARRING</text>
    <text>An individual who receives a Notice of Barring may request an administrativeeview of a barring that is greater than seven (7) days. This request must beade within ten (10) business days of the date on the barring notice. A requestor review should
      be submitted in writing to:</text>
    <text>Director of Public Safety</text>
    <text>Martin Luther King Jr. Memorial Library</text>
    <text>901 G. Street NW</text>
    <text>Washington, D.C. 20001.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>810.5</num>
    <text>810.5 Behavior Rules</text>
    <text>For the safety and comfort of the public and staff, and to create an environmentonducive for library business the following activities are prohibited onibrary property and facilities:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>CATEGORY ONE INFRACTIONS:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Any person(s) who violates rules 1-5 while in or on library premises will bemmediately removed and excluded from all DC Public Library premises. Any persono excluded shall lose all library privileges from one (1) to five (5) years andhe incident will
      be reported to the appropriate law enforcement agency.</text>
    <text>Committing or attempting to commit any activity that would constitute aiolation of any Federal or District criminal statue or ordinance.</text>
    <text>Directing a specific threat of physical harm against an individual, group ofndividuals or property.</text>
    <text>Engaging in sexual conduct/activity, including, but not limited to, the physicalanipulation or touching of a person’s sex organs through a person’slothing in an act of apparent sexual stimulation or gratification.</text>
    <text>Being under the influence of any controlled substance or intoxicating liquor oreverage.</text>
    <text>Possessing, selling, distributing, or consuming any alcoholic beverage, excepts allowed at a library approved event.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>CATEGORY TWO INFRACTIONS:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Any person(s) who violates rules 6-13 while in or on library premises may firste given a warning at the discretion of library staff. Subsequent offenses byhat person will result in that person’s immediate removal and exclusion fromll DC Public Library
      premises. Any person so excluded shall lose all libraryrivileges from six (6) months to one (1) year. Repeated violations of categorywo infractions may lead to category one barring periods (1 year to 5 years).</text>
    <text>Engaging in conduct that disrupts or interferes with the normal operation of theibrary, or disturbs library staff or customers, including but not limited to,onduct that involves the use of abusive or threatening language or gestures,onduct that creates
      unreasonable noise, or conduct that consists of loud oroisterous physical behavior or talking.</text>
    <text>Engaging in conduct that can be considered bullying as defined by the Youthullying Prevention Act of 2012, effective September 14, 2012 (D.C. Law 19-167;9 DCR 7820).</text>
    <text>Using library material, equipment, furniture, fixtures, or buildings in a mannernconsistent with the customary use thereof; or in a destructive, abusive orotentially damaging manner; or in a manner likely to cause personal injury tohemselves or others.</text>
    <text>Failure to comply with the reasonable direction of a library staff member.</text>
    <text>Soliciting, petitioning, or distributing written materials or canvassing forolitical, charitable or religious purposes inside a library building, includinghe entrances or grounds or in a manner on the library premises thatnreasonably interferes with
      or impedes access to the library.</text>
    <text>Smoking or other use of tobacco in the library or within 25 feet of any libraryuilding (including electronic-cigarettes).</text>
    <text>Violating the library&amp;#8217;s rules for Acceptable Use of the Internet and</text>
    <text>Library Public Computers.</text>
    <text>Entering or attempting to enter a Library building while barred (i.e.,respassing). Any customer who trespasses is prohibited from use of all DCublic Library facilities and services. Customers or persons returning to a DCublic Library facility during
      a period of barring may be arrested androsecuted for unlawful entry pursuant to DC Official Code § 22-3302 (2001 ed.#038; 2012 Supp.).</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>CATEGORY THREE INFRACTIONS:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Any person(s) who violates rules 14-30 while in or on library premises may beiven a warning at the discretion of library staff. Offenses by that person willesult in that person&amp;#8217;s immediate removal and exclusion from all DC Publicibrary premises.
      Any person so excluded shall lose all library privileges foreven (7) days. Repeated violations of category three infractions may lead toategory two barring periods (6 months to 1 year).</text>
    <text>Interfering with the free passage of library staff or customers in or on</text>
    <text>library premises, including, but not limited to, placing objects such asicycles, skateboards, backpacks or other items in a manner that interferes withree passage.</text>
    <text>Placing personal belongings on or against buildings, furniture, equipment orixtures in a manner that interferes with library staff or customer use of theibrary facility, or leaving personal belongings unattended.</text>
    <text>Bringing bicycles or other similar devices inside library buildings, including,ut not limited to, vestibules or covered doorways if no bicycle rack isrovided within that area.</text>
    <text>Operating roller skates, skateboards or other similar devices in or on libraryremises.</text>
    <text>Parking vehicles on library premises for purposes other than library use.ehicles parked in violation of this rule may be towed at the owner&amp;#8217;sxpense.</text>
    <text>Consuming food or drink that creates a nuisance or disrupts library use becausef odor, garbage or spills. Non-alcoholic beverages in covered containers andood are only allowed in designated areas.</text>
    <text>Bringing animals inside library buildings (with the exception of servicenimals), except as allowed at a library-approved event, or leaving an animalethered and unattended on library premises.</text>
    <text>Taking library materials into restrooms if the materials have not been checkedut.</text>
    <text>Bringing in items excluding personal items (purse, laptop, and briefcase) thatccupy floor space in excess of 9” L x 14” W x 22” H. Items are measuredn totality and must fit easily into a measuring box of the above dimensions.edrolls, blankets (except
      for use by babies and infants), and frame backpacksre prohibited. Bringing large duffel bags and plastic bags measuring over2’ x 36’ and bringing infested personal items into the library.</text>
    <text>Lying down or sleeping, to include the appearance of sleeping in the restroomsr on any floor, couch, table, or seat in the Library and on the premises, andy blocking aisles, exits, or entrances by sitting or lying down in them.</text>
    <text>Improperly using library restrooms, including, but not limited to, bathing,having, washing hair and changing clothes.</text>
    <text>Using personal electronic equipment at a volume that disturbs others, including,ut not limited to, pagers, stereos, televisions, cellular telephones, computersnd tablets.</text>
    <text>Leaving one or more children eight (8) years old or under, who reasonably appearo be unsupervised or unattended, anywhere in or on library premises. [Pleaseee Unattended Children Policy]</text>
    <text>Adults and teens are prohibited from using the children’s area, unlessccompanying a child twelve (12) years old or younger.</text>
    <text>Adults and children are prohibited from using the teen area unless accompanying teen age thirteen (13) – nineteen (19).</text>
    <text>Adults and teens are prohibited from using any restroom designated for children.hildren’s restrooms are for the sole use of children twelve (12) years old orounger, and their caregivers.</text>
    <text>Children and teens eighteen (18) and younger who are not accompanied by an adulturing regular school hours are considered truant. Students must provideritten proof from school authorities excusing the students from school in ordero enter the library
      or be on library premises on school days between 9 a.m. –:30 p.m.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>CATEGORY FOUR INFRACTIONS</text>
    </level>
    <text>Any person(s) who violates rules 31 and 32 while in or on library premises wille excluded from the premises until the problem is corrected.</text>
    <text>Repeated violations of category four infractions may lead to category twoarring periods (6 months to 1 year).</text>
    <text>Entering library buildings with bare feet or a bare chest.</text>
    <text>Any person creating or emanating an odor that can be detected by a reasonableerson, from six (6) feet away and/or constitutes a public nuisance for otherustomers, will be asked to leave the library until the situation can beorrected.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>810.6</num>
    <text>810.6 Library customers who wish to request a reasonable modification ofhese Guidelines because of a disability or health problem may contact Librarytaff or may call the ADA Coordinator at 202-727-1101.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 1046-1059 (January 30, 2009); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10967 (July 26, 2013); asorrected by Errata Notice published at 60 DCR 11203 (August 2, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>