<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-813</num>
  <heading>ACCEPTANCE OF SOLICITED OR UNSOLICITED CHECKS (ยง 19-813)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>813.1.</num>
    <text>When accepting either solicited or unsolicited checks, the library employee shall immediately submit both the Application To Approve Donations (&amp;#8220;AAD Form&amp;#8221;) electronically and signed hard copy by the Donor and the check to the Office
      of General Counsel (&amp;#8220;OGC&amp;#8221;) for legal sufficiency and the approval process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>813.2.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of the funds, the Office of the General Counsel shall retain the check in a secure area until the Application to Approve Donation (&amp;#8220;AAD form&amp;#8221;), completion of legal sufficiency, and the donation is approved by the DCPL
      Board of Library Trustees and/or Chief Librarian and signed by the appropriate parties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>813.3.</num>
    <text>Upon approval, the OGC shall forward all donor checks to DCPL&amp;#8217;s CFO. The Office of Budget &amp;#038; Finance (&amp;#8220;OB &amp;#038; F&amp;#8221;) shall process the revenue cash receipt (&amp;#8220;RCR&amp;#8221;) document in SOAR using
      the designated funds accounting codes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>813.4.</num>
    <text>The OB&amp;#038;F shall forward all funds and record in SOAR the associated RCR to be deposited.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>813.5.</num>
    <text>OGC will mail a receipt to the donor and copy the OB&amp;#038;F for the donation. OB&amp;#038;F will deposit the funds into the appropriate DCPL account. OFT will complete the following steps to ensure the proper use of the donation:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Issue a receipt to the donor upon check clearance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Record the funds in SOAR based on the associated RCR; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Send a copy of the processed RCR to the agency CFO and to OPGD to confirm that the funds were recorded in SOAR.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 9174-9175 (September 21, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>