<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-805</num>
  <heading>USE OF MEETING ROOMS[COLON] MARTIN LUTHER KING MEMORIAL LIBRARY (§ 19-805)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>805.1.</num>
    <text>Meeting rooms shall be open for use by private groups and individuals for as wide a range of civic, educational, political, and cultural discussions and activities as possible, consistent with the requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.2.</num>
    <text>Use of facilities shall be at times and under circumstances that do not adversely affect public library needs and services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.3.</num>
    <text>Meeting rooms shall not be used for personal or commercial interests.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.4.</num>
    <text>A series of meetings shall be approved on a three (3) month basis only.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.5.</num>
    <text>The public library reserves the right to change or cancel reservations in the event of emergencies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.6.</num>
    <text>The public library reserves the right to cancel meeting-room privileges if library property is not cared for properly.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.7.</num>
    <text>No eating or drinking shall be permitted in conference rooms 221 and 315. Smoking is permitted at the discretion of the group.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.8.</num>
    <text>Meetings shall be conducted in an orderly manner, disturbance of others using the same building shall be avoided, all public safety regulations shall be observed, and each group shall be fully responsible for all damage to library property occasioned
      by its use of the facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.9.</num>
    <text>Meetings shall be open to the general public, and admission to the meetings shall be free of charge.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.10.</num>
    <text>No regular classroom meetings shall be permitted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.11.</num>
    <text>No collection of funds or any other thing of value shall be made during any gathering.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.12.</num>
    <text>Meeting rooms may be used during regularly established library hours.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.13.</num>
    <text>If audio-visual equipment is to be used, the person who has signed for meeting- room space shall contact the Audio-Vision Division in person (Room 226) or by telephone (727-1265) to reserve equipment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.14.</num>
    <text>Films shall be reserved in person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.15.</num>
    <text>All audio-visual equipment shall be returned to the Audio-Visual Division at least fifteen (15) minutes before the library closes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.16.</num>
    <text>[Repealed]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.17.</num>
    <text>[Repealed]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.18.</num>
    <text>[Repealed]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.19.</num>
    <text>The number attending a meeting at one time may not exceed the seating capacity of the room as established by the D.C. Fire Marshal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.20.</num>
    <text>The room capacities are as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Room A-5 &amp;#8211; 440 to 468 persons;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Room 221 &amp;#8211; 42 persons; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Room 315 &amp;#8211; 66 persons.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.21.</num>
    <text>Tipping of library employees is not permitted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.22.</num>
    <text>All reservations shall be received no later than the Wednesday of the week before the scheduled meeting. For reservations, call the Martin Luther King Memorial Librarian’s Office, 727-1221 (Room 319).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.23.</num>
    <text>If refreshments are served in Room A-5, then the area shall be cleaned up before leaving.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.24.</num>
    <text>All clean-up shall be completed by the time the library closes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.25.</num>
    <text>The library provides a listing of meetings, locations, and times of meetings in the outer lobby. No other signs shall be permitted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.26.</num>
    <text>The Book Information Desk (727-1111) shall be notified of all meeting cancellations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.27.</num>
    <text>All private groups and individuals are eligible to use the library meeting rooms; provided, that all the requirements of this section shall be observed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>27 DCRR § 3.1, 24 DCR 11011, 11015-17 (June 30, 1978); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 8977 (November 20, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>