<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2904</num>
  <heading>OFFERINGS OF HOMESTEAD PROPERTIES TO PUBLIC (ยง 14-2904)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2904.1.</num>
    <text>After selection by the Administrator of properties to be included in the Program, there shall be published a list of properties available for homesteading, along with a Notice of Request for Proposals (RFP) from persons who wish to be considered for
      participation in the Program, in the following publications:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>D.C. Register;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>At least two (2) major newspapers of general circulation in the city; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>In newspaper(s) serving minority communities in the city.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2904.2.</num>
    <text>The RFP for single family homesteads shall provide all information necessary for persons to apply for participation in the Program including, but not limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A brief description of the Program including, but not limited to, age, income and residency requirements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>First-time home buyer requirement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Application fee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A brief description of the properties being offered including location and approximate size;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Conditions for acceptance in the Program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Deadline for applications;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Address and telephone number of Homestead Program Administration;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Instructions for obtaining applications and additional Program information;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Assessed value of each available property: and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>The availability of program and other DHCD financing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2904.3.</num>
    <text>The RFP for multi-family homesteads shall provide, at a minimum, the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A brief description of the Program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A description of the property being offered including the current dwelling unit configurations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The availability of Program and other DHCD financing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Guidelines and requirements concerning the submission of proposals including the deadline and location for submission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A description of the proposal evaluation process including a listing of factors affecting selection of proposals; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Assessed value of property.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2904.4.</num>
    <text>The RFPs for single family and multi-family homesteads shall indicate that homesteaders are expected to cover certain costs incurred in connection with the closing or acquisition of rehabilitation and/or permanent financing for the homestead.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 4947, 4951-52 (July 31, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>