<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2911</num>
  <heading>PRE-CONVEYANCE REQUIREMENTS-SCOPE AND ALLOCATION OF WORK (§ 14-2911)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2911.1.</num>
    <text>Prior to the conveyance of a title, the prospective homesteader shall obtain or prepare a listing of the scope of work necessary to meet the requirements of § 2913.5 of this chapter. The DHCD may, upon the request of the prospective homesteader, provide
      technical assistance in the development of this scope of work.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2911.2.</num>
    <text>A homesteader may perform work items which are included in the scope of work provided that he or she can demonstrate to the Administrator the ability to perform those work items.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2911.3.</num>
    <text>When a homesteader contracts for rehabilitation work, he or she shall comply with the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The contractor shall be licensed to work as a general contractor in the District and meet any other requirements as established by DHCD consistent with D.C. law;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The contract shall explicitly state that the work to be performed shall bring the property into conformance with all applicable requirements of the D.C. Building Code (DCMR Title 12A) and D.C. Housing Code (DCMR Title 14);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The homesteader shall secure the Administrator’s approval that all Program requirements have been met before entering into a written agreement with a contractor; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The contract for rehabilitation shall be solely between the homesteader and contractor; DHCD shall not be a party to the contract.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 4947, 4957 (July 31, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>