<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2914</num>
  <heading>CONDITIONS OF MULTI-FAMILY HOMESTEAD PROGRAM (ยง 14-2914)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2914.1.</num>
    <text>Multi-family homesteads shall be subject to abatement agreements containing all the conditions enumerated in ยง 2913, except that the conditions controlling commencement and completion of rehabilitation shall be as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Construction of the rehabilitation of the homestead property shall begin no later than six (6) months from the date of conveyance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Rehabilitation shall be complete and the property shall meet all applicable requirements of the D.C. Building Code (DCMR Title 12A) and the D.C. Housing Code (DCMR Title 14) no later than two (2) years from the date of conveyance.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2914.2.</num>
    <text>A multi-family homestead project shall have at least fifteen percent (15%) of the proprietary interests in its dwelling units transferred to low income person(s), and at least fifty percent (50%) of the proprietary interests in its dwelling units
      transferred to low and moderate income persons.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2914.3.</num>
    <text>For each multi-family project, the homesteaders shall be selected under a project marketing and selection plan approved by the Program and implemented by the developer. All applicants selected by the developer or the homestead governing body for a
      period of five (5) years from conveyance shall submit a homestead application and be approved by the Administrator.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2914.4.</num>
    <text>The management entity for multi-family homesteads shall be responsible for removing participating parties who are in violation of prescribed conditions and for identifying new parties for participation and residency in the property who are acceptable
      to the Administrator.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2914.5.</num>
    <text>Abatement agreements shall contain specific provisions indicating actions that shall be taken by DHCD for failure of the homesteader to meet prescribed conditions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2914.6.</num>
    <text>The Administrator shall require homesteaders of a multi-family homestead to meet additional conditions as may be necessary to ensure compliance with this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 4947, 4959-60 (July 31, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>