<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4103</num>
  <heading>ACTIVE TREATMENT SERVICES (§ 29-4103)
    <text>An individual residing in an ICF/IID shall receive continuous active treatment services, consistent with the requirements set forth in 42 CFR § 483.440.</text>
    <text>Active treatment services shall vary depending on the needs of the beneficiary, as determined by the interdisciplinary team.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <num>4103.2.</num>
    <text>An ICF/IID shall ensure that a beneficiary receives active treatment services on a daily basis. The ICF/IID may affiliate with outside resources to assist with program planning and service delivery or the facility may provide active treatment services
      directly.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4103.3.</num>
    <text>A program of active treatment services shall include aggressive, consistent implementation of a program of specialized training, treatment, health services, and other related services that is directed towards:</text>
    <text>The acquisition of the behaviors necessary for the individual to function with as much self-determination and independence as possible; and</text>
    <text>The prevention or deceleration of regression or loss of current optimal functional status.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4103.4.</num>
    <text>In accordance with 42 C.F.R. §§ 483.440(c) &amp;#8211; (d), an interdisciplinary team shall determine the type of active treatment services that a beneficiary needs based on preliminary evaluations, assessments, and re-assessments. Each beneficiary’s
      active treatment requirements shall be described in his Individual Program Plan (IPP), pursuant to 42 C.F.R. § 483.440(c). The ICF/IID shall ensure that each beneficiary receives all of the services described in the IPP.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4101.5.</num>
    <text>The per diem reimbursement rate for active treatment shall equal the average of FY12 active treatment rates multiplied by two hundred forty-nine (249) days of service, to account for the maximum days of service provided, and divided by three hundred
      sixty-five (365).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11590 (August 9, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>