<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4104</num>
  <heading>SUPPLEMENTAL PAYMENTS FOR QUALITY OF CARE IMPROVEMENTS (§ 29-4104)
    <text>Consistent with the requirements set forth in the Stevie Sellows Intermediateare Facility for the Intellectually and Developmentally Disabled Qualitymprovement Act of 2005, effective March 8, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-68; D.C. Officialode § 47-1270 et seq.),
      implementing rules, and subsequent amendments,eginning in FY 2014 an ICF/IID that meets the criteria in this section shall beligible to receive a supplemental payment based on the cost of trainingrovided to employees other than managers, administrators,
      and contractmployees.</text>
    <text>In addition to the aggregate per diem described in § 4102, anCF/IID may receive an additional payment for participation in qualitymprovement initiatives that are intended to increase the qualifications ofmployees by making available educational opportunities.</text>
    <text>To qualify for a supplemental payment for quality improvements underhis Section for a fiscal year, an ICF/IID shall, by June 30 of the precedingiscal year, provide DHCF with documentation verifying that it:</text>
    <text>Has a legally binding written agreement with its employees to fund quality ofare improvements through measurable efforts to develop and improve staff skillsy increasing staff training and educational opportunities;</text>
    <text>Has written procedures outlining the process, such as arbitration, for employeeso follow to enforce this agreement. The process shall:</text>
    <text>Be expeditious;</text>
    <text>Be economical for the employees; and</text>
    <text>Provide for a neutral decision maker to resolve disputes; and</text>
    <text>Has provided copies of the agreement and the written procedures to its employeesnd their representatives.</text>
    <text>To establish the cost amount for purposes of determining theacility’s supplemental payment amount, an ICF/IID shall provide DHCF withocumentation verifying the amount of training costs no later than June 30 ofhe preceding fiscal year.</text>
    <text>The training cost amount shall include the cost of providing trainingor employees other than managers, administrators, and contractors, and shall behe actual costs incurred by the facility in providing training to thesemployees. For training costs
      to be included, the training shall be:</text>
    <text>Related to patient care;</text>
    <text>Related to improving the skills, competency, and qualifications of employees inroviding care; and</text>
    <text>Approved by DHCF.</text>
    <text>In order to be eligible for the supplemental payment, an ICF/IIDhall incur costs and provide DHCF with evidence that payment has been made inull. Acceptable forms of evidence shall include a copy of any invoice(s) forraining costs and cancelled check(s)
      reflecting the facility’s payment of thenvoice(s).</text>
    <text>All supplemental payments shall be subject to a uniform percentagef thirteen percent (13%) for administrative costs for FY 2013. Thedministrative cost percentage may be adjusted in subsequent fiscal years.djusted rates will be set forth in the D.C.
      Register.</text>
    <text>Supplemental payments associated with the costs of implementinguality improvement initiatives shall be recorded as an offset to the costsncurred, and shall be included in the cost report submitted annually.</text>
    <text>The supplemental payments described in this § shall not be used tonhance training or educational opportunities for management, administration,nd contractual staff.</text>
    <text>The amount and availability of the supplemental payment shall beontingent upon the availability of funding from DHCF. If the total amount ofayments to be made to all eligible providers exceeds the amount of availableunds, then payments made to all
      eligible facilities shall be proportionatelyeduced.</text>
    <text>A determination indicating whether the provider is eligible or ineligible toeceive the supplemental payment;</text>
    <text>If a provider is determined to be ineligible to receive the supplementalayment, a written statement explaining why the facility is ineligible; and</text>
    <text>Language describing the procedures and timeframes for requesting andministrative review with DHCF.</text>
    <text>A provider who disagrees with the Notice of Eligibility and Proposedeimbursement may request an administrative review by submitting a writtenequest for an administrative review to DHCF within thirty (30) days after theate of the Notice of Eligibility
      and Proposed Reimbursement.</text>
    <text>The written request for an administrative review shall include:</text>
    <text>The reason(s) for the request, including an identification of the specifictem(s) to be reviewed; and</text>
    <text>Supporting documentation.</text>
    <text>No later than ninety (90) days after receipt of all requests for administrativeeview DHCF shall issue a Final Notice of Eligibility and Reimbursement to eachrovider that has applied for the supplemental payment. The notice shallontain at a minimum
      the following information:</text>
    <text>A final determination indicating whether the provider is eligible to receive theupplemental payment. If ineligible, the notice shall contain a writtentatement explaining why the provider is ineligible;</text>
    <text>The total amount of the supplemental payment, including the annual salary,enefit, and training cost amounts;</text>
    <text>The annul number of employee hours excluding managers, administrators, andontract employees;</text>
    <text>The timeframe for payment of the supplemental payment; and</text>
    <text>Language describing the procedures and timeframes for requesting an appeal withhe Office of Administrative Hearings (OAH).</text>
    <text>A provider who disagrees with the Final Notice of Eligibility and Reimbursementay file an appeal with the OAH within forty-five (45) days of the date of theinal Notice of Eligibility and Reimbursement.</text>
    <text>Any adjustments to the supplemental payment as a result of a decision renderedy the OAH shall be offset against payments the following fiscal year.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>DHCF shall issue a Notice of Eligibility and Proposed Reimbursemento each provider within sixty (60) days of receipt of all required information.he written notice shall contain at a minimum all of the following information</heading>
      <text />
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11590 (August 9, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>