<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4108</num>
  <heading>RIGHT TO APPEAL (§ 29-4108)
    <text>DHCF shall issue a notice to each beneficiary when DHCF disapproves the acuityevel assignment submitted by the provider. The notice shall comply withistrict and federal law and rules. A copy of the notice shall also be sent tohe provider. If the beneficiary
      consents, a provider may appeal theetermination described in this section on behalf of the beneficiary.</text>
    <text>For Fiscal Years 2013 and after, DHCF shall send a transmittal toll providers notifying them of the rates.</text>
    <text>Provider appeals shall be limited to challenges based on acuityevel assignments and audit adjustments.</text>
    <text>At the conclusion of each rebasing year audit or any other requiredudit, an ICF/IID facility shall receive an audited cost report including aescription of each audit adjustment and the reason for each adjustment. AnCF/IID facility that disagrees with
      the audited cost report may request andministrative review of the audited cost report by sending a written requestor administrative review to DHCF within thirty (30) days of the date of receiptf the audited cost report.</text>
    <text>For annual cost reports submitted by the ICF/IID facility, anyeterminations made following reviews conducted by DHCF shall be communicated tohe ICF/IID Facility within thirty (30) days. Within thirty (30) days of theate of receipt of the DHCF communication
      on the submitted annual cost report,n ICF/IID facility that disagrees with the determination may request andministrative review by sending a written request for administrative review toHCF.</text>
    <text>The written request for an administrative review shall include andentification of the specific audit adjustment to be reviewed, the reason forhe request for review of each audit adjustment and supporting documentation.</text>
    <text>DHCF shall mail a formal response to the ICF/IID facility no laterhan forty-five (45) days from the date of receipt of the written request fordministrative review.</text>
    <text>Decisions made by DHCF and communicated in the formal response maye appealed, within thirty (30) days of the date of DHCF’s letter notifyinghe facility of the decision, to OAH.</text>
    <text>Filing an appeal with OAH pursuant to this section shall not stayny action to recover any overpayment to the ICF/IID, and the provider shall bemmediately liable to the program for overpayments set forth in theepartment’s decision.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11590 (August 9, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>