<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4113</num>
  <heading>DIRECTED PLAN OF CORRECTION (§ 29-4113)
    <text>In lieu of termination in situations where the ICF/IID is not in compliance withhe federal CoPs, and residents are not in immediate jeopardy, DHCF may requiren ICF/IID to take prompt, timely action specified by DHCF to achieve andaintain compliance
      with CoPs and other District of Columbia Medicaidequirements. These actions specified by DHCF shall constitute a Directed Planf Correction (DPoC).</text>
    <text>The DPoC shall be developed in coordination with and approved by DOH,HCF, and DDS, incorporating findings from DDS’ Continuous Quality Improvementlan.</text>
    <text>The DPoC shall specify:</text>
    <text>How corrective action shall be accomplished for beneficiaries found to have beenffected by the deficient practice and include remedies that shall bemplemented;</text>
    <text>How the facility shall identify other individuals who may have been affectedy the same deficient practice but not previously identified, and how theacility shall act to remedy the effect of the deficient practices for thesendividuals;</text>
    <text>What measures and actions shall be put into place to ensure that the deficientractice(s) is/are being corrected and future noncompliance prevented;</text>
    <text>Timelines, including major milestones for completion of all corrective action inhe DCoP;</text>
    <text>How compliance shall be determined; and</text>
    <text>How the DPoC relates to other alternative sanctions.</text>
    <text>A state monitor shall oversee implementation of the DPoC andvaluate compliance with the plan.</text>
    <text>DHCF may terminate the Medicaid provider agreement of an ICF/IIDhat is unable to meet the timeline for completion of all corrective actions inhe DCoP.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11590 (August 9, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>