<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4109</num>
  <heading>UTILIZATION REVIEW REQUIREMENTS (§ 29-4109)
    <text>In accordance with 42 C.F.R. § 456.401, each ICF/IID shall develop, implement,nd maintain a written Utilization Review Plan (URP) for each Medicaideneficiary receiving services furnished by the ICF/IID. The URP shall provideor a review of each beneficiary’s
      need for the services that the ICFurnished him or her.</text>
    <text>Utilization review for ICFs/IID enrolled in D.C. Medicaid may beonducted by any of the following:</text>
    <text>The ICF/IID;</text>
    <text>DHCF or its designee; or</text>
    <text>Any other approved method.</text>
    <text>The URP shall, at minimum, include the following:</text>
    <text>A description of how utilization review shall be performed;</text>
    <text>The frequency of utilization review;</text>
    <text>Assurances and documentation establishing that the personnel who shall performtilization review meet the requirements of 42 C.F.R. § 456.406;</text>
    <text>Administrative staff responsibilities related to utilization review;</text>
    <text>The types of records maintained by the utilization review team;</text>
    <text>The types and frequency of any reports developed by the utilization review team,nd related plan for dissemination; and</text>
    <text>The procedures that shall be used when corrective action is necessary.</text>
    <text>In accordance with 42 C.F.R. §§ 456.431 &amp;#8211; 456.438, each URPhall establish a process whereby each individual residing in the ICF/IIDeceives continued stay reviews, at minimum, every six (6) months.</text>
    <text>The URP shall establish written methods and criteria used to conductontinued stay reviews. The URP shall also set forth enhanced criteria used tossess a case if the individual’s circumstances reflect any of the followingssociations:</text>
    <text>High costs;</text>
    <text>Frequent and excessive services; or</text>
    <text>Attended by a physician or other practitioner whose practices reflectuestionable billing patterns or misrepresentation of facts needed in order toecure claims reimbursement, including but not limited to ordering and/orroviding services that are not
      medically necessary or that fail to meetrofessionally recognized standards of care.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11590 (August 9, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>