<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-4108</num>
  <heading>BID DOCUMENTS AND INFORMATION PROVIDED BY THE ELECTRIC COMPANY TO POTENTIALIDDERS (§ 15-4108)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4108.1.</num>
    <text>The Request For Proposal (“RFP”) is the document pursuant to which the Electric Company shall solicit Wholesale Full Requirements Service to meet its SOS obligations. The RFP shall include the bid request process, the bid evaluation methodology, the
      timeline for the RFP process, and the following five appendices:</text>
    <text>Expression of Interest Form;</text>
    <text>Confidentiality Agreement;</text>
    <text>Credit Application;</text>
    <text>Bid Form Spreadsheets; and</text>
    <text>Binding Bid Agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4108.2</num>
    <text>4108.2 The Electric Company shall provide to potential SOS bidders the following actual and historical information for the thirty-six (36) months preceding the month in which the data is to be submitted to the Commission.</text>
    <text>The Electric Company shall provide such data on its RFP website on a date to be specified by the Commission.</text>
    <text>Monthly and hourly demand, energy consumption and load profile data, as defined by the Commission, aggregated for each SOS customer class. For Large Commercial customers, if an individual customer’s load data will be disclosed, customer written consent
      is required;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Number of customers in each SOS customer class and the number of customers taking SOS within each customer class;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Representative load shapes for each of the Electric Company’s profile group and sub-groups by month, provided that if an individual customer’s load shape will be disclosed, written customer consent is required;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Hourly delivery data;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Billing determinants on electronic spreadsheets;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>System losses; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Other information as determined by the Commission to be necessary or useful to wholesale bidders.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4108.3.</num>
    <text>The general requirements and conditions for information submitted by the Electric Company to potential SOS bidders are as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Aggregate data: All information required to be provided by Section 4108.3 shall be provided on an aggregate class basis. Individual customer information shall not be provided without the customer’s written consent.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Historic Data Period: All information provided will reflect usage during the most recent thirty-six (36) month period. Information describing factors that would cause the information to be unrepresentative of electricity usage during the SOS period
        shall also be provided.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Due Care; Corrections: The Electric Company shall use due care in compiling the required information with the understanding that bidders will be relying on the data to formulate SOS bids. The Electric Company shall have the duty to correct any inaccuracies
        promptly upon discovery.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Affiliated Interests: The Electric Company shall not provide any information to an affiliated competitive provider that is not provided to all potential SOS bidders. The Electric Company must comply with the code(s) of conduct adopted by the Commission.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Electronic Form; Standard Software: The Electric Company shall provide all information in electronic form usable by standard personal computer software packages; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Scope and Format: The Commission will determine the scope and detail of the information required by Sections 4108.2, 4108.3(a), 4108.3(b), and 4108.3(e).</text>
    </level>
    <text>Source: Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5404, 5417 (July 3, 2009).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>