<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-4101</num>
  <heading>SELECTION OF WHOLESALE SOS PROVIDERS (§ 15-4101)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4101.1.</num>
    <text>The Electric Company shall continue as the SOS provider for retail customers in its distribution service territory until such time as the Commission directs otherwise.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4101.2.</num>
    <text>The Electric Company shall obtain electric supply for SOS pursuant to a competitive wholesale procurement process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4101.3.</num>
    <text>The specific procurement format, form of request, process, timeline, and evaluation process, evaluation criteria and process and model contract for electricity supply shall be submitted for Commission approval by the Electric Company by August 1 of
      the previous year. The Electric Company shall coordinate with other jurisdictions to ensure that bidding days do not coincide for multiple jurisdictions in the Mid-Atlantic area.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4101.4.</num>
    <text>Subject to the review and approval of the Commission, the Electric Company shall solicit for wholesale full requirements service pursuant to a Wholesale Full Requirements Service Agreement (“WFRSA”) with the wholesale suppliers of SOS, which shall
      include the provision of electric energy, energy losses, generation capacity, ancillary services and any other PJM- or FERC-approved services associated with the Electric Company’s load obligation, except for network integration transmission service,
      which will be obtained by the Electric Company. The wholesale supplier shall be responsible for all congestion costs up to the delivery point at which the Electric Company takes the power to serve its SOS load.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4101.5.</num>
    <text>The Electric Company shall solicit seasonally differentiated summer and winter prices.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4101.6.</num>
    <text>Contracts for electricity supply may be of varied duration, as approved by the Commission, to stabilize prices for customers.</text>
    <text>Source: Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5404, 5406 (July 3, 2009).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>