<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-4100</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS; SCOPE, APPLICABILITY AND AVAILABILITY OF STANDARD OFFERERVICE; ELIGIBILITY FOR STANDARD OFFER SERVICE (§ 15-4100)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4100.1.</num>
    <text>The purpose of this chapter is to set forth the policies and procedures for the implementation of the “Retail Electric Competition and Consumer Protection Act of 1999,” as amended.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4100.2.</num>
    <text>This chapter establishes the Public Service Commission of the District of Columbia (“Commission”) Rules and Regulations Governing the Provision of Standard Offer Service (“SOS”), the terms and conditions for wholesale electric power supply procurement
      for SOS, reporting and monitoring procedures, pricing and true-up procedures, other services, and miscellaneous provisions and reservations. The procurement process is for full-requirements wholesale electric supply service to meet the SOS retail
      load. This chapter shall be cited as the “District of Columbia Standard Offer Service Rules.”</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4100.3.</num>
    <text>This chapter shall be applicable to the Electric Company designated by the Commission as the SOS provider to retail customers in the Electric Company’s distribution service territory. This chapter also establishes the rules by which the Electric Company
      shall obtain electric supply for SOS pursuant to a competitive wholesale procurement process and will apply to wholesale bidders who compete for the provision of wholesale full requirements services to the Electric Company. The provisions of this
      chapter are promulgated pursuant to authority set forth in Sections 34-1509(c) and 34-1504(c)(7) of the D.C. Code.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4100.4.</num>
    <text>All Electric Company distribution customers are eligible for SOS from the Electric Company and are subject to the general terms and conditions of the Electric Company’s tariffs and the Commission’s regulations, as they may change from time to time
      subject to the Commission’s approval or adoption of new regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4100.5.</num>
    <text>SOS shall be available to: (1) customers who contract for electricity with an electricity supplier, but who fail to receive delivery of electricity under such contracts; (2) customers who cannot arrange to purchase electricity from an electricity
      supplier; and (3) customers who do not choose an electricity supplier.</text>
    <text>Source: Final Rulemaking published at 56 DC 5404, 5405 (July 3, 2009).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>