<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-2506</num>
  <heading>BLANKET PURCHASE AGREEMENT PROCEDURES (ยง 30-2506)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2506.1.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall prepare and issue a blanket purchase agreement (BPA) on a BPA form approved by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2506.2.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall include the following information in each BPA:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A statement that the supplier will furnish supplies or services, described in general terms, if and when requested by the contracting officer during a specified period and within a stipulated total amount;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A statement that the Agency is obligated only to the extent that authorized purchases are actually made under the BPA;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A statement that the prices to the Agency shall be as low or lower than those charged to the supplier&amp;#8217;s most favored customer for comparable quantities under similar terms and conditions, in addition to any discounts for prompt payment;
        and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A statement that specifies the dollar limitation for purchases under the BPA (not to exceed the small purchase limitations set forth in this chapter).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2506.3.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall furnish to each supplier a list of names of individuals authorized to purchase under the BPA, identified by organizational component, and the dollar limitation per purchase for each individual.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2506.4.</num>
    <text>A BPA shall contain a requirement that deliveries or shipments under the agreement (except subscriptions or other charges for newspapers, magazines, or periodicals) shall be accompanied by delivery tickets or sales slips which contain the following
      minimum information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name of the supplier;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The BPA number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The date of purchase;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The purchase order number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>An itemized list of supplies or services furnished;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The quantity, unit price, and extension of each item, less applicable discounts; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The date of delivery or shipment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2506.5.</num>
    <text>A BPA shall require that one (1) of the following procedures be followed:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That a vendor submit to a contracting officer a summary invoice at least monthly or upon expiration of the BPA, whichever occurs first, for all deliveries made during a billing period, identifying the delivery tickets;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That the vendor submit to the contracting officer an itemized invoice at least monthly or upon expiration of the BPA, whichever occurs first, for all deliveries made during a billing period and for which payment has not been received. These invoices
        need not be supported by copies of delivery tickets; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>That an invoice submitted by the vendor to the contracting officer for subscriptions or other charges for newspapers, magazines, or other periodicals, show the starting and ending dates and state either that ordered subscriptions have been placed
        in effect or will be placed in effect upon receipt of payment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2506.6.</num>
    <text>Each order placed against a BPA shall be recorded on a BPA order form which shall include a discreet BPA order number, accounting data identifying the source of funds, the items or services ordered, the name of the person placing the order, the date
      of the order, and other information required by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2506.7.</num>
    <text>Purchases against a BPA may be made orally; Provided, that each order shall be documented on a BPA order form. After making an oral purchase, the contracting officer may send a copy of the BPA order form to the contractor to ensure that the contractor
      and the contracting officer agree concerning the transaction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2506.8.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer executing a BPA shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Maintain adequate records to ensure that the total dollar volume of orders does not exceed the stated total aggregate amount;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Ensure that only authorized individuals are placing purchases against a BPA; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Maintain awareness of changes in market conditions, sources of supply, and other pertinent factors that may warrant new arrangements with different suppliers or the modification of existing arrangements.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6681, 6774 (September 22, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>