<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-2510</num>
  <heading>PURCHASE ORDERS (ยง 30-2510)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2510.1.</num>
    <text>Each purchase order shall be issued on a form prescribed by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2510.2.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in ยง 2511, a contracting officer shall issue purchase order on a fixed-price basis and shall not include economic price adjustment or redetermination provisions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2510.3.</num>
    <text>Each purchase order shall include any trade and prompt payment discounts that are offered.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2510.4.</num>
    <text>Each purchase order shall specify the quantity of supplies or services ordered.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2510.5.</num>
    <text>When applicable, a purchase order shall provide that inspection and acceptance will be at destination. When inspection and acceptance are to be performed at destination, advance copies of the purchase order shall be furnished to the point of receipt.
      Receiving reports shall be completed by the contracting officer immediately upon receipt and acceptance of material.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2510.6.</num>
    <text>Each purchase order shall contain a definite calendar date by which delivery of supplies or performance of services is required.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2510.7.</num>
    <text>Distribution of copies of purchase orders shall be limited to those required for essential administration and transmission of contractual information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2510.8.</num>
    <text>If the contracting officer wants to consummate a binding contract between the parties before the contractor undertakes performance, the contracting officer shall require written acceptance of the purchase order by the contractor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6681, 6777 (September 22, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>