<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-2002</num>
  <heading>EXEMPTIONS FOR AUTHORIZED EMERGENCY VEHICLES (§ 18-2002)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2002.1.</num>
    <text>The driver of an authorized emergency vehicle may exercise the privileges set forth in this section, subject to the conditions contained in this section, in the following circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>When responding to an emergency call;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>When in pursuit of an actual or suspected violator of the law; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>When responding to, but not upon returning from, a fire alarm.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2002.2.</num>
    <text>In those circumstances authorized in § 2002.1, the driver of an authorized emergency vehicle may do any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Park or stand, irrespective of the provisions of this subtitle;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Proceed past a red or stop signal or stop sign, but only after slowing down as may be necessary for safe operation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Exceed the prima facie speed limit so long as it does not endanger life or property; except that this provision does not apply to ambulances; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Disregard regulations governing direction of movement or turning in specified directions.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2002.3.</num>
    <text>The exemptions granted in this section to an authorized emergency vehicle shall apply only when the driver of the vehicle while in motion sounds an audible signal by bell, siren, or exhaust whistle as may be reasonably necessary, and when the vehicle
      is equipped as specified in § 712 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2002.4.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section shall not relieve the driver of an authorized emergency vehicle from the duty to drive with due regard for the safety of all persons, nor shall these provisions protect the driver from the consequences of his reckless
      disregard for the safety of others.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Commissioners’ Order 274,310/949 effective September 1, 1949; as amended by Commissioners’ Order 57-1086 effective June 11 1957; and by Commissioners’ Order64-714 effective May 12, 1964; 17 DCRR §6 (October 19, 1970).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>