<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-3109</num>
  <heading>CONDUCT OF HEARINGS (ยง 16-3109)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3109.1.</num>
    <text>A general partner may represent the partnership at a hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3109.2.</num>
    <text>A director or officer of, or attorney for, a corporation may represent the corporation at a hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3109.3.</num>
    <text>A respondent shall have the following rights at a hearing:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>To appear and be heard in person or be represented by counsel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>To examine the respondent&amp;#8217;s own witnesses and cross-examine opposing witnesses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>To present all relevant evidence; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>To have subpoenas issued to compel the attendance of witnesses and the production of relevant documents upon submission of a written request to an ALJ at least five (5) days prior to the hearing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3109.4.</num>
    <text>If a respondent denies an infraction, the Director shall have the burden of proving the infraction by a preponderance of the evidence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3109.5.</num>
    <text>All testimony shall be given under oath or affirmation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3109.6.</num>
    <text>Parties at a hearing shall make objections in a timely manner and shall briefly state the grounds relied upon.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3109.7.</num>
    <text>At the conclusion of a hearing, the ALJ may hold open the hearing record for an appropriate period of time to allow for the production of additional documentary evidence or submission of briefs by the parties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3109.8.</num>
    <text>A party filing documentary evidence after the hearing but before the record has closed, shall serve a copy of the evidence on the opposing party.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 5718, 5727 (September 4, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>