<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-3105</num>
  <heading>FAILURE TO ANSWER THE NOTICE OF INFRACTION (ยง 16-3105)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3105.1.</num>
    <text>If a respondent fails to answer an NOI within fifteen (15) days of date of service, the Director shall issue and serve upon respondent a second NOI, in a form prescribed by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3105.2.</num>
    <text>A second NOI shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the respondent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An identification of the NOI to which the respondent has failed to respond in a timely manner, and the amount of the fine and penalty for such failure to respond;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Notification of the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>That the respondent is subject to a penalty equal to the amount of the fine because of the respondent&amp;#8217;s failure to respond to the initial NOI in a timely manner, unless the respondent shows good cause for the failure to respond to the
        NOI in a timely manner;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>That the respondent has a right to a hearing to show good cause for the failure to respond to the NOI in a timely manner and that, if the ALJ determines that there is good cause, the respondent has a right to a hearing on the infraction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>That, if the respondent fails to pay the fine and penalty or request a hearing within fifteen (15) days of the date of service of the second NOI the following shall occur:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The penalty for failure to answer in a timely manner shall increase to twice the amount of the initial fine and the respondent&amp;#8217;s license or permit may be suspended; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The respondent shall be required to appear at a hearing to show cause why the respondent&amp;#8217;s license or permit should not be suspended for such failure to make timely payment or request a hearing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>That the respondent has no right to adjudication of the infraction by mail; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>That the acceptable forms of payment are as follows:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Cash, which is not acceptable by mail; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A personal check, company check, certified check, cashier&amp;#8217;s check, postal money order, or bank money order payable to the order of the District of Columbia Treasurer; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any other information that the Director may require.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3105.3.</num>
    <text>A second NOI signed by the Director shall be prima facie evidence that the respondent has not answered the initial NOI in a timely manner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3105.4.</num>
    <text>A second NOI shall be served and answered in the same manner as an initial NOI, with the following exceptions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If a respondent admits the infraction, the respondent is required to include payment of the penalty, in addition to the fine, with the answer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Respondent has no right to adjudication of the infraction by mail; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Respondent has no right to a hearing on the infraction unless the respondent shows good cause for the failure to timely answer the initial NOI. To show good cause, a respondent shall request a hearing in the manner provided by ยง3103 within fifteen
        (15) days of the date the second NOI is served. Upon a showing of good cause, an ALJ may either proceed to consider the infraction or require the respondent to request another hearing on the infraction.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3105.5.</num>
    <text>A respondent who fails to answer a second NOI within fifteen (15) days of service:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Shall have no right to a hearing on the infraction unless the respondent establishes good cause for the failure to answer; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Shall be required to appear at a hearing to show cause why the respondent&amp;#8217;s license or permit should not be suspended for such failure to answer.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 5718, 5723 (September 4, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>