<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-4102</num>
  <heading>USE OF DISTRICT PROPERTY AND FACILITIES (ยง 27-4102)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4102.1.</num>
    <text>Except as provided otherwise in this chapter, each contractor and subcontractor shall furnish all property necessary to perform District contracts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4102.2.</num>
    <text>If a contractor or subcontractor is permitted to use or otherwise possess District property, the contracting officer shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Eliminate to the maximum practical extent any competitive advantage that might arise from using District property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Require contractors (or subcontractors) to use the District property to the maximum practical extent in performing District contracts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Permit the property to be used only when authorized;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Charge appropriate rentals when the property is authorized for use on other than a rent-free basis;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Require contractors and subcontractors to be responsible and accountable for keeping records of District property in their possession or control;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Require contractors and subcontractors to review and provide justification for retaining District property not currently in use; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Ensure maximum practical reutilization of contractor inventory by the District.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4102.3.</num>
    <text>Contractors and subcontractors shall furnish all facilities required for performing District contracts except as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>When, as a result of the prospective contractor&amp;#8217;s written statement asserting inability or unwillingness to obtain facilities, the Director determines that the contract cannot be fulfilled by any other practical means; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>When the Director determines that it is in the best interests of the District to provide the facility.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4102.4.</num>
    <text>Competitive solicitations shall not include any offer by the District to provide District facilities unless adequate price competition cannot otherwise be obtained.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4102.5.</num>
    <text>Facilities may be provided to a contractor or subcontractor under a contract, other than a facilities contract, in any of the following situations:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The actual or estimated cumulative acquisition cost of the facilities provided at one place or general location does not exceed one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The contract is for construction; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The contract is for work within an establishment operated by the District.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4102.6.</num>
    <text>When a facilities contract is not used, the District&amp;#8217;s interests shall be protected by using a District property clause approved by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1736 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>