<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-1114</num>
  <heading>AFFIRMATIVE ACTION TRAINING PROGRAM (ยง 4-1114)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1114.1.</num>
    <text>Each contractor, in fulfilling its affirmative action responsibilities under a contract with the District of Columbia government, shall be required to have, as part of its Affirmative Action Program, an existing training program for the purpose of
      training, upgrading, and promotion of minority and female employees or to utilize existing programs. Those programs shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>To be consistent with its personnel requirements, the contractor shall make full use of the applicable training programs, including apprenticeship, on-the-job training, and skill refinement training for journeymen. Recruitment for the program shall
        be designed to provide for appropriate participation by minority group members and women;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The contractor may utilize a company-operated skill refinement training program. This program shall be formal and shall be responsive to the work to be performed under the contract;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The contractor may utilize formal private training institutions that have as their objective training and skill refinement appropriate to the classification of the workers employed. When training is provided by a private organization the following
        information shall be supplied:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name of the organization;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The name, address, social security number, and classification of the initial employees and any subsequent employees chosen during the course of the contract; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The identity of the trades, and crafts or skills involved in the training.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1114.2.</num>
    <text>If the contractor relies, in whole or in part, upon unions as a source of its workforce, the contractor shall use its best efforts, in cooperation with the unions, to develop joint training programs aimed toward qualifying more minorities and females
      for membership in the union, and increasing the skills of minority and female employees so that they may qualify for higher paying employment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1114.3.</num>
    <text>Approval of training programs by the Contracting Agency shall be predicated, among other things, upon the quality of training, numbers of trainees and trades, crafts or skills involved, and whether the training is responsive to the policies of the
      District of Columbia and the needs of the minority and female community. Minority and female applicants for apprenticeship or training should be selected in sufficient numbers as to ensure an acceptable level of participation sufficient to overcome
      the effects of past discrimination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 4952, 4962 (August 15, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>