<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-3708</num>
  <heading>SERVICE OF SUBPOENAS AND NOTICE OF DEPOSITION (§ 3-3708)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3708.1.</num>
    <text>A subpoena or a notice of a deposition shall be served upon a person by delivering a copy of the subpoena or notice to the named person, pursuant to this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3708.2.</num>
    <text>If a person is represented by counsel in a proceeding, a subpoena or a notice may be served upon counsel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3708.3.</num>
    <text>Service of a subpoena or a notice of deposition and fees to an individual may be made by any of the following means:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Handing the subpoena or notice to the person;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Leaving the subpoena or notice at the person’s office with the person in charge of the office;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Leaving the subpoena or notice at the person’s dwelling place or usual place of abode with some person of suitable age and discretion residing in that dwelling place or abode;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Mailing the subpoena or notice by registered or certified mail to the person at the person’s last known address with return receipt requested; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any other method whereby actual notice is given to the person.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3708.4.</num>
    <text>When the person to be served is not an individual, a copy of the subpoena or notice of the deposition and fees shall be delivered by one (1) of the following means:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Handing the subpoena or notice to a bona fide registered agent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Handing the subpoena or notice to any office, director, or agent in charge of any office of that entity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Mailing the subpoena or notice by registered or certified mail to a representative or agent of the entity at his or her last known address with return receipt requested; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any method whereby actual notice is given to an agent or representative of the entity.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 3161, 3207-08 (May 22, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 1402 (February 8, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11864 (August 16, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>