<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-121</num>
  <heading>PAYMENT FOR DENTAL SERVICES, PRESCRIPTION GOODS, PRESCRIPTION DRUGS AND MEDICALUPPLIES (ยง 29-121)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>121.1.</num>
    <text>The Rehabilitation Services Administration shall pay for dental services for eligible individuals under the following circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The dental condition is documented by a licensed and certified dental professional as:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Necessary to render the individual employable or required to prevent a serious physical illness; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A significant maxillofacial problem and/or disease of the gums that is a serious impediment to employment or may cause or aggravate specific health condition;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Comparable benefits are not available in accordance with ยง 114;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The dental consultant, who is not the treating dentist, has reviewed and approved the dental service to ensure that the service provided is necessary to achieve the individual&amp;#8217;s vocational goal or independent living goal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Rehabilitation Services Administration has approved the services for payment; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The treating dentist provides a post-dental service report.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>121.2.</num>
    <text>The Rehabilitation Services Administration shall purchase prescription goods, prescription drugs, and medical supplies under the following circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Rehabilitation Services Administration determines it is necessary to achieve the individual&amp;#8217;s vocational goal or independent living goal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Rehabilitation Services Administration determines that no comparable benefit is currently avail-able to the client, in accordance with ยง 114;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Rehabilitation Services Administration is provided a current, valid prescription from an authorized, licensed medical or other professional; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Unless a particular brand is specified by an authorized, licensed medical or other professional, the Rehabilitation Services Administration shall purchase generic drugs, goods and supplies.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>121.3.</num>
    <text>The Rehabilitation Services Administration shall procure authorized dental services, prescription goods, and medical supplies in accordance with the Procurement Practices Act (D.C. Official Code ยง 2-301 et. seq.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 6189 (August 1, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 6020 (June 22, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>