<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-153</num>
  <heading>PRE-HEARING CONFERENCE (§ 29-153)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>153.1.</num>
    <text>Upon the hearing examiner’s own motion or the motion of a party, the hearing examiner may request each party, or the party’s representative, to meet for a hearing conference to consider the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Simplification of the issues;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The amendment of documents for purposes of clarification, simplification, or limitation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Stipulations, admissions of fact, and authentication of documents;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Limitation of the number of parties and witnesses offered for the purpose of corroborating or establishing a single material fact or issue, or when the party has not furnished satisfactory evidence that the witness will be able to give testimony
        which is material to an issue at the hearing; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any other matters that may expedite the disposition of the proceeding and assure a just resolution of the complaint.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>153.2.</num>
    <text>Each pre hearing conference shall be held immediately prior to the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>153.3.</num>
    <text>The hearing examiner shall state on the record the stipulations, settlements, and other matters agreed to by each party or the party’s representative at the prehearing conference.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>153.4.</num>
    <text>The hearing examiner shall not be present while the parties are negotiating a voluntary settlement of the case.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 38 DCR 2034 (April 5, 1991); as amended by 54 DCR 6020 (June 22, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>