<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-123</num>
  <heading>THE ENTREPRENEURIAL PROGRAM (§ 29-123)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>123.1.</num>
    <text>The Rehabilitation Services Administration shall provide an entrepreneurial program that assists a client in starting his or her own business in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>123.2.</num>
    <text>When an eligible individual elects a self-employment outcome, the vocational rehabilitation counselor shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Explore and discuss with the individual the nature of the desired business, the feasibility of the business, and the individual&amp;#8217;s preparation for operating the business;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Prepare a written referral to the entrepreneurial program for the individual who wishes to pursue a self-employment goal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Schedule an interview for the individual and the counselor to consult with the entrepreneurial pro-gram;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Inform the individual about:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>How the entrepreneurial program works;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Required training and training sources for would-be entrepreneurs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The type of business funding that is available;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The type of funding the would-be entrepreneur must obtain to start the business enterprise; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The support services that are available to assist the entrepreneur in determining the feasibility of the business, preparing for the business, preparing the business plan, and seeking funding for the business;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Determine, along with the individual, any supportive services the individual may require to participate in the entrepreneurial training, prepare the business plan, and prepare for operation of the business; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>After receipt of the Entrepreneurial Program&amp;#8217;s report and recommendation for entrepreneurial ser-vices, develop an Individualized Plan for Employment (IPE) that addresses the individual&amp;#8217;s entrepreneurial goal, training needs
        and supportive services.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>123.3.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of a referral for entrepreneurial services, the Entrepreneurial Program shall consult with the individual and the counselor to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Assess the individual&amp;#8217;s:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Entrepreneurial interest;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Past training and related experiences;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Practical skills for operating a business; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Command of the skills necessary to operate a business or be self-employed in accordance with the entrepreneurial goal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Determine training required to prepare the individual to open and operate the determined business;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Assess how the individual&amp;#8217;s disability may affect his or her ability to operate the business; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Determine supports or services the individual may require to operate the business.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>123.4.</num>
    <text>The Entrepreneurial Program shall send a report and recommendation for services to the individual&amp;#8217;s counselor for IPE development to provide for the training and support services the individual requires to learn how to operate a business,
      develop a business plan and open and operate the business, after completion of an assessment of the individual&amp;#8217;s entrepreneurial skills and needs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>123.5.</num>
    <text>The Rehabilitation Services Administration may purchase goods and services for a business enterprise, including the occupational licenses, tools, equipment, initial stocks, and supplies necessary to open the business, in accordance with §§ 119, and
      120, only after the individual:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Demonstrates that he or she possesses the basic knowledge and skills required to manage a business through either:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Successful completion of training as required in the individual&amp;#8217;s IPE;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Successful completion of related courses; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Past work experience or entrepreneurial experience;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Submits a business plan completed in accordance with § 123.8, and approved by the Chief of the Entrepreneurial Program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Submits a request for funding; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Provides documentation of any additional funding secured for the business.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>123.6.</num>
    <text>In accordance with § 123.5 (a)(2), an individual may demonstrate knowledge and skills required to manage a business by providing documentation of completion of the following or comparable courses with a cumulative grade point average of &amp;#8220;C&amp;#8221;
      or better at an accredited college or university as a regular or non-degree student:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Entrepreneurship/self-employment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Principles of Accounting;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Introduction to Business;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Principles of Finance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Marketing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>123.7.</num>
    <text>In accordance with § 123.5(a)(3), an individual may demonstrate knowledge and skills required to manage a business through past work or entrepreneurial experience by providing the following documentation:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A detailed description of the work or entrepreneurial experience that he or she believes demonstrates the knowledge and skills required to operate a business;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The nature of the business;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Clientele served;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Numbers of clients/customers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The location of the business;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The number of years he or she operated the business; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The reason why the business ceased to operate or why the individual ceased to function with the business.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>123.8.</num>
    <text>In accordance with § 123.5(b), an individual must provide a business plan that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Describes the nature of the business and the income source;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Identifies funding sources other than the Rehabilitation Services Administration and projects income streams that are sufficient to maintain the business;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Provides a Five Year Plan for the business that addresses:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Five years of projected sales;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The targeted clientele;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The full range of services to be offered; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Sustainability of the business for a five-year period and in a down-turned market;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Identifies the specific items and costs for which the business is seeking funding from the Rehabilitation Services Administration and states the role they are to play in the operation of the business and generation of business income; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Is approved by the Chief of the Entrepreneurial Program.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>123.9.</num>
    <text>The Rehabilitation Services Administration, directly or through its training sources, shall assist the client in identifying a lending institution to which the client may apply for a business loan, if the client successfully completes all of the required
      training and develops a business plan that meets the Rehabilitation Services Administration&amp;#8217;s approval.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>123.10.</num>
    <text>An individual who is receiving services under an IPE which specifically identifies an entrepreneurial vocational goal before the effective date of this section shall continue to be served in accordance with their IPE until the vocational goal identified
      in the IPE is achieved or their record of service is closed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 6189 (August 1, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 6020 (June 22, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>