<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-101</num>
  <heading>PROCESSING REFERRALS AND APPLICATIONS (ยง 29-101)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>101.1.</num>
    <text>An individual may apply for vocational rehabilitation services by contacting the Rehabilitation Services Administration directly or upon referral by an individual, organization, public or private agency and other sources.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>101.2.</num>
    <text>The Rehabilitation Services Administration shall provide technical assistance regarding transitional activities that are available to students with disabilities upon receipt of a referral from the appropriate educational institutional authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>101.3.</num>
    <text>The individual or referral source shall, to the extent possible, make available to the Rehabilitation Services Administration medical, social and vocational information to assist in the determination of eligibility for vocational rehabilitation services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>101.4.</num>
    <text>The Rehabilitation Services Administration may schedule an orientation meeting for an individual upon initial contact or referral to explain the vocational rehabilitation process, the individual&amp;#8217;s rights, including the right to an appeal
      hearing, the right to pursue mediation, and the availability of the resources within the Client Assistance Program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>101.5.</num>
    <text>The Rehabilitation Services Administration shall schedule an interview for an individual with a vocational rehabilitation counselor upon completion of the orientation meeting to assist the individual to apply for vocational and other rehabilitation
      services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>101.6.</num>
    <text>The orientation meeting may be waived by the Chief, Client Services Division or his or her designee. If the orientation meeting is waived, the Client Services Division shall schedule an interview with a vocational rehabilitation counselor to assist
      the individual to apply for vocational rehabilitation services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>101.7.</num>
    <text>An individual shall be considered to have submitted an application for services when the individual or the individual&amp;#8217;s representative, as appropriate:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Applies for services by:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Completing and signing an application form;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Completing a common intake application form in a One-Stop center requesting vocational rehabilitation services; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Otherwise requesting services from the Rehabilitation Services Administration; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Has provided to the Rehabilitation Services Administration the information necessary to initiate an assessment to determine eligibility for services; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Is available to complete the assessment process.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 4611 (October 17, 1980); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 6189 (August 1, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>