<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-9313</num>
  <heading>ASSIGNMENT AND DELEGATION OF NURSING CARE TASKS TO HOME HEALTH AIDES (§7-9313)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>9313.1.</num>
    <text>A licensed nurse or health care professional may assign tasks to HHAs that are among the authorized tasks of the HHA listed in § 9315.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9313.2.</num>
    <text>HHAs shall not practice independently but shall work under the immediate supervision of a licensed nurse or other licensed health care professional if the supervisor determines that immediate supervision is necessary,or work under general supervision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9313.3.</num>
    <text>A registered nurse may delegate tasks to HHAs. The delegating registered nurse shall comply with the standards for delegation listed in 17 DCMR § 5415. Nursing care tasks that may be delegated shall be determined by:</text>
    <text>The knowledge and skills of the HHA;</text>
    <text>Verification of the clinical competence of the HHA by the employing agency;</text>
    <text>The stability of the client’s condition, including factors such as predictability, absence of risk of complication, and rate of change in health status; and</text>
    <text>The variables in each health care setting which include, but are not limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The accessible resources and established policies, procedures, practices, and channels of communication that lend support to the type of nursing tasks being delegated to the home health aide;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The complexity and frequency of care needed by a given client population; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The accessibility of a licensed nurse or other licensed health professionals.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9313.4.</num>
    <text>Nursing tasks that inherently involve on-going assessment, interpretation, or decision making that cannot be logically separated from one or more procedures shall not be delegated to the HHA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8359, 8368 (July 13, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>