<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-9321</num>
  <heading>SUPERVISED PRACTICE OF HOME HEALTH AIDE TRAINEES (§ 17-9321)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>9321.1.</num>
    <text>An HHA trainee may practice only in accordance with the Act and this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9321.2.</num>
    <text>A trainee who is fulfilling educational requirements under §§ 9312.1 and 9315.1 may engage in supervised practice without a District of Columbia certification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9321.3.</num>
    <text>All supervised practice of a trainee shall take place under the general or immediate supervision of a licensed nurse or other appropriate health professional.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9321.4.</num>
    <text>A trainee shall identify himself or herself as a trainee before practicing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9321.5.</num>
    <text>A trainee shall not receive compensation of any nature, directly or indirectly, from a client or client’s family member.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9321.6.</num>
    <text>The nurse supervising the trainee shall be responsible for all practice by a trainee during the period of supervision and may be subject to disciplinary action for violations of the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, effective
      March 15, 1986 (Act) (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code §§ 3-1201.01, et seq. (2007 Repl. &amp;#038; 2012 Supp.)) or this chapter by the trainee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9321.7.</num>
    <text>The Board may deny an application for certification by, or take other disciplinary action against, a trainee who is found to have violated the Act or this chapter. The Board may, in addition to any other disciplinary actions permitted by the Act,
      revoke, suspend, or restrict the privilege of the trainee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8359, 8372 (July 13, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>