<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-9324</num>
  <heading>HOME HEALTH AIDE PROGRAM APPROVAL PROCEDURES (§ 17-9324)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>9324.1.</num>
    <text>Each institution applying for approval to provide HHA training shall do the following:</text>
    <text>Submit to the Board a statement of intent to establish an HHA training program;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Submit to the Board a proposal to establish an HHA training program which shall contain the following information:</text>
    </level>
    <text>A statement of purpose;</text>
    <text>A statement of need for the training program in the District of Columbia;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A description of the proposed program’s potential effect on existing home health aide training programs in the area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The organizational structure of the institution showing the relationship of the proposed training program within the organization;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Evidence of adequate financial resources for planning, implementation, and continuation of the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Evidence of current licensure by the Education Licensure Commission or other Board-approved credentialing or accreditation organization;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The background and qualifications of the proposed instructors;</text>
    </level>
    <text>The number of full time equivalent (FTE) budgeted instructor positions;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Evidence of the availability of adequate clinical facilities;</text>
    </level>
    <text>(10) A description of the anticipated trainee population, including admission criteria and along with a copy of the admissions exam;</text>
    <text>(11) A tentative time schedule for planning and initiating the program; and</text>
    <text>(12) Fee schedules; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Submit the application fee.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9324.2.</num>
    <text>After reviewing the application, based on the applicant’s compliance with §§ 9327 and 9332, a decision shall be made to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Approve the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Defer approval if additional information is needed; or</text>
    </level>
    <text>Deny approval of the program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9324.3.</num>
    <text>If an application approval has been granted, a site visit shall be conducted by the Board in conjunction with the Education Licensure Commission staff to determine the program’s compliance with § 9327 and the program’s ability to meet criteria set
      forth in §§ 9331 and 9332.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9324.4.</num>
    <text>After reviewing the site visit report, the Board shall vote to approve, deny, or defer program approval for resource, facility, or service concerns.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9324.5.</num>
    <text>A training program shall not admit trainees to the program before the program has been approved by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8359, 8373 (July 13, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>