<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2712</num>
  <heading>ANTENNAS SUBJECT TO BZA APPROVAL &amp;#8211; GENERAL (ยง 11-2712)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2712.1.</num>
    <text>An application for special exception approval shall include the following written and graphic documentation:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A map of area to be served by the new antenna;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A map and explanation of the area being inadequately served that necessitates installation of the proposed antenna;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A map indicating the location of any other antennas and related facility sites providing service by the applicant, and any antenna tower or monopole of any provider, within a two mile radius, including public space, of the proposed antenna site,
        with identified heights above grade;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A site, and roof plan if applicable, showing all structures and antennas on site;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Elevation drawings of the structure and proposed antennas from all four directions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A picture of the proposed antenna;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The total mounted height of the antenna relative to the tops of surrounding trees as they presently exist within one-quarter (1/4) mile of the proposed location; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Other information as may be necessary for impact assessment of the antenna.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2712.2.</num>
    <text>In addition to any other conditions deemed necessary to mitigate potential adverse impacts, the Board may impose conditions pertaining to screening, buffering, lighting, or other matter necessary to protect adjacent and nearby property and may require
      the removal of any on-site non-conforming, inoperable, or unauthorized antenna.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 34 (January 4, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>