<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2700</num>
  <heading>PURPOSE (ยง 11-2700)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2700.1.</num>
    <text>The purposes of the regulation of antennas, antenna towers, and monopoles as a particular type of structure shall be as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Zoning Commission has determined that certain antennas, antenna towers, and monopoles because of their size, shape, design, construction, or location, may affect the welfare or safety of the population and may detract from the streetscape, landscape,
        skyline, scenic beauty, or aesthetic interests of Washington, D.C., and its role as the Nation&amp;#8217;s Capital;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Zoning Regulations therefore regulate the size, height, construction, design, and location of antennas, antenna towers, and monopoles which have the greatest potential for adverse impact on the health, safety, and welfare of the population,
        and on neighborhood quality, and those which have the greatest potential for adverse impact on the scenic beauty of the Nation&amp;#8217;s Capital and the national monuments; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The principal types of antennas, antenna towers, and monopoles regulated are those that, because of their shape, size, or quantity, potentially have the greatest visual impact and include, by example, large satellite earth station antennas, certain
        microwave terrestrial antennas, monopoles, and antenna towers.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.2.</num>
    <text>Consistent with these purposes, the construction of new towers or monopoles shall only be permitted subject to certain placement and construction standards.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 34 (January 4, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>