<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-3307</num>
  <heading>COMBINED LOTS (ยง 11-3307)
    <text>In any StE subdistrict with a minimum residential requirement, two (2) or moreots within such a subdistrict may be combined for the purpose of achieving theequired FAR equivalent of residential uses, subject to the following:</text>
    <text>The total height and density limits of the subdistrict(s) shall not be exceeded;nd</text>
    <text>The combined lot provisions may not be used to transfer density to or from anyroperty within the StE-2, StE-10, StE-14a, StE-14b, StE-18, or StE-19ubdistricts.</text>
    <text>No allocation of gross floor area shall be effective unless an instrument,egally sufficient to effect such a transfer, is filed with the Zoningdministrator and recorded by the Recorder of Deeds in the land records againstll lots included in the combined
      lot development.</text>
    <text>The instrument shall be in the form of a declaration of covenants that:</text>
    <text>Is signed by the owners of all affected parcels;</text>
    <text>Runs with the land in perpetuity;</text>
    <text>Burdens all parcels involved in the allocation of gross floor area; and</text>
    <text>States the maximum permitted gross floor areas for all uses in all parcels, theaximum allowed gross floor area for nonresidential uses in all parcels and theross floor area of nonresidential uses allocated. The covenant shall furthertate that, after
      the transfer, the combined lots conform to the maximum grossloor area limitations.</text>
    <text>The declaration of covenants shall expressly state that it may be substantivelymended or terminated only with the approval of the Zoning Administrator.</text>
    <text>The declaration of covenants shall be approved in content by the Zoningdministrator and certified for legal sufficiency by the Office of the Attorneyeneral. The declaration shall also contain a written statement by the Directorf the D.C. Office of
      Planning attesting to:</text>
    <text>The lots&amp;#8217; eligibility to allocate residential and nonresidential uses;</text>
    <text>The accuracy of the computations with respect to the amount of residential andonresidential uses allocated; and</text>
    <text>Whether, after the transfer, the combined lots will conform to the maximum grossloor area limitations for the lots before any such transfer.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 4834 (March 29, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>