<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-3309</num>
  <heading>OFF-STREET PARKING (§ 11-3309)
    <text>The cumulative total of all parking spaces, including below-grade, surface, andbove-grade structured parking, shall not exceed a total of four thousand eightundred (4,800) parking spaces, exclusive of parking on the StE-2 or StE-18ubdistricts, existing
      surface parking lots, historic structures, and anyarking associated with existing District of Columbia Government facilities.</text>
    <text>Each application to the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs for aevelopment that includes above-grade or below-grade structured parking orurface parking shall provide an accounting of the total number of parkingpaces within the StE District
      which count towards the four thousand eightundred (4,800) parking space limit.</text>
    <text>Additional parking spaces beyond the four thousand eight hundred (4,800) spaceimit shall be permitted by special exception by the Board of Zoning Adjustmentursuant to § 3104 and in accordance with the provisions of § 3304.2 and304.3, provided that
      the applicant addresses compliance with the followingtandards:</text>
    <text>The application shall include a detailed accounting of the existing and proposedumber and locations of parking spaces provided pursuant to § 3309.1; andhall also include a traffic study assessing the impacts of the proposeddditional parking spaces
      on local traffic patterns for referral to and commenty the District Department of Transportation;</text>
    <text>The applicant shall include a transportation demand management (TDM) plan, asell as District Department of Transportation analysis of the TDM plan. Thearameters of the analysis shall be outlined by the District Department ofransportation; and</text>
    <text>Vehicular access and egress will be located and designed so as to encourage safend efficient pedestrian movement, minimize conflict with principal pedestrianays, function efficiently, and create no dangerous or otherwise objectionableraffic conditions.</text>
    <text>For any application pursuant to § 3309.3:</text>
    <text>The Board shall judge, balance, and reconcile the need for additional on-sitearking against any adverse impacts the presence of the parking will have onraffic, and the aesthetics and development of the surrounding neighborhood; and</text>
    <text>The Board may impose requirements pertaining to design, appearance, signs,assing, landscaping, and other such requirements as it deems necessary torotect neighboring property and to achieve the purposes of the StE District.</text>
    <text>Any additional commuter parking, beyond parking that may exist as of (date ofnactment) within the StE-18, shall be for the exclusive use of residents of,mployees within, or visitors to the StE District or Federal employees of thedjacent Saint Elizabeths
      West Campus.</text>
    <text>Parking spaces shared by more than one use is permitted.</text>
    <text>Parking spaces need not be located on the same lot as the building or buildingshey are intended to serve, but must be located on a lot within the StE Districtther than the StE-18 or StE-19 subdistrict.</text>
    <text>Parking spaces shall not be located between a street right-of-way line and theore restrictive of either a building façade or a line extending from andarallel to a building façade. A building used solely as a parking attendanthelter shall not trigger
      this restriction.</text>
    <text>Parking spaces provided within a structure shall be located at least twenty feet20 ft.) from all lot lines that abut public streets, unless the surface of thearking spaces is at least ten feet (10 ft.) below grade, at all points alonghe building frontage.</text>
    <text>Parking spaces within an above-grade structure along 13th Street, Dogwoodtreet, and Sycamore Street shall be lined with preferred uses as defined in §305.1 on the ground floor to a depth of thirty feet (30 ft.) minimum.</text>
    <text>All parking spaces, other than mechanical parking spaces shall be accessible atll times from a driveway accessing either an improved street or an improvedlley or alley system with a minimum width of ten feet (10 ft.).</text>
    <text>Parking spaces provided within a mechanized parking system need not meet theccessibility requirement of § 3309.10 as long as the mechanized parking systemoes.</text>
    <text>Parking spaces and drive aisles shall be designed in accordance with thetandards of 11 DCMR Chapter 21 of this title.</text>
    <text>Where other options for access to parking spaces exist, such as from an alley or different street, access to parking shall not be from a section of streethere preferred uses are required in accordance with § 3305; or from Martinuther King Jr. Avenue,
      S.E., Dogwood Street, 13th Street, or Oak Drive.</text>
    <text>Approval of a driveway under this chapter shall not be interpreted to implyermission for a curb cut in public space. An applicant for a driveway with aurb cut in public space shall have the responsibility to obtain all otherecessary approvals and
      permissions.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 4834 (March 29, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>