<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-5703</num>
  <heading>NEW HEATING OIL UST SYSTEMS (§ 20-5703)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5703.1.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § 5700.10, each new heating oil underground storage tank, having a capacity of one thousand and one hundred (1,100) gallons or more, installed after November 12, 1993, whether of single or double-walled construction, shall be
      constructed of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Fiberglass-reinforced plastic;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Steel-fiberglass-reinforced plastic composite; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Steel and shall be cathodically protected in accordance with the requirements of § 5703.2.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5703.2.</num>
    <text>Each steel tank shall be cathodically protected by being coated with a suitable dielectric material, and, in addition:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Field-installed cathodic protection systems shall be designed by a corrosion expert; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Impressed current cathodic protection systems shall be designed to allow determination of current operating status as required by § 5901.6.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5703.3.</num>
    <text>Each cathodic protection system shall be operated and maintained in accordance with § 5901.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5703.4</num>
    <text>5703.4 Secondary containment systems shall be designed, constructed, and installed to do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Contain regulated substances released from the tank system until they are detected and removed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Prevent the release of regulated substances to the environment at any time during the operational life of the UST system; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>In accordance with § 6003.5, check for evidence of a release at least every thirty (30) days.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5703.5.</num>
    <text>Double-walled tanks shall be designed, constructed, and installed to do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Contain a release from any portion of the inner tank within the outer wall; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Detect the failure of the inner wall.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5703.6.</num>
    <text>External liner systems (including vaults) shall be designed, constructed, and installed to do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Contain one hundred ten percent (110%) of the capacity of the largest tank within its boundary;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Prevent the interference of precipitation or ground water intrusion with the ability to contain or detect a release of regulated substances; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Surround the tank completely and be capable of preventing lateral, as well as vertical migration of regulated substances.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 7835, 7855 (November 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7699 (October 1, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 6678 (August 21, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>