<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-3902</num>
  <heading>PROCEDURES UPON FILING PETITION (§ 14-3902)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3902.1.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of a petition, the Rent Administrator shall assign a case number to it, using the following prefixes:</text>
    <text>DOCUMENT PREFIX</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Tenant Petitions TP</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Hardship Petitions HP</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Capital Improvement Petitions CI</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Petitions for Substantial Rehabilitation SR</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Petitions for Changes in Related Services and Facilities SF</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Case numbers for Voluntary Agreements shall be indicated with the prefix VA</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Case numbers for Show Cause hearings shall be indicated with the prefix SC</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Case numbers for Compliance hearings shall be indicated with the word “COMPLIANCE”</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3902.2.</num>
    <text>The Rent Administrator shall enter the receipt and acceptance of each petition in a docket, which shall list the petition number, the address of the affected housing accommodation or rental unit, and the date on which the petition is scheduled to
      be heard before a hearing examiner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3902.3.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of a petition, the Rent Administrator shall, by first class mail, notify the adverse parties named in the petition of their right to a hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3902.4.</num>
    <text>In the case of tenant petitions, a copy of the petition shall be sent to the housing provider of the housing accommodation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3902.5.</num>
    <text>In the case of petitions filed by a housing provider, the housing provider shall provide for each tenant in the housing accommodation one (1) copy of the petition, and a postage paid envelope addressed to each tenant by name which contains the return
      address of the RACD. The copies shall be mailed to the tenants by the Rent Administrator.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 1336, 1352-53 (March 7, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>