<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-3910</num>
  <heading>DELEGATION OF AUTHORITY OF HEARING EXAMINERS (ยง 14-3910)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3910.1.</num>
    <text>Hearing examiners shall conduct fair and impartial hearings and take necessary actions to avoid delay in the disposition of petitions and other matters.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3910.2.</num>
    <text>Hearing examiners shall have all powers necessary to carry out the purposes of ยง 3910.1 in accordance with ยง 3900.3, unless otherwise limited by law including, but not limited to, the authority to do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Administer oaths and affirmations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Issue subpoenas in accordance with ยง 204(h) of the Act and this subtitle;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Convene hearings as appropriate and regulate the course of the hearing, maintain decorum, and exclude from the hearing any disruptive person(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Exclude witnesses, other than parties, during the examination of other witnesses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Rule on the use of discovery procedures as appropriate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Rule on offers of proof and receive relevant evidence;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Rule on all motions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Rule on all contested issues;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Request the filing of memoranda of law and the presentation of oral arguments with respect to any contested issue or any question of law;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Order the production of evidence and the appearance of witnesses whose testimony would be relevant and material;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Impose penalties, as provided by law and this subtitle; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Hold prehearing conferences for the settlement, and simplification of contested issues.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 1336, 1356 (March 7, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>