<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2499</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 11-2499)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2499.1.</num>
    <text>The provisions of § 199.1 and the definitions in that section shall be incorporated by reference in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2499.2.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms shall have the meaning ascribed:</text>
    <text>Affordable Housing &amp;#8211; housing where the occupant is paying no more than thirty-five percent (35%) of gross income for gross housing costs, excluding utility costs.</text>
    <text>Housing Trust Fund &amp;#8211; either the fund established under § 3 of the Housing Production Trust Fund Act of 1988, effective March 16, 1989 (D.C. Law 7-202; D.C. Official Code § 42-2802 (2001)(formerly codified at D.C. Code § 45-3102 (1996 Repl.)));
      or an organization that qualifies as a nonprofit organization under § 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved October 22, 1986 (68A Stat. 163; 26 U.S.C. § 501(c)(3)), and that also:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Exists primarily for the purpose of assisting in the production of affordable housing units;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Operates a trust fund that disburses money for affordable housing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Receives applications for funds directly from developers of affordable housing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Has adopted criteria for selection of projects and allocation of funds among various types of affordable housing developments; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Has been certified by the Director of the D.C. Department of Housing and Community Development as a qualifying nonprofit organization that also complies with the requirements of (a) through (d) of this definition.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Low-income households &amp;#8211; households whose incomes do not exceed eighty percent (80%) of the median income for the area, as determined by the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), with adjustments for smaller and larger families,
      except that HUD may establish income ceilings higher or lower than eighty percent (80%) of the median for the area on the basis of HUD&amp;#8217;s findings that such variations are necessary because of prevailing levels of construction costs or
      fair market rents, or unusually high or low family incomes. Note: HUD income limits are updated annually and are available from local HUD offices.</text>
    <text>Moderate-income households &amp;#8211; households whose incomes are between eighty-one percent (81%) and ninety-five percent (95%) of the median for the area, as determined by HUD, with adjustments for smaller or larger families, except that HUD may
      establish income ceilings higher or lower than ninety-five percent (95%) of the median for the area on the basis&amp;#8217; of HUD&amp;#8217;s findings that such variations are necessary because of prevailing levels of construction costs, fair market
      rents, or unusually high or low family incomes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 695, 700-01 (February 6, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8523-24 (October
        20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>