<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-1300</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 29-1300)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1300.1.</num>
    <text>This chapter governs the administrative actions the Department may take with respect to providers who participate in the District of Columbia Medicaid Program. The administrative actions are as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Exclusion, termination and/or suspension of a provider from the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Suspension of payments, in whole or in part, to recover or aid in the recovery of overpayments to a provider;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Suspension of payments, in whole or in part, to aid in determining if overpayments have been made to a provider or if a program payment is correct;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Determination by the Department of Human Services (DHS) of program reimbursement on the basis of cost reports filed by a provider;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Requests for reinstatement by a provider in the program; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Procedures to appeal actions taken under this subsection.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1300.2.</num>
    <text>This chapter shall be construed in conjunction with Title XIX of the Social Security Act, applicable federal regulations, pertinent District laws, regulations governing the District&amp;#8217;s Medicaid program pursuant to §1-359, D.C. Code, 1981
      ed., and the District of Columbia Office of Health Care Financing Provider Manual.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1300.3.</num>
    <text>This chapter shall not apply if the Department of Human Services does not reimburse a facility due to lack of certification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is D.C. Code, 2001 Ed. §1-307.02; Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1979, 3 D.C. Code, 2001 Ed. at 338; 42 C.F.R. §§431.54(f), 447.45, and 455.200 et seq.; and 42 U.S.C. §1396.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 3870 (August 3, 1984).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>