<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-1306</num>
  <heading>SUSPENSION OF MEDICAID PAYMENTS FOR OVERPAYMENT-PROCEEDING (ยง 29-1306)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1306.1.</num>
    <text>Whenever the Director has determined that a suspension of payments under ยง1305 shall be put into effect with respect to a provider, the Director shall notify the provider of his or her intention to suspend payments, in whole or in part, and the reasons
      for making the suspension.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.2.</num>
    <text>If the reason for suspending payments is that the Director has determined that the provider has been overpaid and the suspension is needed to aid in recovery, the notice to the provider under ยง1306.1 shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The factual basis for the determination of overpayments including the dollar value of the overpayment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>How the overpayment was computed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Specific reference to the particular sections of the statutes, rules, provider&amp;#8217;s manual and/or provider&amp;#8217;s agreement involved.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.3.</num>
    <text>If the reason for the intended suspension is that the Director has reliable evidence that the provider has been overpaid, the notice to the provider shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The reasons for making the suspension; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any actions the Director intends to take to determine if any overpayment has been made.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.4.</num>
    <text>Within thirty (30) days of the date in which the notice is sent to the provider under this section, the provider may submit documentary evidence and written argument against the proposed action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.5.</num>
    <text>For good cause shown, the Director may extend the thirty (30) day period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.6.</num>
    <text>If no statement is received from the provider within the thirty (30) day period or the additional thirty (30) day period specified in the notice, the suspension shall go into effect on the date after the end of the period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.7.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section shall not apply when the Director, after furnishing a provider a written notice of the amount of the program reimbursement pursuant to ยง1309, suspends payment under that section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 3870 (August 3, 1984).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>