<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-1900</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 27-1900)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1900.1.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this chapter shall apply to contracts for the provision of services, as defined in §107(42) of the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985 (the &amp;#8220;Act&amp;#8221;), D.C. Code §1-1181.7 (1981).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1900.2.</num>
    <text>The provisions of the Act and this title requiring competition and setting forth the requirements and procedures for competitive procurement shall apply to the procurement of services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1900.3.</num>
    <text>A contract for services may provide for services to be performed by professional or non-professional personnel on an individual or organizational basis.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1900.4.</num>
    <text>A contract may be used to provide services including, but not limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Maintenance, overhaul, and repair;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Routine recurring maintenance of real property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Housekeeping services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Consulting services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Engineering and technical services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Operation of District-owned equipment, facilities, and systems;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Communications services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Architectural and engineering services (in accordance with chapter 26 of this title);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Transportation and related services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Day care services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Janitorial services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Stenographic reporting services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Human care services (in accordance with §§ 1905 to 1908); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>Real property appraisal services (in accordance with §§1915 to 1922).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1900.5.</num>
    <text>Contracts for services that cross fiscal years or include multiyear provisions and which are funded by annual appropriations shall include a contract provision approved by the Director indicating that payment for services for the period other than
      the current fiscal year will be subject to the availability of funds.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1900.6.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall ensure that the applicable provisions of the Service Contract Act of 1965 (41 U.S.C. §§351-358) and any applicable wage determination are incorporated in accordance with federal regulations into all solicitations in accordance
      with chapter 43 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1900.7.</num>
    <text>In order to provide continuity of services between contractors, or when the District anticipates difficulties during the transition from one contractor to another, the contracting officer shall include a provision approved by the Director in the contract
      providing for phase-in training and other actions by the current contractor to effect an orderly transition to the successor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1900.8.</num>
    <text>Contracts for expert or consulting services shall not be awarded in a manner that gives preferential treatment to former District employees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, D.C. Law 6-85, as amended, D.C. Code §1-1181.1 et seq. (1981).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1489 (February 26, 1988); as amended by Emergency and Proposed rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8590 (October 20, 2000) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 5819 (June 22, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>