<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-1922</num>
  <heading>REAL PROPERTY APPRAISAL PERFORMANCE EVALUATIONS (ยง 27-1922)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1922.1.</num>
    <text>The contract administrator shall prepare a performance evaluation report for contracts of more than ten thousand dollars ($10,000) and may prepare a report for contracts of ten thousand dollars ($10,000) or less.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1922.2.</num>
    <text>The contract administrator shall prepare the performance report after final acceptance of the work or after contract termination, as appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1922.3.</num>
    <text>If the contract administrator concludes that the overall performance of a firm or individual is unsatisfactory, the contracting officer shall advise the firm or individual in writing that a report of unsatisfactory performance is being prepared and
      shall state the basis for the report.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1922.4.</num>
    <text>If the firm or individual responds to the notice issued under ยง1922.3 with any written comments, the contract administrator shall include them in the report, consider them in resolving any alleged factual discrepancies, and make appropriate changes
      in the report.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1922.5.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall review each performance report for accuracy and reasonableness.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1922.6.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall include the performance report in the contract file, and shall send a copy to the office responsible for maintenance of the firm&amp;#8217;s qualifications data. The office shall retain the report for at least six (6)
      years after the date of the report.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1503 (February 26, 1988); as amended by Emergency rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8590 (October 20, 2000) [EXPIRED].</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>