<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-1917</num>
  <heading>REAL PROPERTY APPRAISAL SERVICES SELECTION (ยง 27-1917)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1917.1.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall review the recommendations of the evaluation board and, with the advice of appropriate technical and staff representatives, shall make the final selection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1917.2.</num>
    <text>The final selection shall be a listing, in order of preference, of the firms or individuals considered most highly qualified to perform the work.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1917.3.</num>
    <text>If the firm or individual listed as the most preferred by the contracting officer is not the same as that recommended as the most highly qualified by the evaluation board, the contracting officer shall include in the contract file a written explanation
      of the reason for the selection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1917.4.</num>
    <text>All firms on the final selection list shall be considered &amp;#8220;selected firms&amp;#8221; with which the contracting officer may negotiate in accordance with ยง1915.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1917.5.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall not add firms to the selection report. If the firms recommended in the report are not deemed to be qualified or the report is considered inadequate for any reason, the contracting officer shall record the reasons and
      return the report to the evaluation board for appropriate revision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1917.6.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall promptly notify the board of the final selection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1917.7.</num>
    <text>After final selection has taken place, the contracting officer may release information identifying the real property appraisal firm with which a contract will be negotiated.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1500 (February 26, 1988); as amended by Emergency rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8590 (October 20, 2000) [EXPIRED].</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>