<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-8199</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 29-8199)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8199.1.</num>
    <text>The following terms and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Account &amp;#8211; a demand deposit account, checking or negotiable withdrawal order account, savings account, time deposit account, or money-market mutual fund account held in any financial institution.</text>
    <text>Active Case &amp;#8211; a case in which a current support order exists requiring the obligor to make periodic payments on behalf of his or her minor child.</text>
    <text>Arrears &amp;#8211; past due current child support payments.</text>
    <text>Arrears Only Case &amp;#8211; a case without a current support order in which arrears are owed.</text>
    <text>Current support &amp;#8211; amount of ongoing payments owed for a minor child under a support order.</text>
    <text>Data match &amp;#8211; the process of identifying assets held in financial institutions by obligors who owe child support.</text>
    <text>DCCSES &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia Child Support Enforcement System, the computer system used by CSSD to manage and enforce child support cases.</text>
    <text>Federal Parent Locator Service or FPLS &amp;#8211; the national system for locating custodial and non-custodial parents operated by the federal Office of Child Support Enforcement. The FPLS includes the database of Administrative Financial Institution
      Data Match.</text>
    <text>Financial institution &amp;#8211; a depository institution, institution-affiliated party, any Federal or State credit union, any benefit association, insurance company, safe deposit company, money-market mutual fund, or similar entity.</text>
    <text>Freeze &amp;#8211; to retain an obligor’s assets at the financial institution without allowing the obligor access to the assets.</text>
    <text>Funds &amp;#8211; monetary assets.</text>
    <text>Judgment support &amp;#8211; a court ordered amount that reflects a set period in the past during which child support should have been paid.</text>
    <text>Obligee &amp;#8211; the person or entity to whom child support is owed.</text>
    <text>Obligor &amp;#8211; a person who is required pursuant to a court or administrative order to pay child support.</text>
    <text>Wage withholding &amp;#8211; the direct retention of ongoing support payments from the wages or earnings of an obligor ordered to pay support.</text>
    <text>Writ of Attachment &amp;#8211; legal document that enforces a debt incurred by an obligor by freezing funds at a financial institution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Final Rulemaking at 55 DCR 11165 (October 24, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>