<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-202</num>
  <heading>ACCESSORY USES (R-1) (§ 11-202)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>202.1.</num>
    <text>The uses set forth in §§ 202.2 through 202.9 shall be permitted as accessory uses in an R-1 District incidental to the uses permitted in this chapter; provided, that the particular requirements for each use are met.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.2.</num>
    <text>The use of an office by a physician or dentist shall be permitted, if the following requirements are met:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The physician or dentist shall reside on the premises;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>No goods, chattel, wares, or merchandise shall be created commercially, exchanged, or sold in the office;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Exclusive of domestics, not more than two (2) persons who do not reside on the premises may be employed. No person so employed shall be a physician or dentist; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Only one (1) sign not over one square foot (1 ft.2) in area and affixed to the dwelling or free-standing shall be used. The sign, if illuminated, shall be white and nonflashing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.3.</num>
    <text>For purposes of § 202.2, the term &amp;#8220;physician&amp;#8221; shall include only a person who practices medicine.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.4.</num>
    <text>The child development home shall be permitted as an accessory use in an R-1 District incidental to the uses permitted in this chapter, if the following requirements are met:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The dwelling unit in which the use is located shall be the principal residence of the caregiver;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>There is used no more than one (1) sign or display, which shall not exceed one hundred forty-four square inches (144 in.2) in area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>No stock in trade is kept nor any commodity sold upon the premises;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>No person is employed other than a member of the caregiver&amp;#8217;s immediate family residing on the premises; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>No mechanical equipment is used except such as is permissible for purely domestic or household purposes.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.5.</num>
    <text>The elderly day care home shall be permitted as an accessory use in an R-1 District incidental to the uses permitted in this chapter if the requirements of the child development home are met.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.6.</num>
    <text>A maximum of two (2) roomers or boarders, who shall room or board in the main building, shall be permitted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.7.</num>
    <text>For a one family detached dwelling, in addition to any accessory parking space required by § 2101.1, either of the following is permitted:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>One (1) parking space for the exclusive use of the occupants or their guests; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>  Up to two (2) car-sharing spaces, neither of which may be a space devoted to required parking.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.8.</num>
    <text>Except as is provided in this subsection and § 203.6, no sale of products shall be permitted at a dwelling unit. During a twelve-month (12-month) period, one sale in the nature of a yard sale, garage sale, or home sales party may be held at a dwelling
      unit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.9.</num>
    <text>A home occupation shall be permitted, as provided in and subject to § 203.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.10.</num>
    <text>An accessory apartment may be added within an existing one-family detached dwelling if approved by the Board of Zoning Adjustment as a special exception under § 3104, subject to the following provisions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The lot shall have a minimum lot area for the following zone Districts:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Seven thousand, five hundred square feet (7,500 ft.²) for R-1-A;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Five thousand square feet (5,000 ft.²) for R-1-B; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Four thousand square feet (4,000 ft.²) for R-2 and R-3;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The house shall have at least two thousand square feet (2,000 ft.²) of gross floor area, exclusive of garage space;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The accessory apartment unit may not occupy more than twenty-five percent (25%) of the gross floor area of the house;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The new apartment may be created only through internal conversion of the house, without any additional lot occupancy or gross floor area; garage space may not be converted;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>If an additional entrance to the house is created, it shall not be located on a wall of the house that faces a street;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Either the principal dwelling or accessory apartment unit must be owner-occupied;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The aggregate number of persons that may occupy the house, including the principal dwelling and the accessory apartment combined, shall not exceed six (6);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>An accessory apartment may not be added where a home occupation is already located on the premises; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The Board may modify or waive not more than two (2) of the requirements specified in paragraphs (a) through (h) of this subsection; provided, that the following occurs:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The owner-occupancy requirement of paragraph (f) shall not be waived;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any modification(s) approved shall not conflict with the intent of this section to maintain a single-family residential appearance and character in the R-1, R-2, and R-3 Districts; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any request to modify more than two (2) of the requirements of this subsection shall be deemed a request for a use variance.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.11.</num>
    <text>Other accessory uses customarily incidental to the uses permitted in R-1 Districts under the provisions of this section, including mechanical amusement machines that are accessory to uses specified in § 210, shall be permitted, subject to the provisions
      of § 2501.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 6916 (September 16, 1988); renumbered by Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 6364 (September 3, 1993); and as amended by:</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 8284, 8286 (October 15, 1999); and Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8345, 8347 (October 20, 2000);
        as amended by Final Rulemaking and Order No. 09-16 published at 57 DCR 2961 (April 2, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>