<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-217</num>
  <heading>NON-PROFIT ORGANIZATIONS (R-1) (§ 11-217)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>217.1.</num>
    <text>The use of existing residential buildings and the land on which they are located by a nonprofit organization for the purposes of the nonprofit organization shall be permitted as a special exception in an R-1 District in the following instances if
      approved by the Board of Zoning Adjustment under § 3104, subject to the provisions of this section:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If the building is listed in the District of Columbia&amp;#8217;s Inventory of Historic Sites contained in the comprehensive statewide historic preservation survey and plan prepared pursuant to § 101(a) of the National Historic Preservation Act,
        approved October 15, 1966 (80 Stat. 915, as amended; 16 U.S.C. § 470a), or, if the building is located within a district, site, area, or place listed on the District of Columbia&amp;#8217;s Inventory of Historic Sites; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the gross floor area of the building in question, not including other buildings on the lot, is ten thousand square feet (10,000 ft.2) or greater;</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>217.2.</num>
    <text>Use of existing residential buildings and land by a nonprofit organization shall not adversely affect the use of the neighboring properties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>217.3.</num>
    <text>The amount and arrangement of parking spaces shall be adequate and located to minimize traffic impact on the adjacent neighborhood.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>217.4.</num>
    <text>No goods, chattel, wares, or merchandise shall be commercially created, exchanged, or sold in the residential buildings or on the land by a nonprofit organization, except for the sale of publications, materials, or other items related to the purposes
      of the nonprofit organization.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>217.5.</num>
    <text>Any additions to the building or any major modifications to the exterior of the building or to the site shall require the prior approval of the Board. The Board shall refer any proposed additions or modifications to the State Historic Preservation
      Officer, who, acting with the advice of the D.C. Professional Review Committee for nominations to the National Register of Historic Places, shall provide the Board with a report to determine possible detrimental consequences that the proposed addition
      or modification may have on the architectural or historical significance of the building or site or district in which the building is located.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§ 3101.414 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 20 DCR 583 (January 28, 1974); as renumbered by Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 6916, 6918 (September 16, 1988); Final Rulemaking published
        at 36 DCR 1509, 1517 (February 24, 1989); and as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8352 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>