<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-2301</num>
  <heading>CATEGORIES OF PESTICIDE APPLICATORS (§ 20-2301)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2301.1.</num>
    <text>Individuals shall make application to the Director on the appropriate forms for certification in one (1) of the categories or subcategories of pest control outlined in this subsection (subject categories are numerically classified in accordance with
      40 CFR § 171.3):</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Ornamental and Turf Pest Control &amp;#8211; this category includes commercial applicators using or supervising the use of pesticides to control pests in the maintenance and production of ornamental trees, shrubs, flowers, and turf. This category
        contains the following subcategories:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Exterior Ornamental Plants;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Lawns and Turf; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Interior Ornamental Plants.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Aquatic Pest Control &amp;#8211; this category includes commercial applicators using or supervising the use of pesticides purposefully applied to standing or running water, excluding applicators engaged in public health-related activities included
        in § 2301.1(e);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Right of Way Pest Control &amp;#8211; this category includes commercial applicators using or supervising the use of pesticides in the maintenance of public roads, electric powerlines, pipelines, railway right-of-way, or other similar areas;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Industrial, Institutional, Structural, and Health Related Pest Control &amp;#8211; this category includes commercial applicators using or supervising the use of pesticides in, on, or around food handling establishments, human dwellings, industrial
        establishments (including warehouses and grain elevators), institutions such as schools and hospitals, and any other protection of stored, processed, or manufactured products. This category contains the following subcategories:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>General Pest Control &amp;#8211; preventing, repelling, or controlling insects, fungi, or other pests within or adjacent to structures of any kind, or the adjacent grounds, or where people may assemble or congregate. This subcategory does not include
        work otherwise defined in §§ 2301.1(d)(2) through 2301.1(d)(6);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Wood Destroying Organism &amp;#8211; preventing, repelling, or controlling termites, powder post beetles, fungi, or wood destroying organisms in or on structures of any kind of pre-treating areas or the surrounding grounds where the structures are
        to be constructed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Bird Control &amp;#8211; preventing, repelling, or controlling nuisance birds;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Fumigation &amp;#8211; the use of a fumigant within an enclosed space for the destruction of a pest, not including space treatment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Rodent Control &amp;#8211; preventing, repelling, or controlling rodents; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Industrial Weed Control &amp;#8211; preventing, repelling, or controlling weeds on industrial or commercial sites;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Public Health Pest Control &amp;#8211; this category includes District and federal governmental employees using or supervising the use of pesticides in public health programs for the management and control of pests having medical and public health
        importance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Regulatory Pest Control &amp;#8211; this category includes District and federal governmental employees who use or supervise the use of pesticides in the control of regulated pests;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Demonstration and Research Pest &amp;#8211; Control this category includes the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Individuals who demonstrate to the public the proper use and techniques of application of restricted use pesticides, or who supervise the public demonstration. Included in this group is any person who is an extension specialist, or a commercial
        representative demonstrating restricted use pesticide products, and anyone demonstrating methods used in public programs; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Persons conducting field research with restricted use pesticides and, in doing so, use or supervise the use of restricted use pesticides. Included in this group is any District, federal, commercial, or other person conducting field research on or
        utilizing restricted use pesticides.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Miscellaneous Pest Control &amp;#8211; this category includes commercial applicators using or supervising the use of a pesticide(s) for the management and control of pests which are not related to or described in paragraphs (a) though (g).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2301.2.</num>
    <text>The following categories of pest control certification are not available in the District of Columbia:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Agriculture Pest Control &amp;#8211; including the following subcategories:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Plant; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Animal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Forest Pest Control; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Seed Treatment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 3044 (October 6, 1978), incorporating Proposed Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 2118 (August 25, 1978); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 30 DCR 2204, 2205 (May 13, 1983).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>