<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-2303</num>
  <heading>COMMERCIAL APPLICATORS[COLON] DETERMINATION OF COMPETENCY (ยง 20-2303)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2303.1.</num>
    <text>To be certified as competent in the use and handling of pesticides, an applicant shall meet the requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.2.</num>
    <text>Each applicant for certification shall pass a written examination (and, where appropriate, a performance test) administered by the Director in each category or subcategory for which the applicant seeks to be certified.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.3.</num>
    <text>The required examinations and testing shall be based upon the standards set forth in ยง 2303 and which are approved by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.4.</num>
    <text>The required examinations and testing shall include the general standards applicable to all categories and the additional standards specifically identified for each category or subcategory (if any) in which an applicator is to be certified.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.5.</num>
    <text>Each applicant shall give written notice to the Director at least two (2) weeks prior to the scheduled examination date and shall specify any category or subcategory in which the applicant seeks to demonstrate competence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.6.</num>
    <text>Examinations shall be administered at least two (2) times a year at locations and times designated and announced by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.7.</num>
    <text>To become certified in any category or subcategory, an applicant shall be required to pass the following two (2) separate written examinations:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A general, core examination; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A category examination which shall be specific to the category(ies) or subcategory (ies) as described in ยง 2301 of this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.8.</num>
    <text>There shall be no charge for the initial examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.9.</num>
    <text>A ten dollar ($ 10) fee shall be charged for each re-examination session.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.10.</num>
    <text>[Deleted]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.11.</num>
    <text>A passing score for any examination shall consist of a total correct score equal to or exceeding seventy percent (70%) of the total points on the examination as graded by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.12.</num>
    <text>Each person who takes an examination shall be notified of the results of the examination on a pass-fail basis.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.13.</num>
    <text>An applicant, who fails the general core or category examination may not reapply to take that examination until thirty (30) days after the date of the last failed examination.</text>
    <text>2303 14 Each applicant who has successfully completed the requirements for certification shall be notified by the Director stating the category(ies) or subcategory (ies) in which competency has been demonstrated.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.15.</num>
    <text>The certification shall be valid only when accompanied by a current pesticide applicator&amp;#8217;s license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.16.</num>
    <text>A certified applicator who elects to add one (1) or more categories or subcategories to an existing certification shall be required to take only the category examination for each new category or subcategory for which certification is desired.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.17.</num>
    <text>Any applicator who has any part of his or her certification suspended or revoked may be required to submit to re-examination in those categories or subcategories for which the applicator seeks to be recertified.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 3044 (October 6, 1978), incorporating Proposed Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 2118 (August 25, 1978); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 30 DCR 2204, 2205 (May 13, 1983).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>