<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-6114</num>
  <heading>TENANT SELECTION AND ASSIGNMENT[COLON] COMPREHENSEIVE MODERNIZATION PROPERTIESND NEW DEVELOPMENT (ยง 14-6114)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6114.1.</num>
    <text>Tenants and applicants shall be required to meet the following additional criteria prior to being assigned to a comprehensive modernization or newly developed housing property:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Attend a mandatory training program (if available and offered);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be current in rent and other charges (for current DCHA tenants);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Not be in violation of the dwelling lease (for current DCHA tenants); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Meet the criteria set forth in Section 6105 of this Chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6114.2.</num>
    <text>As renovated units become available for initial occupancy at comprehensive modernization properties, vacancies shall be filled (by tenants or applicants meeting the criteria of Subsection 6113.1) based on the following priorities:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>First preference to former property residents who were relocated to another DCHA dwelling unit or relocated with a Housing Choice Voucher;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Second preference to DCHA tenants in other properties who have been identified as inappropriately housed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Third preference to other tenants who have requested a transfer; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Fourth preference to applicants from the DCHA waiting list.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6114.3.</num>
    <text>Consistent with the priorities listed in Subsection 6113.2, tenants or applicants shall be assigned to available units in accordance with Subsection 6111.5 of this Chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6114.4.</num>
    <text>As units become available for initial occupancy at newly developed housing, the priorities in Subsection 6113.2 shall be applied, except that Subsection 6113.2(a) shall not be applicable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 7973, 8002 (December 26, 1986); and Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 603 (January 22, 1999), incorporating by reference the text of Notice of Proposed Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 7913,
        7914 (November 6, 1998); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 5739 (July 18, 2003); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 10365 (December 5, 2003); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published
        at 51 DCR 9184 (September 24, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>