<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-6103</num>
  <heading>WAITING LISTS (ยง 14-6103)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6103.1.</num>
    <text>DCHA maintains waiting lists for its Public Housing Program and for its Housing Choice Voucher Tenant Based and Moderate Rehabilitation Programs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6103.2.</num>
    <text>Applicants will identify the waiting list or waiting lists their names will be placed on. The waiting lists are organized by date and time of application and order of any applicable preference.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6103.3.</num>
    <text>The waiting lists list shall be maintained to ensure that applicants are referred to suitable unit types (for example for public housing, Mixed Population, General Population or accessible) and sizes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6103.4.</num>
    <text>Applicants who meet the criteria for the preferences of this Chapter may have priority over applicants without preferences.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6103.5.</num>
    <text>Applicant families which include persons with disabilities who require specific accessibility features shall receive priority for those units designed with specific accessibility features.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6103.6.</num>
    <text>The only other system for assigning priority to eligible public housing applicants is date and time of application, unless otherwise specified in this Chapter including Sections 6111, 6112 and 6113 of this Chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6103.7.</num>
    <text>DCHA will mail a waiting list update form to each applicant periodically.</text>
    <text>Applicants who return a completed update form to the DCHA within the time frame specified in the update package, shall retain their place on the waiting list and remain active;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the applicant indicates that his or her circumstances have changed, the appropriate changes shall be made on the waiting list;</text>
    </level>
    <text>Applicants who do not return the completed update form within the specified time frame shall have their waiting list status changed to inactive:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An applicant whose status is inactive will not receive offers of housing placement from DCHA; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If an inactive applicant submits a completed update form at any time after the expiration of the specified time frame, then the applicant shall be restored to active status on the waiting list with the applicant&amp;#8217;s original application
        date; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>If an applicant has been inactive for three (3) years prior to October 1,</text>
    </level>
    <text>2006, for all types of housing assistance offered by DCHA and requested by the applicant; the applicant must reapply for any type of housing assistance offered by DCHA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6103.8.</num>
    <text>Each applicant shall ensure that DCHA maintains his or her current mailing address at all times. Each change of address shall be reported in writing by the applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6103.9.</num>
    <text>All applicants who update their applications shall be notified in writing of receipt of their updated information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 7973, 7987 (December 26, 1986); and Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 603 (January 22, 1999), incorporating by reference the text of Notice of Proposed Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 7913,
        7914 (November 6, 1998); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 10308 (November 15, 2002); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 5739 (July 18, 2003); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published
        at 50 DCR 10350 (December 5, 2003); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 8233 (September 23, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>