<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-6104</num>
  <heading>TEMPORARY CLOSURE OF THE WAITING LIST (ยง 14-6104)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6104.1.</num>
    <text>If the number of families on the public housing or Housing Choice Voucher Program waiting list is such that there is no reasonable prospect that additional applicants for specific units types or sizes can be housed within the next twelve (12) months,
      the Executive Director, DCHA may approve action to do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Suspend the taking of further applications for certain unit types, unit sizes, or projects developed for special purposes; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Limit application taking to certain specified periods of the year.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6104.2.</num>
    <text>When action is taken to suspend, limit or reopen the taking of applications, DCHA shall make known to the public through publication of notice in the D.C. Register and in newspaper(s) of general circulation, minority media, and other suitable means
      the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The nature of the action; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The effective date of the action.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6104.3.</num>
    <text>Action to suspend, limit or reopen the taking of applications shall not take effect without at least ten (10) calendar days advance notice to the public in accordance with Subsection 6104.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6104.4.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the suspension of application taking, DCHA may continue to take applications from priority applicants eligible for priority placement on the waiting list pursuant to Subsection 6105.2 of this Chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 7973, 7988 (December 26, 1986); and Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 603 (January 22, 1999), incorporating by reference the text of Notice of Proposed Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 7913,
        7914 (November 6, 1998); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 5739 (July 18, 2003); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 10347, 10351 (December 5, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>