<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-7708</num>
  <heading>APPROVED CONTINUING EDUCATION PROGRAMS AND ACTIVITIES (ยง 17-7708)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7708.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may, in its discretion, approve continuing education programs and activities that contribute to the growth of an applicant in professional competence in the practice of marriage and family therapy and that meet the other requirements of
      this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7708.2.</num>
    <text>The Board may approve the following types of continuing education if the programs or activity meets the requirement of section 7708.1:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An undergraduate or graduate course given at an accredited college or university;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A seminar or workshop;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An educational program given at a conference;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Engaging in instructional hours while serving as an instructor or speaker at an institution of higher learning, conference, seminar, workshop, or in-service training;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Professional writing, excluding reprints or republications of previously published materials, published within the two (2) years prior to the license renewal date, which consist of articles or books that meet the following requirements:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Journal articles shall be published in professional journals; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Chapters authored in books acceptable under this section;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Participation in research as a principal investigator or research assistant; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Informal study or a home study program (documented by title, author, name of topic, time spent, written summary, and date(s) completed) carried out individually that is approved by the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7708.3.</num>
    <text>A continuing education program shall meet all of the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be current in its subject matter and taught by qualified individuals;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be approved by the Board; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Meet one of the following requirements:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be administered or approved by a health care organization, accredited health care facility, or accredited college or university; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Be submitted by the program sponsors to the Board for review no less than sixty (60) days prior to the date of the presentation and be approved by the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7708.4.</num>
    <text>The Board may issue and update a list of approved continuing education programs or providers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 7845 (September 29, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 8247 (August 24, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>