<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-7799</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 17-7799)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7799.1.</num>
    <text>As used in this chapter, the following terms shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Allied Field &amp;#8211; academic study in, or performing the professional functions associated with, psychology, social work, psychiatry, professional counseling, or other comparable mental health profession.</text>
    <text>Applicant &amp;#8211; a person applying for a license to practice marriage and family therapy under this chapter.</text>
    <text>Board &amp;#8211; the Board of Marriage and Family Therapy, established by section 217 of the Act, as amended by the Marriage and Family Therapy Amendment Act of 2003, effective March 10, 2004 (D.C. Law 15-88; D.C. Official Code ยง 3-1202.17).</text>
    <text>General supervision &amp;#8211; supervision in which an approved marriage and family therapist is available to the supervisee either in person or by a communications device.</text>
    <text>Good cause &amp;#8211; a legally sufficient reason for granting an extension because of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Serious or protracted illness of the applicant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The death or serious and protracted illness of a member of the applicant&amp;#8217;s immediate family; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Deployment in a combat zone by the military whenever the United States is engaged in active military operations against any foreign power.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Group supervision &amp;#8211; supervision in which an approved marriage and family therapist is available in person to between three (3) and five (5) supervisees.</text>
    <text>Immediate supervision &amp;#8211; face-to-face supervision in which an approved marriage and family therapist, psychologist, psychiatrist, licensed independent clinical social worker, licensed professional counselor, or advanced practice nurse is
      either discussing or observing the supervisee&amp;#8217;s practice.</text>
    <text>Individual supervision &amp;#8211; supervision in which an approved marriage and family therapist is available in person to one (1) or two (2) supervisees.</text>
    <text>Instructional hours &amp;#8211; the amount of time spent in actual presentation excluding preparation hours.</text>
    <text>Marriage and family therapist &amp;#8211; a person licensed to practice marriage and family therapy under the Act.</text>
    <text>Unlicensed marriage and family therapist &amp;#8211; a person who has completed the educational requirements for a degree in marriage and family therapy but has not met the clinical requirements for licensure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 7845 (September 29, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 8247 (August 24, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>