<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-3219</num>
  <heading>SUSPENSION OR REDUCTION OF PROGRESS PAYMENTS (ยง 27-3219)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3219.1.</num>
    <text>In each contract that provides for progress payments, the contracting officer shall include provisions, approved by the Director, which assert the District&amp;#8217;s right to reduce or suspend progress payments, or increase the liquidation rate,
      as appropriate, in the following circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If the contractor fails to maintain an efficient and reliable accounting system and controls that are adequate for the proper administration of progress payments;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the contracting officer determines that contract performance, including full liquidation of progress payments, is endangered by the contractor&amp;#8217;s financial condition or by a failure to make progress on the performance of the contract;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If the inventory allocated to the contract exceeds reasonable requirements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>If the contractor is delinquent in paying the costs of contract performance in the ordinary course of business;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>If the unliquidated progress payments exceed the fair value of undelivered work under the contract; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>If the sum of the total costs incurred under a contract, plus the estimated costs to complete performance, are likely to exceed the contract price.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3219.2.</num>
    <text>Actions under this section shall only be taken in accordance with the contract terms and only after the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The contracting officer gives notice to the contractor of the intended action and provides an opportunity for discussion; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The contracting officer evaluates the effect of the action on the contractor&amp;#8217;s operations, based on the contractor&amp;#8217;s financial condition, projected cash requirements, and the existing or available credit arrangements.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3219.3.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall take immediate unilateral action only if warranted by circumstances such as overpayments or unsatisfactory contract performance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3219.4.</num>
    <text>In all cases, the contracting officer shall document the contract file with evidence supporting the contracting officer&amp;#8217;s decisions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1633 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>