<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-3299</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 27-3299)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3299.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Advance payments &amp;#8211; payments made prior to performance of services or delivery of goods.</text>
    <text>Appropriate fiscal authority &amp;#8211; the budget officer, controller, or other designated District official.</text>
    <text>Assignment of contract payments &amp;#8211; the transfer by a contractor to a financial institution of the contractor&amp;#8217;s right to receive payments under the contract.</text>
    <text>Capitation Rate &amp;#8211; The monthly rate per enrollee, fixed annually in advance, paid to a contracted managed care plan for managing the services described in the contracted evidence of coverage, whether or not the enrollee receives services
      during the period covered by the rate.</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; the Director of the Office of Contracting and Procurement or the District of Columbia Chief Procurement Officer.</text>
    <text>Disbursing officer &amp;#8211; the District employee responsible for making payments in settlement of a debt.</text>
    <text>Fixed assets &amp;#8211; property used in operating a business which will not be consumed or converted into cash or its equivalent. It includes machinery, land, and buildings.</text>
    <text>Medicaid Managed Healthcare Program (MMCP) &amp;#8211; a program for the provision and management of specified Medicaid services through contracted health maintenance organizations. The MMCP was established pursuant to the Medicaid Managed Care Amendment
      Act of 1992, effective March 17, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-247, D.C. Official Code. ยง 1-307.02) as amended.</text>
    <text>Partial payment &amp;#8211; the reduction of any debt or demand for payment of a sum less than the whole amount originally due.</text>
    <text>Progress payment &amp;#8211; a payment made on the basis of services completed or goods delivered. Progress payments are either customary or unusual. Customary progress payments are those based on rates specified in ยง3201.5. Unusual payments are those
      authorized at rates higher than those specified in ยง3201.5.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1648 (February 26, 1988); as Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 5562 (June 15, 2001); as Emergency Rulemaking48 DCR 8457 (September 7, 2001) [EXPIRED]; as Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 7918 (August 16,
        2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>