<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5699</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 17-5699)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5699.1.</num>
    <text>As used in this chapter, the following terms have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Act &amp;#8211; Health Occupation Revision Act of 1985 (&amp;#8220;Act&amp;#8221;), effective March 25, 1986(D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code §§ 3-1201.01 et seq.).</text>
    <text>Accreditation &amp;#8211; Board approval to operate a basic nursing program or advanced practice nursing education program in the District of Columbia that is granted only after specified requirements, standards, and conditions have been met.</text>
    <text>Advanced practice program &amp;#8211; a post-basic nursing education program at the master&amp;#8217;s degree or doctoral degree level, whose purpose is to prepare students for practice as nurse-anesthetists, nurse-midwives, nurse-practitioners, or
      clinical nurse specialists.</text>
    <text>Advanced practice nurse &amp;#8211; a registered nurse who has completed an advanced practice nursing education program and has been certified by the Board to practice as a nurse-anesthetist, nurse-midwife, nurse-practitioner, or clinical nurse specialist.</text>
    <text>Basic program &amp;#8211; a nursing education program at the certificate, associate degree, or baccalaureate degree level, whose purpose is to prepare students for practice as practical or registered nurses.</text>
    <text>Board &amp;#8211; the Board of Nursing, established by § 204 of the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6- 99; D.C. Official Code § 3-1203.02(14)).</text>
    <text>CCNE &amp;#8211; Commission on Collegiate Nursing Education.</text>
    <text>Clinical agency &amp;#8211; an agency which provides the facilities for clinical learning experiences in nursing, with the faculty or the clinical instructor of the program responsible for the planning, implementing, and evaluating of the experiences.</text>
    <text>Clinical &amp;#8211; faculty planned and guided learning activities designed to assist students in meeting course objectives and to apply nursing knowledge and skills in the direct care of patients, including clinical conferences and planned learning
      activities in acute care facilities, and other community resources. Clinical shall not include skills lab activities.</text>
    <text>Clinical preceptor &amp;#8211; an individual meeting the requirements of this chapter that is an employee of a clinical agency who works with a nursing student in a clinical setting to facilitate student learning in a manner specified in a signed
      written agreement between the agency and the educational institution.</text>
    <text>Clinical preceptorship &amp;#8211; an organized system of clinical experiences which allows a nursing student to be paired with a clinical preceptor for the purpose of attaining specific learning objectives.</text>
    <text>Conditional accreditation &amp;#8211; the accreditation status that is granted, for a time period specified by the Board, to a nursing school or program to correct deficiencies when the nursing school or program has failed to meet or maintain the
      requirements and standards of this chapter.</text>
    <text>Controlling institution &amp;#8211; a college, university, public agency, or institution responsible for the administration and operation of a nursing school in the District.</text>
    <text>Full accreditation &amp;#8211; the accreditation status that is granted to a program after the graduation of its first class and after the Board has determined that the requirements and standards of this chapter have been met.</text>
    <text>Initial accreditation &amp;#8211; the accreditation status that is granted to a newly established nursing school or program that has not graduated its first class. The status is granted after the Board has determined that the standards and requirements
      of this chapter are being met and continues until after the first class has graduated.</text>
    <text>Management course &amp;#8211; a course offering both didactic and clinical content in clinical decision making and aspects of medical diagnosis and medical management of diseases and conditions.</text>
    <text>National Norm &amp;#8211; as published by the National Council of State Boards of Nursing (NCSBN).</text>
    <text>NCLEX- National Council Licensure Examination.</text>
    <text>NLNAC &amp;#8211; National League for Nursing Accrediting Commission.</text>
    <text>Nursing process &amp;#8211; the problem solving techniques of assessment, planning, implementing, and evaluating a plan of care, which requires technical and scientific knowledge, judgment, and decision making skills.</text>
    <text>Nursing school &amp;#8211; a school of nursing offering a basic program or an advanced practice program in nursing.</text>
    <text>Practical nurse &amp;#8211; a person licensed to practice practical nursing pursuant to chapter 55 of this Title.</text>
    <text>Registered nurse &amp;#8211; a person licensed to practice registered nursing pursuant to chapter 54 of this Title.</text>
    <text>Trending &amp;#8211; the process of studying or evaluating an observable fact or occurrence over a period of time.</text>
    <text>Withdrawal of Accreditation &amp;#8211; Board revocation of the approval to operate a nursing education program or advanced practice nursing education program within the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 7190 (July 23, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 2116 (March 9, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>