<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5603</num>
  <heading>FULL ACCREDITATION OF BASIC PRELICENSURE PROGRAMS (ยง 17-5603)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5603.1.</num>
    <text>Before being granted full accreditation a nursing school shall submit a self-evaluation report of compliance with the provisions of this chapter following the graduation of its first class.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5603.2.</num>
    <text>The Board may recommend a site visit in conjunction with ELC for consideration of full accreditation of a program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5603.3.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant full accreditation to a program after the graduation of its first class if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The percentage of the program&amp;#8217;s first time NCLEX test takers passing the exam is not more than five percent (5%) below the national norm. The passing percentage shall be based on the cumulative results of the first two (2) quarters following
        graduation of the first class; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The program has demonstrated continued ability to meet the standards and requirements of this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5603.4.</num>
    <text>Before granting full accreditation of a program, the Board shall review the program&amp;#8217;s annual report and survey reports for granting accreditation or continued accreditation of programs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5603.5.</num>
    <text>The Board may recommend deadlines for submission of materials and survey materials.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5603.6.</num>
    <text>The Board shall annually review the NCLEX performance of first time test takers from each program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5603.7.</num>
    <text>In order to maintain full accreditation status, a program with full accreditation shall maintain:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>All the standards and requirements of this chapter, as they may be amended or republished from time to time;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A minimum pass rate, for first time test takers on the NCLEX, of not more than five percent (5%) below the national norm, based on the cumulative results of the four (4) quarters in each year; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Accreditation with NLNAC, CCNE, or other accrediting bodies approved by the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5603.8.</num>
    <text>Full accreditation status shall be renewed annually. Each program having full Board accreditation, shall apply for renewal of accreditation not less than sixty (60) days prior to the date of expiration by submitting the following to the Board:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A written annual report on forms provided by the Board; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Payment of the required renewal fee.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5603.9.</num>
    <text>At the Board&amp;#8217;s discretion, the Board may designate persons to perform announced or unannounced on-site visits to a nursing school.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5603.10.</num>
    <text>Nursing programs that are currently accredited by the Board as of the effective date of these regulations, shall have twelve (12) months from the effective date to come into compliance with these regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5603.11.</num>
    <text>The Board may, at its discretion, grant an extension of the twelve (12) month period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5603.12.</num>
    <text>An extension shall not be granted in cases where the Board determines that the program has not made reasonable efforts to comply with the regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 7190 (July 23, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 2116 (March 9, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>