<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5601</num>
  <heading>INITIAL ACCREDITATION (ยง 17-5601)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5601.1.</num>
    <text>A nursing school desiring initial accreditation of a nursing program shall submit to the Board the following information and pay the required review fee:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A statement of intent to establish a basic program or advanced practice program; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A proposal which includes the following information:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Documentation of the present and future need for the program and the need for entry-level nurses in the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The rationale for establishment of the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The potential effect on other nursing programs in the area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The organizational structure of the educational institution documenting the relationship of the program within the institution;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The accreditation status of the controlling institution;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The purpose, mission, and level of the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The availability of qualified administrators and faculty pursuant to the qualifications established under this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Hiring procedures for ensuring administrators and faculty will meet the requirements of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Budgeted faculty positions;</text>
    </level>
    <text>(10) The source and description of adequate clinical resources for the level of the program;</text>
    <text>(11) Documentation of adequate academic facilities and staff to support the program;</text>
    <text>(12) Evidence of financial resources adequate for the planning, implementation, and continuation of the program;</text>
    <text>(13) The anticipated student population;</text>
    <text>(14) The tentative time schedule for planning and initiating the program;</text>
    <text>(15) Admissions criteria and procedures;</text>
    <text>(16) Graduation criteria and procedures;</text>
    <text>(17) A curriculum plan including conceptual framework, program objectives, course objectives, and clinical objectives; and</text>
    <text>(18) A systemic plan for evaluation of the program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5601.2.</num>
    <text>The Board shall approve or disapprove the proposal within one hundred and eighty (1 80) days from the date of receipt of the final proposal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5601.3.</num>
    <text>If the Board disapproves the proposal, the nursing school may reapply pursuant to ยง 5601.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5601.4.</num>
    <text>If the Board approves the proposal, the nursing school may submit to the Board an application for initial accreditation after the following conditions have been met:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A nurse administrator or program coordinator, as applicable, meeting theeducational and experiential requirements of this chapter for the program level has been appointed; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The nursing school has provided documentation that the nurse administrator or program coordinator has a substantially equivalent education or experience; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The nursing school can provide a rationale to the Board for acceptance of other than the minimum required graduate credentials.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>There are sufficient faculty meeting the requirements of this chapter for the program level to initiate the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The nursing school has submitted to the Board a description of each faculty member including credentials; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A site visit has been conducted by the Board, or if applicable, a joint site visit has been conducted by the Board and the Education Licensure Commission.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5601.5.</num>
    <text>Board review of the application for initial accreditation of the proposed program, the Board may grant or deny initial accreditation, or may grant conditional accreditation. The Board shall issue a letter indicating its decision within a reasonable
      time, not to exceed one hundred eighty (180) days from the date of the receipt of the application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5601.6.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant initial accreditation to a newly established program upon receipt of evidence that the standards and requirements of this chapter are being met.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5601.7.</num>
    <text>Following initial accreditation by the Board, the program shall submit progress reports to the Board as requested.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5601.8.</num>
    <text>Initial accreditation status shall remain in effect until two (2) National Council Licensure Examination (NCLEX) reporting quarters have passed from the graduation date of the program&amp;#8217;s first graduating class, unless otherwise withdrawn
      by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 7190 (July 23, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 2116 (March 9, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>