<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-817</num>
  <heading>THREATENING, HARASSING, OR ABUSIVE CONDUCT PROHIBITED (§ 31-817)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>817.1.</num>
    <text>No public vehicle for hire operator, or a person acting on the operator’s behalf, shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Threaten, harass, or abuse a passenger, a Commission representative, civil or law enforcement personnel, government employee, another operator, or other person; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Use, threaten, or attempt to use physical force against a passenger, a Commission representative, civil or law enforcement personnel, government employee, or another operator or other person.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>817.2.</num>
    <text>A public vehicle for hire operator, or a person acting on the operator’s behalf, shall at all times cooperate with civil or law enforcement officers, including Hack Inspectors and other representatives of the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>817.3.</num>
    <text>A public vehicle for hire operator, or a person acting on the operator’s behalf, shall answer and comply as directed with all questions, communications, notices, directives, and summonses from the Commission or its representatives (including Hack
      Inspectors) and all other law enforcement personnel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>817.4.</num>
    <text>No public vehicle for hire operator shall fail or refuse to obey an order or directive of Commission personnel (including Hack Inspectors) and local or federal law enforcement personnel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>817.5.</num>
    <text>A taxicab or public vehicle for hire operator shall produce his or her original Commission license and other documents whenever directed by the Commission or civil or law enforcement personnel. A violation of this section shall represent a failure
      to obey as set forth in § 817.3.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>817.6.</num>
    <text>For each violation of this section, a public vehicle for hire operator or a person acting on the operator’s behalf shall be subject to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The fines set forth in § 825 of this chapter, or if a specific fine or penalty is not listed in this chapter, a fine of one hundred dollars ($100);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Impoundment of the vehicle associated with the violation pursuant to the Taxicab and Passenger Vehicle for Hire Impoundment Act of 1992, effective March 16, 1993 (D.C. Law 9-199; D.C. Official Code § 50-331 (2009 Repl.; 2011 Supp.));</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>License suspension, revocation, or non-renewal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Remedial action to assure the safety of the public as a condition of re-instatement of a license after suspension or revocation, including but not limited to:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Attending an anger management course;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Cultural sensitivity training; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Re-taking the operator training course; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any combination of the sanctions listed in this subsection.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>817.7.</num>
    <text>In the sole discretion of the Commission, a public vehicle for hire operator subject to suspension or revocation for a violation of this section may be offered the opportunity to successfully complete a course of remedial action approved by the Commission
      in lieu of license revocation or suspension.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>817.8.</num>
    <text>The cost of any course of remedial action required pursuant to § 817.6 or 817.7 shall be borne by the licensee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>817.9.</num>
    <text>A decision of the Commission to refuse an offer of remedial action in lieu of license revocation or suspension, or a determination by the Commission that an offered course of remedial action was not successfully completed, is not subject to appeal
      or review.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 9970, 9979 (August 17, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>