<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-901</num>
  <heading>LABELING OF BEER CONTAINERS AND BEER TAPS (ยง 23-901)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>901.1.</num>
    <text>No licensee shall sell, offer for sale, or import for sale, delivery, or shipment within the District of Columbia any beer unless the original container is correctly marked, branded, and labeled in English.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>901.2.</num>
    <text>The label shall be firmly attached and shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The brand name and address of the brewer, bottler, or wholesaler;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The class of the beverage (including beer, ale, porter, lager, bock, stout, or half and half); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The net content of the container.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>901.3.</num>
    <text>The label shall not contain any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Any false or misleading statement, design, or device;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The words &amp;#8220;high test,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;high proof,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;full strength,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;prewar strength,&amp;#8221; or similar words;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any statement, design, or device implying that the use of the beer has curative or therapeutic effects; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any seal, flag, crest, coat of arms, or other insignia likely to mislead the consumer to believe that the product has been endorsed, made, or used by the government, organization, family, or individual with which that seal, flag, crest, coat of
        arms, or other insignia is associated.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>901.4.</num>
    <text>No licensee shall alter, obliterate, or destroy any label attached to a beer container.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>901.5.</num>
    <text>The holder of a Retailer&amp;#8217;s license Class C or D, shall not sell any beer on draft from any tap, faucet, spigot, or other dispensing device unless there shall plainly appear on or be attached to such device an inscription, clearly legible
      for a distance of ten feet (10 ft.) from the dispenser outlet to a person with normal vision, giving the brand or trade name of the beer so sold from the tap.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>