<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-9812</num>
  <heading>RENT CALCULATIONS (§ 14-9812)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>9812.1.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of the AYBL program only AYBL Tenant Rent will be calculated as thirty percent (30%) of the AYBL participants adjusted Unearned Income and the total income of any other non-AYBL participant(s) in the household, if any. In the event
      that the amount calculated is less than zero dollars ($0), the rent charged will be zero dollars ($0).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9812.2</num>
    <text>9812.2 At all Rewards Properties, DCHA will initially pay for all unit utilities. As a means of preparing AYBL Families for homeownership, over the course of an AYBL Family’s Contract of Participation term, the AYBL Family payment of utilities will
      be phased according to a graduated schedule. The following is the graduated schedule of utility payment responsibility that will be applied:</text>
    <text>AYBL Participation Year</text>
    <text>DCHA</text>
    <text>AYBL Family</text>
    <text>Year 1</text>
    <text>100%</text>
    <text>0%</text>
    <text>Year 2</text>
    <text>75%</text>
    <text>25%</text>
    <text>Year 3</text>
    <text>50%</text>
    <text>50%</text>
    <text>Year 4</text>
    <text>25%</text>
    <text>75%</text>
    <text>Year 5</text>
    <text>0%</text>
    <text>100%</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9812.3.</num>
    <text>DCHA will not provide a utility allowance for AYBL families.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9812.4</num>
    <text>9812.4 An AYBL Family is not subject to an eviction proceeding for failure to pay utilities pursuant to this Section; however, failure to pay utilities is a violation of the Contract of Participation; as such, the AYBL Family is subject to termination
      from the AYBL program.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 2460, 2470 (March 18, 2011); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 4346, 4347 (May 20, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>