<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-9817</num>
  <heading>CONTRACT OF PARTICIPATION (§ 14-9817)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>9817.1.</num>
    <text>A Contract of Participation must be executed by the Lessee(s) of the AYBL Family prior to entering into a Dwelling Unit Lease Agreement for a Rewards Property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9817.2.</num>
    <text>AYBL participants must comply with the terms and conditions of the Dwelling Unit Lease Agreement and AYBL lease addendum.</text>
    <text>Failure to abide by the terms of the Contract of Participation shall be</text>
    <text>considered a violation of the lease and/or AYBL lease addendum.</text>
    <text>Contract Term &amp;#8211; Term of the Contract of Participation cannot exceed five (5) years and will be established in consultation with the AYBL Family, based on the agreed upon timeframes for achieving the goals related to homeownership.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9817.5</num>
    <text>9817.5 If at the end of the contract term, the AYBL Family successfully completes the Contract of Participation and is an active participant in HOAP, the family may request a six (6) month extension of the Contract of Participation. Approval of an
      extension is at the sole discretion of DCHA.</text>
    <text>If at the end of the initial six (6) month extension and the AYBL Family has complied with all of the HOAP requirements and is actively looking for a home, an additional six (6) month extension may be granted at the sole discretion of DCHA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9817.6</num>
    <text>9817.6 Requests for extensions of the contract term must be submitted to DCHA in writing in a form approved by DCHA at least thirty (30) days prior to the end of the Contract of Participation or extension and must include evidence justifying the request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9817.7.</num>
    <text>The ITSP, in addition to identifying homeownership as the AYBL Family’s end goal, will establish interim goals by which the ABYL Family’s progress in fulfilling its obligations will be measured. Mandatory minimum interim goals to be included in the
      ITSP and thereby required by the Contract of Participation are that the AYBL Family:</text>
    <text>Has been admitted in the HOAP; or</text>
    <text>Is under contract to purchase a home</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9817.8</num>
    <text>9817.8 The ITSP, in addition to identifying homeownership as the AYBL Family end goal, will establish interim goals by which the ABYL family’s progress in fulfilling its obligations will be measured. Mandatory minimum interim goals to be included
      in the ITSP and thereby required by the Contract of Participation are that the AYBL Family:</text>
    <text>Has been admitted into the HOAP; or</text>
    <text>Is under contract to purchase a home.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9817.9.</num>
    <text>Modification of the Contract of Participation – DCHA and the AYBL Family may mutually agree to modify the Contract of Participation. The Contract of Participation may be modified in writing with respect to the Individual Training and Services plans,
      the contract term, and designation of the Head of Household.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9817.10.</num>
    <text>Completion of the Contract of Participation – A Contract of Participation is considered to be completed and a family’s participation in AYBL is considered to conclude when the AYBL Family has fulfilled all of its obligations under the Contract of
      Participation on or before the expiration of the contract term, including any extension thereof.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9817.11.</num>
    <text>Non-compliance will be determined based on the requirements of the Contract of Participation. AYBL Families will be notified in writing for instances of non-compliance through the issuance of a Notice of Non-Compliance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9817.12.</num>
    <text>Termination of the Contract of Participation for reasons other than a breach of the Public Housing lease, in accordance with this section, may not result in the termination of Public Housing assistance. If the Contract of Participation is terminated
      for reasons required to transfer to a non-Rewards Property unit in accordance with the AYBL transfer policy described in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9817.13.</num>
    <text>Termination of the Contract of Participation for reasons other than a breach of the Public Housing lease, in accordance with subsection 9813.8(a)—(d), may not result in the termination of Public Housing assistance. If the Contract of Participation
      is terminated for reasons required to transfer to a non-Rewards Property unit in accordance with the AYBL transfer policy described in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9817.14</num>
    <text>9817.14 AYBL Families who successfully complete the Contract of Participation will transition to the HCVP/HOAP. All members of the AYBL Family must vacate the AYBL unit at the conclusion of the family’s participation in the program whether by termination
      or successful completion of the Contract of Participation.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 2460, 2473 (March 18, 2011); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 4346, 4348 (May 20, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>