<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-9199</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 29-9199)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>9199.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have the following meanings:</text>
    <text>Advanced Practice Registered Nurse &amp;#8211; A person who is licensed or authorized to practice as an advanced practice registered nurse pursuant to the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revisions Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C.
      Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code §§ 3-1201.01, et seq. (2007 Repl. &amp;#038; 2012 Supp.)).</text>
    <text>Certified Addiction Counselor &amp;#8211; A person who is licensed or authorized to practice as a certified addiction counselor pursuant to the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revisions Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99;
      D.C. Official Code §§ 3-1201.01, et seq. (2007 Repl. &amp;#038; 2012 Supp.)).</text>
    <text>Licensed Independent Clinical Social Worker &amp;#8211; A person who is licensed or authorized to practice as a licensed independent clinical social worker pursuant to the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revisions Act of 1985, effective March
      25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code §§ 3-1201.01, et seq. (2007 Repl. &amp;#038; 2012 Supp.)).</text>
    <text>Licensed Independent Social Worker &amp;#8211; A person who is licensed or authorized to practice as a licensed independent social worker pursuant to the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revisions Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C.
      Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code §§ 3-1201.01, et seq. (2007 Repl. &amp;#038; 2012 Supp.)).</text>
    <text>Licensed Professional Counselor &amp;#8211; A person who is licensed or authorized to practice as a licensed professional counselor pursuant to the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revisions Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99;
      D.C. Official Code §§ 3-1201.01, et seq. (2007 Repl. &amp;#038; 2012 Supp.)).</text>
    <text>Pharmacotherapy &amp;#8211; Medical treatment conducted through the use of pharmaceuticals.</text>
    <text>Physician &amp;#8211; A person who is licensed or authorized to practice medicine</text>
    <text>pursuant to the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revisions Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code §§ 3-1201.01, et seq. (2007 Repl. &amp;#038; 2012 Supp.)).</text>
    <text>Psychologist &amp;#8211; A person who is licensed or authorized to practice as a psychologist pursuant to the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revisions Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code §§ 3-1201.01,
      et seq. (2007 Repl. &amp;#038; 2012 Supp.)).</text>
    <text>Registered Nurse &amp;#8211; A person who is licensed or authorized to practice as a registered nurse pursuant to the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revisions Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code §§ 3-1201.01,
      et seq. (2007 Repl. &amp;#038; 2012 Supp.)).</text>
    <text>Substance Abuse &amp;#8211; A maladaptive pattern of substance use, including alcohol, illicit drugs, and pharmaceuticals. Substance Abuse is manifested by recurrent and significant adverse consequences, including: 1) failure to fulfill obligations;
      2) repeatedly subjecting one’s self to physical hazards; 3) multiple legal problems; and 4) social and interpersonal issues.</text>
    <text>A Substance Abuse diagnosis requires a beneficiary to have had persistent, substance-related problem(s) within a twelve (12)-month period.</text>
    <text>Substance Dependence &amp;#8211; A cluster of cognitive, behavioral, and physiological symptoms that indicate persistent use of a substance. Substance Dependence is manifested by a repeated pattern of self-administration of substances that results
      in physical tolerance, withdrawal symptoms, and compulsive substance consumption. A diagnosis of Substance Dependence requires a beneficiary to have had persistent, substance-related problem(s) within a twelve (12)-month period.</text>
    <text>Treatment Episode &amp;#8211; The period between a beneficiary’s admission to treatment for Substance Use Disorder and the termination or discharge from services prescribed in the rehabilitation (or treatment) plan, as defined in D.C. Official Code
      § 7-3002(10) (2008 Repl.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 11144 (September 28, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>