<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-9107</num>
  <heading>SUBSTANCE ABUSE COUNSELING-INDIVIDUAL, GROUP AND FAMILY (§ 29-9107)
    <text>Substance abuse counseling services shall include individual, group, and familyounseling. These services shall incorporate a face-to-face, interactiverocess focused on assisting a beneficiary who manifests substance use disorder.</text>
    <text>The goal of substance abuse counseling shall be the cultivation of awareness,kills, and supports that are necessary in order to facilitate long-termecovery from substance use disorder.</text>
    <text>Substance abuse counseling services shall address the specific issues identifiedn a treatment plan and shall meet applicable requirements established inhapter 23 of Title 29 DCMR.</text>
    <text>A unit of substance abuse counseling service shall be one (1) fifteen (15)inute increment, pursuant to DHCF’s billing requirement.</text>
    <text>Substance abuse counseling services shall not be provided in conjunction withedication Management, described in § 9108 of this chapter.</text>
    <text>Group and family substance abuse counseling services shall be exclusively forhe recovery of a Medicaid beneficiary enrolled in ASARS treatment.</text>
    <text>Limitations for substance abuse counseling services, by level of care, perreatment episode are as follows:</text>
    <text>Level IV:</text>
    <text>Individual: Shall not exceed twenty (20) units;</text>
    <text>Group: Shall not exceed twelve (12) units; and</text>
    <text>Family: Shall not exceed four (4) units;</text>
    <text>Level III:</text>
    <text>Individual: Not to exceed thirty-two (32) units;</text>
    <text>Group: Not to exceed eight hundred ninety-six (896) units; and</text>
    <text>Family: Not to exceed sixteen (16) units;</text>
    <text>Level II:</text>
    <text>Individual: Not to exceed twenty-four (24) units;</text>
    <text>Group: Not to exceed two hundred sixteen (216) units; and</text>
    <text>Family: Not to exceed twenty-four (24) units;</text>
    <text>Level I for beneficiaries who are also receiving Medication Assisted Treatment:</text>
    <text>Individual: Not to exceed forty-eight (48) units;</text>
    <text>Group: Not to exceed one hundred ninety-two (192) units; and</text>
    <text>Family: Not to exceed twelve (12) units;</text>
    <text>Level I for beneficiaries who are not receiving Medication Assisted Treatment:</text>
    <text>Individual: Not to exceed thirty-two (32) units;</text>
    <text>Group: Not to exceed three hundred eighty-four (384) units; and</text>
    <text>Family: Not to exceed sixteen (16) units and</text>
    <text>Additional units for substance abuse counseling services shall be prioruthorized through a request from the clinical care coordinator, subject to theeneficiary’s level of care.</text>
    <text>Substance abuse counseling services shall be provided in APRA-certifiedubstance abuse treatment facilities or programs; community-based settingstherwise approved or designated by APRA; and private practices with qualifiedractitioners authorized to
      provide substance abuse counseling according toheir licensure pursuant to the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revisionct of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code §§-1201.01, et seq. (2007 Repl. &amp;#038; 2012
      Supp.)).</text>
    <text>Substance abuse counseling services shall be delivered by the followingractitioners who shall be certified in substance abuse counseling:</text>
    <text>Physician;</text>
    <text>Psychologist;</text>
    <text>Licensed Independent Clinical Social Worker;</text>
    <text>Advanced Practice Registered Nurse;</text>
    <text>Registered Nurse;</text>
    <text>Licensed Independent Social Worker;</text>
    <text>Licensed Professional Counselor; and</text>
    <text>Certified Addiction Counselor I and II.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 11144 (September 28, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>