<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-9109</num>
  <heading>MEDICATION ASSISTED TREATMENT (§ 29-9109)
    <text>Medication Assisted Treatment (MAT) is the use of pharmacotherapy as long-termreatment for opiate or other forms of dependence. MAT shall include medicationosing used in conjunction with substance abuse counseling.</text>
    <text>Beneficiaries enrolled in MAT shall also be enrolled in substance abuseounseling.</text>
    <text>A unit of MAT shall be one (1) dose of medication per day.</text>
    <text>Beneficiaries receiving MAT shall require two (2) prior authorizations beforeong-term maintenance can be authorized;</text>
    <text>A beneficiary new to ASARS treatment shall have an initial authorization of upo ninety (90) units of daily medications; and</text>
    <text>The provider may then request prior authorization for an additional ninety (90)nits, if appropriate, after which the patient may receive authorization forong-term MAT up to one hundred eighty (180) units.</text>
    <text>Additional limitations for MAT are as follows:</text>
    <text>MAT shall not exceed three hundred sixty-five (365) units per twelve (12) montheriod;</text>
    <text>Except for MAT covering the administration of buprenorphine, MAT shall berovided in substance abuse treatment facilities or programs certified by APRA,r other community-based settings approved or designated by APRA; and</text>
    <text>MAT that includes the administration of buprenorphine shall be limited torivate practice offices of individuals authorized to prescribe buprenorphineccording to their licensure pursuant to the District of Columbia Healthccupations Revision Act of
      1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C.fficial Code §§ 3-1201.01, et seq. (2007 Repl. &amp;#038; 2012 Supp.)).</text>
    <text>A physician; or</text>
    <text>An advance practice registered nurse or physician assistant who is supervised byualified physicians.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>MAT shall be prior authorized, subject to the beneficiary’s level of care andeet the following requirements</heading>
      <text />
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>MAT shall be delivered by the following qualified practitioners</heading>
      <text />
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 11144 (September 28, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>