<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-8106</num>
  <heading>CONTINUING EDUCATION REQUIREMENTS (§ 17-8106)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8106.1.</num>
    <text>This section shall apply to all applicants for the renewal, reactivation, or reinstatement of a polysomnographic technologist license under this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8106.2.</num>
    <text>A licensed polysomnographic technologist is not required to obtain continuing education credits for the first renewal after initial licensure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8106.3</num>
    <text>8106.3 A licensed polysomnographic technologist shall earn a minimum of twenty (20) continuing education credits during the two (2) year period immediately preceding the date of any subsequent license renewal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8106.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant for the renewal, reactivation, or reinstatement of a polysomnographic technologist license shall prove completion of the required continuing education credits by submitting with the application the following information with respect to
      each continuing education program:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the sponsor of the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A description of the subject matter covered and the name(s) of the instructor(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The dates on which the applicant attended the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The number of hours of credit claimed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Verification by the sponsor, by signature or stamp, of the applicant’s</text>
    </level>
    <text>completion of the program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8106.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant for renewal of a polysomnographic technologist license who fails to submit proof of having completed the continuing education requirements by the date the license expires may renew his or her license during the thirty (30) day period
      after expiration by submitting this proof pursuant to § 8106.4 and by paying the required fees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8106.6.</num>
    <text>If an application is approved pursuant to § 8106.5, the applicant shall be deemed to have possessed a valid license commencing on the date the license or registration is renewed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8106.7.</num>
    <text>If an applicant for renewal of a license fails to submit proof of having completed the continuing education requirements and pay the required fees within thirty (30) days after the expiration of applicant’s license, the license shall be considered
      to have lapsed on the date of its expiration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8106.8.</num>
    <text>The Board may, in its discretion, grant an extension of the thirty (30) day renewal period established by § 8106.5 if the applicant’s failure to submit proof of having completed the continuing education requirements was for good cause. For the purposes
      of this subsection, good cause includes:</text>
    <text>Serious and protracted illness of the applicant; and</text>
    <text>The death or serious and protracted illness of a member of the applicant’s immediate family.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 3758, 3764 (April 29, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>