<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-8107</num>
  <heading>APPROVED CONTINUING EDUCATION PROGRAMS (ยง 17-8107)
    <text>A continuing education credit may be earned only for a program or activity</text>
    <text>approved or recognized by the Board.</text>
    <text>To be eligible for approval by the Board, a continuing education program or activity shall contribute to the knowledge, skills, or professional performance and relationships that a polysomnographic technologist uses to provide services to patients.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <num>8107.3</num>
    <text>8107.3 The Board shall recognize sleep-related continuing education hours approved by one (1) of the following organizations:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The American Medical Association;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The American Association of Sleep Technologists;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The American Academy of Sleep Medicine;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The American Society of Electroneurodiagnostic Technologists;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The American Association for Respiratory Care; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The American Nursing Association</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8107.4.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant permission to attend a course not listed in ยง 8107.3. In order to obtain Board approval of a continuing education program or activity under ยง 8107.2, a program sponsor or licensee shall submit to the Board information regarding
      the program or activity at least ninety (90) days before the start of program or activity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8107.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall bear the burden of verifying whether a program or activity is approved or recognized by the Board pursuant to this section before attending the program or engaging in the activity.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 3758, 3765 (April 29, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>