<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-8103</num>
  <heading>QUALIFICATIONS FOR REGISTRATION AS A POLYSOMNOGRAPHIC TECHNICIAN (ยง 17-8103)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8103.1.</num>
    <text>An applicant for registration as a polysomnographic technician shall submit to the Board:</text>
    <text>A completed application on a form provided by the Board;</text>
    <text>A completed criminal background check in accordance with 17 DCMR ยง 8501;</text>
    <text>Proof that the applicant holds current certification in cardiopulmonary Resuscitation (CPR) provided by either the American Heart Association or the American Red Cross;</text>
    <text>Proof that the applicant has successfully completed a polysomnographic training program accredited by the Commission on the Accreditation of Allied Health Education Programs (CAAHEP) or an Accredited Sleep Technologist Education Program (A-Step) accredited
      by the American Academy of Sleep Medicine;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Proof that the applicant passed the Certified Polysomnographic Technician (CPSGT) Exam; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Attestation on a form provided by the Board that the applicant will be</text>
    </level>
    <text>supervised by a licensed polysomnographic technologist or a licensed</text>
    <text>physician while acting as a polysomnographic technician.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8103.2.</num>
    <text>Within five (5) business days after the application for registration has been</text>
    <text>received by the Board, the Board shall, at the request of the applicant, issue a supervised practice letter to the applicant to document that his or her application is pending and that he or she is authorized to practice as a polysomnographic technician
      under this chapter. The practice letter shall not be renewable and shall expire on the earlier of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Ninety (90) days after the date of issuance; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Upon receipt of written notice from the Board that the application for registration has been denied.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8103.3.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of a supervised practice letter, the applicant shall inform his or her employer of the date of expiration of the letter and shall immediately cease to practice as a polysomnographic technician on that date or upon receipt of written notice
      from the Board that the application for licensure has been denied, whichever date is earlier. The applicant thereafter may practice in a non-professional healthcare occupation, until receipt of a registration or issuance of a registration number.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8103.4.</num>
    <text>If the applicant obtains a new supervisor, he or she must inform the Board and submit a new attestation form within fifteen (15) days after the change in supervisor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8103.5.</num>
    <text>If the applicant changes jobs, he or she must notify the Board and have a new attestation form on file before beginning the new job.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 3758, 3760 (April 29, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>