<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-1200</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (ยง 28-1200)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1200.1.</num>
    <text>The purpose of this chapter shall be to provide organizations, citizens, officials, and residents with a mechanism for filing complaints of a non-criminal nature about community-based programs for alleged or adjudicated Persons in Need of Supervision
      (PINS), delinquent offenders, or alleged or convicted adult offenders (also referred to in this chapter as &amp;#8220;court-involved persons&amp;#8221;). These procedures are intended to ensure the timely investigation and review of complaints.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1200.2.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this chapter shall provide a clearinghouse for monitoring the extent and nature of non-criminal complaints about community-based residential facilities for court involved persons, and a mechanism to ensure that non-criminal investigations
      involving multiple District agencies are conducted in a timely, responsive, and coordinated fashion.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1200.3.</num>
    <text>The procedures set forth in this chapter shall apply to complaints received by the Office of Criminal Justice Plans and Analysis (also referred to in this chapter as the &amp;#8220;OCJPA&amp;#8221;) concerning publicly or privately operated community-based
      residential facilities housing District court involved persons. OCJPA shall maintain a listing of all of this type of facility known to the District government and the listing shall be available for public review.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1200.4.</num>
    <text>Complaints concerning facilities housing District residents located outside of the District shall be accepted and pursued in cooperation with the appropriate jurisdiction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 79-172, dated July 30, 1979.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 1107 (March 14, 1980).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>