<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-2106</num>
  <heading>PROJECT COORDINATING COMMITTEE (§ 15-2106)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2106.1.</num>
    <text>Once an application has been properly filed, the applicant may request the formation of a project coordinating committee. If the request is approved, the Committee shall consist of the following members:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A chairperson, who shall be designated by the Commission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A representative of the applicant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A representative from the Office of the People&amp;#8217;s Counsel, if a notice of intent to participate on the committee is filed within ten (10) days of the date of the filing of a request to form a project coordinating committee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A representative from each District of Columbia agency that has as follows:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Authority to issue a license, permit, or authorization before the construction or operation of the project; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A direct interest in the project.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Pepco, if Pepco is not the applicant.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A representative designated by the Executive Office of the Mayor; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A representative of any federal agency or independent system operator that, in the Commission&amp;#8217;s view, has an interest in the project.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2106.2.</num>
    <text>The committee shall develop a coordinated time schedule for the review of the application by each committee member&amp;#8217;s agency or company and oversee the preparation of any environmental impact statement required by D.C. Code, 2001 Ed. §§ 8-109.01
      to 8-109.11. Additionally, the committee shall provide the Commission with the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A list of proposed issues to be addressed in an application;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A list of any proposed analyses or studies regarding the proposed construction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Recommendations concerning the timing, preparation, and submission of required materials;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Recommendations concerning compliance with the requirements of each committee member&amp;#8217;s agency; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any other information that the committee believes would be relevant.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2106.3.</num>
    <text>The committee is advisory in nature and shall not have authority to do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Approve or disapprove an application;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Approve or disapprove proposed studies of the applicant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Require or prohibit any action by a committee member; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Require or prohibit any expenditure by a committee member.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 8644 (September 3, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>