<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2103</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION PROCEDURES (ยง 24-2103)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2103.1.</num>
    <text>The Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department is authorized to issue press passes to bona fide media representatives of print, electronic or online, university or college, television, radio, and newsreel media who gather information or pictures
      for distribution or broadcast to the public as news. Media representatives include self-employed or freelance writers / journalists who regularly gather news.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2103.2.</num>
    <text>Press passes shall be issued in a form approved by the Chief of Police or his or her designee and shall be valid for two years. Holders of expired press passes shall surrender them upon issuance of new passes. The Chief of Police or his or her designee
      may withhold the issuance of a press pass to any person convicted of a felony, a crime of violence as defined in D.C. Official Code ยง 23-1331 (4), or a crime of moral turpitude, if such withholding is based on a reasonable belief the person would
      be disruptive or will use the press pass for an unlawful purpose. The Chief of Police or his or her designee shall inform the applicant in writing of the basis for any denial of a press pass. An applicant may appeal the denial of the issuance of
      a press pass to the Chief of Police.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2103.3.</num>
    <text>An application for a police press pass shall include a statement that the holder of a press pass:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>assumes all risks incident to the use of the pass;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>will obey all lawful orders and directions of any member of the Metropolitan Police Department; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>will comport himself or herself in a manner that does not interfere with, hinder, or obstruct any authorized person engaged in preserving the peace, maintaining order, and protecting life and property. Nothing in this section shall constitute a
        waiver or release of any claim the holder of a press pass may have for harm or injury intentionally or negligently caused to such person. Any conflicts or disagreements with such orders or directions shall be resolved through consultation with
        the Metropolitan Police Department&amp;#8217;s Director of the Office of Public Information or his or her designee.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2103.4.</num>
    <text>A person displaying a valid press pass shall not be arrested or taken into custody at the scene of a First Amendment assembly or other news event in the absence of probable cause for the arrest. A person displaying a valid press pass shall not be
      arrested merely because he or she is in an area where other people have committed criminal acts or are being arrested.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2103.5.</num>
    <text>A press pass issued pursuant to this section automatically expires upon the holder&amp;#8217;s termination of employment or occupation as a media representative. Upon such expiration, the holder shall immediately surrender the pass to the Metropolitan
      Police Department Office of Public Information or to his or her employer, who shall forward the press pass to the Office of Public Information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2103.6.</num>
    <text>Press passes shall not be transferable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2103.7.</num>
    <text>Pursuant to this section, the Chief of Police, upon a showing of good cause, shall have the authority to limit the total number of press passes issued to media representatives and organizations for an event.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 6, ยง5(c) of the Police Regulations (May 1981); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 7086 (June 27, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>