<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-5502</num>
  <heading>DENYING PORTABILITY MOVES DUE TO INSUFFICIENT FUNDING (§ 14-5502)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5502.1.</num>
    <text>If DCHA denies a request for portability due to insufficient funding such requests shall be documented with proper financial documentation demonstrating DCHA’s inability to support the portability request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5502.2.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall only deny a request to move to a higher cost area if DCHA would be unable to avoid terminations of housing choice voucher assistance for current participants during the calendar year in order to remain within its budgetary allocation (including
      any available HAP reserves) for housing assistance payments.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5502.3.</num>
    <text>Before denying the Family’s request to move due to insufficient funding, DCHA shall contact the Receiving PHA to determine whether the Receiving PHA will absorb the Family.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5502.4.</num>
    <text>If the Receiving PHA is willing to absorb the Family, there shall be no grounds to deny the portability move for insufficient funding.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5502.5.</num>
    <text>If DCHA denies a Family’s request for a portability move due to insufficient funding, it shall not admit any additional families to its voucher program until it determines that sufficient funding exists to approve the move and has notified the Family
      that the Family may now exercise its move to the higher cost area.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5502.6.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall consider a Family’s request for a portability move for thirty (30) days from the date the request was filed if there is insufficient funding to immediately grant the request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5502.7.</num>
    <text>If funds become available within thirty (30) days which would allow the Family to move to a higher cost area, DCHA shall notify the Family by first class mail that funds are available, and that the request is granted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5502.8.</num>
    <text>If funding is unavailable after thirty (30) days, DCHA shall notify the Family by first class mail that the request to port is denied, and that they may reapply to port after ninety (90) days from the date of denial.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 7926, 7927 (June 29, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>