<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-5503</num>
  <heading>OUTGOING PORTABILITY PROCEDURES (§ 14-5503)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5503.1.</num>
    <text>Once DCHA approves the Family’s portability move out of DCHA’s jurisdiction, DCHA shall schedule the Family to attend a portability briefing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5503.2.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall brief the Family on:</text>
    <text>The estimated time frame for submitting paperwork to the Receiving PHA;</text>
    <text>How to contact the Receiving PHA;</text>
    <text>Any special requirements from the Receiving PHA regarding appointments;</text>
    <text>Policy on voucher extensions for portable families;</text>
    <text>Expiration of Vouchers;</text>
    <text>Requirement to provide a Notice to Vacate to the owner of the current unit;</text>
    <text>Determination of Voucher size and Payment Standards; and</text>
    <text>Procedure for returning to DCHA or portability to any other jurisdiction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5503.3.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall notify the Receiving PHA of the Family’s choice to get necessary contact information and incoming portability procedures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5503.4.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall complete an outgoing portability packet containing the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Part I of the HUD Form-52665 along with a copy of the voucher issued to the Family;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A current copy of HUD Form-50058 for program participant; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Copies of the income verification backing up the form.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5503.5.</num>
    <text>In the case of an applicant, DCHA will not have a completed HUD Form-50058 because the Family is not yet a new admission, however DCHA shall provide the Family information and income information in a format similar to the HUD Form-50058.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5503.6.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall mail, fax, or email the portability packet to the Receiving PHA, in accordance with the Receiving PHA’s policy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 7926, 7928 (June 29, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>