<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-5505</num>
  <heading>INCOMING PORTABILITY PROCEDURES (§ 14-5505)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5505.1.</num>
    <text>Once DCHA receives the portability packet, the assigned Housing Programs Specialist shall ensure that the Family’s voucher has not expired and will not expire within thirty (30) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5505.2.</num>
    <text>If an incoming Family’s voucher has expired, the specialist shall contact the Initial PHA to see if any extensions are granted. If the Initial PHA grants an extension, the PHA must provide a corrected voucher and HUD Form-52665 before DCHA will schedule
      an appointment for the Family.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5505.3.</num>
    <text>If the voucher is expired or the term of the voucher will not allow sufficient time to process, and the Initial PHA has already been contacted, the portability packet shall be returned to the Initial PHA with a cover letter stating the reasons for
      returning the packet.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5505.4.</num>
    <text>When DCHA is billing the Initial PHA, the assigned Housing Programs Specialist shall ensure that the Family has at least thirty (30) days left on the voucher before scheduling an appointment. If the time left on the voucher is less than thirty (30)
      days, the specialist shall contact the Initial PHA and request the maximum time allowed on the voucher, in order to ensure that the voucher term shall leave sufficient time to process a Request for Lease Approval, HQS, and execution of HAP contract,
      and cover the anticipated delivery time so that it shall be received by the Initial PHA by the deadline date on the HUD Form-52665.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5505.5.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall schedule the portability appointment within two (2) weeks of receiving the portability packet. The notice of appointment date and time will be sent by first-class mail. The letter shall also tell the Family what documents are needed for
      the portability appointment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5505.6</num>
    <text>5505.6 DCHA shall not re-determine eligibility for a portable Family that was already receiving voucher assistance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5505.7.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall issue the voucher at the time of portability appointment and shall not delay the voucher issuance or approval of unit due to new income recertification unless the Family refuses to comply with DCHA procedures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5505.8</num>
    <text>5505.8 After issuing a portable voucher, DCHA may take subsequent action against the Family based on the results of a background check or adjusted income determination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 7926, 7930 (June 29, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>