<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-1101</num>
  <heading>OFFENSES RELATED TO TITLE, REGISTRATION, AND IDENTIFICATION TAGS (§ 18-1101)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1101.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall lend to another person any temporary registration certificate, registration certificate, identification tag, or temporary identification tag issued to him or her if the person desiring to borrow the same would not be entitled to the
      use thereof, nor shall any person knowingly permit the use of any of these items by another person not entitled to them, nor shall any person display on a vehicle any temporary registration certificate, identification tag, or temporary identification
      tag not issued for that vehicle or not otherwise lawfully used on the vehicle under this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1101.2.</num>
    <text>No person shall display in or on any motor vehicle any of the items or documents described in § 1104.4; Provided, that no person shall be liable under this subsection when such items or documents are displayed under the good faith belief that such
      items or documents are genuine.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1101.3.</num>
    <text>REPEALED</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1101.4.</num>
    <text>No person shall operate or move, or permit the operation or moving of any vehicle displaying dealer&amp;#8217;s identification or dealer&amp;#8217;s transport identification tags for the transportation of merchandise for hire or passengers for hire.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1101.5.</num>
    <text>No dealer&amp;#8217;s identification nor dealer&amp;#8217;s transport identification tag shall be used on vehicles used by a dealer for the transportation of merchandise or as service vehicles.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1101.6.</num>
    <text>No dealer shall permit the operation of a vehicle bearing dealer&amp;#8217;s identification or dealer&amp;#8217;s transport identification tags assigned to him by a person who does not hold a valid operator&amp;#8217;s permit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1101.7.</num>
    <text>No dealer&amp;#8217;s identification nor dealer&amp;#8217;s transport identification tags shall be used for the purpose of evading the motor vehicle registration requirements for the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1101.8.</num>
    <text>No special use tag shall be used for any other purpose other than the purpose for which it was issued and shall not be used as a means of evading payment of registration fees due and payable on the date a motor vehicle or trailer was newly acquired
      by a purchaser.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 72-13, effective June 30, 1972, 32 DCRR §§ 8.105-8.107 and 8.109, Special Edition; as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 9295 (October 28, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking
        published at 58 DCR 10342 (December 9, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>