<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6306</num>
  <heading>CONTINUING EDUCATION REQUIREMENTS (§ 17-6306)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6306.1</num>
    <text>6306.1 This section shall not apply to applicants for an initial license by examination, reciprocity, or endorsement, nor does it apply to applicants for the first renewal of a license granted by examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6306.2</num>
    <text>6306.2 A continuing education contact hour shall be valid only if it is part of program or activity that the Board approves in accordance with § 6307.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6306.3</num>
    <text>6306.3 Practitioners applying for license renewal shall complete contact hoursf qualified activities for maintaining continuing education during the two2) year period preceding the date the license expires in the followinganner:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Occupational therapists shall complete a minimum of twenty-four (24)ontact hours; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Occupational therapy assistants shall complete a minimum of twelve (12)ontact hours.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6306.4</num>
    <text>6306.4 An applicant under this section shall prove completion of required continuing education contact hours by submitting with the application the following information with respect to each program:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the sponsor of the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name of the program, its location, a description of the subject</text>
    </level>
    <text>matter covered, and the names of the instructors;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The dates on which the applicant attended the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The number of contact hours claimed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Verification by the sponsor of the applicant&amp;#8217;s completion, byignature or stamp of the sponsor; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The name of the attendee.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6306.5</num>
    <text>6306.5 An applicant for renewal of a license who fails to submit proof ofaving completed continuing education requirements by the date the license expired may renew the license up to sixty (60) days after expiration by submitting the proof pursuant
      to § 6306.4 and by paying the required additional late fee. The license shall be effective on the date of theenewal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6306.6</num>
    <text>6306.6 The Board may, in its discretion, grant an extension of the sixty (60)ay period to renew after expiration if the applicant&amp;#8217;s failure toubmit proof of completion was for good cause. As used in this section,good cause” includes the
      following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Serious and protracted illness of the applicant; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The death or serious and protracted illness of a member of the</text>
    </level>
    <text>applicant&amp;#8217;s immediate family.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6306.7</num>
    <text>6306.7 If the license of an occupational therapist or occupational therapyssistant lapses while serving in the military whenever the United States isngaged in active military operations against any foreign power or hostileorce, and the required continuing
      education hours were not earned during theearning period, the licensee shall be required to complete the requiredcontinuing education hours needed no later than six (6) months after dischargerom active service, return to inactive military status,
      or return to thenited States from an active war zone.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6306.8</num>
    <text>6306.8 The continuing education contact hours completed shall not be used forthe next licensing period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6306.9</num>
    <text>6306.9 The continuing education contact hours for the next licensing periodhall not be prorated.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6306.10</num>
    <text>6306.10 Practitioners who are licensed to practice in a jurisdiction other thanhe District shall meet the requirements of this section in order to maintainlicensure in the District. The licensee shall ensure that the continuingeducation courses fall
      within the relevant time period for the District ofColumbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6306.11</num>
    <text>6306.11 Any applicant for licensure as an occupational therapist orccupational therapy assistant who applies after the renewal date shall submitroof of having completed all continuing education requirements with theapplication.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 936, 939 (February 12, 1988); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 4551 (June 9, 2006); as amendedy Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 3133, 3134 (April 20, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>