<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6311</num>
  <heading>ENDORSEMENT (ยง 17-6311)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6311.1</num>
    <text>6311.1 The Board shall issue a license by endorsement to an occupationalherapist or an occupational therapy assistant who has a valid unrestrictedicense in good standing from another jurisdiction of the United States and whoeets all other requirements
      of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6311.2</num>
    <text>6311.2 An applicant for licensure as an occupational therapist or anccupational therapist assistant by endorsement shall submit with a completedpplication the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Official, certified proof of active licensure in at least one (1)urisdiction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Proof of good standing from all jurisdictions in which the occupational therapist ever held a license in the United States;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Official, certified proof, from the body administering the examination,hat the applicant has passed the Board-approved occupational therapy or occupational therapy assistant national licensure examination (as relevant to the license); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Proof that the applicant is a graduate of a professional occupationalherapy</text>
    </level>
    <text>or occupational therapy assistant education program, as relevant to the license, accredited by an agency that the United States Department of Education recognizes for that purpose, or that the Board approves.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 1060 (February 3, 1989); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 4551 (June 9, 2006); as amendedy Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 2598 (March 14, 2008)j; as amended byotice of Final Rulemaking published
        at 59 DCR 3133, 3140 (April 20, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>