<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6303</num>
  <heading>APPLICANTS EDUCATED IN FOREIGN COUNTRIES (§ 17-6303)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6303.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant a license to practice to an applicant who has his or her exam scores submitted from the National Board for Certification in Occupational Therapy (NBCOT) to the Board and who has completed an educational program in a foreign country
      whose program is approved by the World Federation of Occupational Therapists.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6303.2.</num>
    <text>The applicant shall be currently certified by the National Board for Certification in Occupational Therapy (NBCOT).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6303.3.</num>
    <text>In lieu of meeting the requirements of § 6302.1(a) an applicant for licensure as an occupational therapist shall submit evidence of successful completion of the occupational therapy certification examination developed by NBCOT for occupational therapists,
      to the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6303.4.</num>
    <text>In lieu of meeting the requirements of § 6302.2(a) an applicant for licensure as an occupational therapy assistant shall submit evidence of successful completion of the occupational therapy assistant certification examination developed by NBCOT for
      occupational therapy assistants, to the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6303.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall arrange for the evaluation required by § 6303.2 or § 6303.3 to be sent directly from NBCOT to the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6303.6.</num>
    <text>Repealed</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 936, 937 (February 12, 1988), as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 1059 (February 3, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 4551 (June 9, 2006); as amended by Notice of Final
        Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 3133 (April 20, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>