<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4405</num>
  <heading>SUPERVISED PRACTICE BY STUDENTS AND GRADUATES (REGISTERED DIETITIANS ELIGIBLERDE)) (§ 17-4405)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4405.1.</num>
    <text>The following unlicensed persons may practice dietetics under supervision:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A student fulfilling educational requirements in a program that meets the requirements of §§ 4402.1, 4402.2, and 4402.3; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A graduate enrolled in a postgraduate training program recognized by the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4405.2.</num>
    <text>Only a supervisor shall be authorized to supervise the practice of a student or graduate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4405.3.</num>
    <text>A student or graduate may practice dietetics only in accordance with the Act and this subtitle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4405.4.</num>
    <text>A student or graduate who practices pursuant to this section shall practice only at a hospital, nursing home, health facility, health education center, business, or other health care facility considered appropriate for the practice of dietetics.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4405.5.</num>
    <text>A student or graduate under this section shall not assume administrative or technical responsibility for the operation of a program of dietetics, clinical service, or unit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4405.6.</num>
    <text>All supervised practice shall take place under general or immediate supervision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4405.7.</num>
    <text>A student or graduate shall identify himself or herself as such before practicing under supervision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4405.8.</num>
    <text>A supervisor shall be fully responsible for all practice by a student or graduate during the period of supervision and shall be subject to disciplinary action for any violation of the Act or this subtitle by the student or graduate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4405.9.</num>
    <text>A student or graduate shall not receive compensation of any kind directly or indirectly from a patient, except for a salary based on hours worked under supervision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4405.10.</num>
    <text>A graduate eligible to practice under § 4405.1(b) may practice for no more than twelve (12) months or for the duration of the graduate&amp;#8217;s postgraduate training program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4405.11.</num>
    <text>A student or graduate shall be subject to all of the applicable provisions of the Act and this chapter. In accordance with Chapter 41 of this title, The Board may deny an application for a license by, or take disciplinary action against, a student
      or graduate who is found to have violated the Act or this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4405.12.</num>
    <text>As used in this section:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>&amp;#8220;General supervision&amp;#8221; means supervision in which the supervisor is available on the premises or within vocal communication either directly or by a communication device at the time the student or graduate is practicing.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>&amp;#8220;Immediate supervision&amp;#8221; means supervision in which the supervisor is with the student or graduate and is either discussing or observing the student&amp;#8217;s or graduate&amp;#8217;s practice.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>&amp;#8220;Supervisor&amp;#8221; means a registered dietitian licensed under the Act who is responsible for the supervision of a student or graduate.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 4927 (July 22, 1994).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>