<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-4701</num>
  <heading>REQUEST FOR ELECTION AND CERTIFICATION (ยง 14-4701)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4701.1.</num>
    <text>An owner of a housing accommodation who wishes to convert shall provide to each tenant household and to the Conversion and Sale Regulatory Office a request for election.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4701.2.</num>
    <text>The request shall be sent by first class mail to the tenants and posted in the common areas of the housing accommodation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4701.3.</num>
    <text>The request shall indicate whether the election is for condominium conversion or cooperative conversion.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4701.4.</num>
    <text>Included with the request must be the tenant information available at the Conversion and Sale Regulatory Office. A Spanish translation of that information, to be sent to each household where Spanish is the primary language, is also available at the
      Office.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4701.5.</num>
    <text>In addition to providing a copy of the request for election, the owner shall provide the following information to the Conversion and Sale Regulatory Office:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Name(s) of owner(s); partners, if a partnership entity; or, if a corporation, the principal officers, and owners of ten percent (10%) or more of the corporation stock;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Address and phone number of owner;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Address of housing accommodation, including lot and square, and Advisory Neighborhood Commission number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Date of purchase of the housing accommodation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Number of units;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Estimated sale price per unit after conversion, and estimate of the conversion fee and request for reduction of fee, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>List of current tenants with corresponding apartment numbers and date tenancy commenced; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>A notarized statement attesting to the truthfulness of the information provided.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4701.6.</num>
    <text>If the owner owns a housing accommodation which operates as part of a housing complex, the owner may request, as part of the application, that the housing accommodation be combined for the purposes of the election. The owner shall provide evidence
      that the housing accommodations have been treated as an integrated complex in the past and indicate the intent to combine the structures as one condominium or cooperative.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4701.7.</num>
    <text>A certification fee in the amount set forth in ยง 4717 shall accompany the request for election filed with the Conversion and Sale Regulatory Office Rental Conversion and Sale Division.</text>
    <text>reference the text of Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 694, 695</text>
    <text>(February 13, 1981); as amended by Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Act of 2010, effective September</text>
    <text>24, 2010 (D.C. Law 18-223), published at 57 DCR 6242, 6290 (July 23, 2010).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 2443 (May 29, 1981), incorporating by</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>