<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-4703</num>
  <heading>CONFIRMATION OF ELECTION (ยง 14-4703)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4703.1.</num>
    <text>If more than fifty percent (50%) of the total number of qualified voters on the Qualified Voters List as determined by the Conversion and Sale Regulatory Office vote for approval of the conversion, the Conversion and Sale Regulatory Office shall confirm
      the results of the election within five (5) business days of the election, absent the filing of an allegation of fraud or coercion.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4703.2.</num>
    <text>Any allegation of fraud or coercion by any party in the conduct of the election shall be filed with the Conversion and Sale Regulatory Office within ten (10) business days of the posting of the election results or within ten (10) business days of
      discovery of the alleged fraud or coercion, whichever is later. The complaint shall specifically set forth the facts in support of the allegations of fraud or coercion and shall be notarized.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4703.3.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of a complaint, the Conversion and Sale Regulatory Office may conduct an investigation or take other appropriate action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4703.4.</num>
    <text>If an election is invalidated due to a finding of coercion or fraud on the part of the tenant organization, a new election will be scheduled and conducted by the Conversion and Sale Regulatory Office within forty-five (47) days of the invalidation,
      or such longer time as may be necessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4703.5.</num>
    <text>If fifty percent (50%) or less of the qualified voters vote in favor of the conversion, or if the election is invalidated due to a finding of fraud or coercion on the part of the owner, the Conversion and Sale Regulatory Office shall issue a notice
      of the result and indicate that the owner may not request another election for that housing accommodation for one (1) year from the date of the election.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 2443 (May 29, 1981), incorporating by reference the text of Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 694, 698-699 (February 13, 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>