<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-1103</num>
  <heading>REVIEW OF STREETSCAPE PLANS (ยง 24-1103)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1103.1.</num>
    <text>The Director shall review the submitted streetscape plans to ensure that the submitted streetscape plan and the application have all the required and necessary information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1103.2.</num>
    <text>The Director shall notify the applicant within five (5) working days of the adequacy of the information included in the submitted streetscape plan. When necessary, the streetscape plan shall be returned to the applicant for the inclusion of any information
      that is required or necessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1103.3.</num>
    <text>The applicant may request, and the Director may grant, upon good cause shown, that the streetscape plan be reviewed in an expeditious manner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1103.4.</num>
    <text>The Director shall convene a Committee to review a submitted streetscape plan and to provide a recommendation to the Director on whether the Director should approve or disapprove the submitted streetscape plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1103.5.</num>
    <text>The Committee shall be appointed by the Director and shall consist of representatives of the Design, Engineering and Construction Administration, Parking Services Administration and the Office of Policy and Planning.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1103.6.</num>
    <text>The Director shall request that a representative from the District of Columbia Office of Planning, the American Institute of Architects and the American Society of Landscape Architects serve as advisory members to the Committee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1103.7.</num>
    <text>The Committee shall, within three (3) weeks of the submission of the streetscape plan, review the streetscape plan to determine if the streetscape plan conforms to the requirements of this chapter and recommend to the Director whether the streetscape
      plan (and any requested variation or exception to the standards) should be approved, disapproved, or modified.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1103.8.</num>
    <text>Variations or exceptions may be recommended for approval if the applicant has demonstrated that the following conditions (a) through (c) have been satisfied or that condition (d) has been adequately demonstrated:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The exception or variation will improve or raise the quality of the streetscape materials or improve or raise the quality of the design of the public space;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The exception or variation is compatible with the adjoining sidewalk and public space;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>That if the project is an historic landmark or in an historic district, the exception or variation is compatible with the historic landmark or historic district; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Compliance with these rules or any provision thereof imposes an undue hardship on the applicant.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1103.9.</num>
    <text>Except as provided for in subsection 1103.10, the applicant shall be notified within five (5) business days of the date the Director receives the Committees&amp;#8217;s recommendation. Written notification of the decision shall be transmitted to the
      applicant within ten (10) business days of the Director&amp;#8217;s decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1103.10.</num>
    <text>When the Committee recommends disapproval of the submitted streetscape plan, or of an element of the plan, the Executive Secretary of the Committee shall notify the applicant and arrange a meeting between the applicant and members of the Committee,
      as deemed necessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1103.11.</num>
    <text>When applicable, the applicant shall submit an amended streetscape plan to the Committee. The Committee shall consider the amended streetscape plan pursuant to subsection 1103.7.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1103.12.</num>
    <text>When appropriate, copies of the Director&amp;#8217;s decision shall be forwarded to the Public Space Permits and Records Division, D.C. Department of Public Works.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1103.13.</num>
    <text>Following notification of Step 2 approval by the Director, the applicant shall submit three (3) copies of the approved streetscape plan to the Director.</text>
    <text>Source: Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7117 (September 1, 2000).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>