<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-433</num>
  <heading>ORGANIZATION TAGS (§ 18-433)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>433.1.</num>
    <text>This Director may issue a tag bearing markings related to an organization (“Organization Tag”) only if the tag has been established by the Council of the District of Columbia or approved by the Director as provided in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>433.2.</num>
    <text>An organization seeking the Director’s approval of an organization tag must be a non-profit corporation, as that term is defined in § 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code (46 U.S.C.§ 501(c)(3)), and must submit an application to the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>433.3.</num>
    <text>The application shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A sample of the proposed markings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A copy of the organization’s charter or articles of incorporation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Proof of the organization’s non-profit status;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Signatures from at least twenty-five (25) members of the organization attesting to their intent to display the organization tag proposed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Proof that the person submitting the application is authorized by the organization to submit that application.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>433.4.</num>
    <text>The organization tag shall only display either the name or the adopted insignia of the organization, or both.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>433.5.</num>
    <text>The format of any organization tag design shall be approved by the Director and shall not obscure any of the lettering or numbering on the tag.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>433.6.</num>
    <text>Any person requesting an organization tag must, in addition to payment of the annual and reservation fees provided for in Section 3(a) of Title IV of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, approved August 17, 1937 (50 Stat. 679; D.C. Official
      Code § 50-1501.03(a)), provide evidence that the person is a member of that organization.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>433.7.</num>
    <text>Upon notification that a person is no longer a member of the organization, the Director may notify that person that they must surrender, within thirty (30) days of notice, the organization tags in their possession.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>433.8.</num>
    <text>The Director may rescind or revoke any organization tag issued to a person who fails to surrender their tag as provided in § 433.7.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>433.9.</num>
    <text>Organization tags shall only be issued for use on registered private passenger vehicles.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 5029 (May 14, 2004) and 51 DCR 10223 (November 5, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>