<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-430</num>
  <heading>VERIFICATION OF INSURANCE INFORMATION (§ 18-430)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>430.1.</num>
    <text>The Director may, at any time, request that an insurance company verify the insurance information provided by a person pursuant to §§ 411.10, 413.12, or 430.4 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>430.2.</num>
    <text>An insurance company shall respond to the Director’s request within ten (10) business days, except as provided in § 430.5 of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>430.3.</num>
    <text>The Director may, at any time, request that a person verify or provide additional information on the insurance information previously provided by that person pursuant to §§ 411.10, 413.12, or 430.4 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>430.4.</num>
    <text>A person shall respond to the Director’s request within fifteen (15) business days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>430.5.</num>
    <text>Within thirty (30) days following the effective date of any cancellation, termination, or expiration of any motor vehicle insurance policy the insurance company shall notify the Department of the cancellation, termination, or expiration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>430.6.</num>
    <text>Any notice of cancellation, expiration or termination sent pursuant to § 430.5 shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The full name and address of the insured;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The insurance policy number or binder number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The expiration or termination date of the motor vehicle insurance policy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Operator’s permit number, if known, of the insured;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The corresponding vehicle identification number(s), if known; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Any other information the Director may require.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>430.7.</num>
    <text>An insurance company shall not notify the Director of the termination, expiration, or cancellation of a motor vehicle insurance policy if the termination, expiration, or cancellation is due to the replacement of one covered vehicle with another covered
      vehicle under the same policy or another policy issued by the same insurer or another insurer in the same group. Notice is also not required if a policy is replaced by another policy or policies covering the same vehicle or vehicles issued by the
      same insurer or another insurer in the same insurance group.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>430.8.</num>
    <text>Based upon the information received by the Director pursuant to this title or based upon the failure of a person to provide the information requested pursuant to this section, the Director may order the suspension or revocation of a license, reciprocity
      sticker, or registration certificate pursuant to the provisions of this title or may refer the matter to the Corporation Counsel for prosecution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>430.9.</num>
    <text>An insurance company shall provide to the Director by October 1, 1983, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The current policy number series or binder number format utilized by that insurance company for motor vehicle insurance policies sold or offered to be sold in the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name, title, address, and phone number of a designated contact person to the Department on insurance verification matters; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The information processing address to which verification requests are to be sent.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>430.10.</num>
    <text>The information required pursuant to § 430.9 of this section shall be updated as necessary by the insurance company.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>430.11.</num>
    <text>Effective June 1, 2005, the notices required by § 430.5 shall be submitted or transmitted in electronic files, following the procedures for such submissions or transmissions established by the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 3133 (March 25, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>