<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-8608</num>
  <heading>CONTINUING EDUCATION CREDITS (§ 17-8608)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8608.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant continuing education credit for whole hours only, with a minimum of fifty (50) minutes constituting one (1) credit hour.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8608.2.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant a maximum of ten (10) continuing education credits per licensure period to an applicant who participates in one (1) or more in-service education programs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8608.3.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant a maximum of fifty percent (50%) of an applicant’s continuing education requirement for completing continuing education activities under § 8607.6.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8608.4.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant credit to an applicant who serves as an instructor or speaker at an approved program for preparation and presentation time, subject to the restrictions under § 8608.7 through § 8608.9.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8608.5.</num>
    <text>The amount of continuing education credit that may be granted shall be fifty percent (50%) of the amount of actual presentation time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8608.6.</num>
    <text>If an applicant has previously received credit in connection with a particular presentation, the Board shall not grant credit for a subsequent presentation unless it involves either a different subject or substantial additional research concerning
      the same subject.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8608.7.</num>
    <text>The presentation shall have been completed during the period for which credit is claimed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8608.8.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant continuing education credit under § 8607.6 only if the applicant proves to the satisfaction of the Board that the work has been published or accepted for publication during the period for which credit is claimed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8608.9.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant continuing education credits for the following activities in the following amounts:</text>
    <text>For serving as a reviewer of articles submitted for publication, one (1) continuing education credit may be granted for each article reviewed up to a maximum of three (3) articles;</text>
    <text>For providing a published critique or response to a published article, one (1) continuing education credit may be granted up to a maximum of three (3) critiques or responses;</text>
    <text>For publishing an article, a maximum of three (3) continuing education credits may be granted;</text>
    <text>For publishing a book, a maximum of fifteen (15) continuing education credits may be granted;</text>
    <text>For serving as a co-editor of a published book, a maximum of fifteen (15) continuing education credits may be divided among the co-editors with each co-editor receiving at least three (3) continuing education credits;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>For publishing a book chapter, a maximum of three (3) continuing education credits may be granted;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>For reviewing a book, a maximum of three (3) continuing education credits may be granted;</text>
    </level>
    <text>For serving as a senior editor for a journal or periodical, a maximum of</text>
    <text>twelve (12) continuing education credits may be granted;</text>
    <text>For serving as an associate editor for a journal or periodical, a maximum of nine (9) continuing education credits may be granted;</text>
    <text>For serving as a junior (or comparable level) editor, six (6) continuing education credits may be granted;</text>
    <text>For serving as a speaker or instructor for a seminar, workshop, conference, or in-service training, a maximum of six (6) continuing education credits per total presentation time may be granted; or</text>
    <text>For serving as a developer of an online or home study continuing education course, a maximum of three (3) continuing education credits per course may be granted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8608.10.</num>
    <text>A registrant shall receive no more than fifteen (15) continuing education credits for any combination of the activities listed in § 8608.11 or for completing any combination of online and home study courses.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8608.11.</num>
    <text>No continuing education credit shall be awarded for any activity of a registrant if either of the following is true:</text>
    <text>The activity is an expected responsibility of a paid position held by the registrant (such as a professor on a tenure track publishing an article); or</text>
    <text>The registrant received compensation for the activity (including honoraria) or the registrant shall receive compensation in the future.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 3246, 3252 (April 15, 2011); as corrected by Errata Notice published at 59 DCR 8356, 8357 (July 13, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>