<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-8612</num>
  <heading>STANDARDS OF CONDUCT (§ 17-8612)
    <text>A registrant shall adhere to standards set forth in the “Ethical Principles</text>
    <text>of Psychologists and Code of Conduct” as published from time to time</text>
    <text>by the American Psychological Association.</text>
    <text>A psychology associate shall not reveal to another person a communication made to the psychology associate by a client about a</text>
    <text>matter where the client has utilized the services of the psychology associate in a professional capacity. This section shall not</text>
    <text>apply to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A case conference with other mental health professionals or with</text>
    </level>
    <text>physicians or surgeons;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A case in which the client authorized, in writing, the psychology</text>
    </level>
    <text>associate to reveal a communication;</text>
    <text>A case where an immediate threat of serious physical harm to an</text>
    <text>identifiable victim is communicated to the psychology associate by</text>
    <text>a client;</text>
    <text>Evidence in criminal cases where the accused is charged</text>
    <text>with causing the death of, or inflicting injuries upon, a human</text>
    <text>being, and the disclosure is required in the interest of public</text>
    <text>justice;</text>
    <text>Evidence relating to the mental competency or sanity of an accused person in a criminal trial where the accused person raises the defense of insanity or where the court is required under prevailing law to raise the defense sua sponte, or in the pretrial
      or post-trial proceedings involving a criminal case where a question arises concerning the mental condition of an accused person or convicted person;</text>
    <text>Evidence relating to the mental competency or sanity of a child alleged to be delinquent, neglected, or in need of supervision in any proceeding before the Family Division of the District of Columbia Superior Court;</text>
    <text>Evidence in criminal or civil cases where a person is alleged to have defrauded the District of Columbia or federal government in relation to receiving or providing services under the District of Columbia medical assistance program authorized by Title
      19 of the Social Security Act, approved July 30, 1965 (79 Stat. 343; 42 U.S.C. §§ 1396, et seq.)</text>
    <text>Proceedings conducted by the Office of Administrative</text>
    <text>Hearings where the disclosure of confidential communications is</text>
    <text>necessary to defend against charges that the psychology associate</text>
    <text>has violated provisions of this chapter or the Act; or</text>
    <text>Information regarding incidents of child abuse as required pursuant to the Prevention of Child Abuse and Neglect Act of 1977, effective September 23, 1977 (D.C. Law 2-22; D.C. Official Code § 4-1321.02(b)).</text>
    <text>A psychology associate shall refer to himself or herself as a “psychology</text>
    <text>associate under the supervision of (name and license number of supervisor)” in all written and oral communications relating to the provision of psychological services.</text>
    <text>A psychology associate shall not refer to himself or herself as a</text>
    <text>psychologist, either orally or in writing, and shall discourage others from</text>
    <text>making these representations.</text>
    <text>A supervisor or psychology associate shall inform clients of the</text>
    <text>supervision arrangement and its possible implications for insurancereimbursements and confidentiality.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <num>8612.6.</num>
    <text>A psychology associate may not engage in, or give the appearance of,</text>
    <text>practicing independently of the supervisor.</text>
    <text>A supervisor and a psychology associate shall ensure that parties who are</text>
    <text>billed for services by the psychology associate are informed that the</text>
    <text>supervisor has full responsibility.</text>
    <text>A supervisor and a psychology associate shall cosign all reports related to</text>
    <text>psychological services provided by the psychology associate.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 3246, 3256 (April 15, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>