<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-3415</num>
  <heading>RESPONSIBILITY FOR SALARY ADMINISTRATION (§ 19-3415)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3415.1.</num>
    <text>The Personnel Office shall be responsible for the administration and maintenance of the Commission’s salary administration program. The responsibilities of the Personnel Office of the Commission shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Conducting salary surveys;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Establishing pay levels, job descriptions and job classifications subject to the approval of the Executive Director; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Monitoring all personnel actions and pay practices to ensure compliance with Commission policies and federal and local laws.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3415.2.</num>
    <text>The Personnel Office shall recommend salary ranges based upon periodic surveys of comparable positions within other organizations in the Washington Metropolitan area, the stadium, auditorium, and arena industry.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3415.3.</num>
    <text>Salary ranges for each job classification include a minimum and maximum salary. Ordinarily, the Commission shall hire new employees at or near the minimum salary level for their position. However, in some cases, the Commission may establish a starting
      salary at a higher level in order to successfully recruit the best qualified applicant for certain positions identified by the Personnel Office.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3415.4.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director may authorize an increase to the Commission salary administration program. Employees shall have completed at least ninety (90) days service in order to be eligible for increase in pay.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 4938, 4945-46 (August 29, 1997).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>