<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-3420</num>
  <heading>CORRECTIVE ACTION PROCESS (ยง 19-3420)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3420.1.</num>
    <text>Corrective actions are formal actions of the Commission. The corrective action process consists of a number of steps that may or may not be followed in sequence, including, but not limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Oral Reprimand;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Written Reprimand;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Suspension; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Dismissal or Termination.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3420.2.</num>
    <text>Disciplinary leave (suspension) may be given to an employee under one of the following two sets of circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>As a follow-up to a written notice of unsatisfactory performance in the corrective action process; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>As an interim measure following an act of serious misconduct or breach of organizational rules or regulations. The Executive Director or his/her designee shall review and approve every disciplinary action.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3420.3.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall terminate an employee who has been charged with serious misconduct or neglect of duty. The Executive Director or his/her designee shall approve every involuntary termination, except those involving probationary employees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3420.4.</num>
    <text>Examples of serious misconduct or neglect of duty include, but are not limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Insubordination, incompetency or gross inefficiency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Fighting on the job or using abusive or profane language;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Possession of controlled substances;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Intoxication;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Misrepresentation in securing employment or falsification of official records;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Breach of confidentiality, theft or dishonesty;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Failure to exercise reasonable judgment in performance of job duties;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Failure to follow organizational rules, policies and procedures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Sexual harassment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Tardiness, poor attendance or lack of dependability;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Discourteous treatment of the Commission clients, the public, supervisors, or other employees;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Misuse, mutilation or destruction of Commission property or funds; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Failure of good behavior during duty hours which is of such a nature that it causes discredit to the Commission.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 4938, 4848-49 (August 29, 1997).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>