<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-113</num>
  <heading>BUSINESS STREETS (§ 24-113)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>113.1.</num>
    <text>The streets within the following boundary areas shall be denominated &amp;#8220;business streets&amp;#8221; for the purposes of this chapter:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>K Street N.W., between Fifth and Sixth Streets;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The west side of Seventh Street, N.W., between the northern limit of the market building of the Northern Market Co., and the south building line of P Street;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The west side of Eleventh Street, S.W., between Maine Avenue and F Street; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The south side of F Street, S.W., from Eleventh Street westward, a distance not exceeding one hundred feet (100 ft.).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>113.2.</num>
    <text>The business streets and the sidewalks adjacent to business streets may be used by occupants of abutting property for business purposes under the conditions set forth in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>113.3.</num>
    <text>Permission to occupy more space on business streets than is allowed in § 112 shall not be granted by the Director of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs, except under special order extending the limits of permissible occupation along the front of an entire
      block.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>113.4.</num>
    <text>No permit shall be granted to occupy any portion of the sidewalk or parking to any person who is not the owner or occupant of the property abutting that sidewalk or parking.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>113.5.</num>
    <text>Permits to occupy parking, sidewalks, or other public space shall not be transferable, and the space shall not be sublet.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>113.6.</num>
    <text>Whenever any occupant of an adjacent building vacates the building, or sells or otherwise transfers his or her business in whole or in part, any permit previously issued to the occupant shall become void.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>113.7.</num>
    <text>The subdivision of the space shall be under the direction of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>113.8.</num>
    <text>If meat, fish, poultry, or game of any kind is sold, the person or persons holding the permit(s) shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Have those commodities under roof, and screened or covered as provided by the health and food regulations of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Have a clean water supply for cleaning the hands and utensils of food dealers; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Ensure that these foods are kept from insanitary and contaminating products.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>113.9.</num>
    <text>Anyone who uses public space to display merchandise and wares shall keep clean metal receptacles with covers for the deposit of all kinds of garbage, trash, and waste.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>113.10.</num>
    <text>No papers, trash, or rubbish shall be thrown on any public space or in the streets adjacent to any public space; and no person shall allow any barrels, boxes, crates, or other property owned by him or her to be placed on any space not assigned to
      the person for occupancy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>113.11.</num>
    <text>The hours during which commodities may be sold on public space under this section are as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>During the months of April, May, June, July, August, and September, from 4:30 a.m. to 8:00 p.m.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>During the months of October, November, December, January, February, and March, from 5:00 a.m. to 8:00 p.m.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>During all months, on Saturdays until 11:30 p.m.; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>At no time on Sundays.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>113.12.</num>
    <text>The schedule of distribution of the space between the building line and the curb line on each side of K Street, shall be as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A total of twenty-one feet (21 ft.) may be used for spaces;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The twenty-one feet (21 ft.) shall be divided into not more than three (3) spaces, one (1) of which shall not exceed five feet (5 ft.) wide, and two (2) of which shall not exceed eight feet (8 ft.) wide;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The five foot (5 ft.) wide space shall be contiguous to the curb; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Each space shall be separated from each other space by an aisle for pedestrian traffic at least ten feet (10 ft.) wide, with an aisle between the building line and the nearest eight foot (8 ft.) space the width of the remaining portion of the sidewalk
        space.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>113.13.</num>
    <text>The spaces are authorized to be used for the temporary display, handling, and sale of goods, and for the placing of counters. The counters shall be no more than four feet (4 ft.) in height; and shall not be placed or maintained in the space during
      the hours when spaces may not be used under this section, nor when spaces are otherwise not in use for the display of goods, unless any authorized canopy is adequately lighted for protection of pedestrians; Provided, that foods that are eaten in
      an uncooked condition, such as peaches, apples, grapes, and other fruits or vegetables, shall be placed on stands or tables that are not less than eighteen inches (18 in.) in height, or placed on the counters authorized by this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>113.14.</num>
    <text>All aisles shall be kept open and unobstructed at all times.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>113.15.</num>
    <text>The name of the owner of the merchandise displayed for sale on any of space or stand shall be conspicuously posted on the top of each stand.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 4, §§7 &amp;#038; 8 of the Police Regulations (May 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>