<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-208</num>
  <heading>BUSINESS LICENSE REQUIREMENTS (§ 17-208)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>208.1.</num>
    <text>A business license shall be required of each contractor whose work includes the removal and reinstallation of electrical applicances, apparatus, fixtures, equipment, and devices or any installation coming within the scope of the D.C. Electrical Code.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.2.</num>
    <text>A license shall be required to engage in the business of electrical contractor, special contractor, or electrical fixture contractor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.3.</num>
    <text>No electrician, master electrician, or master electrician specialist shall engage in a business for which a license is required without first having obtained a business license as a contractor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.4.</num>
    <text>A business licensee who has more than one (1) business location shall obtain a separate license and file a separate bond for each location.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.5.</num>
    <text>A business license may be issued to a contractor to engage in a specified business at a specified location, as required in this section, conditioned upon one of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The licensee shall be licensed as a master electrician;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The licensee shall have a master electrician as an officer or substantial stockholder in the firm or corporation; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The licensee shall have as an employee a master electrician.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.6.</num>
    <text>A limited business license to engage in work as an electrical contractor, special contractor, or an electrical fixture contractor may be issued to a contractor to engage in a limited business at a specified location, conditioned upon one of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The licensee shall be licensed as a master electrician or a master electrician specialist;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The licensee shall have a master electrician or a master electrician specialist as an officer or substantial stockholder in the firm or corporation; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The licensee shall have as an employee a master electrician or a master electrician specialist.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.7.</num>
    <text>The master electrician or master electrician specialist referred to in §208.6 must be qualified and licensed in the same specialty as the business licensed under that subsection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.8.</num>
    <text>All work done under a license or limited license to engage in a business under this section shall be under the personal supervision of the master electrician or master electrician specialist designated under §208.5 or §208.6, and the master electrician
      or master electrician specialist shall be responsible for all work performed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.9.</num>
    <text>No master electrician or master electrician specialist shall be responsible for the work of more than one (1) contractor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.10.</num>
    <text>The limitations on a business license shall not be greater than the limitations specified for the master electrician specialist responsible for work done.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>5J DCRR §§408, 424, 427, 443, 444, 446, 502, 505 and 822.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>