<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-213</num>
  <heading>SUSPENSION AND REVOCATION OF LICENSES (§ 17-213)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>213.1.</num>
    <text>Any license issued under this chapter shall be revoked if the surety on the bond becomes unsatisfactory to the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>213.2.</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall revoke any license issued under this chapter when it is shown to his or her satisfaction that the licensee, in his or her license application or application for renewal, knowingly made a false statement or misrepresentation deemed
      material to the issuance or renewal of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>213.3.</num>
    <text>A business or occupational license issued under this chapter may be suspended or revoked by the Mayor for a violation of this chapter or other District law or regulation applicable to the licensed activity; Provided, that the Board has held a hearing
      on the question of the violation after at least five (5) days notice to the licensee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>213.4.</num>
    <text>After a suspension or revocation hearing, the Board shall forward its findings and recommendation to the Mayor through the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>213.5.</num>
    <text>The licensee may appeal the decision of the Electrical Examining Board to the Mayor within thirty (30) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>213.6.</num>
    <text>On information that any person licensed under this chapter has been convicted of an offense involving moral turpitude, the Mayor may, within his or her discretion, suspend or revoke the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>213.7.</num>
    <text>Upon the application of any person whose license has been revoked or suspended and upon showing a good cause, the Mayor may reinstate the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>5J DCRR §§462, 463, 465 and 469.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>