<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-5107</num>
  <heading>RECORDS (ยง 29-5107)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5107.1.</num>
    <text>Each Provider shall maintain accurate records reflecting past and current findings, the initial and subsequent plans of care, and the ongoing progress of each client.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5107.2.</num>
    <text>Each Provider shall maintain accurate records reflecting the specific services provided to each client.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5107.3.</num>
    <text>Each Provider shall maintain patient records that are confidential, complete and contain up-to-date information relevant to each patient&amp;#8217;s care and treatment. For purposes of record confidentiality, the disclosure of treatment information
      by the Provider is subject to all the provisions of applicable District and Federal Laws.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5107.4.</num>
    <text>Each patient&amp;#8217;s record shall include written documentation of the patient&amp;#8217;s treatment needs and services. The documentation shall be written so that it is easily understood by a lay person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5107.5.</num>
    <text>Each patient&amp;#8217;s record shall be kept in a locked room or file maintained and safeguarded against loss or unauthorized use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5107.6.</num>
    <text>Each patient&amp;#8217;s record shall be available for review by MAA staff at all times.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5107.7.</num>
    <text>Each Provider shall maintain patient records for a minimum of six (6) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5107.8.</num>
    <text>Each patient&amp;#8217;s record shall include, but is not limited to, the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Medical information, including the initial and annual assessments, and the initial certification and re-certifications of the plan of care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>General information including each patient&amp;#8217;s name, Medicaid identification number, address, telephone number, age, sex, name and telephone of emergency contact person, physician&amp;#8217;s name, address and telephone number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Description and dates of services rendered, including the name of the home health aide performing the services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Documentation of each supervisory visit of the registered nurse or therapist, including signed and dated clinical progress notes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Extended authorizations for services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Discharge summary, if applicable; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Any other appropriate identifying information that is pertinent to patient care.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 3957 (May 23, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>