<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-5104</num>
  <heading>PROGRAM SERVICES (ยง 29-5104)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5104.1.</num>
    <text>Home health aide services shall be prescribed by a physician in accordance with the patient&amp;#8217;s plan of treatment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5104.2.</num>
    <text>Home health aide services shall be initiated no later than 48 hours after completion of the initial assessment unless the patient or the patient&amp;#8217;s representative agree to a later date to begin the services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5104.3.</num>
    <text>Home health aide services shall be provided by an individual who is not a member of the patient&amp;#8217;s family.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5104.4.</num>
    <text>Home health aide services include, but are not limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Basic personal care including bathing, grooming and assistance with toileting, or bed pan use;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Changing urinary drainage bags;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Assisting patients with self-administered medications;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Reading and recording temperature, pulse, and respiration;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Assisting patients with transfer, ambulation and exercises as directed by the nurse or therapist;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Simple dressing changes that do not require the skills of a licensed nurse;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Assisting patients with activities that are directly supportive of skilled therapy services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Routine care of prosthetic and orthotic devices;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Observing and documenting the patient&amp;#8217;s status and reporting all services provided;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Meal preparation in accordance with dietary guidelines and assistance with eating;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Recording and reporting to the supervisory health professional, changes in the patient&amp;#8217;s physical condition, behavior or appearance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Infection control; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Tasks related to keeping the patient&amp;#8217;s living areas in a condition that promotes the patient&amp;#8217;s health and comfort.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5104.5.</num>
    <text>Home health aide services shall not include services that require the skills of a licensed professional, such as catheter insertion, procedures requiring the use of sterile techniques and administration of medication.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5104.6.</num>
    <text>Home health aide services shall not include tasks usually performed by chore workers, such as cleaning of areas not occupied by the patient, laundry for family members and shopping for items not used by the patient.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5104.7.</num>
    <text>Home health aide services shall be provided in the patient&amp;#8217;s place of residence subject to the exclusions set forth in ยง 5104.8 and shall be made available seven (7) days per week.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5104.8.</num>
    <text>Home health aide services shall not be provided in a hospital, nursing facility, intermediate care facility for the mentally retarded or institution for mental disease.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 3957 (May 23, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>