<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-103</num>
  <heading>EXECUTIVE SESSIONS (ยง 3-103)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>103.1.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term &amp;#8220;executive session&amp;#8221; means a Board meeting where the public, employees of the Board, or any other persons may be excluded.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.2.</num>
    <text>The Board may enter into executive session, and discuss any matter upon which it will not vote, make resolutions or rulings, or take action of any kind, including the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Personnel matters, including the recruitment, appointment, employment, assignment, promotion, discipline, compensation, removal, or resignation of employees, or other individuals over whom it has jurisdiction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Employee disciplinary actions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>General Counsel briefings on litigation strategy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Confidential proceedings under the Campaign Finance Act;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Quasi-judicial deliberations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Matters which would result in the disclosure of information specifically exempted from disclosure by statute;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Matters which would result in the disclosure of trade secrets and commercial or financial information;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Matters which would involve a clear and unwarranted invasion of privacy, an accusation of a crime, or formal censure; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Matters which would result in the disclosure investigatory records compiled for law enforcement purposes.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 28 D.C. Reg. 1726 (April 17, 1981), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 28 D.C. Reg.684, 687-88 (February 13, 1981); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 D.C. Reg. 3937,
        3938 (May 15, 2009); and as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 D.C. Reg. 3263, 3265 (April 16, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>