<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-1507</num>
  <heading>PRE-HEARING PROCEDURES (§ 24-1507)
    <text>The President or his or her designee shall notify the respondent, both inriting and, if possible, by phone, of the date, time, and place of the hearing.The notice shall be provided at least three (3) days in advance of the hearing.</text>
    <text>The hearing shall be held within ten (10) days of the date of the hearingequest, unless the time is extended for good cause.</text>
    <text>The notice of hearing shall:</text>
    <text>Include a summary of or a copy of the rules governing the hearing process;</text>
    <text>Advise the respondent:</text>
    <text>Of his or her right to be represented by a lawyer or other person at theearing, at the respondent’s own expense;</text>
    <text>Of the right to present documents and witnesses, including WHS employees, inupport of the appeal;</text>
    <text>Of the right to examine and duplicate, at respondent’s expense, the writtenummary, and any evidence appended to the summary, described in § 1505 at leasthree (3) days prior to the date of the hearing;</text>
    <text>Of the right to examine and duplicate, at respondent’s expense, the writtenummary of expenses described in § 1506 at least three (3) days prior to theate of the hearing;</text>
    <text>Of the right to examine any part of the case record, except for informationhat the President or his or her designee classifies as confidential, at leasthree (3) days prior to the hearing;</text>
    <text>That if the respondent or a witness is deaf or cannot readily understand orommunicate the spoken English language, the respondent may apply to WHS for theppointment of a qualified interpreter and such services will be provided;</text>
    <text>Of the name and telephone number of the person to call if the respondent cannotttend the hearing; and</text>
    <text>The failure to attend the hearing without good cause may result in dismissal ofhe appeal.</text>
    <text>The respondent may request a change of the date, time, or place of the hearing.If the President or his or her designee finds that good cause for a changexists, he or she shall set another date, time, or place for the hearing. Theime limit established
      by § 1502.2 shall be extended by the period of delay.</text>
    <text>The respondent may request, in writing, assistance to secure the attendance athe hearing of any WHS employee. The request shall state the reasons why themployee’s attendance is required. If the President or his or her designeeecides that the employee’s
      attendance is necessary for the fair determinationf the issues on appeal, the President or his or her designee shall require themployee, if still employed by WHS, to be present at the hearing.</text>
    <text>The President or his or her designee may require the presence at the hearing ofny WHS employee.</text>
    <text>The respondent may examine and/or duplicate the written summary, and anyvidence appended to that summary, described in § 1505 at least three (3) daysrior to the hearing.</text>
    <text>The respondent may examine and/or duplicate the written summary of expensesescribed in § 1506 at least three (3) days prior to the hearing.</text>
    <text>The respondent may examine any part of the case record, except for informationhat the President or her designee classifies as confidential, at least three3) days prior to the hearing.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 316January 9, 2009)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published6 DCR 2374, 2379 (March 27, 2009).</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>