<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-1505</num>
  <heading>WRITTEN SUMMARY OF REASONS SUPPORTING SEIZURE AND CUSTODY (§ 24-1505)
    <text>The WHS humane officer who seized the animal shall prepare a written summaryxplain the reasons why the humane officer seized the animal and why WHSontinues to retain custody of the animal. An incident report qualifies as aritten summary under this
      chapter provided that it complies with § 1502.2.</text>
    <text>The written summary shall include:</text>
    <text>The facts supporting the humane officer’s determination that seizure wasecessary to protect the animal from neglect or cruelty, if the seizure was madeursuant to D.C. Official Code § 22-1004(b)(1);</text>
    <text>The actions that the owner must take in order to regain custody of the animal;nd</text>
    <text>If the humane officer determines that WHS cannot return the animal to the ownerithout subjecting the animal to ongoing neglect or cruelty, the factsupporting a determination that WHS should retain permanent custody of thenimal.</text>
    <text>The humane officer may append to the written summary:</text>
    <text>Documentary evidence collected during the course of the investigation,including written notes taken by the humane officer or other WHS employees;</text>
    <text>Physical evidence collected during the course of the investigation;</text>
    <text>Written statements by other WHS employees or third-party witnesses; and</text>
    <text>Medical reports based on first-hand examinations of the animal.</text>
    <text>The humane officer may seek assistance from other WHS employees in thereparation of the written summary.</text>
    <text>The written summary, and any evidence appended to the summary, shall beompleted at least three (3) days before the date of the scheduled hearing. Theompleted written summary, and any evidence appended to the summary, shall beade available to the respondent
      and his or her representative for examinationnd/or duplication. Any duplication costs shall be paid for by the respondent.</text>
    <text>The failure to make available to the respondent and his or her representativeshe written summary and any evidence appended to the summary is good cause for aontinuance of the hearing pursuant to § 1507.4.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 316January 9, 2009)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published6 DCR 2374, 2377 (March 27, 2009).</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>