<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4010</num>
  <heading>REINSTATEMENT OF AN EXPIRED LICENSE (ยง 17-4010)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4010.1.</num>
    <text>This section applies to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An applicant for reinstatement of an expired licensed issued under the Act, in accordance with ยง512 of the Act, D.C. Code ยง2-3305.12 (1987 Supp.); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An applicant for reinstatement of an expired license or certificate issued under a law repealed or amended by the Act.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4010.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant for reinstatement under this section shall file an application with the board on the prescribed form and shall pay the required reinstatement fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4010.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant for reinstatement under this section shall demonstrate fitness to resume practice by submitting evidence satisfactory to the board that the applicant has the competency and knowledge of District and federal laws necessary to resume practice
      of the health occupation and that the applicant&amp;#8217;s resumption of practice will not be detrimental to the public interest or the integrity of the health profession.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4010.4.</num>
    <text>In making a determination pursuant of ยง4010.3, the board shall consider the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The length of time that the applicant had practiced in the District or other jurisdictions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The length of time after expiration of the applicant&amp;#8217;s license that the applicant was not practicing the health profession in the District or other jurisdictions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any violations by the applicant of the Act, this subchapter, or other laws, or other conduct by the applicant that would be grounds for discipline under the Act;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s present character; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s present qualifications and competency to practice the health occupation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4010.5.</num>
    <text>A board may require an applicant to complete certain educational or training requirements, in addition to any continuing education requirements, to be completed prior to or after reinstatement to ensure that the applicant is competent to practice
      the health occupation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4010.6.</num>
    <text>A person who was licensed as a health professional under a law repealed by the Act and who was not licensed under the Act may apply for reinstatement pursuant to this section by March 25, 1991. After this date, such a person must apply as an applicant
      for a new license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 5859, 5867 (September 11, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>