<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4011</num>
  <heading>REINSTATEMENT AFTER REVOCATION (ยง 17-4011)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4011.1.</num>
    <text>A health professional whose license, certificate, or registration has been revoked, or whose application for reinstatement has been denied, shall be ineligible to apply for reinstatement for a period of one (1) year from the date of the revocation
      or denial, unless otherwise provided in the board order of revocation or denial.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4011.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant for reinstatement under this section shall file an application with the board on the prescribed form and shall pay the required reinstatement fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4011.3.</num>
    <text>In addition to the requirements of ยง4011.2, and applicant for reinstatement shall demonstrate fitness to resume practice by submitting evidence satisfactory to the board that the applicant has the moral qualifications, competency, and knowledge of
      District and federal laws necessary to resume practice of the health occupation and that the applicant&amp;#8217;s resumption of practice will not be detrimental to the public interest or the integrity of the health profession</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4011.4.</num>
    <text>In making a determination pursuant to ยง4011.3, the board shall consider, among other factors, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The nature and circumstances of the conduct, or the mental or physical condition, for which the applicant&amp;#8217;s license, certificate, or registration was revoked;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s recognition and appreciation of the seriousness of any misconduct;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s conduct, or mental or physical condition, since the revocation, including steps taken by the applicant to remedy prior misconduct and prevent future misconduct, or to remedy the mental or physical condition;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s present character; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s present qualifications and competency to practice the health occupation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 5859, 5868 (September 11, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>