<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-705</num>
  <heading>REQUIREMENTS FOR NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS FORMED BY SPECIAL ACT OF CONGRESS (§7-705)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>705.1.</num>
    <text>This section applies to nonprofit corporations formed in the District of Columbia by a special act of Congress, except to the extent that a requirement of this section is in irreconcilable conflict with a provision of the special act of Congress.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.2.</num>
    <text>A nonprofit corporation described in § 705.1 that elects to become subject to Chapter 4 (Nonprofit Corporations) of the Act (D.C. Official Code § 29-401 et seq. (2011 Repl.) before January 1, 2014, shall file with the Superintendent:</text>
    <text>A copy of the corporation’s congressional charter and any amendments thereto;</text>
    <text>A copy of a resolution adopted by the corporation electing to be subject to the Act; and</text>
    <text>A copy of the corporation’s articles of incorporation, if any.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.3.</num>
    <text>A nonprofit corporation that makes an election under § 705.2 shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>File a biennial report with the Superintendent by April 1, 2014; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>File subsequent biennial reports every two (2) years following the first April 1 filing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.4.</num>
    <text>A nonprofit corporation described in § 705.1 that does not make an election to become subject to Chapter 4 (Nonprofit Corporations) of the Act (D.C. Official Code § 29-401 et seq. (2011 Repl.) shall file with the Superintendent, no later than January
      1, 2014, a statement containing the following:</text>
    <text>The corporation’s name;</text>
    <text>The corporation’s date of formation;</text>
    <text>The name and address of at least one (1) governor of the corporation;</text>
    <text>The name and address of the registered agent of the corporation; and</text>
    <text>A copy of the corporation’s congressional charter and any amendments thereto.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.5.</num>
    <text>A nonprofit corporation described in § 705.4 shall:</text>
    <text>File a biennial report by April 1, 2014;</text>
    <text>File subsequent biennial reports every two (2) years following the first April 1 filing; and</text>
    <text>Maintain a registered agent pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 29-104.04 (2011 Repl.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.6.</num>
    <text>If a nonprofit corporation described in § 705.1 fails to file a timely biennial report or fails to maintain a registered agent, as required by § 705.5, the Superintendent may administratively dissolve the corporation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.7.</num>
    <text>A nonprofit corporation described in § 705.6 that is administratively dissolved may apply for reinstatement subject to the requirements of D.C. Official Code § 29-106.03 (2011 Repl.); provided, that the nonprofit corporation files the documents required
      by § 705.2 and the biennial report required by § 705.3(a).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 13139 (September 20, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>