<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-1099</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 27-1099)
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Contingent fee &amp;#8211; any commission, percentage, brokerage, or other fee thats dependant upon or tied to the success that a person or concern has inecuring a District contract.</text>
    <text>Contract &amp;#8211; a mutually binding agreement between the District and aontractor, which must be in writing unless otherwise authorized by the Act,ncluding agreements in which a party other than the District is obligated toay the contractor.</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; the agency head of the Office of Contracting and ProcurementOCP) or the Chief Procurement Officer (CPO).</text>
    <text>Market survey &amp;#8211; a testing of the marketplace to ascertain whether otherualified sources capable of satisfying the District&amp;#8217;s requirement exist.t may range from written or telephone contacts with knowledgeable expertsegarding similar
      or duplicate requirements, and the results of any market testecently undertaken, to the more formal sources-sought announcements inertinent publications (such as technical or scientific journals, or theommerce Business Daily) or solicitations for
      information or planning purposes.</text>
    <text>Person &amp;#8211; any business entity, individual, union, committee, club, or otherrganization or group of individuals.</text>
    <text>Pre-solicitation &amp;#8211; prior to the transmittal by the District of anyroposed contract documents to the proposed contractor before the issuance of aolicitation or in a proposed sole source procurement.</text>
    <text>Procurement planning &amp;#8211; the process by which the efforts of all personnelesponsible for an acquisition are coordinated and integrated through aomprehensive plan for fulfilling agency needs in a timely manner and at aeasonable cost. It includes
      developing the overall strategy for managing thecquisition.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1394 (February 26, 1988); asmended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 9071September 27, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemakingublished at 58 DCR 11071, 11077
        (December 23, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>