<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-1004</num>
  <heading>AUTHORITY AND RESPONSIBILITIES OF CONTRACTING OFFICERS (ยง 27-1004)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1004.1.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall be authorized to enter into, administer, and terminate contracts. However, the contracting officer may bind the District only to the extent of the contracting authority set forth in his or her delegation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1004.2.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall:</text>
    <text>Make all determinations and findings required by the Act or this title for each solicitation or contract for which he or she is responsible;</text>
    <text>Not enter into a contract unless he or she has ensured that all requirements of law, Mayor&amp;#8217;s Orders, Mayor&amp;#8217;s Memoranda, rules, and all other applicable procedures (including approvals) have been met;</text>
    <text>Have wide latitude to exercise business judgment;</text>
    <text>Ensure that contractors receive impartial, fair, and equitable treatment in accordance with the Act and this title;</text>
    <text>Request and consider the advice of specialists in auditing, law, engineering, transportation, and other fields when necessary or appropriate to the exercise of the contracting officer&amp;#8217;s authority;</text>
    <text>Ensure that sufficient unencumbered budget authority is available for obligation for each contract, in accordance with chapter 32 of this title; and</text>
    <text>Not make any purchase or enter into any contract for an amount in excess of his or her specifically delegated contracting authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1387 (February 26, 1988); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 9071 (September 27, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 11071,
        11074 (December 23, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>