<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-209</num>
  <heading>SICK LEAVE (ยง 19-209)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>209.1</num>
    <text>209.1 All regular full-time employees shall earn eight (8) hours of sick leaveer month. All regular full-time employees begin to accrue leave starting withheir first day of employment. Accrual for regular part-time employees andmployees in non-pay
      status shall be prorated to correspond with the actualumber of hours worked.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>209.2</num>
    <text>209.2 All regular part-time employees shall earn sick leave by the same methods regular full-time employees, provided that the amount earned shall berorated to correspond with the actual number of hours worked.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>209.3</num>
    <text>209.3 An employee may use sick leave for personal illness or to care for aelative and other children and adults for whom the employee is a primaryaretaker.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>209.4</num>
    <text>209.4 If there is any reason to suspect an abuse of sick leave by an employee,he employee may be required to submit a letter signed by the attendinghysician certifying the illness of the employee, relative, or other child ordult for whom the employee
      is the primary caretaker, as the basis for themployee&amp;#8217;s inability to work on the days for which leave is requested. Theresident and Chief Executive Officer may require an employee to undergo anndependent medical examination in the event
      the employee&amp;#8217;s use of leaveor personal illness exceeds seven (7) consecutive workdays. The Authority shallay the cost of such a medical examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>209.5</num>
    <text>209.5 An employee who uses all of his or her accrued sick leave and annualeave may be placed on leave of absence without pay status for the duration ofhe illness of the employee, relative, or other child or adult for whom themployee is the primary
      caretaker.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>209.6</num>
    <text>209.6 The number of hours that may be carried forward in an employee&amp;#8217;sick leave account into a new calendar year shall not exceed two hundred forty240) hours. Employees shall not be compensated for unused sick leave uponeparation from employment
      with the Authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 6236, 6240 (July 30, 1999); asmended by 55 DCR 8524, 8525 (August 8, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemakingublished at 59 DCR 8191, 8195 (July 6, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>