<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-299</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 19-299)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>299.1</num>
    <text>299.1 When used in this chapter, the following words and terms shall have theeanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Authority &amp;#8211; the Washington Convention and Sports Authority established byhe Washington Convention Center Authority Act of 1994, effective September 28,994, D.C. Law 10-188, as amended by the Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Act of009, effective
      March 3, 2010 (D.C. Law 18-111; D.C. Official Code §§0-1201.01, et seq. (2008 Repl. &amp;#038; 2011 Supp.))</text>
    <text>Board &amp;#8211; the Board of Directors of the Authority.</text>
    <text>Casual employee &amp;#8211; an employee whose terms of appointment provide formployment either: (1) for a brief period of time or (2) on a casual or aseeded basis.</text>
    <text>Executive Staff &amp;#8211; an employee at the level of Division Director or above.</text>
    <text>President and Chief Executive Officer- the President and Chief Executive Officerf the Authority or his or her designee.</text>
    <text>Public body &amp;#8211; any body described by § 1503 of the District of Columbiaovernment Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1979, D.C. Official Code §-616.3 (2006 Repl..).</text>
    <text>Regular full-time employee &amp;#8211; an employee whose terms of appointmentrovide that the employee shall work at least forty (40) hours per week either:1) for an unlimited or extended period of time or; (2) for as long as funds arevailable and
      the position is necessary to the objectives of the Authority.</text>
    <text>Regular part-time employee &amp;#8211; an employee whose terms of appointmentrovide that the employee shall work less than forty (40) hours per Week either:1) for an unlimited or extended period of time or; (2) for as long as funds arevailable and
      the position is necessary to the objectives of the Authority.</text>
    <text>Relative &amp;#8211; the spouse, parent, parent-in-law, child, step-child, sister,rother, sister-in-law, brother-in-law, step-parent, aunt, uncle, niece, nephew,randparent, grandchild or registered domestic partner (as defined by Chapter 7f Title
      32 of the District of Columbia Official Code) of an employee of theuthority.</text>
    <text>Vice President &amp;#8211; the Vice President, Human Resources appointed by theresident and Chief Executive Officer of the Authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 6236, 6244-45 (July 30, 1999); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8191, 8200 (July 6, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>