<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-201</num>
  <heading>RECRUITING AND HIRING (ยง 19-201)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>201.1</num>
    <text>201.1 The President and Chief Executive Officer shall be responsible forecruiting and hiring for vacant or new positions, in consultation withppropriate Division Directors.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.2</num>
    <text>201.2 The President and Chief Executive Officer shall post vacancynnouncements for regular full-time and regular part-time positions at theuthority, except for the President and Chief Executive Officer and Executivetaff positions, for a minimum of
      five (5) working days before any job offersay be extended.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.3</num>
    <text>201.3 The following information shall be included in the advertisement for aosition vacancy:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Position title;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Brief description of the work to be performed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Minimum desirable skills and experience required;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Salary information;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Information required to be submitted with application; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Equal employment opportunity language as required.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.4</num>
    <text>201.4 Current employees of the Authority shall be eligible to apply fordvertised vacant positions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.5</num>
    <text>201.5 The President and Chief Executive Officer shall use criteria specificallyelated to the requirements for the position in evaluating an applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.6</num>
    <text>201.6 The President and Chief Executive Officer may authorize reimbursement of prospective employee for interviewing expenses.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 6236, 6237 (July 30, 1999); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8191, 8192 (July 6, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>