<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-200</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 19-200)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>200.1</num>
    <text>200.1 Employees of the Authority shall have regular full-time, regularart-time, or casual status.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>200.2</num>
    <text>200.2 Casual employees shall be eligible only for those benefits required byaw. Regular full-time and regular part-time employees shall be eligible forenefits as provided by these regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>200.3</num>
    <text>200.3 All employees of the Authority shall be at-will employees and serve athe pleasure of the Authority, unless otherwise provided for as members of aargaining unit in a collective bargaining agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>200.4</num>
    <text>200.4 The Authority is an equal opportunity employer. Officers and employeeshall make all decisions on recruiting, hiring, training, compensation,enefits, promotions, transfers, layoffs, and recall from layoffs, and otheranagement actions, free of
      discrimination on the basis of race, color,eligion, national origin, sex, age, marital status, personal appearance, sexualrientation, gender identity or expression, family responsibilities,atriculation, genetic information, disability, or political
      affiliation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>200.5</num>
    <text>200.5 The Authority shall maintain an affirmative action plan to ensure thatqual opportunity in employment is provided for minorities, women, and disabledersons.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>200.6</num>
    <text>200.6 Employees in collective bargaining units will be governed by therovisions set forth in their collective bargaining agreements to the extenthat those differ from the policies set forth in these rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 6236 (July 30, 1999); as amended byinal Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8191 (July 6, 2012).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR&amp;#8217;S NOTE An editorial change was made to the text of the proposedulemaking for this chapter published at 45 DCR 3826 (June 12, 1998) as follows:</heading>
      <text>General Manager of the Authority or his [or her] designee” was substitutedor “various named officers of the Authority where they appear in theules.” 46 DCR 6236. The former rules governing the Authority’s personnelolicies and procedures published
        at 38 DCR 7603 (December 20, 1991) wereescinded in their entirety.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>