<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-807</num>
  <heading>SELF-INSURERS (§ 18-807)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>807.1.</num>
    <text>Any person in whose name twenty-six (26) or more motor vehicles are registered in the District may qualify as a self-insurer by applying to the Director for a certificate of self-insurance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>807.2.</num>
    <text>The Director shall require that the applicant furnish a financial statement and other pertinent information on a form prescribed by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>807.3.</num>
    <text>If the Director is satisfied that the applicant has and will continue to have the ability to pay benefits in the amounts specified by the Act, the Director may issue a certificate authorizing that person to act as a self-insurer for property damage,
      for bodily injury, or for personal injury protection benefits.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>807.4.</num>
    <text>For the purpose of satisfying the requirements of the Act and the No-Fault Insurance Act, each self-insurer approved by the Director shall file an agreement that, with respect to accidents occurring while the certificate of self-insurance is in effect,
      the self-insurer will pay the same monetary amounts that an insurance company would have been obliged to pay under an owner’s motor vehicle insurance policy if an insurance company had issued a motor vehicle insurance policy to the insurer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>807.5.</num>
    <text>A certificate of self-insurance shall be effective for a period of one (1) year from the date of issuance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>807.6.</num>
    <text>After not less than five (5) days notice and a hearing, if requested, pursuant to that notice, the Director may revoke a certificate of self-insurance for any reasonable grounds including, but not limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Failure to pay any required benefits within thirty (30) days after the notice of injury:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Failure to own and register the required number of motor vehicles;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Financial inability of the self-insurer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Failure of the self-insurer to pay an assessment levied pursuant to the No-Fault Act and rules issued by the Superintendent of Insurance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Failure to comply with all District laws applicable to self-insurers.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>&amp;#8212; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 5243, 5247 (June 18, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>