<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-811</num>
  <heading>BALLOT ACCOUNTING (§ 3-811)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>811.1.</num>
    <text>Following the tabulation of all votes, a full accounting of official ballots shall be made prior to certification of the official election results.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>811.2.</num>
    <text>The accounting of official ballots shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>For each precinct, and for each party in a primary election, the sum of the number of ballots issued to the voters, less the number of spoiled ballots, should equal the total number of ballots cast in the precinct;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For each precinct, and for each party in a primary election, the sum of the number of cards issued to voters and exchanged for ballots, plus the number of special ballots, should equal the total number of voters;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>For each precinct, and for each party in a primary election, upon completion of the election day count and exclusive of special and absentee ballots, the sum of the number of polling place ballots counted plus the number of special ballots cast
        should equal the totals from §§ 811.2(a) and (b);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>For each entire election and for each type of ballot used in it, the sum of the number of absentee ballots issued to voters electronically, by mail, in person, by affidavit (emergency), spoiled absentee ballots, plus the number of absentee ballots
        remaining unused, should equal the total number of absentee ballots;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>For each entire election and for each type of ballot used in it, the sum of the number of absentee ballots cast, absentee ballots spoiled, and absentee ballots not returned, should equal the total number of absentee ballots issued to voters; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>For each Single-Member District, the total number of Single-Member District ballots cast should equal the sum of the ballots cast in each precinct servicing that Single-Member District.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>811.3.</num>
    <text>Following tabulation, the ballots and VVPATS for each precinct shall be transferred to a secure and locked storage location where they shall remain secured for twenty-two (22) months; thereafter, if no election contest or other proceeding is pending
      in which the ballots may be needed as evidence, the ballots may be destroyed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>811.4.</num>
    <text>The Board shall retain and store all data processing materials related to the vote counting from the time the canvass is completed until the expiration of the period for challenging elections in an secured area and conforming to data security practices
      outlined in EAC Election Management Guidelines &amp;#8211; Security—Voting Equipment and Peripheral Devices.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 27 D.C. Reg. 1836 (May 2, 1980), incorporating the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 27 D.C. Reg. 1222, 1247 (March 21, 1980); renumbered by Final Rulemaking published at 31 D.C. Reg. 2129, 2130 (May 4, 1984);
        as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 D.C. Reg. 7431 (July 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 D.C. Reg. 5069 (May 14, 2004); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 7705 (August
        20, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11149, 11160 (November 26, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>