<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-816</num>
  <heading>RECOUNT PROCEDURES (§ 3-816)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>816.1.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director shall conduct recount proceedings in accordance with provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>816.2.</num>
    <text>The validity of ballots and votes recounted shall be determined pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>816.3.</num>
    <text>Manual tabulation of votes in a recount proceeding shall be conducted in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>816.4.</num>
    <text>Within two (2) days following the Board’s determination to grant a recount petition or a court order directing the Board to conduct a recount, notice of recount proceedings shall be delivered by courier to all qualified candidates for the contest
      being recounted. Public notice of recount proceedings shall be posted on the Board’s website at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance of the commencement of the recount.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>816.5.</num>
    <text>Each candidate, or organizational group in support of or opposition to a ballot question, in a contest involved in a recount shall be permitted to have no more than two (2) poll watchers at all phases of the recount, regardless of whether the candidate
      properly applied for poll watcher credentials pursuant to § 706.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>816.6.</num>
    <text>Apart from the election officials necessary to conduct the recount, priority of access to the place where the recount will occur will first be given to the candidate, or organizational groups in support of or opposition to a ballot question, in the
      contest being recounted. Space permitting, poll watchers and election observers credentialed pursuant to § 706, then members of the public, shall also be given access.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>816.7.</num>
    <text>For paper ballots, recount officials shall rerun all official ballots through a tabulator and count only the votes for the office or ballot question at issue in the recount. All ballots which are not machine readable shall be tabulated manually, pursuant
      to the rules provided in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>816.8.</num>
    <text>For ballots cast on a DRE machine, the recount officials shall open the containers with the voter-verified paper audit trail (“VVPAT”) printouts and manually count the results of the recounted contest from the printout.</text>
    <text>Whenever the VVPAT is damaged or illegible, the VVPAT shall be reproduced in accordance with vendor guidelines and in a public manner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>816.9.</num>
    <text>At the conclusion of the recount proceedings, a recount results report shall be presented to the Board and posted on the Board’s website. The Board shall determine the number of votes received by each candidate as a result of the recount, but shall
      not make a new certification of the results of the election unless the outcome of the contest has changed as a result of the recount.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>816.10</num>
    <text>816.10 There shall be only one (1) recount per contest.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>816.11.</num>
    <text>Results of the recount are final and not appealable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 28 D.C. Reg. 1726 (April 26, 1981), incorporating the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 28 D.C. Reg. 403, 411 (January 23, 1981); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 D.C. Reg. 7433 (July 30, 2004);
        as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 D.C. Reg. 5071 (May 14, 2004); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 7705 (August 20, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at
        57 DCR 11149, 11166 (November 26, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>