<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6412</num>
  <heading>ADMINISTRATION OF DIAGNOSTIC PHARMACEUTICAL AGENTS (ยง 17-6412)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6412.1.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, &amp;#8220;diagnostic pharmaceutical agent&amp;#8221; means any pharmaceutical agent used in the diagnosis of ocular disease and conditions of the visual system.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6412.2.</num>
    <text>Only an optometrist certified in accordance with this section or a physician may administer a diagnostic pharmaceutical agent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6412.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant for certification to administer diagnostic pharmaceutical agents shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Submit a completed, notarized application; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Demonstrate to the satisfaction of the Board that he or she:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Has either applied for licensure under this chapter as an optometrist, or has been issued a license under this chapter as an optometrist;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Has completed a course approved by the Board in general and ocular pharmacology that meets the requirements of ยง 207 of the Act, D.C. Code ยง 2-3302.7, and has arranged for the institution to submit a transcript directly to the Board; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Has passed the treatment and management of ocular disease (TMOD) section of the examination administered by the National Board of Examiners in Optometry, or any other examination approved by the National Board of Examiners in Optometry or the Board,
        and has arranged for the test results to be submitted directly to the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6412.4.</num>
    <text>A course approved by the Board shall be any course in the treatment and management of ocular disease offered or approved by an institution with an accredited program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6412.5.</num>
    <text>An optometrist authorized under this section to administer a diagnostic pharmaceutical agent shall not do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Administer a diagnostic pharmaceutical agent by any means other than topical application to the eye;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Administer a diagnostic pharmaceutical agent when the medical condition of the patient contraindicates such use; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Administer any pharmaceutical agent for therapeutic purposes unless authorized in accordance with the provisions of section 6413 of this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 4494, 4502 (June 17, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 4197 (May 7, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>