<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6408</num>
  <heading>CONTINUING EDUCATION CREDITS (§ 17-6408)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6408.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant continuing education credit for whole hours only, with a minimum of fifty (50) minutes constituting one (1) credit hour.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6408.2.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant a maximum of two (2) continuing education credits per year for attending programs under § 6407.2 or completing activities under § 6407.6 determined by the Board to be in practice management.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6408.3.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant fifteen (15) hours of continuing education credit for each semester hour and ten (10) hours of continuing education credit for each quarter hour for undergraduate or graduate courses under § 6407.2(a).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6408.4.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant a maximum of five (5) continuing education credits per year to an applicant for attending in-service education programs under § 6407.2(d).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6408.5.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant a maximum of twenty-five percent (25%) of the applicant&amp;#8217;s continuing education requirement for taking correspondence courses under § 6407.2(e).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6408.6.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant a maximum of fifty percent (50%) of an applicant&amp;#8217;s continuing education requirement for completing continuing education activities under § 6407.6.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6408.7.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant an applicant who serves as an instructor or speaker under § 6407.6(a) credit for preparation and presentation time, subject to the following restrictions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The maximum amount of credit that may be granted for preparation time is twice the amount of the associated presentation time;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If an applicant has previously received credit in connection with a particular presentation, the Board shall not grant credit for a subsequent presentation unless it involves either a different subject or substantial additional research concerning
        the same subject; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The presentation shall have been completed during the period for which credit is claimed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6408.8.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant continuing education credit for publications under § 6407.6(b) only if the applicant proves to the satisfaction of the Board that the work has been published or accepted for publication during the period for which credit is claimed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6408.9.</num>
    <text>The Board may not grant continuing education credit for programs or activities designed to promote specific instruments or other products of profit-making entities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 4494, 4499 (June 17, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>