<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-2404</num>
  <heading>APPLICANT ELIGIBILITY (ยง 1-2404)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2404.1.</num>
    <text>To be eligible to participate in the Program, an applicant shall, at the time of application and throughout participation in the Program:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Hold, or presently plan to secure, eligible employment; provided that a participant must hold eligible employment:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Before any payment may be disbursed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Continuously throughout the service obligation after disbursement of the first payment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be a resident of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Be a lawyer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Have an adjusted gross annual income of less than sixty-five thousand dollars ($65,000);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Have exhausted all other available avenues for loan repayment assistance, including participation in any available law school debt repayment program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Have no current service obligation from a scholarship;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Be in a satisfactory repayment status on all eligible debt; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Execute a release to allow the Administrator access to records, credit information, and information from lenders necessary to verify eligibility of debt and determine loan repayments.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2404.2.</num>
    <text>A law student attending the David A. Clarke School of Law (or a successor entity) at the University of the District of Columbia who is in his or her final year of study may apply and be approved for loan repayment assistance if the applicant demonstrates
      that he or she will meet all the requirements of this section before the first payment is disbursed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2404.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant who submits an application based on his or her present plan to secure eligible employment may be approved for loan repayment assistance if the applicant demonstrates that he or she will hold eligible employment within ninety (90) days
      after the application is approved and the loan is awarded.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 1025 (February 2, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>