<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-2402</num>
  <heading>ADMINISTRATION (§ 1-2402)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2402.1.</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Bar Foundation is appointed as the Administrator for the Program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2402.2.</num>
    <text>In implementing the Program, the Administrator shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Publicize and provide information about the nature and requirements of the Program to potentially eligible lawyers and law students;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Develop a list of eligible employment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Establish and publicize application deadlines;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Develop and distribute application forms and informational materials;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Receive and evaluate completed applications;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Determine the eligibility of applicants, their debt, and their employment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Select participants for the award of benefits;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Determine the level of loan repayment assistance to be awarded;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Award loans in accordance with the criteria stated in this chapter and the Act;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Secure the execution of promissory notes by participants;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Receive and administer funds appropriated for the payment of loan repayment assistance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Disburse semi-annual loan payments to selected participants;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Verify semi-annually continuing participant eligibility and compliance with service obligations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>Forgive loans made to participants upon the participant’s satisfactory completion of the service obligation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>Develop a schedule for the repayment of loans that are not forgiven and collect the repayment amounts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(p)</num>
      <text>Participate in annual financial and management audits of the Program; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(q)</num>
      <text>Provide financial and statistical reports concerning the Program as required by the Attorney General.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2402.3.</num>
    <text>The Attorney General shall conduct an annual financial and management audit of the Program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 1025 (February 2, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>