<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-2499</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 1-2499)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2499.1.</num>
    <text>The following terms and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Act &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia Poverty Lawyer Loan Assistance Repayment Program Emergency Act of 2006, effective October 25, 2006, D.C. Act 16-512, 53 DCR 9086, and any substantially identical successor legislation.</text>
    <text>Adjusted gross annual income &amp;#8211; has the same meaning as provided in D.C. Official Code § 47-1803.02(b).</text>
    <text>Administrator &amp;#8211; the person or entity appointed to administer the Program.</text>
    <text>Applicant &amp;#8211; an individual who applies for loan repayment assistance from the Program.</text>
    <text>Attorney General &amp;#8211; the Attorney General for the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Eligible debt &amp;#8211; outstanding principal, interest, and related expenses from loans obtained for reasonable educational expenses associated with attendance at and enrollment in law school for the purpose of obtaining a law degree, made by government
      and commercial lending institutions or educational institutions, but not loans extended by a private individual or group of individuals, including families.</text>
    <text>Eligible employment &amp;#8211; employment that meets the requirements of § 2405 and section 2(6) of the Act.</text>
    <text>Lawyer &amp;#8211; a graduate of an accredited law school who is licensed to practice law in the District of Columbia, authorized under the provisions of Rule 49(c) (9) of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals to practice law in the District of
      Columbia, or a member in good standing of the highest court of any state and has submitted an application for admission to the District of Columbia Bar.</text>
    <text>Participant &amp;#8211; an eligible lawyer whose application to the Program has been approved.</text>
    <text>Program &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia Poverty Lawyer Loan Assistance Repayment Program.</text>
    <text>Reasonable educational expenses &amp;#8211; the cost of tuition for law school as well as the costs of education considered to be required by the school’s degree program, such as fees for room, board, transportation and commuting costs, books, supplies,
      and educational equipment and materials that are part of the estimated student budget of the school in which the participant was enrolled.</text>
    <text>Service obligation &amp;#8211; the duration of eligible employment necessary to sustain participation in the Program.</text>
    <text>ATTACHMENT 1</text>
    <text>CHAPTER 24</text>
    <text>DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA POVERTY LAWYER LOAN ASSISTANCE REPAYMENT PROGRAM</text>
    <text>QUALIFYING ORGANIZATIONS PROVIDING ELIGIBLE EMPLOYMENT</text>
    <text>Advocates for Justice and Education</text>
    <text>Archdiocesan Legal Network</text>
    <text>Asian Pacific American Legal Resource Center</text>
    <text>Ayuda</text>
    <text>Bread for the City Legal Clinic</text>
    <text>Break the Cycle &amp;#8211; Washington, DC Office</text>
    <text>Capital Area Immigrants’ Rights Coalition</text>
    <text>Central American Resource Center</text>
    <text>Children’s Law Center</text>
    <text>Columbus Community Legal Services</text>
    <text>D.C. Bar Pro Bono Program</text>
    <text>D.C. Coalition Against Domestic Violence &amp;#8211; SAFE Project</text>
    <text>D.C. Employment Justice Center</text>
    <text>D.C. Law Students in Court Program</text>
    <text>DV LEAP</text>
    <text>Human Rights First</text>
    <text>Lawyers for Children America &amp;#8211; Washington, D.C. Program</text>
    <text>Legal Aid Society of D.C.</text>
    <text>Legal Counsel for the Elderly</text>
    <text>Mid-Atlantic Innocence Project</text>
    <text>Neighborhood Legal Services Program</text>
    <text>Our Place, D.C.</text>
    <text>US Committee for Refugee &amp;#038; Immigrant Children &amp;#8211; DC</text>
    <text>University of the District of Columbia School of Law &amp;#8211; Community Development/Small Business Clinic</text>
    <text>University Legal Services</text>
    <text>Washington Lawyers’ Committee for Civil Rights &amp;#038; Urban Affairs</text>
    <text>Disability Rights Project</text>
    <text>EEO Intake Project</text>
    <text>Immigrant &amp;#038; Refugee Rights Project</text>
    <text>DC Prisoners Rights Project</text>
    <text>Washington Legal Clinic for the Homeless</text>
    <text>Whitman-Walker Clinic Legal Services Program</text>
    <text>Women Empowered Against Violence</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 1025 (February 2, 2007); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 2228 (March 19, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>