<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-2405</num>
  <heading>SOLE SOURCE DETERMINATIONS AND FINDINGS (ยง 30-2405)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2405.1.</num>
    <text>When a sole source procurement is proposed, the contracting officer shall prepare a written D&amp;#038;F that sets forth the justification for the sole source procurement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2405.2.</num>
    <text>Each sole source D&amp;#038;F shall include the following, when applicable:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Specific identification of the document as a sole source D&amp;#038;F;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The nature or description of the proposed procurement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A description of the requirement, including the estimated value or cost;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A specific citation to the applicable provisions of ยง 2401 of this chapter that provide authority for the sole source procurement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>An explanation of the unique nature of the procurement or other factors that qualify the requirement for sole source procurement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>An explanation of the proposed contractor&amp;#8217;s unique qualifications or other factors that qualify the proposed contractor as a sole source for the procurement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A determination that the anticipated costs to the Agency will be fair and reasonable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>A description of the market survey conducted and the results, or a statement of the reasons why a market survey was not conducted, and a list of the potential sources contacted by the contracting officer or which expressed, in writing, an interest
        in the procurement; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Any other pertinent facts or reasons supporting the use of a sole source procurement.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6681, 6764 (September 22, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>