<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-3307</num>
  <heading>DETERMINING REASONABLENESS (ยง 27-3307)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3307.1.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall determine a cost to be reasonable if it does not differ from or exceed in amount that which would be incurred by a prudent person in the conduct of a competitive business, in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3307.2.</num>
    <text>In determining the reasonableness of a given cost, the contracting officer shall consider the following factors:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Whether the cost is of a type generally recognized as ordinary and necessary for the conduct of the contractor&amp;#8217;s business or the performance of the contract;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The restraints or requirements imposed by generally accepted sound business practices, arms length bargaining, federal and District laws and regulations, and contract terms and specifications;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The action that a prudent business person would take, considering responsibilities to the owner of the business, employees, customers, the District, and the public at large;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any significant deviations from the established practices of the contractor that may unjustifiably increase the contract costs; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any other relevant factors.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3307.3.</num>
    <text>Reasonableness of specific costs must be examined with particular care in connection with firms or their separate divisions that may not be subject to effective competitive restraints.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3307.4.</num>
    <text>No presumption of reasonableness shall be attached to the incurrence of costs by a contractor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3307.5.</num>
    <text>If an initial review of the facts results in a challenge of a specific cost by the contracting officer or the contracting officer&amp;#8217;s representative, the burden of proof shall be upon the contractor to establish that such cost is reasonable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1653 (February 26, 1988); as Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 1429 (February 6, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>