<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-3344</num>
  <heading>EXPERT AND CONSULTANT SERVICES COSTS (ยง 27-3344)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3344.1.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in ยง3344.2, costs of expert and consultant services shall be allowable when reasonable in relation to the services rendered and when not contingent upon recovery of costs from the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3344.2.</num>
    <text>In determining the allowability of expert and consultant services costs, the contracting officer shall consider the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The nature and scope of the services rendered in relation to the services required under the contract;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The necessity of contracting for the service considering the contractor&amp;#8217;s capability in the particular area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The past pattern of the contractor&amp;#8217;s incurring this type of costs, particularly in the years prior to the award of District contracts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The impact of District contracts in the contractor&amp;#8217;s business;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Whether the proportion of District work to the contractor&amp;#8217;s total business justifies incurring the cost, particularly when the services rendered are not of a continuing nature and have little relationship to work under District contracts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Whether the service can be performed more economically by employment rather than by contracting;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The qualifications of the individual or firm rendering the service and the customary fee charged, especially on non-government contracts; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The adequacy of the contractual agreement for the services, including the description of the service, the estimate the time required, rate of compensation, and termination provisions.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3344.3.</num>
    <text>Fees for services rendered shall be allowable only when supported by evidence of the nature and scope of the service furnished.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1673 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>