<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-3300</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (ยง 27-3300)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3300.1.</num>
    <text>The cost principles and procedures set forth in this chapter shall be used when cost analysis is performed in connection with any contract or solicitation under the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, D.C. Law 6-85 (the &amp;#8220;Act&amp;#8221;),
      in accordance with the Act or this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3300.2.</num>
    <text>The cost principles and procedures set forth in this chapter shall be used by the contracting officer to negotiate or to determine reimbursable costs or the allowability of claims for reimbursement of costs in accordance with the clause, approved
      by the Director, contained in all cost-reimbursement contracts in accordance with ยง310(b) of the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3300.3.</num>
    <text>In accordance with ยง601 of the Act, the cost principles and procedures set forth in this chapter shall be used in the following situations:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The pricing or estimation of costs in contracts based on other than competitive sealed bidding;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The pricing or estimation of costs in change orders or contract modifications;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Settlement of contract costs for contracts which have been terminated; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Allowability of costs under contract provisions which provide for reimbursement of costs.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3300.4.</num>
    <text>In addition to those contracts where the application of cost principles is required under the Act or this title, the contracting officer may include a clause, approved by the Director, requiring the use of cost principles and procedures set forth
      in this chapter to determine the allowability of estimated or incurred costs in any contract where the contracting officer determines that the negotiation, allowance, determination, or estimation of costs may be required or necessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3300.5.</num>
    <text>The application of cost principles to fixed-price contracts and subcontracts shall not be construed as a requirement to negotiate agreements on individual elements of cost in arriving at agreement on the total price. The final price accepted by the
      parties may reflect agreement only on the total price.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3300.6.</num>
    <text>The cost principles and procedures set forth in this chapter shall not apply to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The establishment of prices under contracts awarded on the basis of competitive sealed bidding;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Prices fixed by law or regulation; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Prices based on established catalog prices or established market prices.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, D.C. Law 6-85, as amended, D.C. Code ยง1-1181.1 et seq. (1981).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1650 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>