<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-2703</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION[COLON] RESERVED PARKING SPACE (§ 18-2703)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2703.1.</num>
    <text>Each application for a reserved on-street parking space pursuant to § 2710, shall be made on a form furnished by the Director. Each applicant shall first have been qualified or requalified for special license tags or a special parking permit since
      the effective date of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2703.2.</num>
    <text>Each application for a reserved space shall state the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Applicant’s full true and legal name;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Date of birth;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Social security number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Occupation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Residential address, including zip code;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Ward;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Home and office telephone number; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>A brief description of applicant, including but not limited to, applicant’s sex, height, weight, color of eyes, and color of hair.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2703.3.</num>
    <text>Each application for a reserved space shall provide specific information relative to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Applicant’s place of residence;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Availability of off-street parking at or in proximity to the residence;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Inability to utilize alternative modes of transportation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Accessibility of parking in vicinity of applicant’s residence; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Other information as may be required by the Director.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2703.4.</num>
    <text>Each application shall contain a licensed physician’s assessment of the applicant’s degree of immobility which precludes the utilization of alternative modes of transportation, or the inability to utilize parking, if available, in vicinity of applicant’s
      residence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2703.5.</num>
    <text>Each application shall indicate in feet, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The distance from applicant’s residence to the nearest available off &amp;#8211; street parking;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The maximum distance the applicant can reasonably be expected to ambulate or to propel a wheelchair; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Environmental conditions which affect utilization of the available parking, including terrain and weather.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2703.6.</num>
    <text>Each applicant for a reserved parking space shall have the completed application notarized.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2703.7.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of an application for a reserved parking space pursuant to this chapter, the Director shall cause public notice of the pending request to be published in the District of Columbia Register. A copy of the notice shall at the same time be
      mailed to the applicant’s Advisory Neighborhood Commissioner. The Commissioner shall have a period of thirty (30) days within which to comment on the pending request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2703.8.</num>
    <text>The Director shall make an assessment of the availability and accessibility of off-street parking at applicant’s residence or in the nearby vicinity, and the applicant’s inability to utilize alternative modes of transportation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2703.9.</num>
    <text>In considering any application for a reserved space under this section, the Director may gather information from any source deemed necessary and appropriate to assist in making a determination to approve or deny an application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>