<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2906</num>
  <heading>AGREEMENT WITH OTHER AGENCIES (ยง 29-2906)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2906.1.</num>
    <text>The Department of Human Services may enter into agreements with District, other public or private agencies for the provision of protective services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2906.2.</num>
    <text>The designated agency shall comply with all applicable procedures related to the APS program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2906.3.</num>
    <text>The designated agency shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Provide a description of the investigative or protective services to be provided;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Indicate the areas of the city it intends to cover;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Indicate the number of cases it intends to accept and serve;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Indicate the agency or client eligibility such as age, and income, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>State the staffing patterns and qualifications of the proposed adult protective services workers, including bilingual capabilities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>State the cost of services to the District government, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Indicate the agency fee schedule, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Indicate the capability of the agency to provide proposed services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Explain how confidentiality of clients will be ensured, and how case records and information will be safeguarded; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Provide any other relevant information which may be requested by DHS.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2906.4.</num>
    <text>The designated agency shall agree to accept all referred cases as defined by D.C. Law 5-156 which do not exceed its limits for number of cases, and which meet the criteria that have been proposed by the agency and accepted by DHS as outlined in the
      contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2906.5.</num>
    <text>The agency shall set the following criteria for social workers who provide protective services:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be licensed to practice social work in the District of Columbia; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Have three (3) years experience in the provision of adult protective services and under the supervision of a licensed social worker.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2906.6.</num>
    <text>The agency may use paraprofessional staff to supplement the work of the licensed social worker or experienced caseworker so long as the para-professional staff receives professional supervision and guidelines.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2906.7.</num>
    <text>The Department of Human Services shall make known to agencies interested in designation what the need is for investigation and protective services, and when District government funds are available to contract with agencies for the provision of the
      services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2906.8.</num>
    <text>The Director of DHS shall receive requests for designation and forward all requests for agency designation to the Adult Protective Services (APS) Branch, Social Services Division, Family Services Administration, Commission on Social Services for review
      and recommendation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2906.9.</num>
    <text>The Director shall make his or her decision based on the review of this recommendation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2906.10.</num>
    <text>The Department of Human Services shall retain the responsibility for receiving all reports, after which it will determine who will perform the necessary investigations and provide the required protective services in accordance with the contracts executed
      between the Department and the designated agencies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2906.11.</num>
    <text>Agencies interested in designation shall have the responsibility to submit a written request to the Director of the Department of Human Services, which shall address the criteria for designated agencies described in ยง 2906.2(b) through (j), 2906.3
      and 2906.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2906.12.</num>
    <text>Agencies to be designated shall enter into a contract with the Department agreeing to adhere to the criteria outlined in ยง 2906.3 through 2906.5, and all other applicable legislation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2906.13.</num>
    <text>The Director, upon recommendation of the Adult Protective Services Branch, may terminate the contract if the following conditions exist:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>When the criteria are not sustained;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For the convenience of the Department;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>When the contractor is in default; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>When the designated agency requests termination in writing with thirty (30) days advance notice and follows the appropriate contracting procedures as outlined in District law.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2906.14.</num>
    <text>The designated agency shall provide reports as requested and required by the Department, and shall allow the Department access to client records.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2906.15.</num>
    <text>Any fees that the designated agency charges for services shall be consistent with the fee charging policy of the Department of Human Services and specified within the request for designation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2906.16.</num>
    <text>The designated agency shall have the responsibility to ensure that the contract contains a provision outlining the procedure for transferring cases in the event that the contract is terminated or not renewed and a provision regarding the final disposition
      of files.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 6646, 6650 (October 19, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>