<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5507</num>
  <heading>REACTIVATION OF AN INACTIVE LICENSE (§ 17-5507)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5507.1.</num>
    <text>A licensee in an inactive status, pursuant to § 511 of the Act, D.C. Official Code § 3-1205.11, may apply for reactivation of the license by submitting a completed application on the forms required by the Board and paying the required fees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5507.2.</num>
    <text>A licensee in inactive status, pursuant to § 511 of the Act, D.C. Official Code § 3-1205.11, for twelve (12) months or more, who submits an application to reactivate a license shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Submit proof as set forth in § 5508.7 of having completed nine (9) hours of continuing education in the licensee&amp;#8217;s current area of practice for each year, or any portion thereof, the license was in inactive status up to a maximum of eighteen
        (18) hours of continuing education. Only continuing education taken in the two (2) years immediately preceding the application date will be accepted; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Submit proof of a current license in good standing to practice practical nursing from a state or territory of licensure in the United States. Verification of good standing must be sent directly to the Board by the verifying Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5507.3.</num>
    <text>A licensee in an inactive status, pursuant to § 511 of the Act, D.C. Official Code § 3-1205.11, for two (2) years or more, who submits an application to reactivate a license shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Submit proof as set forth in § 5508.7 of having completed nine (9) hours of continuing education in the licensee&amp;#8217;s current area of practice for each year, or any portion thereof, the license was in inactive status up to a maximum of eighteen
        (18) hours of continuing education. Only continuing education taken in the two (2) years immediately preceding the application date will be accepted;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Submit proof of completion of a re-entry program approved by the Board; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Submit proof of a current license in good standing to practice practical nursing from a state or territory of licensure in the United States. Verification of good standing must be sent directly to the Board by the verifying Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 632, 636 (January 20, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 701 (January 26, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>