<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2710</num>
  <heading>MONITORING OF INVESTIGATIONS AND PRELIMINARY INQUIRIES (ยง 24-2710)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2710.1.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director, Intelligence Fusion Division, or a commanding officer of similar rank designated in the MPD regulations, including the Watch Commander for the Intelligence Fusion Division (who possesses the same authority as the Commander),
      shall monitor the compliance of undercover officers and informants with the requirements of these rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2710.2.</num>
    <text>The Chief of Police shall annually prepare a report on the MPD&amp;#8217;s investigations and preliminary inquiries involving First Amendment activities. The report shall be transmitted to the Mayor and Council and a notice of its publication shall
      be published in the District of Columbia Register. The report shall include, at a minimum:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The number of investigations authorized;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The number of authorizations for investigation sought but denied;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The number of requests from outside agencies, as documented by forms requesting access to records of investigations conducted pursuant to this title;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The number of arrests, prosecutions, or other law enforcement actions taken as a result of such investigations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A description of any violations of the Police Investigations Concerning First Amendment Activities Act of 2004 or of the rules issued pursuant to that Act, and the actions taken as a result of the violations, including whether any officer was disciplined
        as a result of the violation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking Published at 55 DCR 1091 (February 1, 2008); as amended by Errata Published at 55 DCR 3271 (March 28, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>