<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-547</num>
  <heading>CERTIFICATE OF COURSE COMPLETION (§ 29-547)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>547.1.</num>
    <text>An educational program shall issue to each successful participant a certificate or proof of successful completion of a course no later than thirty (30) calendar days after completion of the course.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>547.2</num>
    <text>547.2 A certification course completion certificate or documentation of successful completion shall contain:</text>
    <text>The name of the participant;</text>
    <text>The course title and DOH-assigned course number;</text>
    <text>The length of the course in total hours;</text>
    <text>The name of the sponsoring educational institution and its DOH EMS educational institution number;</text>
    <text>The course completion date;</text>
    <text>The program director’s signature; and</text>
    <text>The medical director’s signature.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>547.3.</num>
    <text>A refresher or CE course completion certificate or documentation of successful completion shall contain:</text>
    <text>The name of participant and his or her NREMT, State, or District EMS certification number;</text>
    <text>The course title and DOH-assigned course number;</text>
    <text>The total number of hours of continuing education awarded;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The educational institution or Emergency Medical Services Agency name, address, and DOH EMS educational institution number or Emergency Medical Services Agency number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The date(s) of the course, class, or activity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The program director’s signature; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The medical director’s signature.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>547.4.</num>
    <text>If a refresher or CE course is used to satisfy the requirements for maintaining an EMS provider’s certification, the refresher and CE course shall be completed during the current certification cycle, and the provider shall submit the CE certificate
      to NREMT in accordance with its policies in effect at the time of submission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>547.5.</num>
    <text>No person shall receive credit for taking the same refresher or CE course, class, or activity more than once during a single certification or licensure cycle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>547.6.</num>
    <text>An instructor may receive credit for instructing a certification, refresher, or CE course. Credit received shall be the same as the number of CE hours approved for the course, class, or activity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>547.7</num>
    <text>547.7 The instructor shall receive credit only once during a certification cycle for instructing the same CE course, class, or activity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 16569 (December 6, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>