<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-511</num>
  <heading>EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES AGENCY VEHICLES[COLON] NON-TRANSPORT VEHICLES (§9-511)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>511.1</num>
    <text>511.1 An emergency medical response vehicle maintained and operated for response to the location of a medical emergency to provide immediate medical care at the basic or advanced life support level, but not to provide patient transport, shall be certified
      as a non-transport emergency medical response vehicle. Such vehicles would include fire apparatus, response cars, and other non-transport vehicles, but does not include air or watercraft.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>511.2.</num>
    <text>A non-transport EMS vehicle shall be certified pursuant to § 510 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>511.3.</num>
    <text>A non-transport EMS vehicle shall not be used for the transportation of patients except in the case of unstable or potentially unstable patients when there is no transport unit immediately available. In such an event, the circumstances of the call
      shall be documented by the Emergency Medical Services Agency and reported to the Director within seventy-two (72) hours.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>511.4.</num>
    <text>A non-transport emergency medical response vehicle shall be constructed to provide sufficient space for the safe storage of the equipment and supplies required by this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>511.5.</num>
    <text>A non-transport emergency medical response vehicle used for advanced life support shall have a locking storage compartment or approved locking bracket for the security of medications and medication kits within the vehicle interior, locked compartment,
      or trunk, which shall be inaccessible to the public. When not in use, medications and medication kits shall be kept locked in the required storage compartment or approved bracket at all times.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>511.6.</num>
    <text>A non-transport emergency medical response vehicle shall have a motor vehicle safety inspection performed by the District of Columbia Department of Motor Vehicles after the completion of its conversion to a non-transport emergency medical response
      vehicle and before an application for a non-transport emergency medical response vehicle certificate is submitted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>511.7.</num>
    <text>Each non-transport emergency medical response vehicle shall be equipped with not less than twenty (20) triage tags.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>511.8</num>
    <text>511.8 A non-transport emergency medical response vehicle certificate shall be issued if all of the following conditions are met:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>All information contained in the application is complete;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The applicant is a certified District Emergency Medical Services Agency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The vehicle is registered by the motor vehicle agency for the jurisdiction from which the vehicle will operate; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The vehicle meets the minimum requirements as provided in this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>511.9.</num>
    <text>The Director shall issue two (2) decals with each non-transport emergency medical response vehicle certificate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>511.10</num>
    <text>511.10 The decals, which indicate when the certificate expires, shall be affixed in prominent places on the front and rear of the vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>511.11.</num>
    <text>The certificate shall be kept on file either at the place from which the non-transport emergency medical response vehicle operates or other designated place of the Emergency Medical Services Agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 8542 (December 4, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 16569 (December 6, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>