<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-527</num>
  <heading>EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICE EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTION STANDARDS (§ 29-527)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>527.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall provide EMS certification education, continuing education, or refresher education in the District without being certified as an EMS educational institution pursuant to this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>527.2</num>
    <text>527.2 Each EMS educational institution shall obtain approval from the Director prior to offering a course of study.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>527.3</num>
    <text>527.3 In order to be state approved for purposes of the NREMT, an educational institution shall obtain approval under this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>527.4</num>
    <text>527.4 Paramedic educational institutions shall be accredited through the Committee on Accreditation of Educational Programs for the Emergency Medical Services Professions (CoAEMSP) after January 1, 2013.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>527.5.</num>
    <text>In order to receive certification as an EMS educational institution, an applicant shall submit to the Director an application indicating compliance with §§ 527 through 531.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>527.6</num>
    <text>527.6 Each education program shall have adequate space at facilities to accommodate the program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>527.7</num>
    <text>527.7 Each education program shall have sufficient financial resources to ensure complete course delivery for all enrolled students.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>527.8</num>
    <text>527.8 An EMS educational institution that is not part of the District of Columbia government or a component of an accredited institution of higher learning shall be licensed through the District of Columbia Education Licensure Commission (ELC) in
      addition to being certified by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>527.9.</num>
    <text>After review of the application, the EMS educational institution shall be subject to a site visit as part of the certification process. The site visit is to verify the information contained in the application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>527.10.</num>
    <text>Each EMS educational institution, its equipment, all associated records, and the premises designated in its application shall be available for inspection by the District EMS Officer or designee during the usual hours of operation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>527.11</num>
    <text>527.11 The Director may subject any EMS educational institution certified under this chapter to an unscheduled inspection to determine compliance with certification standards.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>527.12.</num>
    <text>Each education program shall have written criteria for:</text>
    <text>Admission;</text>
    <text>Multiple evaluations of each student during the course of study including evaluation of competency in providing patient care;</text>
    <text>Student requirements for:</text>
    <text>Attendance; and</text>
    <text>Educational performance, including:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Attitudes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Knowledge; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Behavior;</text>
    </level>
    <text>Student access to program information including:</text>
    <text>Fees;</text>
    <text>Requirements;</text>
    <text>Policies and procedures;</text>
    <text>The student handbook; and</text>
    <text>Support services;</text>
    <text>Selection of:</text>
    <text>A medical director;</text>
    <text>A program director;</text>
    <text>Faculty; and</text>
    <text>Other necessary personnel;</text>
    <text>Nondiscrimination and fair practices with regard to students, faculty, and program personnel;</text>
    <text>Review and improvement of the effectiveness of student evaluation techniques; and</text>
    <text>HIPAA privacy training.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>527.13</num>
    <text>527.13 Each education program shall require that each student wear some type of distinctive identification during his or her field and clinical internship. The identification shall clearly identify the:</text>
    <text>Student’s name;</text>
    <text>Student’s status; and</text>
    <text>Education program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>527.14</num>
    <text>527.14 Each education program shall maintain an organizational chart that shows the relationships among students, the program director, the medical director, and the instructors for each course.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>527.15</num>
    <text>527.15 Each education program shall maintain accurate and appropriate records of:</text>
    <text>Students;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Faculty;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Courses, including:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Course statistics as specified in DOH policy; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Demographics of students; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Written agreements with facilities and agencies that provide clinical and field experience, which shall include:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Liability policies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Scope of practice for the student;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Evaluation criteria; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The responsibility for and level of supervision of students.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>527.16</num>
    <text>527.16 The education program shall maintain records at least five (5) years following course completion in a manner to prevent loss, destruction, or unauthorized use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>527.17</num>
    <text>527.17 Each education program shall teach the appropriate curriculum which shall include:</text>
    <text>Didactic instruction which shall impart fundamental knowledge, skills, and attitudes which contribute to the delivery of state-of-the-art pre-hospital emergency medical care; and</text>
    <text>Supervised field internships that include practice of skills while functioning in a pre-hospital environment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>527.18</num>
    <text>527.18 Training programs may utilize distance education for cognitive components of initial training leading to EMS provider certification if the program:</text>
    <text>Demonstrates the methods of distance education utilized are educationally and technically appropriate for the content and audience; and</text>
    <text>Ensures the quality of the distance education method, including:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Stating the educational objectives clearly; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Offer sufficiently comprehensive, accurate, up-to-date, educationally sound instructional materials.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>527.19</num>
    <text>527.19 Each EMS educational institution shall maintain written agreements and position descriptions stating the roles and responsibilities of the following program positions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Medical director;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Program director; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>EMS instructors.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 16569 (December 6, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>