<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-539</num>
  <heading>EMERGENCY MEDICAL TECHNICIAN INSTRUCTOR STANDARDS (§ 29-539)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>539.1</num>
    <text>539.1 Emergency Medical Technician (EMT) courses shall be taught by:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>District-certified EMT instructors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>EMT instructor trainees under the supervision of a District-certified EMT instructor; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>District-certified Advanced Emergency Medical Services (AEMS) instructors.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>539.2</num>
    <text>539.2 An EMT instructor who is not an AEMS instructor shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Maintain a valid District EMT or greater provider certification or license, to include but not limited to Advanced Emergency Medical Technician, Emergency Medical Technician-Intermediate, Paramedic, Nurse, or Physician;</text>
    </level>
    <text>Maintain a valid instructor certification in a related discipline, such as CPR;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Successfully complete a competency-based evaluation based on current District policy; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Submit a completed EMT instructor application signed by the medical director verifying successful evaluations and practice teaching dates to the Director.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>539.3</num>
    <text>539.3 EMT instructor certification shall not exceed two (2) years and shall be concurrent with the sponsoring EMS educational institution’s certification period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>539.4</num>
    <text>539.4 In order to remain in good standing during the two (2) year certification period, an EMT Instructor shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Successfully complete a competency-based evaluation based on current District policy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Maintain a current District EMS provider certification or license at the EMT level or greater, to include but not limited to Advanced Emergency Medical Technician, Emergency Medical Technician-Intermediate, Paramedic, Nurse, or Physician;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Attend EMT instructor workshops as required; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Submit to the Director a completed EMT instructor application signed by the medical director verifying competency evaluations and teaching dates.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>539.5.</num>
    <text>If the educational institution’s medical director approves, the EMT may also function as the EMT Program director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>539.6</num>
    <text>539.6 An EMT instructor whose certification has expired may apply to the Director for reinstatement within two (2) years of expiration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>539.7</num>
    <text>539.7 An EMT instructor reinstatement candidate shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Maintain a valid District EMT or greater provider certification or license, to include but not limited to Advanced Emergency Medical Technician, Emergency Medical Technician-Intermediate, Paramedic, Nurse, or Physician;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Successfully complete a competency-based evaluation based on current District policy; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Submit a completed EMT instructor application signed by the medical director verifying successful evaluations and teaching dates to the Director at the end of the interim teaching period.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>539.8.</num>
    <text>EMT instructor certification shall not exceed two (2) years and shall be concurrent with the sponsoring EMS educational institution’s certification period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>539.9</num>
    <text>539.9 An EMT instructor whose certification has lapsed for more than two (2) years shall be required to meet initial EMT instructor requirements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 16569 (December 6, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>