<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-540</num>
  <heading>ADVANCED EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES INSTRUCTOR STANDARDS (§ 29-540)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>540.1</num>
    <text>540.1 Advanced Emergency Medical Technician (AEMT) courses, Emergency Medicalechnician-Intermediate (EMT-I) courses, and Paramedic courses shall be taughty:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>District-certified Advanced Emergency Medical Services (AEMS) instructors;r</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>AEMS instructor trainees under the supervision of a District-certified AEMSnstructor.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>540.2</num>
    <text>540.2 A candidate for AEMS instructor shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Maintain a valid District Paramedic or greater certification or license, tonclude but not limited to Nurse or Physician;</text>
    </level>
    <text>Maintain a valid instructor certification in a related ALS discipline, such asdvanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS) or Pediatric Advanced Life Support (PALS);</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Successfully complete a competency-based evaluation based on currentistrict policy; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Submit to the Director at the end of the interim teaching a completed AEMSnstructor application signed by the medical director verifying successfulvaluations and practice teaching dates.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>540.3</num>
    <text>540.3 Certification as an AEMS instructor shall not exceed two (2) years andhall be concurrent with the sponsoring EMS educational institution’sertification period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>540.4</num>
    <text>540.4 In order to remain in good standing during the two (2) year period ofpproval an AEMS Instructor shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Maintain current District EMS provider certification or license at thearamedic level or greater, to include but not limited to Nurse or Physician;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Successfully complete a competency-based evaluation based on currentistrict policy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Attend AEMS instructor workshops as required; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Submit to the Director a completed AEMS instructor application signed by theedical director verifying successful evaluations and teaching dates.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>540.5</num>
    <text>540.5 If the educational institution’s medical director approves, the AEMSnstructor may also function as the AEMS program director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>540.6</num>
    <text>540.6 An AEMS instructor whose certification has expired may apply to theirector for reinstatement within two (2) years of expiration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>540.7</num>
    <text>540.7 An applicant for reinstatement as an AEMS instructor shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be certified or licensed as a District Paramedic or greater provider, tonclude but not limited to Nurse or Physician;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Successfully complete a competency-based evaluation based on currentistrict policy; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Submit a completed AEMS instructor application showing successfulvaluations from practice teaching.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>540.8</num>
    <text>540.8 An AEMS instructor certification shall not exceed two (2) years and shalle concurrent with the sponsoring EMS educational institution’s certificationeriod.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>540.9</num>
    <text>540.9 An AEMS instructor whose certification has lapsed for more than two (2)ears shall be required to meet initial AEMS instructor requirements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 16569 (December 6, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>