<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-102</num>
  <heading>AMENDMENTS (§ 11-102)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>102.1.</num>
    <text>As provided in the Zoning Act of 1938, approved June 20, 1938 (52 Stat. 797, as amended, D.C. Official Code §§ 6-641.01 to 6-641.15 (2001)(formerly codified at D.C. Code §§ 5-413 to 5-432 (1994 Repl. &amp;#038; 1999 Supp.)), the Zoning Commission
      for the District of Columbia may from time to time amend any part or all of the regulations in this title and the Zoning Maps adopted in this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.2.</num>
    <text>Amendments to this title or the Zoning Maps may be proposed by any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The owner of property for which amendments are proposed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Zoning Commission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The National Capital Planning Commission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The D.C. Office of Planning;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The Department of Housing and Community Development; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Any other department of the District or federal government.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.3.</num>
    <text>Proposed amendments to this title or the Zoning Maps and applications for planned unit development proposals under chapter 24 of this title shall be submitted to the Office of Zoning.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.4.</num>
    <text>The Zoning Commission shall adopt a form of application, and establish the number of copies, the required supporting data to accompany each application, and the time and manner of filing all applications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.5.</num>
    <text>The Zoning Commission may from time to time amend the form of application, number of copies, the required supporting data, and the time and manner of filing by announcing at a public hearing and posting a notice of the change in the Office of Zoning
      without any advance notice and without amending the provisions of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.6.</num>
    <text>Before adopting any proposed amendment to this title or the Zoning Maps, the Zoning Commission shall submit the proposed amendment to the D.C. Office of Planning for opinion or report; provided, that if the Office of Planning fails to transmit its
      opinion or report to the Zoning Commission within the period specified in § 2509, the Zoning Commission may proceed to take final action on the amendment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.7.</num>
    <text>Before adopting any proposed amendment to this title or the Zoning Maps, the Zoning Commission shall hold a public hearing on the proposed amendment in accordance with §§ 102.8 through 102.11.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.8.</num>
    <text>Notice of the time and place of each public hearing shall be published at least once in a daily newspaper or newspapers of general circulation in the District of Columbia at least thirty (30) days in advance of the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.9.</num>
    <text>The hearing notice shall include a general summary of the proposed amendment to this title and the boundaries of any territory included in the proposed amendment to the Zoning Map.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.10.</num>
    <text>The Zoning Commission shall give additional notice of the hearing as it deems feasible and practicable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.11.</num>
    <text>The public hearing may be adjourned from time to time. If the time and place of the adjourned hearing is publicly announced when the hearing is adjourned, no further notice of the adjourned hearing needs to be published.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.12.</num>
    <text>Any amendment to this title or the Zoning Maps shall require the favorable vote of not less than a majority of the full membership of the Zoning Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§ 9101 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958, and Final Rulemaking published at 29 DCR 1013 (May 29, 1973); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed
        Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8337 (October 20, 2000). See also D.C. Official Code § 6-641.03 (formerly codified at D.C. Code § 5-415 (1994 Repl.)).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>