<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-106</num>
  <heading>ZONING MAP (§ 11-106)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>106.1.</num>
    <text>The official Zoning Map of the District of Columbia shall be the zoning map that is drawn and maintained on the Geographic Information System, also known as “GIS,” located in the Office of Zoning effective on April 13, 2012.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>106.2.</num>
    <text>The official Zoning Map shall be published for public access on the Office of Zoning’s website.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>106.3.</num>
    <text>REPEALED</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>106.4.</num>
    <text>Properties owned by the Government of the United States and used for or intended to be used for a Federal public building or use and properties owned by the Government of the District of Columbia in the Central Area (as set forth in D.C. Official
      Code § 2-1004(c) (formerly codified at D.C. Code § 1-2004(c) (1999 Repl.)), are not included in any zone district.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>106.5.</num>
    <text>Properties of the District of Columbia Government shall be subject to zoning; provided:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Any governmental land or building uses that were either in existence or were substantially planned, documented and invested in prior to May 23, 1990, shall not be subject to zoning;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>With regard to the properties referenced in paragraph (a) of this subsection, any change or expansion in the use of land or buildings or any new construction or additions to buildings shall be subject to zoning; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>District of Columbia public buildings in the Central Area shall be exempt from zoning but shall continue to require approval of the National Capital Planning Commission, pursuant to § 5(c) of the National Capital Planning Act of 1952, approved July
        10, 1952 (66 Stat. 781, 788; D.C. Official Code §§ 2-1004(c) (formerly codified at D.C. Code § 1-2004(c) (1999 Repl.))).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>106.6.</num>
    <text>Properties acquired by the government of the United States and properties in the Central Area acquired by the government of the District of Columbia which are intended to be used for public building or use shall become automatically unzoned.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>106.7.</num>
    <text>No building permit or certificate of occupancy shall be issued nor proceeding instituted before the Board of Zoning Adjustment, nor shall any property in private ownership be used for any purpose until after the Zoning Commission has designated zoning
      for the property, except for the water tower and related water utility facilities authorized by § 2523.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>106.8.</num>
    <text>Zoning shall be designated after public hearing in the manner prescribed by the Zoning Act of 1938, approved June 20, 1938 (52 Stat. 797, as amended; D.C. Official Code §§ 6-641.01 to 6-641.15 (formerly codified at D.C. Code §§ 5-413 to 5-432 (1994
      Repl. &amp;#038; 1999 Supp.))).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>106.9.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall prevent either of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Minor repairs and alterations to buildings and structures for which no building permit is required under the Construction Code (Title 12 DCMR); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A caretaker from residing on property formerly owned by the Government of the United States, or property in the Central Area formerly owned by the Government of the District of Columbia, for which zoning has not been designated, for the purpose
        of maintaining and preventing the deterioration of the premises.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>106.10.</num>
    <text>The official Zoning Map and all explanatory material on the map shall be incorporated by reference and made a part of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>106.11.</num>
    <text>In addition to the official Zoning Map, a printable electronic summary extract of the official Zoning Map shall be prepared quarterly beginning July 1, 2012, published on the Office of Zoning’s website, and made available to the public for printing
      upon request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>106.12.</num>
    <text>The electronic summary extract of the official Zoning Map shall not supersede the official Zoning Map, but shall be prepared for the purpose of guidance only.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE §§ 2201 and 2202 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by:</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 5 DCR 174 (January 12, 1959); Final Rulemaking published at 19 DCR 1013 (May 29, 1973); Final Rulemaking published at 30 DCR 299-300 (January 21, 1983); Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 1045 (February 27, 1998);
        Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8339-40 (October 20, 2000); Notice of Final Rulemaking and Order No. 09-10 published at 57 DCR
        3487 (April 23, 2010); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 2915, 2917 (April 13, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>