<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-101</num>
  <heading>INTERPRETATION AND APPLICATION (§ 11-101)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>101.1.</num>
    <text>In their interpretation and application, the provisions of this title shall be held to be the minimum requirements adopted for the promotion of the public health, safety, morals, convenience, order, prosperity, and general welfare to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Provide adequate light and air;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Prevent undue concentration of population and the overcrowding of land; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Provide distribution of population, business and industry, and use of land that will tend to create conditions favorable to transportation, protection of property, civic activity, and recreational, educational, and cultural opportunities; and that
        will tend to further economy and efficiency in the supply of public services.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>101.2.</num>
    <text>The regulations in this title and the Zoning Maps are designed with consideration of the:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Character of the respective districts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Suitability of each district for the uses permitted in each district under this title; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Encouragement of the stability of districts and of land values in those districts.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>101.3.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this title shall govern whenever they:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Require larger yards, courts, or other open spaces;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Require a lower height or bulk of buildings or a smaller number of stories;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Require a greater percentage of lot to be unoccupied; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Impose other higher standards than are required in or under any statute or by any other municipal regulations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>101.4.</num>
    <text>The provisions of any statute or other municipal regulations shall govern whenever they:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Require larger yards, courts, or other open spaces;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Require a lower height or bulk of buildings or a smaller number of stories;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Require a greater percentage of lot to be unoccupied; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Impose higher standards than are required by this title.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>101.5.</num>
    <text>No building, structure, or premises shall be used, and no building, structure, or part of a building or structure shall be constructed, extended, moved, structurally altered, or enlarged except in conformity with this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>101.6.</num>
    <text>Where a lot is divided, the division shall be effected in a manner that will not violate the provisions of this title for yards, courts, other open space, minimum lot width, minimum lot area, floor area ratio, percentage of lot occupancy, parking
      spaces, or loading berths applicable to that lot or any lot created.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>101.7.</num>
    <text>If any section or provision of this title, or any boundary of any district on the Zoning Maps adopted under this title, is decided by the courts to be unconstitutional or invalid, that decision shall not affect the validity of the regulations and
      the Zoning Maps as a whole or any part of the regulations or maps, other than the part determined to be unconstitutional or invalid.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§§ 1301, 1302, and 9201 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8336-37
        (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>