<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-3012</num>
  <heading>JOINT FUNDRAISING (§ 3-3012)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3012.1.</num>
    <text>Prior to conducting any joint fundraising activities, the participant political committees shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Create a political committee to act as their fundraising representative;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Agree in writing to a formula for allocating proceeds and expenses among themselves; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Amend their Statements of Organization.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3012.2.</num>
    <text>The amended Statements of Organization shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The writing as agreed upon pursuant to § 3012.1(b); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The fundraising representative’s (political committee’s) account as an additional depository; provided, that the fundraising representative shall be an affiliated committee.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3012.3.</num>
    <text>The fundraising representative (political committee) shall be responsible for:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Establishing a depository account for joint fundraising receipts and expenditures; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Filing a Statement of Organization with the Director.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3012.4.</num>
    <text>In accordance with this title, the duties of the fundraising representative (political committee) shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Screening all contributions to assure that none are in excess of the limitations under § 3011;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Collecting and depositing joint fundraising contributions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Paying expenses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Allocating proceeds and expenses to the participants; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Reporting all joint fundraising receipts and expenditures in the reporting period made or received.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3012.5.</num>
    <text>Upon allocation of proceeds, the participant political committees shall report their shares on the R&amp;#038;E Report in accordance with the financial guidelines and procedures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 3161, 3174 (May 20, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 1402 (February 8, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11864 (August 16, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>