<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-3014</num>
  <heading>CONSTITUENT-SERVICE PROGRAM (§ 3-3014)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3014.1.</num>
    <text>A constituent-service program shall encompass any activity or program that provides emergency, informational, charitable, scientific, educational, medical, recreational, or other services to the residents of the District of Columbia, and promotes
      their general welfare.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.2.</num>
    <text>Funds raised by constituent-service programs may be expended only for services, activities, or programs which inure to the primary benefit of the residents of the District of Columbia, in accordance with § 3014.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.3.</num>
    <text>Allowable expenditures from constituent-service programs shall include the following:</text>
    <text>Funeral arrangements;</text>
    <text>Emergency housing and other necessities of life;</text>
    <text>Past due utility payments;</text>
    <text>Food and refreshments or an in-kind equivalent on infrequent occasions;</text>
    <text>Community events sponsored by the constituent-service program or an entity other than the District of Columbia government; and</text>
    <text>Community-wide events.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.4.</num>
    <text>Constituent-service programs shall be prohibited from engaging in any of the following activities:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Promoting or opposing, as a primary purpose, a political party or committee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Promoting or opposing, as a primary purpose, the nomination or election of an individual to public office;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Promoting or opposing, as a primary purpose, any initiative, referendum, or recall measure;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Distributing campaign literature or paraphernalia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Using any funds for personal purposes of the elected official;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Using any funds to pay fines or penalties inuring to the District of Columbia government;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Making any expenditure of cash;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Making any expenditure for the sponsorship of a political organization; or</text>
    </level>
    <text>Making any mass mailing within the ninety (90) day period immediately preceding a primary, special, or general election by a member of the Council, or the Mayor, who is a candidate for office.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.5.</num>
    <text>A constituent-service program may be maintained only by the following elected public officials:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Chairman and Members of the Council of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.6.</num>
    <text>A constituent-service program may be operated in the following locations:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>In the ward represented by the Member of the Council elected by ward; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>In the ward of the at-large member’s choice.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.7.</num>
    <text>An elected official shall fund the constituent-service program only by:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Transferring any surplus, residue, or unexpended campaign funds to the constituent-service program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Receiving contributions that do not exceed, in the aggregate, forty thousand dollars ($40,000) in any one (1) calendar year;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Receiving cash contributions from any person which, when aggregated with all other contributions received from the same person, do not exceed five hundred dollars ($500) in any one (1) calendar year; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Receiving personalty from any person which, when aggregated with all other contributions received from the same person, do not exceed one thousand dollars ($1,000) in any one (1) calendar year.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.8.</num>
    <text>The amount of any transfer of surplus, residue, or unexpended campaign funds by the elected official shall not be subject to the forty thousand dollars ($40,000) contribution limitation under § 3014.7(b).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.9.</num>
    <text>The amount of any funds contributed by the elected official to the official’s constituent-service program shall not be subject to the five hundred dollars ($500) contribution limitation under § 3014.7(c).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.10.</num>
    <text>No person shall receive or make any cash contribution of twenty-five dollars ($25) or more in legal tender to a constituent-service program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.11.</num>
    <text>A connected organization, under § 3000.9(a), and each affiliated committee established, financed, maintained, or controlled by the connected organization share a single contribution limitation with respect separately to cash and personalty.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.12.</num>
    <text>Corporations may make contributions to constituent-service programs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.13.</num>
    <text>A corporation and its subsidiaries, and each political committee established, financed, maintained, or controlled by the corporation and its subsidiaries share a single contribution limitation with respect separately to cash and personalty.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.14.</num>
    <text>A corporation is deemed to be a separate entity; provided, that a corporation (corporation B) which is established, financed, maintained, or controlled (51% or more) by another corporation (corporation A) is considered, for the purposes of the contribution
      limitations, a subsidiary of the other corporation (corporation A).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.15.</num>
    <text>Partnerships may make contributions in the District of Columbia; provided, that each contribution by a partnership shall be subject to each contributing partner’s individual contribution limitation, under § 3014.5.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.16.</num>
    <text>Contributions by a partnership shall be attributed to each partner, only by one (1) of the following methods:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Instructions from the partnership to the constituent-service program or the elected official; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Agreement of the partners; provided, that the profits of non-contributing partners are not affected.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.17.</num>
    <text>No portion of any contribution under § 3014.15 shall derive from the profits of a corporation that is a partner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.18.</num>
    <text>Limited liability companies may make contributions in the District of Columbia, under the contribution limitations of § 3014.15, dependent on whether the limited liability company is established as a corporation or partnership.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.19.</num>
    <text>The contribution limitations set forth in this section shall apply only to the elected official’s constituent-service program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.20.</num>
    <text>An elected official shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Spend no more than forty thousand ($40,000) in any one (1) calendar year for the constituent-service program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>File a Statement of Organization for a Constituent-Service Program form, prescribed by the Director, within ten (10) days of organization;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Amend the Statement of Organization within ten (10) days of any change in the information previously reported on the Statement of Organization; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Sign and file all R&amp;#038;E Reports, in accordance with §§ 3008 and 3017.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.21.</num>
    <text>Each constituent-service program shall have a chairperson and a treasurer, and may elect to list a designated agent, in the Statement of Organization filed pursuant to § 3014.20(b).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.22.</num>
    <text>When either the office of chairperson or treasurer of a constituent-service program is vacant, the constituent-service program shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Designate a successor chairperson or treasurer, within five (5) days of the vacancy; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Amend its Statement of Organization within ten (10) days of the designation of the successor; provided, that the successor officer agrees to accept the position.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.23.</num>
    <text>A constituent-service program shall neither accept a contribution nor make an expenditure while the office of treasurer is vacant, and no other person has been designated and has agreed to perform the functions of a treasurer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.24.</num>
    <text>Each expenditure made for, or on behalf of, a constituent-service program shall be authorized by either:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The chairperson;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The treasurer; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Their designated agent, as listed on the Statement of Organization filed under § 3014.20(b) or (c).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.25.</num>
    <text>A chairperson shall be required to file:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A Statement of Acceptance of Position of Chairperson form, prescribed by the Director, and a copy of written notification sent to the address of record of the treasurer, within five (5) days of assuming the office; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A Statement of Withdrawal of Position of Chairperson form, prescribed by the Director, and a copy of written notification sent to the address of record of the treasurer, within five (5) days of vacating the office.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.26.</num>
    <text>A treasurer shall be required to file:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A Statement of Acceptance of Position of Treasurer form, prescribed by the Director, and a copy of written notification sent to the address of record of the chairperson, within forty-eight (48) hours of assuming the office;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Periodic R&amp;#038;E Reports, under § 3008, signed by the treasurer or, if unavailable, the designated agent as listed on the Statement of Organization filed under § 3014.20; provided, that the treasurer shall be responsible for all R&amp;#038;E
        Reports and statements due to the Director during the treasurer’s tenure; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A Statement of Withdrawal of Position of Treasurer form, prescribed by the Director, and a copy of written notification sent to the address of record of the chairperson, within forty-eight (48) hours of vacating the office.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.27.</num>
    <text>A person shall not simultaneously serve as the chairperson and treasurer of a constituent-services program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.28.</num>
    <text>All funds of a constituent-services program shall be segregated from, and may not be commingled with, anyone’s personal funds.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.29.</num>
    <text>A constituent-service program shall neither establish nor maintain a petty cash fund.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 3161, 3176-78 (May 20, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 2171, 2179-82 (March 24, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 2229, 2244 (March 19, 2010); as amended by Final
        Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 1402 (February 8, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11864 (August 16, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>