<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-3017</num>
  <heading>FILINGS AND DEADLINES (§ 3-3017)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3017.1.</num>
    <text>Reports of Receipts and Expenditures (R&amp;#038;E Reports) shall be filed with the Office of Campaign Finance by:</text>
    <text>The treasurer of each political committee supporting a candidate;</text>
    <text>Each candidate required to register pursuant to § 3002.2, unless reporting is otherwise exempted or waived under § 3004; and</text>
    <text>The treasurer of each political committee engaged in obtaining signatures on any initiative, referendum, or recall petition, or promoting or opposing the ratification of any initiative, referendum, or recall measure placed before the District of Columbia
      electorate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3017.2.</num>
    <text>All candidates and political committees, except as otherwise noted in this chapter, shall file R&amp;#038;E Reports on the following dates:</text>
    <text>March 10, June 10, August 10, October 10, and December 10 in the seven (7) months preceding the date on which an election is held for which the candidate seeks office and the political committee supports a candidate for office;</text>
    <text>January 31, March 10, June 10, August 10, October 10, December 10, and the eighth (8th) day next preceding the date of any election, in any year in which there is held an election for which the candidate seeks office and the political committee supports
      a candidate for office;</text>
    <text>January 31 and July 31; provided, that a political committee no later than January 31 declares its intention to not support a candidate during an election year under § 3000.10; and</text>
    <text>January 31 and July 31, in a non-election year; provided, that a political committee no later than July 31 of the non-election year, (January 31) declares its intention to not support a candidate during an election year under § 3000.10.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3017.3.</num>
    <text>Constituent-service program R&amp;#038;E Reports shall be filed quarterly each year on the first (1st) day of the following months:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>January;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>April;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>July; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>October.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3017.4.</num>
    <text>Statehood Fund R&amp;#038;E Reports shall be filed quarterly each year on the first (1st) day of the following months:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>January;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>April;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>July; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>October.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3017.5.</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, R&amp;#038;E Reports shall be filed on January 31 and July 31 of each year until all debts and obligations are satisfied by the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Authorized committees pursuant to § 3015.8;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A Statehood Fund when the U.S. Senator or Representative vacates office; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A constituent-service program when the elected official vacates office.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3017.6.</num>
    <text>All R&amp;#038;E Reports shall contain all financial transactions through and including the fifth (5th) day preceding the filing deadline for each R&amp;#038;E Report; provided, that the reporting period for the next R&amp;#038;E Report shall commence
      on the day following the closing date of the prior R&amp;#038;E Report.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3017.7.</num>
    <text>All contributions of two hundred dollars ($200) or more, received after the filing deadline for the eighth (8th) day preceding the election Report, shall be reported in writing within twenty-four (24) hours of receipt.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3017.8.</num>
    <text>All reports and statements filed in person or by first class mail shall be deemed timely filed when received by 5:30 p.m. of the prescribed filing date.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3017.9.</num>
    <text>All reports and statements electronically filed shall be deemed timely filed if received by midnight of the prescribed filing deadline; provided, that the original paper report, verified by the treasurer, is also filed within five (5) days of the
      filing deadline. The filing of the paper copy may be eliminated where the treasurer electronically certifies the contents of the report through the use of a PIN Number assigned by the Office of Campaign Finance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3017.10.</num>
    <text>Upon written request submitted by the candidate or committee, on or before the filing deadline, the Director may allow an extension for filing a Report or statement for a reasonable period of time, for good cause shown.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3017.11.</num>
    <text>Any reference to days in this chapter is to calendar days, unless otherwise indicated.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 3161, 3183-84 (May 20, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 2171, 2183 (March 24, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 3230 (April 21, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 57 DCR 2229, 2251 (March 19, 2010); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 10607 (December 16, 2011); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 1402 (February 8, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking published
        at 60 DCR 11864 (August 16, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>