<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-3016</num>
  <heading>TERMINATION OF POLITICAL COMMITTEES, CONSTITUENT-SERVICE PROGRAMS, AND STATEHOODUNDS (§ 3-3016)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3016.1.</num>
    <text>A final R&amp;#038;E Report and a verified statement of termination, on a form prescribed by the Director, shall be filed upon termination of any political committee (committee), constituent-service program (program), or Statehood Fund (fund).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3016.2.</num>
    <text>An elected official shall terminate a program or fund if the elected official:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Fails to win re-election;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Resigns; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Becomes ineligible to serve, by operation of law.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3016.3.</num>
    <text>An authorized committee shall terminate, upon satisfaction of all debts and obligations, when the purpose for which the committee was organized ceases.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3016.4.</num>
    <text>Any committee, program, or fund may terminate its reporting requirements by filing a final R&amp;#038;E Report; provided, that the committee, program, or fund:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Has ceased to receive contributions or make expenditures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Has extinguished all debts and obligations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Is not involved in any enforcement, audit, or litigation action with the Office of Campaign Finance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Has disbursed all surplus funds in accordance with § 3015.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3016.5.</num>
    <text>A committee, program, or fund that cannot extinguish its outstanding debts and obligations may qualify to terminate its reporting requirements by:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Settling its debts for less than the full amount owed to its creditors; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Demonstrating that a debt is unpayable.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3016.6.</num>
    <text>The types of debts that are subject to debt settlement include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Amounts owed to commercial vendors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Debts arising from advances by individuals;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Salary owed to committee or program employees; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Loans owed to political committees.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3016.7.</num>
    <text>The types of debts that are not subject to debt settlement include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Disputed debts; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Bank loans.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3016.8.</num>
    <text>A qualifying committee, program, or fund shall be settled if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Credit was initially extended in the ordinary course of business;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Reasonable efforts, including, for example, fundraising, reducing overhead costs, and liquidating assets, were undertaken to satisfy the outstanding debt; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The creditor made the same efforts to collect the debt as those made to collect debts from a non-political debtor in similar circumstances.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3016.9.</num>
    <text>Once a committee, program, or fund has reached an agreement with a creditor, the treasurer shall file a debt settlement proposal with the Director on a form prescribed by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3016.10.</num>
    <text>Following receipt of the debt settlement proposal, the Director shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Review each debt settlement proposal for substantial compliance with the Act; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Notify the committee or program within thirty (30) days of its approval or disapproval.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3016.11.</num>
    <text>A debt may be considered unpayable, under § 3016.5(b), if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The debt has been outstanding for at least twenty-four (24) months;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The creditor is out of business, and no other entity has the right to collect the amount owed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The creditor cannot be located after best efforts to do so.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3016.12.</num>
    <text>A committee, program, or fund may apply to the Director to determine whether a specific debt may be unpayable upon a showing that best efforts to locate the creditor have been made.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3016.13.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, the term &amp;#8220;Best efforts&amp;#8221; shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Ascertaining of the creditor’s current address and telephone number; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Contacting the creditor by registered or certified mail, in person, or by telephone.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3016.14.</num>
    <text>The reporting obligation of a committee, program, or fund ends when the Director notifies the committee, program, or fund that the final Report has been approved, and the official record closed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 3161, 3180-82 (May 20, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 2229, 2248 (March 19, 2010); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 1402 (February 8, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 60 DCR 11864 (August 16, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>