<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-1600</num>
  <heading>PURPOSE AND GOVERNANCE (§ 7-1600)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1600.1.</num>
    <text>Board. In accordance with section 121(i) of the &amp;#8220;District of Columbia Retirement Reform Act,&amp;#8221; as amended, Public Law 96-122 (codified at D.C. Official Code § 1-711(i) (2001)), the District of Columbia Retirement Board (“Board”)
      is vested with contracting authority and is required to issue rules governing the procurement of goods and services pursuant to such authority to carry out its responsibilities under the Reform Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.2.</num>
    <text>District Procurement Law. The Board’s statutory contracting authority is unencumbered by the District’s procurement provisions in chapter 3 of title 2 of the D.C. Official Code (D.C. Official Code § 2-303.20(h) (2001)).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.3.</num>
    <text>Appropriations. The Mayor and the Council may not specify the purposes for which funds appropriated for the administrative expenses of the Board may be expended or the amounts which may be expended for the various activities of the Board. Pub. L.
      96-122 § 121(f)(3) (codified at D.C. Official Code § 1-711(f)(3) (2001)).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.4.</num>
    <text>Administration. The Executive Director appointed by the Board pursuant to Title 7, Chapter 15, Section 1503.1 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations, who serves as the Chief Contracting Officer, shall develop and administer operating policies,
      procedures, and guidelines implementing this Chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.5.</num>
    <text>Applicability. This Chapter applies to the procurement of goods and services, except for contracts with the governments of the District of Columbia and the United States. This Chapter is not applicable to the retention of investment counsel and investment-related
      services, which is governed by separate rules developed and adopted by the Board&amp;#8217;s Investment Committee and approved by a majority vote of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.6.</num>
    <text>Rules of Construction. The titles to sections and subparts of sections contained in these rules are for convenience and reference only. Unless otherwise stated, a listing of factors, criteria, or subjects in these rules does not constitute an order
      of precedence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.7.</num>
    <text>Severability. If any provision of this Chapter is deemed by a court of competent jurisdiction to be invalid, void or unenforceable for any reason, such a determination shall not affect the validity of any other provision of this Chapter.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 12594 (December 31, 2010).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>