<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-1601</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 7-1601)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1601.1.</num>
    <text>These regulations shall govern the procurement of goods and services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1601.2.</num>
    <text>Procurements shall be conducted using full and open competition, except as otherwise provided for in these regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1601.3.</num>
    <text>In conformity with its statutory mandate, the Board reserves the right, at any time and in its sole discretion, to modify, rescind, delete, or otherwise change the provisions of the regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1601.4.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director shall issue a Procurement Manual setting forth guidelines and procedures to be followed consistent with these regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1601.5.</num>
    <text>The Board delegates to the Executive Director the authority to develop, implement and enforce such policies and procedures, consistent with these regulations, as deemed necessary or useful.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1601.6.</num>
    <text>Contract Funding</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Prior to the execution of any contract or modification increasing the price of the contract, the Chief Financial Officer shall certify that sufficient funds are available for obligation in accordance with applicable legal requirements.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>In accordance with the District of Columbia Antideficiency Act (D.C.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Official Code §§ 47-355.01, et seq.) and the federal Antideficiency Act (31 U.S.C. §§ 1341, et seq.), the Board shall not make or authorize the encumbrance or expenditure of funds, in advance of appropriations, which exceeds the budget authority available.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If the contract provides for expenditures in a future fiscal year, the Contracting Officer shall not sign the contract unless the contract contains a provision which expressly provides that the portion of the contract requiring expenditures in a
        future fiscal year is conditioned upon the appropriation of budget authority for that fiscal year.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1601.7.</num>
    <text>Books and records of services rendered to the Board shall be maintained by the Contractor for a period of not less than six (6) years from the date of final payment under a contract and shall be made available for inspection upon reasonable request
      by the Board.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 12594, 12595 (December 31, 2010).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>