<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-500</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (SP) (§ 11-500)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>500.1.</num>
    <text>The SP District (Special Purpose) is designed to stabilize those areas adjacent to C-3-C and C-4 Districts and other appropriate areas that contain:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Existing apartments, offices, and institutions; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Mixed use buildings.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>500.2.</num>
    <text>The major purpose of the SP District shall be to act as a buffer between adjoining commercial and residential areas, and to ensure that new development is compatible in use, scale, and design with the transitional function of this zone district.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>500.3.</num>
    <text>The SP District is designed to preserve and protect areas adjacent to Commercial Districts that contain a mix of row houses, apartments, offices, and institutions at a medium to high density, including buildings of historic and architectural merit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>500.4.</num>
    <text>The SP District is divided into SP-1 (medium density) and SP-2 (medium-high density) Districts. In both districts, new residential development shall be permitted at a higher density than new office development, both to be compatible with surrounding
      properties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>500.5.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in chapters 20 through 25 of this title, in the SP District, no building or premises shall be used and no building shall be erected or altered that is arranged, intended, or designed to be used except for one (1) or more of the
      uses listed in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>500.6.</num>
    <text>Upon receiving an application for an approval of a use specified in §§ 505 and 506,508 through 510, and 512 through 515, the Board of Zoning Adjustment shall submit the application to the D.C. Office of Planning for coordination, review, report, and
      impact assessment, along with reviews in writing from all relevant District departments and agencies, including the Departments of Transportation and Housing and Community Development and, if a historic landmark or historic district is involved,
      the State Historic Preservation Officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is the Zoning Act of 1938, approved June 20, 1938 (52 Stat. 797, as amended; D.C. Official Code §§ 6-641.01 to 6-641.15 (2001) (formerly codified at D.C. Code §§ 5-413 to 5-432 (1994 Repl. &amp;#038;
        1999 Supp.))).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE §§ 4101.1, 4101.2, and 4101.5 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by:</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 2756 (September 22, 1978); Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9725, 9731-9732 (December 8, 2000); and Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference, in part, the
        text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8371-72 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>