<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-299</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 31-299)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>299.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following words and phrases shall have the meaning ascribed.</text>
    <text>Chairperson &amp;#8211; the Chairperson of the Commission.</text>
    <text>Commission &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission.</text>
    <text>Day &amp;#8211; calendar days, unless otherwise expressly defined.</text>
    <text>Ex Parte Communication &amp;#8211; an oral or written communication, not on the public record, which is relevant to the merits of a proceeding and with respect to which reasonable prior notice to all parties has not been given.</text>
    <text>Intervenor &amp;#8211; a person whose petition to intervene in a proceeding has been granted.</text>
    <text>Office &amp;#8211; the Office of Taxicabs.</text>
    <text>Panel &amp;#8211; the Panel on Rates and Rules of the Commission.</text>
    <text>Party &amp;#8211; any person who is a petitioner, respondent, or intervenor in a proceeding.</text>
    <text>Person &amp;#8211; an individual, partnership, association, firm, corporation, body politic, municipal organization, governmental body, joint stock company, receiver, trustee, official acting in his or her official capacity, or any other organization
      or institution.</text>
    <text>Petitioner &amp;#8211; a person who files a petition with the Commission.</text>
    <text>Pleading &amp;#8211; petitions, applications, answers, written motions, and amendments to any thereof.</text>
    <text>Respondent &amp;#8211; a person against whom a complaint is made or an order of investigation or an order to show cause is directed.</text>
    <text>Secretary &amp;#8211; the Secretary appointed pursuant to ยง 201.2.</text>
    <text>APPENDIX 2-1</text>
    <text>DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA TAXICAB COMMISSION</text>
    <text>SUBPOENA</text>
    <text>DUCES TECUM (Produce Documents)</text>
    <text>AD TESTIFICANDUM (To Testify)</text>
    <text>(Name)</text>
    <text>Pursuant to section 337 of the Rules of Organization and Procedure of the Panel on Adjudication of the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission, YOU ARE COMMANDED TO APPEAR before the Panel on Adjudication at the following location:</text>
    <text>At (a.m./p.m.)</text>
    <text>on the day of , 20 , to testify concerning: and to bring</text>
    <text>with you</text>
    <text>Chairman Secretary Secretary</text>
    <text>District of Columbia District of Columbia</text>
    <text>Taxicab Commission Taxicab Commission</text>
    <text>If you fail to appear at the time and place stated, or fail to bring with you the documents or items requested, the Panel may refer the matter to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for an order compelling your attendance and/or production
      of the items requested. Failure to obey such an ORDER of the COURT may be punished as CONTEMPT OF COURT. DO NOT FAIL TO APPEAR OR PRODUCE THE REQUESTED ITEMS AT THE TIME REQUIRED.</text>
    <text>I, , certify that I served a copy of this subpoena on the name party at</text>
    <text>(address) on the day of , 20</text>
    <text>, at</text>
    <text>(a.m./p.m.) by:</text>
    <text>Personal Service</text>
    <text>Other</text>
    <text>Process Server</text>
    <text>(Address)</text>
    <text>SUBSCRIBED AND AFFIRMED TO BEFORE ME ON</text>
    <text>THIS THE DAY OF , 20</text>
    <text>NOTARY PUBLIC, D.C.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 6715, 6748 (October 23, 1987).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>ISSUED BY ATTEST:</heading>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>IMPORTANT</heading>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>RETURN</heading>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA</heading>
      <text>SS</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>MY COMMISSION EXPIRES</heading>
      <text />
    </level>
  </level>
</level>