<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-222</num>
  <heading>INITIAL PLEADINGS (ยง 31-222)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>222.1.</num>
    <text>Each initial petition shall contain the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of petitioner;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A clear and concise statement of facts upon which the petition is based and the position and interest of the petitioner in the matter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A description of the nature and basis of the changes proposed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A listing of the existing rates and proposed rates for each service for which changes are being proposed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A full statement and description of any new or revised rates; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Financial information showing increases and decreases since the last rate making proceeding in the costs of doing business, including but not limited to, costs of gasoline, insurance, cost of repairs to vehicles, increased driving time to destinations
        due to construction or other matters, and such other financial information as will aid the Panel in its consideration of the petition.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>222.2.</num>
    <text>Whenever, in a rate change petition, a party proposes to change the rate making principles adopted by the Panel in its most recent rate case, the party shall also file with its ยง 222.1 filing a statement describing each proposed change in the rate
      making principles adopted by the Panel or Public Service Commission of the District of Columbia in the last rate proceeding, showing the effect of each change upon the petitioner&amp;#8217;s request if no changes were made, and the effect should
      the proposed change be granted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>222.3.</num>
    <text>Each document initiating new proceedings shall leave a space for the docket number. Each subsequent document for filing shall show on the first page the caption for each proceeding, the docket number, the title of the document, and leave sufficient
      space in the upper right hand corner for a time and date stamp.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 6715, 6723 (October 23, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>