<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-240</num>
  <heading>INTERROGATORIES (§ 31-240)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>240.1.</num>
    <text>Depositions may be taken and submitted on written interrogatories in substantially the same manner as oral depositions as described in § 238 and shall be permitted under similar circumstances by the Chairperson. One (1) copy shall be served on each
      party.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>240.2.</num>
    <text>Within seven (7) days after service, any party may file with the Chairperson his or her objections, if any, to the interrogatories and may file such cross-interrogatories as he or she desires to submit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>240.3.</num>
    <text>Cross-interrogatories shall be served in the same manner on each party as are interrogatories. One (1) copy together with a copy of any objections to interrogatories shall be served on each party who shall have five (5) days thereafter to file and
      serve his or her objections.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>240.4.</num>
    <text>Objections to interrogatories or cross-interrogatories shall be decided by the Chairperson.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>240.5.</num>
    <text>Objections to interrogatories or cross-interrogatories shall be made before the order for taking and deposition issues, and if not so made shall be deemed waived.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>240.6.</num>
    <text>The provisions of §§ 238.9 through 238.11 shall be applicable to written interrogatories.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>240.7.</num>
    <text>Interrogatories shall confirm to the specifications of §§ 230 and 231.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>240.8.</num>
    <text>The fact that interrogatories are filed in a proceeding as provided in this section does not constitute a determination that they are admissible in evidence or that they may be used in the proceeding.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>240.9.</num>
    <text>Only those parts or the whole of interrogatories received in evidence at a hearing shall constitute a part of the record in the proceeding upon which a decision is based.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 6715, 6738 (October 23, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>