<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-236</num>
  <heading>PRE-HEARING CONFERENCE (ยง 31-236)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>236.1.</num>
    <text>The Panel shall give notice directing all parties to attend a pre-hearing conference.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>236.2.</num>
    <text>At least five (5) calendar days before the pre-hearing conference, each party shall serve and file a statement of proposed issues and order of procedure with the Panel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>236.3.</num>
    <text>The parties to the proceeding, or their representatives, and representatives of the Panel and staff of the Commission designated by it for the purpose, shall be given notice of the conference.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>236.4.</num>
    <text>The purpose of the pre-hearing conference shall be to do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Formulate the issues;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Arrange for the exchange of proposed exhibits;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Make any necessary amendments to the pleadings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Obtain admissions of fact and of documents which will avoid unnecessary proof;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Determine the number of witnesses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Set forth any extraordinary rule of procedure for the conduct of the hearing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Adopt a procedural schedule for the proceedings; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Pursue any other matters, which may aid in the disposition of the proceeding.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>236.5.</num>
    <text>Any agreements reached at the conference by the parties shall be promptly reduced to writing by the Secretary and submitted to the Panel for approval.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>236.6.</num>
    <text>Any participant who fails to attend a pre-hearing conference of which the participant had due notice shall, with respect to any matter reasonably encompassed in the notice of the pre-hearing conference, be deemed to have waived any objections to any
      agreement reached, or ruling made thereon at the conference.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>236.7.</num>
    <text>At the conclusion of the pre-hearing conference, the Panel shall issue, as soon thereafter as possible, an Order and Report on Pre-hearing Conference, which includes the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Designation of the parties;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Setting forth the issues to be decided in the hearing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any extraordinary rules or procedure;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The procedural schedule of the proceeding; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Date, time, place and attendees.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 6715, 6734 (October 23, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>