<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-246</num>
  <heading>CONDUCT OF HEARINGS (ยง 31-246)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>246.1.</num>
    <text>Evidence shall be presented by those participating in the sequence set forth in the Order and Report on Pre-hearing Conference.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>246.2.</num>
    <text>Continuances, extensions of time, and adjournments may be ordered by the Panel upon written motion of a party or upon its own motion.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>246.3.</num>
    <text>If, in the judgment of the Panel convenience or necessity so require, it may, after opening a hearing, postpone the hour or change the place of the hearing without the requirement of a motion.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>246.4.</num>
    <text>Motions made during a hearing may be oral; provided, that the following motions shall be in writing:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Motions to dismiss;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Motions requesting a more sufficient pleading;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Motions for a Bill of Particulars;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Motions to strike objectionable written matter other than pre-filed testimony;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Motions for the addition of parties or dismissal of improper parties; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Motions to quash a subpoena.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>246.5.</num>
    <text>All written motions affecting the conduct of a hearing shall be filed not later than three (3) business days before the scheduled hearing date.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>246.6.</num>
    <text>If a party desires to file a written motion later than three (3) business days before the hearing, that party shall request permission from the Panel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>246.7.</num>
    <text>All persons responding to motions shall file answers by 3:45 p.m. on the business day immediately preceding the scheduled hearing date.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>246.8.</num>
    <text>There shall be submitted to the Panel no later than 9:00 a.m. on the first day of a hearing a list of the witnesses who are scheduled to appear before the Panel on that day and the following day, and an identification of the material and subject areas
      on which each witness is to be examined.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>246.9.</num>
    <text>The list of witnesses shall be cumulative and shall be submitted no later than 9:00 a.m. on each succeeding day of hearings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>246.10.</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise ordered, the General Counsel shall be responsible for submitting the list of witnesses.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>246.11.</num>
    <text>Counsel and all other participants other than witnesses testifying shall stand while addressing the Panel and witnesses. Not more than one counsel for each party shall be entitled to examine any witness or address the Panel on any one matter without
      the permission of the Panel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 6715, 6741 (October 23, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>