<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-300</num>
  <heading>R-2 DISTRICTS[COLON] GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 11-300)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>300.1.</num>
    <text>The R-2 District consists of those areas that have been developed with one-family, semi-detached dwellings, and is designed to protect them from invasion by denser types of residential development. It shall be expected that these areas will continue
      to contain some small one-family detached dwellings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>300.2.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in chapters 21 through 25 of this title, in an R-2 District, no building or premises shall be used and no building shall be erected or altered that is arranged, intended, or designed to be used except for one (1) or more of the
      uses listed in §§ 301 through 319.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>300.3.</num>
    <text>The following uses shall be permitted as a matter of right in R-2 Districts:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Any use permitted in R-1 Districts under § 201;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Community house existing on May 12, 1958;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>One-family, semi-detached dwelling; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Youth residential care home, community residence facility, or health care facility for seven (7) to eight (8) persons, not including resident supervisors or staff and their families; provided, that there is no property containing an existing community-based
        residential facility for seven (7) or more persons either in the same square or within a radius of five hundred feet (500 ft.) from any portion of the property.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is the Zoning Act of 1938, approved June 20, 1938 (52 Stat. 797, as amended; D.C. Official Code §§ 6-641.01 to 6-641.15 (formerly codified at D.C. Code §§ 5-413 to 5-432 (1994 Repl. and 1999
        Supp.))).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE § 3101 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by:</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 3482, 3490 (August 7, 1931); Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 726 (January 22, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of
        Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8355-56 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>