<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-305</num>
  <heading>EMERGENCY SHELTERS (R-2) (ยง 11-305)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>305.1.</num>
    <text>Emergency shelters for five (5) to fifteen (15) persons, not including resident supervisors or staff and their families, shall be permitted as special exceptions in an R-2 District if approved by the Board of Zoning Adjustment under ยง 3104, subject
      to the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.2.</num>
    <text>There shall be no other property containing a community-based residential facility for seven (7) or more persons in the same square.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.3.</num>
    <text>There shall be no other property containing a community-based residential facility for seven (7) or more persons within a radius of five hundred feet (500 ft.) from any portion of the property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.4.</num>
    <text>There shall be adequate, appropriately located, and screened off-street parking to provide for the needs of occupants, employees, and visitors to the facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.5.</num>
    <text>The proposed facility shall meet all applicable code and licensing requirements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.6.</num>
    <text>The facility shall not have an adverse impact on the neighborhood because of traffic, noise, operations, or the number of similar facilities in the area.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.7.</num>
    <text>The Board may approve more than one (1) community-based residential facility in a square or within five hundred feet (500 ft.) only when the Board finds that the cumulative effect of the facilities will not have an adverse impact on the neighborhood
      because of traffic, noise, or operations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.8.</num>
    <text>The Board may approve a facility for more than fifteen (15) persons, not including resident supervisors or staff and their families, only if the Board finds that the program goals and objectives of the District of Columbia cannot be achieved by a
      facility of a smaller size at the subject location and there is no other reasonable alternative to meet the program needs of that area of the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.9.</num>
    <text>The Board shall submit the application to the D.C. Office of Planning for coordination, review, report, and impact assessment, along with reports in writing of all relevant District departments and agencies, including but not limited to the Departments
      of Transportation, Human Services, and Corrections and, if a historic district or historic landmark is involved, the State Historic Preservation Officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>ยง 3102.44 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as added by Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 3482, 3492 (August 7, 1981); Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 726 (January 22, 1993); and as amended by Final Rulemaking published
        at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8357-58 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>