<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2111</num>
  <heading>BOXING GLOVES (§ 19-2111)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2111.1.</num>
    <text>A contestant may wear one winding of surgeon’s standard white adhesive tape not over one inch (1”) wide, placed directly on the hand, one inch (1&amp;#8243;) behind the knuckle to protect the part of the hand near the wrist.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2111.2.</num>
    <text>A contestant may wear soft surgical bandages held in place by not more than two feet (2’) of surgeon’s adhesive tape for each hand. Ten yards (10 yds.) of soft surgical bandages are allowed for each hand.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2111.3.</num>
    <text>Contestants shall not adjust the bandages except in the dressing room under the</text>
    <text>Supervision of an inspector and in the presence of the other contestant, or as the</text>
    <text>Commission’s representative directs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2111.4.</num>
    <text>Gloves for the main event shall be put in the ring after the referee has inspected the bandaged hands of both contestants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2111.5.</num>
    <text>The promoter shall supply new gloves for the main event.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2111.6.</num>
    <text>Gloves that are to be reused shall be whole, clean, and in sanitary condition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2111.7.</num>
    <text>A glove used in a boxing event shall weigh at least eight ounces (8 oz.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2111.8.</num>
    <text>A glove shall have the thumb secured so that it is not independently mobile. The Commission may waive this requirement in championship contests.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2111.9.</num>
    <text>Contestants shall not break, roughen, or twist the gloves.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2111.10.</num>
    <text>The inspector shall examine the gloves. If padding is found to be misplaced or lumpy or, if the gloves are found to be imperfect, other gloves shall be substituted before the contest.</text>
    <text>The inspector shall ensure that the tape, gloves, and other accoutrements worn or used by each contestant and second comply with this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3731, 3736-37 (May 20, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>