<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-931</num>
  <heading>FLOOR AREA RATIO (W) (§ 11-931)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>931.1.</num>
    <text>In the W-0 District, the floor area ratio of all buildings and structures shall not exceed five-tenths (0.5), provided that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The floor area ratio on a lot used exclusively for recreational use, marina, yacht club, or boathouse buildings and structures shall not exceed 0.75; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this sub-section, floor area ratio shall be the gross floor area of all buildings and structures located on land and any associated permanent structure located on, in, or over water, other than a floating home, divided by the
        total area of the lot.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>931.2.</num>
    <text>In the W-1 District, the floor area ratio of all buildings and structures on a lot shall not exceed two and five-tenths (2.5), not more than one (1.0) of which may be used for other than residential purposes. The floor area ratio of public recreation
      and community centers shall not exceed 1.8.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>931.3.</num>
    <text>In the W-2 District, the floor area ratio of all buildings and structures on a lot shall not exceed four (4.0), not more than two (2.0) of which may be used for other than residential purposes. The floor area ratio of public recreation and community
      centers shall not exceed 1.8.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>931.4.</num>
    <text>In the W-3 District, the floor area ratio of all buildings and structures on a lot shall not exceed six (6.0), not more than five (5.0) of which may be used for other than residential purposes. The floor area ratio public recreation and community
      centers shall not exceed 1.8.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>931.5.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, &amp;#8220;residential purposes&amp;#8221; shall include dwellings, flats, multiple dwellings, rooming and boarding houses, community-based residential facilities, inns, and guestroom areas and service areas within
      hotels.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§§ 4404.1 through 4404.4 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 2066, 2070 (May 16, 1980); Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 3482, 3500 (August 7, 1981); and Final Rulemaking published
        at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8434 (October 20, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 10137 (November 28, 2003); as amended by Final
        Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 3440 (April 2, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 6358 (July 8, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>