<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-923</num>
  <heading>YACHT CLUB (W-0) (§ 11-923)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>923.1.</num>
    <text>If appropriate in furthering the objectives of the Waterfront District, a yacht club shall be permitted as a special exception in the W-0 District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>923.2.</num>
    <text>In addition to demonstrating that the yacht club meets the criteria for special exceptions set forth in §§ 927 and 3104 of this Title, the applicant shall further demonstrate that the yacht club and associated facilities:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Will be primarily for the use of the members of the yacht club, except that the yacht club may provide transient berths;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Will be located so as not likely to become objectionable to surrounding and nearby property because of noise, traffic, or parking; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Will not result in the filling of normally submerged areas and will minimize excavation to that reasonably required for a facility that is principally above-grade.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>923.3.</num>
    <text>Floating homes shall be permitted within a permitted yacht club provided that the maximum density of floating home berths shall not exceed fifty percent (50%) of the total number of berths in the yacht club. This percentage may be increased by special
      exception, subject to the provisions of § 927.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>923.4.</num>
    <text>A home occupation within a floating home, including a Bed and Breakfast, is permitted, subject to the provisions of § 203.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>923.5.</num>
    <text>Off-street parking spaces for a yacht club and each floating home shall be provided in the amount and manner specified in Chapter 21 &amp;#8211; Off-Street Parking Requirements, except as may be permitted in accordance with the provisions of § 926.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 3440 (April 2, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 6358 (July 8, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>