<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-900</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS[COLON] WATERFRONT DISTRICTS (§ 11-900)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>900.1.</num>
    <text>The Waterfront (W) Districts are applied to waterfront areas that have one (1) or more of the following characteristics:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Geographically, historically, or locationally unique;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Adjacent to well-established residential areas;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Undergoing transition from light and heavy industrial uses to office and commercial uses; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Where the public health, safety, general welfare, and amenity would be promoted and protected by the encouragement of mixed uses.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>900.2.</num>
    <text>The Waterfront District shall be subdivided into W-0, W-1, W-2, and W-3 Districts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>900.3.</num>
    <text>The W-0 District permits open space, park, and low-density and low-height waterfront-oriented retail and arts uses, the W-1 District permits a moderate height and density, the W-2 District allows a medium height and density, and the W-3 District allows
      the greatest height and density of the Waterfront Districts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>900.4.</num>
    <text>The purpose of the Waterfront Districts is to encourage a diversity of compatible land uses at various densities, including combinations of residential, offices, retail, recreational, arts and cultural, and other miscellaneous uses.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>900.5.</num>
    <text>The W-1, W-2, and W-3 Districts are also intended to be relatively self-contained by supplying a variety of housing, service, employment, and recreational opportunities in one (1) location. This characteristic allows one (1) area to serve many different
      needs of a single population and to thereby reduce the amount of vehicular traffic generated by the uses in the districts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>900.6.</num>
    <text>The W-0 District is intended to provide waterfront recreation areas with related waterfront-oriented or waterfront-enhancing uses, to serve local and regional open space recreation needs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>900.7.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in chapter 21 of this title, in the Waterfront Districts, no building or premises shall be used and no building shall be erected or altered that is arranged, intended, or designed to be used except as specified in §§ 901, 902, and
      906 through 925.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is the Zoning Act of 1938, approved June 20, 1938 (52 Stat. 797, as amended; D.C. Official Code §§ 6-641.01 to 6-641.15 (formerly codified at D,C. Code §§ 5-413 to 5-432 (1994 Repl. &amp;#038;
        1999 Supp.))).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§§ 4401.1 and 4402.1 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9725, 9734 (December 8, 2000); and Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference
        the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8429 (October 20, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 3440 (April 2, 2004) ; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 6358 (July 8, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>