<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2912</num>
  <heading>MINIMUM STANDARDS FOR ANIMAL FACILITIES (§ 17-2912)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2912.1.</num>
    <text>This section sets forth the minimum standards for animal facilities. This section, except for §2912.9, is applicable to mobile clinics.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2912.2.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in §2912.3, a facility shall have the following areas:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A reception area separate from other designated areas;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An examination room;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A laboratory area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A surgery room separate from all other areas;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>An animal housing area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>An animal exercise area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>An animal treatment area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>A lavatory;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>A radiology area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>A radiology processing room;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>A drug storage and dispensing area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>A record keeping area; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>An isolation area for effective separation of contagious and non-contagious cases.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2912.3.</num>
    <text>A facility shall not be required to have a laboratory area, surgery room, radiology area, or radiology processing room if the facility proves to the satisfaction of the Director that the facility uses consultant services for diagnostic-quality X-rays,
      laboratory services, and surgery.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2912.4.</num>
    <text>A facility shall at a minimum have the following equipment in good working order:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A stethoscope;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An ophthalmoscope;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An otoscope;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A thermometer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Scales;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>An oxygen and delivery system; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>If surgery is performed, the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An autoclave with monitoring devices; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Anesthetic support equipment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2912.5.</num>
    <text>Each examination room shall meet the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be of sufficient size to accommodate the veterinarian, assistants, animal, and owner; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Have, at a minimum, the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A table with a non-porous surface;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A waste receptacle; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Sanitizing solution.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2912.6.</num>
    <text>Cages or housing systems of an animal facility shall meet the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Have sufficient space to allow animals freedom of movement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Maintain a temperature between sixty-five and seventy-five degrees Fahrenheit (65° to 75° F.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Provide access to adequate food and water as required by §2913;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Maintain animals that must be in a group without overcrowding;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Maintain animals in good health as measured by such factors as the maintenance of normal body weight and the prevention of the spread of communicable diseases;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Be designed for effective sanitary maintenance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Be kept in good repair to prevent injury to the animal and to promote physical comfort, and be free of sharp corners and edges, broken wires, and any dangerous surfaces; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Be of materials that are impervious to water, wear, and corrosion, not including wood.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2912.7.</num>
    <text>The buildings and grounds of the facility shall be maintained to provide for the well-being of the animals and health and safety of the facility&amp;#8217;s personnel and public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2912.8.</num>
    <text>The animal facility shall be kept clean. A regular schedule of sanitary maintenance is required, including the elimination of wastes as described in §§2912.9 to 2912.17.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2912.9.</num>
    <text>The animal facility shall provide an area readily susceptible to proper sanitation which is available for the sole purpose of exercising animals.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2912.10.</num>
    <text>Animal rooms, corridors, storage areas, and other parts of the animal facility shall be cleaned as often as necessary, using appropriate detergents and disinfectants to keep them free of dirt, debris, and contamination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2912.11.</num>
    <text>If litter or bedding, such as paper, is used in animal cages or pens, it shall be changed as often as necessary to keep the animals dry and clean and to minimize offensive odors.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2912.12.</num>
    <text>Cages or pens from which animal waste is removed hosing or flushing shall be cleaned and suitably disinfected at least once a day. Animals shall be removed from cages during servicing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2912.13.</num>
    <text>Animal cages, racks, and accessory equipment, such as feeders and water utensils, shall be washed and sanitized as often as necessary to keep them clean and free from contamination. In addition, cages shall be sanitized before new animals are placed
      in them. Sanitizing may accomplished either by washing all soiled surfaces with a cleaning agent having an effective bactericidal action or with live steam or the equivalent thereof.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2912.14.</num>
    <text>Waste containers and implements shall be maintained in sanitary condition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2912.15.</num>
    <text>All waste shall be collected and removed in a safe and sanitary manner. If waste cans are used, they shall be made of metal or plastic, be leakproof, and be equipped with tight fitting lids. Leakproof, disposalable containers such as plastic bags
      or plastic-lined paper bags as liners in waste cans shall be used for disposal of animal tissues and carcasses.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2912.16.</num>
    <text>Waste materials shall be removed regularly and frequently.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2912.17.</num>
    <text>Used hypodermic needles, suture needles, catheter needles, and other needles shall be stored and disposed of in containers so as to prevent injuries to persons handling the trash.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2912.18.</num>
    <text>Insects, rodents, and other pests shall be eliminated or effectively controlled.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 6630, 6636 (September 2, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>