<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2914</num>
  <heading>FACILITIES, EQUIPMENT, AND SUPPLIES FOR ANIMAL SURGERY AND POST SURGICAL CARE§ 17-2914)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2914.1.</num>
    <text>If surgery is to be performed, appropriate facilities and equipment shall be provided. Surgery shall be performed in a room which is reserved only for surgery and used for no other purpose. A surgery room may not serve as a corridor. The operating
      area shall be run in accordance with accepted surgical practice with regard to anesthesia, asepsis, life support, monitoring procedures, and recovery care.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2914.2.</num>
    <text>A suitably equipped area shall include the following equipment and supplies:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A surgical table with non-porous surface;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Autoclave for effective sterilization of instruments, linens, gloves, gowns, and similar items, will have internal and external sterilization monitors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Instrument table, stand, or tray and waste receptacle;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A scrub sink or a similar container for surgical preparation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Operating light with sufficient power to illuminate the surgical area clearly with a minimum of one hundred (100) foot-candles;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Automatic emergency lighting;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Instruments, supplies, and equipment appropriate for the surgical procedures performed in the hospital;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Instruments and equipment for artificial respiration, including but not limited to, resuscitation (Ambu) bag and endotracheal tubes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Circle gas anesthesia machine in working condition utilizing an anesthetic vaporizer and effective scavenger system; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Provision for proper and adequate post-surgical care and monitoring.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2914.3.</num>
    <text>Surgeons and assistants shall wear clean or sterile attire and sterile gloves appropriate to the procedure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 6630, 6639 (September 2, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>