<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2332</num>
  <heading>SERVICES AND SUPPORTS &amp;#8212; PATIENT INTAKE AND SCREENING STANDARDS (§9-2332)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2332.1.</num>
    <text>A substance abuse treatment facility or program shall collect sufficient information on an individual seeking treatment to establish a patient profile for purposes of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Triaging patients based on presenting status;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Establishing a baseline against which treatment outcomes will be measured; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Analyzing aggregate data on individuals seeking treatment for addiction in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2332.2.</num>
    <text>Facilities and programs shall transmit electronically to the Department utilization and profile data and epidemiological and other studies for reporting requirements consistent with this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2332.3.</num>
    <text>The Department shall provide to the facility or program information on minimum data sets, method of transmission, and reporting frequency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2332.4.</num>
    <text>The Department may require facilities and programs to use standardized tools based on national criteria for the collection of intake and screening information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2332.5.</num>
    <text>A substance abuse treatment facility or program shall comply with the following standards for conducting intake and screening:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Identify staff responsible for intake and screening functions by title, functional description of duties, qualifications and orientation requirements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Provide intake and screening within 24 hours of an individual’s request for services by telephone or in a face-to-face interview. Providers must maintain individual and aggregate data to demonstrate compliance with this standard;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Provide intake and screening staff with emergency clinical consultation capability as necessary;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Refer individual based on critical need to nurse or other skilled clinician for expedited in-depth assessment and level of care placement decision;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Accept for admission only individuals whose service needs are consistent with the program description;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Establish referral procedures for those individuals screened ineligible or inappropriate for admission to the level(s) of care available within the program or facility if</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The individual does not need addiction treatment; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Requires acute medical detoxification services, other medical services, or psychiatric services; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Document the individual’s refusal or acceptance of a referral for services, and the individual’s arrival at referral site by facilitating transport of patient to referral site as necessary.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9341 (November 24, 2000), adopting Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7708, 7752 (September 22, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>