<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2363</num>
  <heading>SPECIALITY SERVICES &amp;#8212; STANDARDS FOR MEDICAL DETOXIFICATION (§ 29-2363)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2363.1.</num>
    <text>Medical detoxification services shall comply with all standards identified in this section and all other applicable standards in this chapter, and guidelines as recommended by the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA)
      Treatment Improvement Protocols.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2363.2.</num>
    <text>A substance abuse facility or program shall have a written agreement with a nearby hospital for transferring patients in cases of medical emergencies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2363.3.</num>
    <text>There shall be a written physician-approved detoxification protocol or standing detoxification orders for each substance for which the program detoxifies patients.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2363.4.</num>
    <text>To ensure that the appropriate rehabilitative services are provided, the patient shall be assigned a primary addiction therapist who shall follow the patient’s progress during detoxification. Such progress shall be documented in the patient’s treatment
      record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2363.5.</num>
    <text>A substance abuse facility shall have a written policy for involuntary discharge procedures that shall include a requirement that all patients shall be informed of the facility’s or program’s rules and regulations, and shall sign a statement that
      he or she knows and understands the rules and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2363.6.</num>
    <text>There shall be a written policy for any patient who leaves detoxification treatment against the advice of staff. The patient shall sign an Against Medical Advice Form and it shall be witnessed by a staff member.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2363.7.</num>
    <text>Patients shall remain in a medical detoxification program for the period of time deemed medically necessary and documented by the attending physician.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2363.8.</num>
    <text>Coercion or force shall not be used to induce any person to remain in treatment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9341 (November 24, 2000), adopting Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7708, 7802 (September 22, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>