<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2302</num>
  <heading>CERTIFICATION[COLON] APPLICATION &amp;#8212; SCHEDULE OF SUBMISSION, QUALIFICATIONS§ 29-2302)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2302.1.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall apply for certification on a form provided by the Department at least ninety (90) calendar days before the opening date of a substance abuse treatment program or facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2302.2.</num>
    <text>A substance abuse treatment facility or program applying for re-certification shall submit its application at least ninety (90) days before the expiration date of its existing certification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2302.3.</num>
    <text>A substance abuse treatment program or facility already in operation shall apply for its initial certification as soon as possible but not later than ninety days (90) after the effective date of these rules, or within thirty (30) days after an application
      package for certification is made available to the public, whichever comes later.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2302.4.</num>
    <text>To qualify for certification, an applicant shall demonstrate that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>It offers an organized program for the treatment of drug abuse, alcohol abuse, or any combination thereof;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>It operates under the direct day-to-day supervision of a clinical director with demonstrable training and experience in the treatment of drug abuse or alcohol abuse; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>It employs sufficient numbers of professional staff members to deliver adequately the services offered to its patient caseload.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9341 (November 24, 2000), adopting Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7708, 7712 (September 22, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>