<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2313</num>
  <heading>ADMINISTRATIVE SERVICES[COLON] MANAGEMENT AND ADMINISTRATION &amp;#8212; GOVERNINGODY STANDARDS (§ 29-2313)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2313.1.</num>
    <text>Each substance abuse treatment facility or program shall have a governing body with legal and fiduciary authority, as well as responsibility for the overall operation of the program. In addition:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If a public facility, the governing body shall have a description of its administrative framework and the lines of authority within which it operates; and,</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If a private facility, the governing body shall have written documentation of the source of its authority through either a charter, constitution, articles of incorporation, by-laws or certification.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2313.2.</num>
    <text>The governing body shall establish policies for and exercise general direction over the operation of a substance abuse treatment facility or program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2313.3.</num>
    <text>The methods used by the governing body to establish policy and provide general direction must be documented, including frequency of meetings, appointment of officers, establishment of committees, establishment of attendance requirements for board
      members, fiscal reviews, record keeping and recording of minutes, and any other structural guidelines necessary to demonstrate compliance with the scope of authority held by the governing body.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2313.4.</num>
    <text>In addition to the annual business meeting of the board, meetings shall be held as required to maintain proper oversight and control.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2313.5.</num>
    <text>The governing body shall orient new board members to the structure and operation of its facility or program and shall establish a continuing education program for all board members of the governing body.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2313.6.</num>
    <text>The governing body shall review triennially the independent audit of fiscal operations, including the management letter, prepared by an independent certified public accountant (CPA). The review shall occur at the meeting following receipt of the audit
      and management letter and the governing body shall take corrective action accordingly. The audit, management letter, and records of all meetings shall be available to the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2313.7.</num>
    <text>The governing body shall develop and approve:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A detailed description of the parent organization that includes:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Mission statements with clear identification of philosophy, purpose, and goals;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The scope of the organization’s operating elements and programs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The management and leadership structure; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The relationship among components within the organization and with agencies outside of the organization.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9341 (November 24, 2000), adopting Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7708, 7719 (September 22, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>