<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2325</num>
  <heading>ADMINISTRATIVE SERVICES &amp;#8212; FOOD AND NUTRITION STANDARDS (§ 29-2325)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2325.1.</num>
    <text>All patients shall have a nutritional assessment within three (3) days of admission if admitted to a treatment facility or program that provides food service and prepares and serves food</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2325.2.</num>
    <text>All treatment facilities or programs that provide food service that includes preparing and serving food shall comply with the District of Columbia Food Code.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2325.3.</num>
    <text>A contractor or other source providing food to a treatment facility or program that serves food to patients shall comply with all applicable District laws and regulations concerning the storage, preparation, and serving of food.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2325.4.</num>
    <text>Nutritional services shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Review and approval of menus;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Education for individuals with nutrition deficiencies or special needs; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Coordination with medical personnel as appropriate.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2325.5.</num>
    <text>Nutritional services may only be provided and rendered by a licensed dietician or licensed nutritionist, a copy of whose current license shall be maintained on file.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2325.6.</num>
    <text>A substance abuse treatment facility or program providing meals shall implement written plans to meet the dietary needs of its patients, ensuring access to nourishing, well-balanced, healthful meals.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2325.7.</num>
    <text>In addition to meeting dietary needs, a substance abuse treatment facility or program shall make reasonable efforts to prepare meals that consider the cultural background and personal preferences of the clients.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2325.8.</num>
    <text>The written dietary plan shall identify the methods and parties responsible for food procurement, storage, inventory and preparation, and the procurement of commodity and other supplemental foods and food stamps, where applicable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2325.9.</num>
    <text>The written dietary plan shall ensure special provisions for individuals unable to have a regular diet as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Providing clinical diets for medical reasons when necessary;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Recording clinical diets in the record;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Providing special diets for patients’ cultural and personal preferences; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Maintaining menus of special diets or a written plan stating how special diets will be developed or obtained when needed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2325.10.</num>
    <text>If appropriate, a substance abuse treatment facility or program shall maintain a fully equipped and supplied code-compliant kitchen area unless meals are catered by an outside facility, in which case the outside facility must maintain a fully equipped
      and supplied code-compliant kitchen.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2325.11.</num>
    <text>A substance abuse treatment facility or program may share kitchen space with other programs if the accommodations are adequate to perform required meal preparation for all programs using the kitchen.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2325.12.</num>
    <text>A substance abuse treatment facility or program shall provide meals and snacks including fresh fruit for the hours of operation and the population served as recommended by the most recent edition of the Manual of Clinical Dietetics developed by the
      American Dietetic Association.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2325.13.</num>
    <text>Meals shall be served in a pleasant, relaxed dining area. The dining area shall accommodate families and children.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2325.14.</num>
    <text>Meals shall be scheduled so as to have no more than fourteen (14) hours between a substantial dinner meal and breakfast.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9341 (November 24, 2000), adopting Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7708, 7736 (September 22, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>