<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2368</num>
  <heading>ACCESS TO RECOVERY PROGRAM (ยง 29-2368)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2368.1.</num>
    <text>A provider intending to provide recovery support services under this section shall submit an application on a form approved by the Director. The certification provided under this section shall be in addition to certification under this chapter for
      substance abuse treatment services if the provider currently offers or intends to offer substance abuse treatment services. The application shall include the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Evidence of a valid Certificate of Occupancy and other government certifications necessary for the specific services the provider intends to provide;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A current organizational chart;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A list of the specific recovery support services the provider intends to provide for each target population;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A physical description of the facility where services are to be provided;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A description of the provider&amp;#8217;s staffing capacity including:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Total number of staff providing recovery support services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Client to staff ratio;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Number of program clients the provider can serve;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Language fluency of the staff; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Minimum qualifications, experience, and training required of staff;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A description of the provider&amp;#8217;s program operations including staffing, location, and days and hours of operation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The specific qualifications, licensure, training, experience and certification of the staff providing recovery support services; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Documentation of the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Organization mission statement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Organization directors or governing members;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Policies and procedures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Organization code of ethics;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Risk management strategy, including liability insurance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Consent form for services to be rendered;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Statement of confidentiality; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Financial infrastructure of the organization.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2368.2.</num>
    <text>The Director shall review each application and inform the applicant of any deficiencies. The applicant shall supply any missing or incomplete information or documentation. The Director shall approve or disapprove a completed application within thirty
      (30) days of receipt by the Department. Certification under this section shall be for a period of two (2) years and shall be renewable for additional two (2) year periods, subject to the availability of ATR Program funding.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2368.3.</num>
    <text>The Department and its authorized agents, upon presentation of proper credentials, shall have the authority to enter the premises of a provider during normal operating hours for the purpose of conducting announced or unannounced inspections to ensure
      compliance with certification standards. An inspection conducted under this subsection shall comply with the requirements of sections 2306, 2307, and 2308 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2368.4.</num>
    <text>A provider certified under this section shall comply with the records management standards for confidentiality, and maintenance and reporting, and storage and retention under sections 2353, 2354, and 2355 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2368.5.</num>
    <text>A provider certified under this section shall comply with the fiscal management standards under section 2315 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2368.6.</num>
    <text>A provider certified under this section shall comply with the facility environment and safety standards under section 2322 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2368.7.</num>
    <text>If the provider provides transportation services, the provider shall comply with the vehicle environment and safety standards under section 2323 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2368.8.</num>
    <text>If the provider provides a food service, the provider shall comply with the food and nutrition standards under section 2325 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2368.9.</num>
    <text>The Department may refuse to issue or renew, or may revoke or suspend a certification under this section for failure to comply with the provisions of this section, or other applicable District or federal laws. Action to deny, suspend or revoke certification
      under this section shall be conducted pursuant to the procedures set forth in section 2367 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9341 (November 24, 2000), adopting Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7708, 7806 (September 22, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 8867,8868,8869(August 15, 2008)</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>