<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2346</num>
  <heading>SERVICES AND SUPPORTS[COLON] STANDARDS FOR CORE REQUIREMENTS &amp;#8212; GROUPDUCATION (ยง 29-2346)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2346.1.</num>
    <text>Key service functions of group education may include but are not limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Classroom style didactic lectures to present information about a topic and its relationship to substance abuse;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Presentation of audiovisual materials that are educational in nature with required follow-up discussion;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Promotion of discussion and questions about the topic presented to those in attendance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Generalization of the information and demonstration of its relevance to recovery and enhanced individual functioning.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2346.2.</num>
    <text>Group education services shall be provided by an individual who:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Demonstrates competency and skill in educational techniques;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Has knowledge of chemical dependency and its relationship to the topic(s) being taught; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Is present throughout the group education session.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2346.3.</num>
    <text>The usual and customary size of group educational sessions shall not exceed thirty-five (35) persons in order to promote participation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2346.4.</num>
    <text>A substance abuse treatment facility or program shall develop a schedule and curriculum for delivery of group education services addressing topics and material relevant to the patients.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2346.5.</num>
    <text>A substance abuse treatment facility or program shall provide basic information to patients regarding:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The progressive nature of dependency and the disease model, to include 12 step programs, principles and availability of self-help groups, and health and nutrition;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Support for the personal recovery process, including overcoming denial, recognizing feelings and behavior, promoting self-awareness and self-esteem, encouraging personal responsibility and constructively using leisure time;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Skill development, such as communication skills, stress reduction and management, conflict resolution, decision-making, assertiveness training, and parenting;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The promotion of positive family relationships and relationships with significant others;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Relapse prevention;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The effects of alcohol and other drug abuse upon pregnancy and child development;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>HIV/AIDS, including related conditions, risk factors, preventive measures and the availability of diagnostic testing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Substance abuse and mental health conditions; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Parenting and child development, as appropriate.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9341 (November 24, 2000), adopting Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7708, 7772 (September 22, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>