<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2343</num>
  <heading>SERVICES AND SUPPORTS[COLON] STANDARDS FOR CORE REQUIREMENTS &amp;#8212; FAMILYHERAPY (§ 29-2343)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2343.1.</num>
    <text>Family therapy is defined as planned, goal-oriented therapeutic interaction of a qualified individual with the patient and/or one or more members of the patient’s family in order to address and resolve the family system’s dysfunction as it relates
      to the patient’s substance abuse problem in accordance with the patient’s rehabilitation plan. An individual living in the same household with the patient who has a significant relationship with the patient, may be considered a family member.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2343.2.</num>
    <text>At least one (1) of the participating family members shall be age five (5) or older in order to qualify for family therapy service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2343.3.</num>
    <text>At least one (1) family member who participates in therapy sessions shall agree to activities he or she will do if patient relapses.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2343.4.</num>
    <text>Family therapy may be provided in the facility, program or home setting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2343.5.</num>
    <text>Key service functions of family therapy may include, but are not limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Utilization of generally accepted principles of family therapy to influence the family;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Examination of family interaction styles and identifying patterns of behavior;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Development of a need or motivation for change in family members;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Development and application of skills and strategies for improvement in family functioning;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Identification and treatment of domestic violence and child abuse and neglect; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Generalization and stabilization of change through insight, structure and enhanced skills to promote healthy family interaction independent of formal helping systems.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2343.6.</num>
    <text>Family therapy shall be performed by a person who:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Is certified by the American Association of Marriage and Family Therapists; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Is a licensed clinical social worker and has one (1) year of supervised experience in family counseling or specializes in family counseling; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Has a master’s degree in psychology or counseling and one (1) year supervised experience in family counseling or specializes in family counseling.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9341 (November 24, 2000), adopting Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7708, 7768 (September 22, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>