<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2338</num>
  <heading>SERVICES AND SUPPORTS &amp;#8212; OFF-SITE, OFF-HOURS CRISIS INTERVENTION STANDARDS§ 29-2338)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2338.1.</num>
    <text>A substance abuse treatment facility or program shall provide for its patients a twenty-four (24) hour per day, seven (7) day per week on-call system for crisis intervention counseling, and referral to appropriate emergency substance abuse treatment
      resources.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2338.2.</num>
    <text>A substance abuse treatment facility or program shall have a written plan for &amp;#8211; a crisis intervention on-call telephone communication system for patients to access in the event of a crisis during hours when the facility or program is not
      operational.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2338.3.</num>
    <text>A substance abuse treatment facility’s or program’s crisis intervention on call system shall provide off-hour patient linkage to a licensed and/or certified care provider, preferably someone with whom the patient has some interaction during his/her
      normal course of treatment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2338.4.</num>
    <text>Upon admission, a patient shall be given the emergency on-call telephone number, and shall receive orientation and written instructions on how to access the on-call crisis intervention system.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2338.5.</num>
    <text>Qualified individuals staffing the on-call crisis intervention system shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Facilitate admission to an appropriate program or facility on an emergency referral basis, if indicated; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Have the ability to conduct face-to-face crisis intervention with the individual at a pre-designated location when indicated.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2338.6.</num>
    <text>The facility or program shall have affiliation agreements with other service providers to accept patients in crisis, for services not directly provided by the program or facility, or for access to a facility during off-hours for crisis management,
      if necessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2338.7.</num>
    <text>The facility or program shall document in the patient’s record any activity related to off-hours interventions on the next day of operation of the facility or program, subsequent to the event. The documentation of the crisis intervention shall include
      but is not limited to the nature of the crisis, the location of the intervention, the resolution of the crisis, the disposition of the patient, and the follow-up plan. The patient’s primary addiction counselor shall also be notified.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9341 (November 24, 2000), adopting Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7708, 7763 (September 22, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>