<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2304</num>
  <heading>CERTIFICATION &amp;#8212; EXEMPTIONS FROM STANDARDS (ยง 29-2304)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2304.1.</num>
    <text>If a certification standard interferes with a service provision, the Department may, at its discretion, exempt a certification standard if the exemption does not jeopardize the health and safety of patients, infringe on patient rights, or diminish
      the quality of the service delivery.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.2.</num>
    <text>If the Department approves an exemption, such exemption shall end on the expiration date of the facility or program certification, unless the facility or program requests renewal of the exemption prior to expiration of its certificate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.3.</num>
    <text>The Department may deny a request or revoke an exemption at any time if the Department makes a determination that a substance abuse treatment facility or program is not in compliance with the provisions of the Act, rules adopted pursuant to this chapter,
      and applicable District and federal laws or regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.4.</num>
    <text>All requests for an exemption from certification standards must be submitted in writing to the Department at the time of application or anytime thereafter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.5.</num>
    <text>A provider certified to provide services solely under ยง 2368 shall be exempt from any other requirements in this chapter, unless otherwise required under ยง 2368, and provided that the provider is not also a substance abuse treatment provider</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9341 (November 24, 2000), adopting Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7708, 7715 (September 22, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 8866 (August 15, 2008)</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>