<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-358</num>
  <heading>AMENDMENTS (ยง 31-358)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>358.1.</num>
    <text>Whenever the Chairperson or the Panel proposes to adopt, amend, or repeal a rule, any interested party or parties may submit data or views on the action proposed in the form of a written petition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>358.2.</num>
    <text>Any interested party or parties may petition in writing to the Chairperson for the adoption, repeal, or amendment of rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>358.3.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt, the Chairperson may refer a petition to the staff of the Office with a request for a written report on the advisability of any action to be taken upon the petition. The staff shall promptly submit a report to the Chairperson who shall
      transmit it to the Panel for its consideration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>358.4.</num>
    <text>If the Panel determines that the petition discloses sufficient reasons in support of the proposals therein to justify the institution of rulemaking, an appropriate notice thereof will be issued to all petitioners and the public that proposed rulemaking
      will be held on the matter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>358.5.</num>
    <text>If the Panel determine that the petition does not show sufficient grounds to justify rulemaking procedures, the Chairperson shall notify the petitioner together with the grounds for denial.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>358.6.</num>
    <text>The Panel may order that a public hearing be held prior to the adoption, amendment, or repeal of a rule in the manner prescribed in this chapter, insofar as the procedures are applicable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>358.7.</num>
    <text>Amendments to this chapter may be adopted at any duly convened meeting of the Panel by a majority vote of those present and voting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>358.8.</num>
    <text>Notice of the proposed amendments shall be provided to all members of the Panel at least thirty (30) days in advance of the meeting at which they will be considered unless a majority of the members of the Panel waive the notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>358.9.</num>
    <text>Final rulemaking action to amend this chapter, following publication in the D.C. Register of a thirty (30) day notice of proposed rulemaking and public hearing, may be taken by a majority of the members of the Panel present and voting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>358.10.</num>
    <text>The Chairperson shall file any rule, amendment, or repeal thereof approved by the Panel to the Office of Documents.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>358.11.</num>
    <text>If any rule is adopted pursuant to proceedings initiated by petition of any interested party, a copy of the rule shall be delivered to such party.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 6751, 6794 (October 23, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>