<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-333</num>
  <heading>STYLE OF PLEADINGS AND PETITIONS (§ 31-333)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>333.1.</num>
    <text>Except for documents filed pursuant to § 322 which shall comply with the provisions of Chapter 10 of Title 18, DCMR, all pleadings, notices, orders and other papers filed under the provisions of this chapter shall be captioned &amp;#8220;Before the
      Panel on Adjudication of the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission.&amp;#8221;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>333.2.</num>
    <text>A document shall contain a docket number, if assigned.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>333.3.</num>
    <text>Each petition filed under this chapter shall be styled in the manner of pleadings as provided in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>333.4.</num>
    <text>Each document shall contain a title appropriate to the proceedings which described generally the type of document it purports to be, such as one of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>&amp;#8220;In the Matter of the Proposed Revocation (or Suspension or Denial) of the of &amp;#8220;;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>&amp;#8220;In the Matter of a Complaint against Taxicab Owner (or Operator, or Association, or Company, or Fleet) &amp;#8220;;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>&amp;#8220;In the Matter of Contest to the Imposition of a Civil Fine&amp;#8221;;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>&amp;#8220;In the Matter of a Request for a Declaratory Order relating to</text>
    </level>
    <text>&amp;#8220;;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>In the Matter of an Intraindustry Complaint or Dispute Pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 50-307(b)(2)(B) (2001)&amp;#8221;; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>&amp;#8220;In the Matter of a Review by the Bureau of Traffic Adjudication of the Immediate Suspension of the of &amp;#8220;;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>&amp;#8220;Motion to &amp;#8220;.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>333.5.</num>
    <text>Each petition shall meet the general requirements of documents under §§ 327, 328, and 329.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>333.6.</num>
    <text>Upon filing, each petition shall be given a docket number and shall become a matter of public record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>333.7.</num>
    <text>Each petition shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A concise statement of the facts which tend to show the petitioner&amp;#8217;s interest;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Supporting data, facts, or evidence upon which petitioner relies as justification for the action requested; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A request for the order to which the petitioner believes he or she may be entitled.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 6751, 6769 (October 23, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>