<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-323</num>
  <heading>HEARINGS AND PROCEEDINGS BEFORE THE HEARING PANELS (§ 31-323)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>323.1.</num>
    <text>Any of the following persons may request a hearing which shall be granted:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A person whose license or licenses to act as a taxicab or passenger vehicle for hire owner or operator has been denied by the Office;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A person whose license or licenses to act as a taxicab or passenger vehicle for hire owner or operator has been recommended by the Office for revocation or suspension (except for immediate suspensions described in § 322);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A person whose conduct as a taxicab or passenger vehicle for hire owner or operator has caused the filing of a complaint, such complaint having not been resolved by the Office pursuant to § 801.4 of this title;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A person who wishes to contest the imposition of a civil fine pursuant to § 825 of this title for alleged infractions; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A person who wishes to contest a decision entered by the Bureau of Traffic Adjudication pursuant to § 322.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>323.2.</num>
    <text>The request for a hearing shall be made to the Chairperson, in writing on a form substantially similar to that shown as Appendix 3-1 to this chapter, within fifteen (15) days after personal service, or within eighteen (18) days after mail posting,
      of the action complained of, except as provided in § 323.3.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>323.3.</num>
    <text>The request for a hearing to contest the imposition of a civil fine shall be made to the Chairperson, in writing on a form within fifteen (15) days of the issuance of the Notice of Civil Infraction(s).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>323.4.</num>
    <text>There shall be no extensions of the time period prescribed in § 323.2, except as provided in §§ 320.4 to 320.7.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>323.5.</num>
    <text>A person shall not be entitled to a hearing if that person has previously been afforded, after appropriate notice, an opportunity for a hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>323.6.</num>
    <text>If any person fails to appear at a hearing scheduled by the Chairperson before a hearing panel without good cause shown, the proposed order of suspension or revocation or imposition of civil fine shall become effective immediately without further
      notification to the person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>323.7.</num>
    <text>Appeals from any final decision of the hearing panel pursuant to this section shall, pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 2-510 (2001) be taken to the District of Columbia Court of Appeals.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 6751, 6760 (October 23, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>