<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-8013</num>
  <heading>SCOPE OF PRACTICE (ยง 17-8013)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8013.1.</num>
    <text>A surgical assistant shall, in accordance with this chapter and the Act, have the authority to perform the following tasks:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Provide local infiltration or the topical application of a local anesthetic and hemostatic agents at the operative site;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Incise tissues;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Ligate and approximate tissues with sutures and clamps;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Apply tourniquets, casts, immobilizers, and surgical dressings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Check the placement and operation of equipment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Assist in moving and positioning the patient;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Assist the surgeon in draping the patient;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Prepare a patient by cleaning, shaving, and sterilizing the incision area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Retract tissue and expose the operating field area during operative procedures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Place suture ligatures and clamp, tie, and clip blood vessels to control bleeding during surgical entry;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Use cautery for hemostasis under direct supervision;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Assist in closure of skin and subcutaneous tissue;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Assist in the cleanup of the surgical suite; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>Check and restock the surgical suite.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8013.2.</num>
    <text>A surgical assistant shall not perform the following tasks;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Perform any surgical procedure independently;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Prescribe any medications or controlled substances; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Write any progress notes or orders on hospitalized patients, except operative notes.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 9549 (October 5, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>