<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-216</num>
  <heading>OPTIONAL ACCELERATED PROCEDURES (ยง 27-216)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>216.1.</num>
    <text>In appeals where the amount in dispute is one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000) or less, the appellant may elect to have the appeal adjudicated under the accelerated procedure set forth in this rule.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>216.2.</num>
    <text>Decisions under the accelerated procedure shall be rendered within one hundred and eighty (180) days from the date the Board receives notice that the appellant has elected to utilize the accelerated procedure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>216.3.</num>
    <text>The appellant&amp;#8217;s election of the accelerated procedure shall be exercised by written notice within sixty (60) days after receipt of notice of docketing the appeal. The election, once exercised, may not be withdrawn, except with the permission
      of the Board for good cause shown.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>216.4.</num>
    <text>In a case proceeding as an accelerated appeal, the Board shall encourage the parties to waive or limit pleadings, discovery, and briefs to the maximum possible extent consistent with the adequate presentation of their factual and legal positions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>216.5.</num>
    <text>Within thirty (30) days of receiving appellant&amp;#8217;s election of the accelerated procedure, the respondent shall file an answer as prescribed by Rule 205 and the appeal file as prescribed by Rule 203.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>216.6.</num>
    <text>Within forty-five (45) days of receiving appellant&amp;#8217;s election of the accelerated procedure, the Board shall convene an informal meeting, or a telephone conference, with the parties and shall proceed with the case as described in Rule 215.3(b).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>216.7.</num>
    <text>The Board shall permit discovery by the parties consistent with its requirement to decide their case under the time limit imposed by Rule 216.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 2078 (March 8, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>