<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-204</num>
  <heading>ISSUANCE OF ORIGINAL AND RENEWAL LICENSES (ยง 30-204)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>204.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may vote to issue a license to sell lottery tickets upon the favorable recommendation of the Executive Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>204.2.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director&amp;#8217;s recommendation shall include a determination that all requirements of this chapter have been met.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>204.3.</num>
    <text>All licenses shall be issued in the name of the establishment listed in the license application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>204.4.</num>
    <text>All licenses shall be valid for a period determined by the Board and shall expire at midnight of the last day of the designated period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>204.5.</num>
    <text>For the purpose of staggering license renewals and for the orderly administration of the licensing process, the Board may vary the period of a new or renewal license to coincide with the scheduled renewal cycle for that license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>204.6.</num>
    <text>For the purpose of staggering license renewals, the Board may require an agent to file a renewal application ninety (90) days prior to the expiration date of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>204.7.</num>
    <text>At least one hundred and twenty (120) days prior to the expiration date of the license, the Board shall give an agent written notice of the Board&amp;#8217;s intent to require the agent to file a renewal application pursuant to the provisions of ยง204.6.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>204.8.</num>
    <text>The Board may require an applicant for a new or a renewal license to pay a license fee and other fees or costs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>204.9.</num>
    <text>All fees and costs may be prorated according to the period of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 8665, 8669 (December 29, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 38 DCR 2286 (April 3, 1992).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL NOTE</heading>
      <text>Prior to December 29, 1989, the D.C. Lottery and Charitable Games Control Board published Final Rulemaking published at 29 DCR 2202 (May 28, 1982); and at 30 DCR 1597. 1609 (April 8, 1983).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>