<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-1602</num>
  <heading>PRESOLICITATION NOTICES AND CONFERENCES (ยง 27-1602)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1602.1.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer may use presolicitation notices and conferences as preliminary steps in procurements by CSP in order to accomplish any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Develop or identify interested sources;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Request preliminary information based on a general description of the goods or services involved;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Obtain comments on a draft request for proposals (RFP);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Explain complicated specifications and requirements to interested sources; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Aid prospective offerors in later submitting proposals without undue expenditure of effort, time, and money.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1602.2.</num>
    <text>If presolicitation notices are used, the contracting officer shall publicize the notice on the OCP Internet and, if the Director deems appropriate, in newspapers of general circulation and trade publications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1602.3</num>
    <text>1602.3 At a minimum, the notice shall contain sufficient information to permit a potential offeror to make an informed decision about whether to participate in the acquisition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1602.4.</num>
    <text>In complex procurements, the presolicitation notice may request information pertaining to management, engineering, or production capabilities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1446 (February 26, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 1136 (February 1, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>