<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-1622</num>
  <heading>CHANGES IN DISTRICT REQUIREMENTS (ยง 27-1622)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1622.1.</num>
    <text>When, either before or after receipt of proposals, the District increases, decreases or otherwise changes its requirements, the contracting officer shall issue a written amendment to the solicitation in accordance with ยง 1623.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1622.2</num>
    <text>1622.2 In deciding which firms to notify of a change, the contracting officer shall consider the state in the procurement cycle at which the change occurs and the magnitude of the change, as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If proposals are not yet due, the amendment shall be published in the same manner as the solicitation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the time for receipt of proposals has passed but proposals have not yet been evaluated, the amendment shall be sent only to the responding offerors; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If a competitive range has been established, the amendment shall be sent only to those offerors within the competitive range.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1622.3.</num>
    <text>If a change is so substantial that it warrants complete revision of a solicitation, the contracting officer shall cancel the original solicitation and issue a new one, regardless of the state of the procurement. The new solicitation shall be advertised
      in accordance with the requirements of Chapter 13 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1622.4.</num>
    <text>If the proposal considered to be most advantageous to the District (as determined by using the established evaluation criteria and selection procedure) involves a departure from the stated requirements, the contracting officer shall provide all offerors
      an opportunity to submit new or amended proposals on the basis of the revised requirements, if this can be done without revealing to the other offerors the solution proposed in the original departure or any other information that is entitled to
      protection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1460 (February 26, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 1136 (February 1, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>