<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-603</num>
  <heading>WATERPROOF FLOORS IN TOILETS (§ 14-603)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>603.1.</num>
    <text>The owner of a building used for residential purposes shall provide each water closet compartment, privy, toilet room, and bathroom in the building with a waterproof floor surface and wall base.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.2.</num>
    <text>The wall base shall be at least three inches (3”) in height.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.3.</num>
    <text>The waterproof floor surface shall consist of one of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Smooth-finished tile or masonry which is effectively sealed so that it has a nonporous surface, laid in a manner free from cracks or open joints, and tightly joined to the base;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Tongue-and-groove hardwood flooring that is tightly laid without open cracks or joints, and which is tightly joined to the base. Both the base and surface shall be covered with a seal coat of waterproof finish; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Linoleum, plastic, or rubber floor covering, or linoleum, asphalt, rubber or plastic floor tiles, firmly cemented to a smooth substantial subfloor, laid without overlapping or open joints, and tightly joined to the base.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.4.</num>
    <text>The term “linoleum” as used in this section, means a floor covering made of special preparations of linseed oil, gum, coloring matter, and wood flour, firmly affixed to a cloth or feltpaper base, and does not include enameled and cottonlinter composition
      coverings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>The Housing Regulations of the District of Columbia, 5G DCRR § 1202, Commissioners’ Order 55-1503 (August 11, 1955).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>