<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-122</num>
  <heading>INFORMATION REQUESTS (ยง 15-122)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>122.1.</num>
    <text>A party&amp;#8217;s request for information from parties other than a utility shall be submitted in writing no later than ten (10) days after the filing of testimony by the party receiving the request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>122.2.</num>
    <text>A party to whom a request is made other than a utility company shall respond to that request within fifteen (15) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>122.3.</num>
    <text>In proceedings where a utility company is a party, requests for information from the utility company shall be served on the company no later than thirty (30) days from the date of the Order and Report on the Prehearing Conference unless otherwise
      specified by the Commission. The utility company shall respond to each of the requests within twenty-one (21) days after service of the data request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>122.4.</num>
    <text>Data requests shall be considered continuing in nature. Substantially revised information shall be provided without specific additional requests.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>122.5.</num>
    <text>Additional data requests may be served upon amendment of previous testimony or subsequent to the filing of supplemental or rebuttal testimony; Provided, that those requests are served within ten (10) days of the filing of the amended, supplemental
      or rebuttal testimony. Responses to these requests shall be served on the requesting party within ten (10) days after service of the request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>122.6.</num>
    <text>Any party to whom a response is provided who believes that the data needs clarification may within five (5) business days request the clarification or follow-up information; however, follow-up data requests shall be limited to one (1) per original
      request; Provided, that the information is within the scope of the original request. Responses to those requests shall be provided to the requesting party within five (5) business days after receipt of the request. If a party or Staff desires more
      than one follow-up request, that party may seek permission from the Commission to ask for additional follow-up data requests. The Commission will allow for additional follow-up data requests only upon a showing of a compelling need for the additional
      requests.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>122.7.</num>
    <text>Data requests shall be in writing and shall be served upon all parties. One copy of each data request shall be submitted to the Commission&amp;#8217;s Secretary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>122.8.</num>
    <text>The staff may request information from the utility at any time, and those requests originally need not be in writing. The oral request, if submitted with respect to a contested case in which Staff is participating shall be reduced to a written memorandum
      and served on all parties within three (3) days of the initial request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>122.9.</num>
    <text>Responses to data requests shall be submitted to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The party making the request;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Secretary of the Commission; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If a party or Staff wishes to obtain data supplied in response to another party&amp;#8217;s request, that party or Staff shall obtain the information from the Commission Secretary&amp;#8217;s Office.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>122.10.</num>
    <text>If a response to a particular information request is so voluminous that sending copies to all parties would be unduly burdensome, the responding party may serve the response on the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The requesting party;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Secretary of the Commission; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Commission&amp;#8217;s Office of Accounting and Finance.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>122.11.</num>
    <text>If a response is served pursuant to ยง122.10, the responding party shall give notice to other parties expecting a response, that a copy may be inspected by applying to the Secretary of the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>122.12.</num>
    <text>Large volumes of materials to be examined in response to a request may be made available for examination at reasonable times at the responding party&amp;#8217;s offices.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>122.13.</num>
    <text>Data responses, to the extent possible, shall be submitted in the requested format, including machine readable forms. All data responses shall identify the name and the title of the person sponsoring the response.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 2984, 3001 (July 3, 1981); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 29 DCR 2719 (June 25, 1982); by Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 2229 (April 11, 1986); by Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 5117,
        5120 (July 10, 1992); and by Final Rulemaking published at 42 DCR 2340, 2341 (May 12, 1995).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>