<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-6501</num>
  <heading>CERTIFICATION PROCEDURES (§ 20-6501)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6501.1.</num>
    <text>The Director shall certify to perform UST System activities as set forth in §6500 in the District of Columbia, any individuals who satisfy the following requirements:</text>
    <text>Show evidence of having satisfactory completion of a recognized training program in the UST System activity(ies) for which the applicant seeks certification;</text>
    <text>Submission of a completed application and payment of the initial application fee of $200.00 in the form of a check made payable to the D.C. Treasurer;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Possess a current OSHA certification; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Satisfactory completion of a test upon their knowledge in the technical area in which they seek certification as well as the District&amp;#8217;s statutes and regulations pertaining to USTs.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6501.2.</num>
    <text>The Director shall certify businesses that wish to perform UST System activities in the District of Columbia, as set forth in §6500, provided they satisfy the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Submission of a completed application and payment of the initial application fee of $350.00 in the form of a check made payable to the D.C. Treasurer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Demonstrate, to the satisfaction of the Director, that the business is qualified to perform the UST System activities for which it seeks certification;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Demonstrate, to the satisfaction of the Director, that the business employs at least one individual who has expertise and is certified in the District in each of the UST System activities the business will offer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Possess a current OSHA certification; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Possess a valid, current District of Columbia business license for</text>
    </level>
    <text>the business in which certification is sought.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6501.3</num>
    <text>6501.3 The Director may recognize individuals or businesses that are certified by neighboring states and so certify, to perform UST System activities as set forth in § 6500, individuals or businesses that satisfy the requirements of this section:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Possess a current valid certification as a UST System Technician, Closer Specialist or Tester, or an equivalent certification category as determined by the Director, issued by either of the states of Virginia, West Virginia, Maryland, Delaware,
        or Pennsylvania;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Are currently in good standing in each of the states, named in §6501.3(a), for which it holds a certification;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Possess a current OSHA certification;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Possess a valid, current District of Columbia business license for the business in which certification is sought;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Demonstrate, to the satisfaction of the Director, a knowledge of the provisions of this Subtitle; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Submit a completed application form and pay an initial application fee of $150.00 for individuals or $250 for businesses.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6501.4</num>
    <text>6501.4 An applicant certified in one of the states in §6501.3(a) may be tested by the Director to verify the knowledge of the provisions of this subtitle or shall submit the following documents or information with the application for certification:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A letter or statement from the state official or office in which the individual or business is currently certified stating that the individual or business is currently in good standing in that state;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A list of additional states in which the individual or business is certified and/or licensed as a UST System Technician, Closer Specialist or Tester, or an equivalent certification category;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A copy of the current OSHA certification;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A copy of a valid, current District of Columbia business license for the business in which certification is sought;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Submission of an initial application fee of $100 for individual or $250 for business by check or money order made payable to the D.C. Treasurer; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Evidence of possession of the District of Columbia UST regulation and its amendments.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6501.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant who relies upon an out-of-state certification may only be certified in the same UST System activity, as determined by the Director, in which the out-of-state certification was received.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6501.6</num>
    <text>6501.6 The initial certification issued by the Director shall be valid for no more than one (1) year from date of issue. The Certification may be renewed annually for a fee of $100 for individuals or $150 for businesses upon presentation of the expiring
      certification or renewed bi-annually for a fee of $200 for individuals, or $300 for businesses, upon presentation of the expiring certification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7699 (October 1, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 6678 (August 21, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>