<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-6502</num>
  <heading>OPERATOR TRAINING (§ 20-6502)
    <text>An owner of any active regulated UST system in the District shall designate ateast one Class A, one Class B, and one Class C operator for each active USTacility.</text>
    <text>A facility may not dispense or store a regulated substance after August 8, 2012,nless operators have been designated and trained as required in this Section.</text>
    <text>Trained operators shall be readily available to respond to suspected oronfirmed releases, other unusual operating conditions, emergencies andquipment failures as follows:</text>
    <text>Either the Class A or the Class B operator shall be available for immediateelephone consultation at all times when a facility is in operation;</text>
    <text>A Class A or B operator shall be on-site at the UST facility within 24 hours ofeing contacted;</text>
    <text>For manned facilities, a Class C operator shall be on-site whenever the facilitys in operation; and</text>
    <text>For unmanned facilities, a Class C operator shall be available for immediateelephone consultation and shall be able to be on-site within 2 hours of beingontacted.</text>
    <text>Emergency contact information shall be prominently displayed at the facility.</text>
    <text>Emergency procedures for users of unmanned facilities shall also be prominentlyosted at the facility.</text>
    <text>Designated operators shall successfully complete required initial training underhis Section by August 8, 2012.</text>
    <text>An operator may be designated as more than one class of operator.</text>
    <text>All operators designated as Class A and/or Class B for a petroleum UST systemhat has been determined to be out of compliance with a requirement or standardn this Subtitle shall, at a minimum, be required to repeat the trainingpplicable to the area(s)
      with which the UST system has not complied. Operatorshall complete the required retraining within a reasonable time, not to exceedixty (60) days of being notified that the UST system is out of compliance.</text>
    <text>A Class A operator has primary responsibility to operate and maintain the USTystem and facility. The Class A operator’s responsibilities include managingesources and personnel, such as establishing work assignments, to achieve andaintain compliance
      with regulatory requirements. In general, a Class Aperator focuses on the broader aspects of the statutory and regulatoryequirements and standards necessary to properly operate and maintain the USTystem and facility. Class A operators shall:</text>
    <text>Ensure that UST systems are properly installed and expeditiously repaired andhat records of UST financial responsibility, system installation, modificationnd repair are retained and made available to the Director;</text>
    <text>Be familiar with training requirements for each class of operator and mayrovide required training for Class C operators; and</text>
    <text>Prepare facility procedures for Class B and C operators.</text>
    <text>A Class B operator implements applicable UST system regulatory requirements andtandards in the field or at the UST facility. A Class B operator oversees andmplements the day-to-day aspects of operations, maintenance, and recordkeepingor the UST(s)
      at one or more facilities as stated in this regulation. Class Bperators shall:</text>
    <text>Check spill prevention and overfill control equipment and corrosion protectionquipment to ensure proper function and that any required system tests areerformed at appropriate intervals;</text>
    <text>Ensure release detection equipment is operational, release detection iserformed at proper intervals and release detection records are retained andade available to the Director; and</text>
    <text>Shall be familiar with all aspects of Class B and Class C operatoresponsibilities and may provide required training for Class C operators.</text>
    <text>A Class C operator is the first line of response to events indicating anmergency condition. A Class C operator is responsible for responding to alarmsr other indications of emergencies caused by a spill or release from a USTystem and equipment failures.
      The Class C operator notifies the Class A or Bperator and appropriate emergency responders when necessary. There may be morehan one Class C operator at a UST facility. Class C operators shall:</text>
    <text>Control or monitor the dispensing and sale of regulated substances; and</text>
    <text>After August 8, 2012, follow written instructions or procedures on how toespond to alarms or releases provided by the Class A or Class B operators andade visible at manned UST facilities, and shall be readily available fornmanned facilities for persons
      performing the duties of the Class C operator.</text>
    <text>Class A operators shall successfully complete a training course approved by theirector that includes a general knowledge of UST system requirements. At theompletion of the training course, the operator shall be able to demonstratenowledge and be able
      to make informed decisions regarding compliance andnsuring that appropriate persons are fulfilling operation, maintenance andecordkeeping requirements and standards, including the following:</text>
    <text>Spill and overfill prevention;</text>
    <text>Release detection and related reporting requirements;</text>
    <text>Corrosion protection;</text>
    <text>Emergency response;</text>
    <text>Product and equipment compatibility;</text>
    <text>Financial responsibility;</text>
    <text>Notification and UST registration requirements;</text>
    <text>Temporary and permanent UST closure requirements; and</text>
    <text>Class B, and C operator training requirements.</text>
    <text>Class B operators shall successfully complete a training course approved by theirector that includes in-depth understanding of operation and maintenancespects of UST systems and related regulatory requirements. Training shallrovide specific information
      pertaining to the components of UST systems,aterials of construction, methods of release detection, and release preventionpplied to UST systems and components. Training and knowledge shall address theperation and maintenance requirements of this
      regulation including theollowing:</text>
    <text>Spill and overfill prevention;</text>
    <text>Release detection and related reporting requirements;</text>
    <text>Corrosion protection;</text>
    <text>Emergency response;</text>
    <text>Product and equipment compatibility;</text>
    <text>Report and recordkeeping requirements; and</text>
    <text>Class C operator training requirements.</text>
    <text>At a minimum, training provided by the Class A or B operator shall enable thelass C operator to take action in response to emergencies or alarms caused bypills or releases from a UST system. Training shall include writtennstructions or procedures
      for the Class C operator to follow and to provideotification necessary in the event of emergency conditions. After the initialraining, Class C operators shall be briefed by the Class A or B operator onhese instructions or procedures at least annually
      (every 12 months).</text>
    <text>Successful completion of training for Class A and B operators means attendanceor the entire training course and demonstration of knowledge of the courseaterial as follows:</text>
    <text>Receipt of a passing grade (80% or higher) on an examination containing materialresented in the training course; or demonstration to the trainer at theonclusion of on-site training, through practical (hands-on) application, ofperation and maintenance
      checks of UST equipment, including performance ofelease detection at the UST facility; and</text>
    <text>Receipt of a training certificate by an approved trainer upon verification ofuccessful completion of training course.</text>
    <text>Class A or Class B operators may meet the operator training requirements of thisection by presenting proof of successful completion of Class A and Class Bperator training from another State, in accordance with regulatory standardsonsistent with 40
      CFR Part 280 and with Title 20 Chapter 65 of the District ofolumbia Municipal Regulations (20 DCMR Chapter 65).</text>
    <text>An owner shall ensure that all Class A, B, and C operators are trained no laterhan August 8, 2012.</text>
    <text>When a Class A or B operator is replaced, a new operator shall be trained within0 days of assuming duties for that class of operator.</text>
    <text>Class C operators shall be trained before assuming duties of a Class C operator.</text>
    <text>The owner of an underground storage tank shall maintain a list of designatedperators. The list shall represent the current Class A, B, and C operators forhe petroleum storage facilities and shall include:</text>
    <text>The name of each operator, class of operation designated and the date eachperator successfully completed training; and</text>
    <text>For Class A and B operators that are not permanently on-site or who are assignedo more than one facility, emergency telephone numbers to contact the operators.</text>
    <text>A copy of the following documentation shall be on-site, and readily availableor inspection at the facility:</text>
    <text>Certificates of training for Class A and B operators;</text>
    <text>A copy of the facility list of Class A, B, and C operators; and</text>
    <text>Class C operator instructions or procedures.</text>
    <text>Class C operator and owner contact information, including names and telephoneumbers and any emergency information, shall be conspicuously posted at unmannedacilities.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 6678 (August 21, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>