<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-5812</num>
  <heading>PROHIBITED ACTIONS (§ 14-5812)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5812.1.</num>
    <text>A participant in the HCVP shall not knowingly:</text>
    <text>Make a false statement, either oral or written, to DCHA;</text>
    <text>Commit fraud, bribery, or any other corrupt or criminal act in connection with any federal housing program;</text>
    <text>Make payments to the Owner in excess of amounts authorized by DCHA for rent, security deposit, and additional services;</text>
    <text>Offer bribes or illegal gratuities to DCHA Board of Commissioners, employees, contractors, or other DCHA representatives;</text>
    <text>Offer payments or other incentives to the Owner or a third party as an inducement for the third party to make false or misleading statements to DCHA on the Family’s behalf;</text>
    <text>Use a false name or the use of falsified, forged, or altered documents;</text>
    <text>Misreport Family information or circumstances (such as income, Family composition);</text>
    <text>Omit facts that were obviously known by a Family member (such as, not reporting employment income); or</text>
    <text>Permit program abuse by an adult Family member.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5812.2.</num>
    <text>In the case of program abuse caused by a Family member DCHA may, at its discretion, impose any of the following remedies:</text>
    <text>Require the Family to repay excess subsidy amounts paid by DCHA, as described earlier in this section;</text>
    <text>Require, as a condition of receiving or continuing assistance, that a culpable Family member not reside in the unit;</text>
    <text>Deny or terminate the Family’s assistance;</text>
    <text>Refer the Family for state or federal criminal prosecution; or</text>
    <text>Require participation in the Good Neighbor Program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5812.3.</num>
    <text>An Owner participating in the HCV program shall not knowingly:</text>
    <text>Make any false statement to DCHA; or</text>
    <text>Commit fraud, bribery, or any other corrupt or criminal act in connection with any federal housing program including:</text>
    <text>Charging the Family rent above or below the amount specified by DCHA;</text>
    <text>Charging a security deposit other than that specified in the Family’s lease or greater than one (1) month’s rent;</text>
    <text>Charging the Family for services that are provided to unassisted tenants at no extra charge;</text>
    <text>Knowingly accepting housing assistance payments for any month(s) after the Family has vacated the unit or the sole-Family member is deceased;</text>
    <text>Knowingly accepting incorrect or excess housing assistance payments;</text>
    <text>Offering bribes or illegal gratuities to DCHA Board of Commissioners, employees, contractors, or other DCHA representatives;</text>
    <text>Offering payments or other incentives to an HCV Family as an inducement for the Family to make false or misleading statements to DCHA; or</text>
    <text>Residing in the unit with an assisted Family.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5812.4.</num>
    <text>When DCHA determines that the Owner has committed program abuse, DCHA may take any of the following actions:</text>
    <text>Require the Owner to repay excess housing assistance payments, as discussed earlier in this section and in accordance with the policies in the administrative plan and DCMR;</text>
    <text>Terminate the HAP contract;</text>
    <text>Bar the Owner from future participation in any DCHA programs; or</text>
    <text>Refer the case to state or federal officials for criminal prosecution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 7942, 7953 (June 29, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>