<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-1301</num>
  <heading>NOTICE OF PROPOSED SOLICITATIONS (§ 27-1301)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1301.1.</num>
    <text>An agency shall give public notice of a solicitation in accordance with §§ 402 and 403 of the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Reform Act of 2010, effective April 8, 2011 (D.C. Law 18-371; D.C. Official Code §§ 2-354.02 and 2-354.03) (2011
      Repl.)) (Act).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1301.2.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § 1301.5 of this chapter, the contracting officer shall publish each proposed solicitation over one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000) and up to two hundred fifty thousand dollars ($250,000) on OCP’s Internet site, and may publish
      the solicitation using any other methods reasonably available, such as newspapers or trade publications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1301.3.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § 1301.5 of this chapter, the contracting officer shall publish each proposed solicitation over two hundred fifty thousand dollars ($250,000) on the OCP Internet site and in a newspaper of general circulation and in trade publications
      considered by the Director to be appropriate to give adequate public notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1301.4.</num>
    <text>A contracting officer may place additional advertisements of solicitations when it is in the best interest of the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1301.5.</num>
    <text>The requirements for advertisement of solicitations set forth in this section shall not apply to the following:</text>
    <text>Emergency procurements;</text>
    <text>Small purchases;</text>
    <text>Procurement of architect-engineering services;</text>
    <text>Procurement of medical and human care services; and</text>
    <text>Procurements exempt from competition under § 413 of the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1419 (February 26, 1988) ); as amended by Emergency Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 4703 (June 2, 2000) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9887 (December 15, 2000); as amended by Final
        Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 5874(July 21, 2006); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 1375 (February 12, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergency Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 4008 (May 7,
        2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergency Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 8253 (September 10, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergency Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 558 (January 21, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergency
        and Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 4665 (May 27, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 8383 (September 30, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58
        DCR 9514 (November 11, 2011); as corrected by Errata Notice published at 58 DCR 9830 (November 18, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>