<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-1605</num>
  <heading>FILING AN OBJECTION (§ 19-1605)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1605.1</num>
    <text>1605.1 The affected Advisory Neighborhood Commission or any resident or ownerf property within six hundred (600) feet of the boundary lines of the lot onhich the public hall is situated may file an objection to the issuance of a newr a renewal license.
      If an objection is filed, the Director shall hold aearing to make the determinations required by D.C. Official Code §7-2820(b-1)(2).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1605.2</num>
    <text>1605.2 An objection shall be in writing and must be filed with theepartment’s Business and Professional Licensing Administration at least five5) calendar days prior to the date of the hearing. The objection shall list theame and address of the person
      making the objection and shall describe theeasons for the objection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1605.3</num>
    <text>1605.3 When a party retains counsel, the attorney so retained shall include hisr her name, address, phone number, and D.C. Bar number on the first documentiled by that party after retaining counsel. If the party retains counsel afteriling a document
      and the party does not file additional documents, the attorneyetained shall promptly file with the Department a notice of appearanceontaining the attorney’s name, address, phone number, and D.C. Bar number.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1605.4</num>
    <text>1605.4 When a party is proceeding without representation by counsel, the partyhall include his or her name, address, and phone number on any document filedith the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 9292, 9294-95 (December 11, 1992);s amended by Notice of emergency and proposed rulemaking at 52 DCR531(September 16, 2005) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at7 DCR 521, 524 (January 8, 2010).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR&amp;#8217;S NOTE</heading>
      <text>Section 1605 published at 39 DCR 9292 (December 11, 1992)as renumbered as section 1603 by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 521January 8, 2010). Section 1608 published at 39 DCR 9292 (December 11, 1992)as renumbered as section 1605 by Final Rulemaking
        published at 57 DCR 521January 8, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>