<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-1632</num>
  <heading>EFFORTS TO LOCATE PARENT (§ 29-1632)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1632.1.</num>
    <text>If one or both birth parents cannot be located, the child-placing agency responsible for preparing the investigative report and recommendations for a proposed adoption shall make efforts to locate the missing natural parent. The efforts shall be documented
      in the record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1632.2.</num>
    <text>The child-placing agency shall document that the following resources have been used in the efforts to locate the missing parent(s) and the results of their use:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Vital Statistics Branch of the Office of Policy and Planning of the Department of Human Services for birth, marriage and death records;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>DHS Child Support Locator;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Military Locator;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Court criminal records;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Metropolitan area telephone books;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Metropolitan area hospital records (if they can be released);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Public assistance, Medicaid, motor vehicle, and police records (if they can be released); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Family and friends of both birth parents (if appropriate).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1632.3.</num>
    <text>If a birth parent does not name the other birth parent, the child-placing agency or petitioner shall make a good faith effort to obtain the information from the known parent. If the name of the unknown parent is not given, and an affidavit is required
      by the court, the child-placing agency shall file an affidavit outlining the known parent’s reason for refusing to give the information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1632.4.</num>
    <text>If the birth mother names two or more possible fathers, the child-placing agency shall attempt to locate all of the alleged fathers. Paternity may be judicially determined.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 3033, 3058 (May 11, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>