<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-1100</num>
  <heading>TEMPORARY STREET CLOSINGS (§ 19-1100)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1100.1.</num>
    <text>The temporary use of streets by private persons and organizations for activities of a recreational, educational, civic, or charitable nature may be authorized by the Secretary of the District of Columbia, subject to the conditions set forth in this
      section and the application procedures set forth in § 1101.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.2.</num>
    <text>Activities shall be sponsored (or co-sponsored, in the case of an organization) by either of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Three (3) adult residents of the District, twenty-one (21) years of age or older, residing in premises abutting the street for which temporary use is requested; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An organization that has headquarters, offices, or a meeting place in the District and has been in existence for more than sixty (60) days.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.3.</num>
    <text>The three (3) adult sponsors, or co-sponsors, as provided in § 1100.2, must be present to supervise the activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.4.</num>
    <text>The sponsors or co-sponsors shall provide at least one (1) additional monitor for each twenty-five (25) persons in excess of seventy-five (75) persons attending the activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.5.</num>
    <text>The co-sponsors and monitors shall be identified by the use of armbands or other appropriate means, to be supplied by the Secretary to the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.6.</num>
    <text>The hours during which the activities are to be held shall be set forth on the application and, if approved, upon the letter of authority; but in no event shall the activities be conducted later than 10:00 p.m.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.7.</num>
    <text>The area must be left in the same condition as it was prior to the activity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.8.</num>
    <text>Sponsors shall be responsible for the removal of all litter within a period of twelve (12) hours after the conclusion of the activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.9.</num>
    <text>Refuse containers shall be provided for sanitation purposes by the Department of Environmental Services. Refuse containers shall be picked up by that Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.10.</num>
    <text>Loud speakers or other means of amplification may be authorized when requested in the application. The instruments shall be adjusted to accommodate only those people in the area of the activities, and so as not to disturb persons outside the confines
      of the block.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.11.</num>
    <text>No fee, collection, or donations shall be solicited or accepted at activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.12.</num>
    <text>The selling of pamphlets, food, beverages, or other articles is prohibited, except in compliance with the laws and regulations applicable to the solicitations or sales.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.13.</num>
    <text>The sponsors, co-sponsors, and monitors shall comply with any instructions from members of the Metropolitan Police Department or other District officials relating to the preservation of good order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.14.</num>
    <text>The sponsors shall agree to indemnify and hold harmless, the District of Columbia, and its officers and employees in the event of injury to any person or damage to property arising out of the use of the street.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.15.</num>
    <text>The area to be used for the activities shall not exceed that part of a street located between two (2) intersecting streets.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.16.</num>
    <text>If any one (1) of the following agencies objects to the use of the street, action on the application shall be decided by the Mayor:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>D.C. Department of Transportation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>D.C. Fire Department;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Metropolitan Police Department; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Commission.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.17.</num>
    <text>Activities shall not be permitted within two (2) blocks of any zone of quiet established under District noise control regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.18.</num>
    <text>Upon approval of the application, the District Secretary shall prepare a letter of authorization which shall be obtained by the applicant at the appropriate police precinct.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.19.</num>
    <text>The letter of authorization provided in § 1100.18 shall be kept available at the scene of the activities, and shall be exhibited upon request to any member of the Metropolitan Police Department or other District officials.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.20.</num>
    <text>Any person who knowingly and willfully falsifies the signatures required by § 1101, furnishes false signatures, sponsors or conducts an activity on public space without authorization, or in any way violates any other provisions of this section or
      § 1101, shall, upon conviction, be punished by fine of not more than three hundred dollars ($ 300) or imprisoned for not more than ten (10) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 38 DCR 4096 (July 5, 1991).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is D.C. Code, Section 8-127 and 8-137 (1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>