<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-1104</num>
  <heading>SLEEPING ACCOMMODATIONS (§ 14-1104)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1104.1.</num>
    <text>No sleeping facilities shall be permitted in any room which is a part of any room where food is prepared, served or stored, or in which utensils are washed or stored.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1104.2.</num>
    <text>No room shall be used for sleeping purposes unless the clear height over the required floor area is at least the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Eight feet (8&amp;#8242;) in buildings erected after July 10, 1942; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Seven feet (7&amp;#8242;) in buildings erected before July 10, 1942.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1104.3.</num>
    <text>Sleeping accommodations shall be determined by consideration of one (1) person for each single or three-quarters bed, and two (2) persons for each double bed present.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1104.4.</num>
    <text>The inspector shall accept the affidavit of an owner, lessee, proprietor, or manager to establish the actual number of persons occupying beds if it is claimed that double beds are of single occupancy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1104.5.</num>
    <text>All bedding shall be kept in a clean and sanitary condition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1104.6.</num>
    <text>A clean pillow slip, a clean sheet, and two (2) clean bath towels shall be provided at least once a week for each regular roomer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1104.7.</num>
    <text>Each new roomer shall be provided with a complete change of linens and towels.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1104.8.</num>
    <text>The requirements of subsections 1104.5, 1104.6, and 1104.7 shall not apply if the roomer agrees in writing to furnish his or her own linens and towels.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>The Housing Regulations of the District of Columbia, 5G DCRR §§ 4108 and 4109, Commissioners’ Order 55-1503 (August 11, 1955).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>