<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-1109</num>
  <heading>FOOD PREPARATION AND DISHWASHING FACILITIES (§ 14-1109)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1109.1.</num>
    <text>The rooms in which food is prepared shall be of adequate size and construction to permit easy cleaning and the unhampered performance of kitchen operations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1109.2.</num>
    <text>Running hot and cold water supply shall be easily accessible to all rooms in which food is prepared or utensils are washed, and shall be adequate and of a safe, sanitary quality.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1109.3.</num>
    <text>All eating and cooking utensils, and all windows, counters, shelves, tables, refrigerating equipment, sinks, and other equipment shall be kept clean and in a sanitary condition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1109.4.</num>
    <text>All cloths used by waiters, chefs and other employees shall be clean.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1109.5.</num>
    <text>Single-service containers shall be used only once.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1109.6.</num>
    <text>All except single-service eating and drinking utensils shall be thoroughly cleansed and sterilized and shall, at the time of service to the public, be thoroughly clean and sterilized.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1109.7.</num>
    <text>All multi-use containers and utensils used in the preparation, cooking or serving of food and drink shall be thoroughly cleansed and sterilized immediately following the day’s operations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1109.8.</num>
    <text>All boarding houses where dishwashing is done by other than mechanical means, shall be provided with facilities to ensure sterilization of all common eating and drinking utensils and thorough cleansing of all cooking utensils.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1109.9.</num>
    <text>Mechanical dishwashing machines used for sterilizing purposes shall be equipped to provide a minimum temperature of at least one hundred eighty degrees Fahrenheit (180º F.) when in use for sterilizing purposes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>The Housing Regulations of the District of Columbia, 5G DCRR §§ 4207-4209, Commissioners’ Order 55-1503 (August 11, 1955).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>