<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-5802</num>
  <heading>ACTIVITY REPORTS (§ 3-5802)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5802.1.</num>
    <text>Each registrant shall file an activity report, on a form prescribed by the Director, for each person from whom compensation is received during the reporting period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5802.2.</num>
    <text>Each activity report shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A complete and current statement of the information required to be supplied pursuant to § 5800;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Total expenditures on lobbying broken down into the following categories:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Office expenses;</text>
    </level>
    <text>(ii) Advertising and publications;</text>
    <text>(iii) Compensation to others;</text>
    <text>(iv) Personal sustenance, lodging, and travel, if compensated; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(v)</num>
      <text>Other expenses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Each expenditure of $50 or more shall also be itemized by the date, name, and address of the recipient, and the amount and purpose of the expenditure;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Each political expenditure, loan, gift, honorarium, or contribution of $50 or more made by the registrant or anyone acting on behalf of the registrant to benefit an official in the legislative or executive branch, a member of his or her staff or
        household, or a campaign or testimonial committee established for the benefit of the official, shall be itemized by date, beneficiary, amount, and circumstances of the transaction, including the aggregate of all expenditures that are less than
        $50;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Each official in the executive or legislative branch and any member of the official’s staff, including personal and committee staff, who has a business relationship or a professional services relationship with the registrant shall be identified
        by name and the nature of the business relationship with the registrant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Each official in the executive or legislative branch with whom the registrant has had written or oral communications during the reporting periods related to lobbying activities conducted by the registrant shall also be included in the report, identifying
        the official with whom the communication was made; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Each person to whom the registrant has given compensation to lobby on his or her behalf shall also be listed in the report.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5802.3.</num>
    <text>Each registrant shall obtain and preserve all accounts, bills, receipts, books, papers, and documents necessary to substantiate the activity reports required to be made pursuant to this section for 5 years from the date of filing of the report containing
      these items. These materials shall be made available for inspection upon requests by the Director after reasonable notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5802.4.</num>
    <text>Each registrant who does not file a report required by this section for a given period is presumed not to be receiving or expending funds that are required to be reported under this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5802.5.</num>
    <text>A registrant shall exclude from activity reports any transactions related to the registrant’s exempt status, if any, under § 5801.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5802.6.</num>
    <text>No later than 10 days after a registrant files a registration form with the Director he or she shall publish on the Board’s website a summary of all information required to be submitted under this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 2852 (March 8, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>