<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6199</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 17-6199)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6199.1.</num>
    <text>As used in this chapter, the following terms have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Administer &amp;#8211; (a) The direct application of medication to the human body whether by ingestion, inhalation, insertion, sublingual, or topical means; or (b) An injection of epipen or equivalent injection system for emergency purposes only.</text>
    <text>Applicant &amp;#8211; A person applying for certification as a trained medication employee under this chapter.</text>
    <text>Board &amp;#8211; The Board of Nursing as established by section 204 of the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Code § 2-3302.4).</text>
    <text>Client or Consumer &amp;#8211; A program participant who is the recipient of nursing care.</text>
    <text>Direct supervision &amp;#8211; supervision in which the supervising nurse is available to the trained medication employee on the premises and within vocal communication either directly or by a communication device.</text>
    <text>General supervision &amp;#8211; supervision in which the supervising nurse is available to the trained medication employee for consultation either in person or by a communication device, but need not be physically present on the premises at the time
      the actions are performed.</text>
    <text>Licensed practitioner &amp;#8211; An individual licensed in the District of Columbia pursuant to the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Code § 2-3301.1 et seq.).</text>
    <text>MAR &amp;#8211; Medication Administration Record.</text>
    <text>Medication &amp;#8211; a controlled (excluding Classes I and II) or non-controlled substance or treatment regarded as effective in bringing about recovery, restoration of health, alleviation of pain or symptoms of an illness, or the normal functioning
      of the body.</text>
    <text>Medication Administration Course &amp;#8211; The assembled curriculum encompassing all phases of medication administration authorized under D.C. Code §§ 21-1201 through 21-1204, for the instruction of applicants seeking certification as trained medication
      employees.</text>
    <text>Practicum &amp;#8211; A demonstration by a trainee of the correct procedures to administer medications, including the preparation, physical administration, recordation and documentation of the medication process. The practicum shall also include a
      demonstration of knowledge of a program participant&amp;#8217;s rights, universal precautions, vital signs, and aseptic technique.</text>
    <text>Program &amp;#8211; An agency licensed, certified, or approved by the District government as a child care facility, private school, day program, community based residence, or other agency providing residential services, education, habilitation, vocational,
      or employment training services to individuals with mental retardation or other developmental disability.</text>
    <text>Program participant &amp;#8211; An individual with mental retardation or other developmental disability who is enrolled in or attending a public or private program.</text>
    <text>Supervisory registered nurse &amp;#8211; A District of Columbia licensed registered nurse that provides general supervision and review of a trained medication employee administering medications.</text>
    <text>Trained medication employee &amp;#8211; an individual employed to work in a program who has successfully completed a training program approved by the Board and is certified to administer medication to program participants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 2581 (March 23, 2001); as amended by Emergency Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 3071 (April 18, 2003) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 6464 (August 8, 2003) [EXPIRED];
        as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 9242 (October 31, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>