<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6106</num>
  <heading>CERTIFICATION OF TRAINED MEDICATION EMPLOYEES (ยง 17-6106)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6106.1.</num>
    <text>Upon successful completion of a Trained Medication Employee Course approved by the Board, a trained medication employee applicant shall submit:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Documentation signed by the Medication Administration Trainer verifying satisfactory completion of the Trained Medication Employee Course;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Proof of a least one (1) year of clinical experience in a program or a health care facility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Proof of satisfactory current completion of cardio-pulmonary (CPR) training and a First Aid program; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A completed application and required fee.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant may request a waiver from participation in the Medication Administration Course if the applicant has successfully completed a substantially equivalent course in another jurisdiction. Program employees that have successfully completed
      a Medication Administration Course approved by the State of Maryland or the Commonwealth of Virginia need not participate in the Medication Administration Course.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant requesting a waiver from participation in the Medication Administration Course shall submit to the Board:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Proof of current certification in the administration of medication in Maryland or Virginia or any other jurisdiction approved by the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Proof of at least one (1) year of clinical experience in a program or a health care facility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Proof of satisfactory current completion of a cardio-pulmonary (CPR) training and First Aid program; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A completed application and required fee.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.4.</num>
    <text>The Board shall issue to qualified applicants a certification as a trained medication employee authorized to administer medication to program participants in a program licensed, certified or approved by the District of Columbia government as defined
      in D.C. Official Code ยง 21-1201(10).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.5.</num>
    <text>The Board shall maintain a registry of certified trained medication employees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.6.</num>
    <text>If, after certification, the supervisory registered nurse or licensed practitioner observes serious or multiple deficiencies or errors, he or she shall report the deficiencies to the Board in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.7.</num>
    <text>If a licensed nurse or licensed practitioner observe serious or multiple deficiencies or errors that have jeopardized the health or welfare of any program participant which include, but are not limited to, errors involving medication administration,
      dosage documentation and storage of medications, the licensed nurse or licensed practitioner shall report the deficiencies to the Board and the employing program shall prohibit the trained medication employee from administering medication until
      the Board has taken action on the notice of deficiency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.8.</num>
    <text>REPEALED.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.9.</num>
    <text>REPEALED.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.10.</num>
    <text>REPEALED.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.11.</num>
    <text>If, after certification, the supervisory registered nurse or licensed practitioner observes serious or multiple deficiencies or errors that have not jeopardized the health or welfare of any program participant, he or she shall report the deficiencies
      to the Board in writing within twenty-four (24) hours.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.12.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of written notification alleging medication errors or deficiencies by the trained medication employee, the Board shall notify the employee of the receipt of the allegations and shall request that the employee respond in writing to the
      allegations within three (3) business days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.13.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt and consideration of the allegations, any response from the trained medication employee, and other evidence the Board deems appropriate, the Board shall determine whether the employee was deficient. If the employee is found to have been
      deficient, the employee shall be required to repeat and successfully complete the Medication Administration Course.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.14</num>
    <text>6106.14 &amp;#8211; 6106.19 REPEALED.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 2581 (March 23, 2001); as amended by Emergency Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 3071 (April 18, 2003) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 6464 (August 8, 2003) [EXPIRED];
        as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 9242 (October 31, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>