<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-500</num>
  <heading>PURPOSE (ยง 4-500)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>500.1.</num>
    <text>In order to meet the obligations set forth in the Human Rights Act of 1977, effective December 13, 1977 (D.C. Law 2-38; D.C. Official Code ยง 2-1401.01 et seq.) (Act), the District of Columbia Office of Human Rights (Office) and the District of Columbia
      Commission on Human Rights (Commission) have adopted this chapter for the following purposes:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>To resolve a number of issues which have been or may be raised before them;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>To provide advice to interested parties as to how they intend to interpret the law in cases which arise before them; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>To assist in the internal processing of cases through Office and Commission procedures with respect to discrimination against any individual in employment because of race, color, religion, national origin, sex, age, marital status, personal appearance,
        sexual orientation, gender identity or expression, family responsibilities, genetic information, disability, matriculation, or political affiliation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>500.2.</num>
    <text>In general, the Office and the Commission adopt and incorporate by reference current regulations of the federal Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC) and shall follow general principles of Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (42 U.S.C.
      ยง 2000e et seq.) wherever applicable in interpreting the Act, unless specific regulations in this chapter state the contrary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>500.3.</num>
    <text>Each employer shall provide an employment atmosphere free from discrimination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 006029 (July 31, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>