<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-511</num>
  <heading>MATRICULATION GUIDELINES (§ 4-511)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>511.1.</num>
    <text>An employer shall not use different pay scales for students performing the same work duties as other employees with the same experience, skills, work schedule, hours, and the like, unless those differences are made pursuant to either of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A federal government or District government approved summer job program; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>“Student certificate” programs issued by the U.S. Department of Labor under the Fair Labor Standards Act (29 U.S.C. § 201 et seq.).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>511.2.</num>
    <text>An employer shall not set aside specific job classifications for students in order to give low compensation to all persons in such job classification; provided, that an employer shall not be prohibited from creating jobs for the purpose of providing
      financial assistance to students. For example, a school may provide research or teaching assistantships to students while compensating researchers or instructors, hired solely for the purpose of their contribution to the school, at a higher scale.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>511.3.</num>
    <text>An employer shall not refuse to hire or discharge a person because he or she is a part-time student if the matriculation status does not interfere with that person’s ability to efficiently and effectively perform the duties of the job. An employer
      shall not assume that an applicant will be unable to work full-time and be a matriculant in a school or college.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>511.4.</num>
    <text>An employer shall grant reasonable periods of leave to an employee for the purpose of registration in a school or college when reasonable accommodation can be made.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 006029 (July 31, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>