<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-1100</num>
  <heading>PROHIBITED STATEMENTS (ยง 23-1100)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1100.1.</num>
    <text>The use of any picture or illustration depicting a child or immature person, or objects (such as toys), suggestive of the presence of a child, and any statement, design, device, picture, or illustration designed to be especially appealing to children
      or immature persons, which promotes the sale, service, or consumption of alcoholic beverages shall be prohibited.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.2.</num>
    <text>Any statement, picture, or illustration referring to Easter, Holy Week, Mother&amp;#8217;s Day, &amp;#8220;Santa Claus,&amp;#8221; including names synonymous with &amp;#8220;Santa Claus&amp;#8221;, or a religious holiday or religious symbol, which
      promotes the sale, service, or consumption of alcoholic beverages shall be prohibited. Nothing in this section shall prohibit references to Christmas or any other holiday season if the references do not include statements, pictures, or illustrations
      on strictly religious themes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.3.</num>
    <text>The words &amp;#8220;Wholesale,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Wholesale Department&amp;#8221; (except to the extent required by federal law), or any other word or words intended to mislead or deceive the general public into believing that the advertiser is
      authorized or licensed to sell alcoholic beverages as a wholesaler under the provisions of the Act shall be prohibited.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.4.</num>
    <text>A statement that is known by the retailer to be false or misleading with respect to advertised price charged to the consumer, ingredients of alcoholic beverages, source of manufacturer, or statements as to health benefits, shall be prohibited.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>D.C. Code ยง 25-351</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>