<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-8707</num>
  <heading>APPLICANTS EDUCATED IN FOREIGN COUNTRIES (§ 17-8707)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8707.1.</num>
    <text>The Board shall waive the educational requirements of § 8702 for an applicant for certification to practice as an addiction counselor I or II to anyone who has completed an educational program in a college or university in a foreign country which
      is not accredited in accordance with § 8702, if the applicant demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Board that the applicant’s education and training are substantially equivalent to the requirements of this chapter and the Act in ensuring that
      the applicant is qualified to practice as an addiction counselor I or II, by submitting documentation required by § 8707.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8707.2</num>
    <text>8707.2 An applicant under this section shall, in lieu of meeting the requirements</text>
    <text>of §§ 8702.1 or 8702.2, submit one of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Proof satisfactory to the Board that the applicant has received an</text>
    </level>
    <text>Associate’s degree or higher to qualify for certification as an addiction counselor I, or Bachelor’s degree or higher to qualify for certification as an addiction counselor II, from a foreign institution which was accredited, at the time the degree
      was conferred, by the national government or an accrediting body recognized by the national government of the country in which the institution is located; or</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A certification from a private education evaluation service approved by the Board that the applicant’s foreign education is substantially equivalent to the education provided in an accredited program.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8707.3</num>
    <text>8707.3 The Board may interview an applicant under this section to determine</text>
    <text>whether the applicant’s education or training meets the requirements of the Act and this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8707.4</num>
    <text>8707.4 If a document required by this chapter is in a language other than English,</text>
    <text>an applicant shall arrange for its translation into English by a translation</text>
    <text>service acceptable to the Board and shall submit a translation signed by the translator attesting to its accuracy.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11937, 11943 (December 17, 2010).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>