<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-8708</num>
  <heading>CONTINUING EDUCATION REQUIREMENTS (§ 17-8708)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8708.1.</num>
    <text>This section shall apply to applicants for the renewal, reactivation, or reinstatement of a certification expiring on December 31, 2014, or later; except, that this section shall not apply to applicants for first time renewal of a certification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8708.2</num>
    <text>8708.2 To qualify for a certification, an applicant for renewal of a certification shall submit proof of having completed forty (40) hours of approved continuing education credit during the two-year (2) period preceding the date the certification
      expires.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8708.3</num>
    <text>8708.3 At least six (6) of the forty (40) hours of continuing education credits required by § 8708.2 shall be in ethics and at least three (3) of the forty (40) hours shall be in trauma counseling. A maximum of six (6) of the remaining thirty one
      (31) hours may be taken online.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8708.4.</num>
    <text>The ethics and trauma counseling continuing education credits required by § 8708.3 shall be earned in a face-to-face classroom setting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8708.5</num>
    <text>8708.5 A person in inactive status within the meaning of § 511 of the Act, D.C. Official Code § 3-1205.11, who submits an application to reactivate his or her certification shall submit proof of having completed twenty (20) hours of approved continuing
      education credits within the year preceding the application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8708.6</num>
    <text>8708.6 A person seeking reinstatement of his or her certification shall submit proof of having completed twenty (20) hours of approved continuing education credits for each full year after December 31, 2000, that the applicant was not certified. A
      minimum of six (6) of the twenty (20) hours shall be in ethics.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8708.7</num>
    <text>8708.7 A continuing education credit required by this section shall be valid only if it is part of a program or activity approved by the Board in accordance with § 8709.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8708.8</num>
    <text>8708.8 An applicant under this section shall prove completion of required continuing education credits by submitting with the application the following information with respect to each program:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the sponsor of the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name of the program, its location, a description of the subject</text>
    </level>
    <text>matter covered, and the names of the instructors;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The dates on which the applicant attended the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The hours of credit claimed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Verification by the sponsor of completion, by signature or stamp.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8708.9.</num>
    <text>In addition to the requirements of § 8708.8, an applicant shall prove completion of continuing education course work, if taken at a college or university, by submitting with the transcript or certificate of completion, a signed statement from the
      instructor on college university stationery for each class attended.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8708.10</num>
    <text>8708.10 An applicant for renewal of a certification who fails to submit proof of having completed continuing education requirements by the date the registration expires may renew the certification up to sixty (60) days after expiration by submitting
      proof and paying the required additional late fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8708.11</num>
    <text>8708.11 Upon submitting proof and paying the late fee, the applicant shall be deemed to have possessed a valid certification during the period between the expiration of the certification and the submission of the required documentation and payment
      of the late fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8708.12</num>
    <text>8708.12 If an applicant for renewal of a certification fails to submit proof of completion of continuing education requirements or pay the late fee within sixty (60) days after the expiration of the applicant’s certification, the certification shall
      be deemed to have lapsed on the date of expiration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8708.13</num>
    <text>8708.13 The Board may, in its discretion, grant an extension of the sixty (60) day period to renew after expiration if the applicant’s failure to submit proof of completion was for good cause.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8708.14</num>
    <text>8708.14 The Board may, in its discretion, audit the renewal applications to ensure that the continuing education requirement has been met. The applicant shall maintain a copy of the continuing education certificate(s) for at least four (4) years.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11937, 11944 (December 17, 2010).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>