<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-8705</num>
  <heading>DISTRICT JURISPRUDENCE EXAMINATION (§ 17-8705)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8705.1.</num>
    <text>An individual who submits an initial application to qualify for certification under this chapter as an addiction counselor I or addiction counselor II, shall receive a passing score on an examination developed by the Board on laws, rules, and ethical
      standards pertaining to the practice of addiction counseling (the District jurisprudence examination).</text>
    <text>In addition to applicants identified in § 8704.1, the following applicants shall take and pass the District examination prior to issuance of a license if the examination has not been previously been taken:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An applicant who is seeking renewal of a certification;</text>
    </level>
    <text>An applicant who is seeking re-activation of an inactive certification;</text>
    <text>An applicant who is seeking reinstatement of a certification; and</text>
    <text>An applicant who is seeking certification by waiver of educational</text>
    <text>requirements pursuant to §§ 8706.1 or 8706.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8705.3.</num>
    <text>The Board shall administer the District jurisprudence examination at least</text>
    <text>three (3) times a year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8705.4.</num>
    <text>If an applicant fails the District jurisprudence examination three (3) times, the applicant shall not be eligible to take the examination again until he or she has taken a Board-approved refresher course.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8705.5.</num>
    <text>The District examination may consist of questions on the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The District of Columbia statutes and rules concerning the practice of addiction counseling; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Code of Ethics of the NAADAC.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11937, 11942 (December 17, 2010).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>