<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-3108</num>
  <heading>VARIANCES (ยง 20-3108)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3108.1.</num>
    <text>Requests for a variance from the requirements of this Chapter may be granted upon a written request to DCRA. Requests for a variance that may affect the base flood elevation as provided by ยง 3105.8 shall also be submitted to DDOE. Consideration shall
      be given, but shall not be limited to, the following factors:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That there is good and sufficient cause to grant the request;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That the full performance of the requirements of this chapter would result in undue hardship by reason of excessive structural or mechanical difficulty or impracticality of bringing the premises affected into full compliance with this Chapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Granting the variance would not result in an unacceptable or prohibited increase in flood heights, additional threats to public safety, extraordinary public expense, create nuisances, cause fraud on, or victimization of the public or conflict with
        any other applicable laws and regulations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3108.2.</num>
    <text>No variance shall be granted for any construction, development, use or activity within any floodway area that would cause any increase in the base flood elevation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3108.3.</num>
    <text>Except for a possible modification of the freeboard requirements involved, no variance shall be granted for any of the other requirements pertaining specifically to development which may endanger human life (ยง 3106.2).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3108.4.</num>
    <text>A variance shall involve only the least modification necessary to provide relief.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3108.5.</num>
    <text>In granting any variance, the Director of DCRA or his or her delegated representative shall attach reasonable conditions and safeguards considered necessary in order to protect the public health, safety, and welfare, and to achieve the objectives
      of D.C. Law 1-64 and this Chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3108.6.</num>
    <text>Whenever a variance is granted, the Director of DCRA or his or her delegated representative shall notify the applicant, in writing, of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The granting of the variance may result in increased premium rates of up to twenty-five dollars ($25.00) for every one hundred dollars ($100.00) for flood insurance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The variances may increase the risks to life and property.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3108.7.</num>
    <text>A complete record of all variance requests and related actions shall be maintained by the Director of DCRA or his or her delegated representative. In addition, a report of all variances granted during the year shall be included in the annual report
      to the Federal Insurance Administration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3108.8.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any provision of this section, however, all structures shall be designed and constructed so as to have the capability of resisting the base flood.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE Final Rulemaking published at 32 DCR 6547, 6560 (November 15, 1985):</heading>
      <text>as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 962, 963 (February 12, 1988); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 10779 (November 19, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>