<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-2315</num>
  <heading>SELECTION OF A CONTRACTOR (ยง 30-2315)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2315.1.</num>
    <text>The selection procedures set forth in this chapter shall be designed to accomplish the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Maximize competition;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Minimize the complexity of the solicitation, evaluation, and the selection decision;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Ensure impartial and comprehensive evaluation of offerors&amp;#8217; proposals; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Ensure selection of the offeror whose proposal has the highest degree of realism and whose performance is expected to best meet stated Agency requirements.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2315.2.</num>
    <text>Selection of a contractor through the use of the competitive sealed proposal (&amp;#8220;CSP&amp;#8221;) process shall be based on competition involving an evaluation and comparison of cost or price and other factors among proposals that meet the
      Agency&amp;#8217;s minimum requirements as stated in the solicitation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2315.3.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall be responsible for selection of a contractor from among the qualified offerors.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2315.4.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall be responsible for contractual actions related to the selection process, including, but not limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Issuing solicitations in accordance with the provisions of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Conducting or controlling all negotiations concerning cost or price, technical requirements, and other terms and conditions; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Selecting the contractor for contract award.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6681, 6748 (September 22, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>