<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-2313</num>
  <heading>EVALUATION OF UNSOLICITED PROPOSALS (ยง 30-2313)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2313.1.</num>
    <text>When performing an evaluation of an unsolicited proposal, the following factors shall be considered, in addition to any others appropriate for the particular proposal:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The unique and innovative methods, approaches, or concepts demonstrated by the proposal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The overall scientific, technical, or socio-economic merits of the proposal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The potential contribution of the effort to the specific mission of the Agency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The offeror&amp;#8217;s capabilities, related experience, facilities, techniques, or unique combinations of these which are integral factors for achieving the proposal objectives; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The qualifications, capabilities, and experience of the proposed team leader or key personnel who are critical to achieving the proposal objective.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2313.2.</num>
    <text>The Agency shall return an unsolicited proposal to an offeror, citing reasons, when its substance meets any of the following criteria:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>It is available to the Agency without restriction from another source;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>It closely resembles a pending competitive requirement; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>It does not demonstrate any innovative or unique method, approach, or concept.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6681, 6748 (September 22, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>