<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-2322</num>
  <heading>COMPETITIVE RANGE AND PRE-NEGOTIATION OBJECTIVES (ยง 30-2322)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2322.1.</num>
    <text>The competitive range shall be determined on the basis of cost or price and other factors, in accordance with the evaluation criteria that were stated in the solicitation, and shall include all proposals that have a reasonable chance of being selected
      for award.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2322.2.</num>
    <text>If there is doubt as to whether a proposal is in the competitive range, that proposal shall be included.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2322.3.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall notify, in writing, an unsuccessful offeror at the earliest practicable time that the offeror&amp;#8217;s proposal is no longer being considered for award.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2322.4.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall establish pre-negotiation objectives before the negotiation of any contract or modification in excess of one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000). When cost analysis is required under ยง 2326, the contracting officer shall
      address the pertinent issues to be negotiated, the cost objectives, and a profit or fee objective.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2322.5.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall develop pre-negotiation objectives to judge the overall reasonableness of proposed prices and to negotiate a fair and reasonable price or cost and fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2322.6.</num>
    <text>In determining the pre-negotiation objectives, the contracting officer shall analyze the offeror&amp;#8217;s proposal and consider technical analysis and other pertinent data, such as Agency cost estimates and price histories.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6681, 6752 (September 22, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>