<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-2302</num>
  <heading>PRESOLICITATION NOTICES AND CONFERENCES (ยง 30-2302)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2302.1.</num>
    <text>Presolicitation notices and conferences may be used as preliminary steps in procurements by competitive sealed proposals in order to accomplish any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Develop or identify interested prospective offerors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Request preliminary information based on a general description of the supplies or services involved;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Explain complicated specifications and requirements to interested prospective offerors; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Aid prospective offerors in later submitting proposals without undue expenditure of effort, time, and money.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2302.2.</num>
    <text>If presolicitation notices are used, the contracting officer shall prepare and issue each notice to prospective offerors and shall publicize the notice in a newspaper of general circulation and any trade publication deemed appropriate by the Director
      of Procurement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2302.3.</num>
    <text>A presolicitation notice shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A description of the information to be furnished in the response;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An indication whether the notice will be followed by a conference and a formal solicitation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A request that parties interested in the contemplated procurement respond by a specified date.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2302.4.</num>
    <text>In complex procurements, the presolicitation notice may request information pertaining to management, engineering, and production capabilities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2302.5.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall furnish copies of the solicitation to all those responding affirmatively to the presolicitation notice and to other prospective offerors upon request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2302.6.</num>
    <text>A presolicitation conference may be used only when approved by the contracting officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6681, 6741 (September 22, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>