<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-2320</num>
  <heading>PROPOSAL EVALUATION FACTORS (ยง 30-2320)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2320.1.</num>
    <text>The evaluation factors that will be considered in evaluating proposals shall be tailored to each procurement and shall include only those factors that will have an impact on the selection of a contractor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2320.2.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall include in the solicitation the evaluation factors, including price or cost and any significant subfactors. The solicitation shall include the minimum requirements that apply to each evaluation factor and significant
      subfactor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2320.3.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer may include in the solicitation the numerical weights which may be used in the evaluation of the proposals.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2320.4.</num>
    <text>Evaluation factors shall be stated in descending order of importance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2320.5.</num>
    <text>Price or cost to the Agency shall be included as an evaluation factor in each RFP.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2320.6.</num>
    <text>While the lowest price or lowest total cost to the Agency may be an important or even a deciding factor in many contractor selections, the contracting officer may select the contractor whose proposal offers the greatest value to the Agency in terms
      of technical merit and other factors, even though the proposal selected does not offer the lowest price or cost, if it is in the best interests of the Agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2320.7.</num>
    <text>When awarding a cost-reimbursement contract, the cost proposal shall not be controlling. The contracting officer shall consider which offeror can perform the contract in a manner most advantageous to the Agency, as determined by evaluation of proposals
      according to the established evaluation criteria.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6681, 6751 (September 22, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>