<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4413</num>
  <heading>TERMINATION AND SUSPENSION PROCEDURES (§ 29-4413)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4413.1.</num>
    <text>If a grantee has materially failed to comply with the terms of a grant agreement, the Grant Officer may, after giving reasonable written notice to the grantee, do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Suspend the grant in whole or in part;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Terminate the grant for cause; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Take any other remedial action that may be legally available.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4413.2.</num>
    <text>The notice of suspension shall state the reasons for the suspension, any corrective action required of the grantee, and the effective date.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4413.3.</num>
    <text>The suspension may be made effective at once if a delayed effective date would be unreasonable considering the Grant Officer’s responsibilities to protect the District government’s interest.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4413.4.</num>
    <text>The Grant Officer may reinstate a suspended grant if the grantee has taken corrective action satisfactory to the Grant Officer, or given satisfactory evidence that corrective action will be taken.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4413.5.</num>
    <text>The Grant Officer may terminate the grant before the date of expiration if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The grantee has materially failed to comply with the terms of the grant agreement and appropriate corrective actions have not been taken during the period of suspension; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The failure to comply with the terms of the grant agreement is so serious that immediate termination is in the best interest of the District government.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4413.6.</num>
    <text>The notice of termination shall state, in writing, the reasons for the termination, together with the effective date.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4413.7.</num>
    <text>A grant may be terminated at the request of the grantee upon notification to, the Grant Officer, in accordance with the provisions of the grant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 6246, 6255 (August 27, 1993).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>