<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-2022</num>
  <heading>SEPARATION OF RECYCLABLE MATERIAL AT COMMERCIAL PROPERTIES (ยง 21-2022)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2022.1.</num>
    <text>Each owner and each occupant of a commercial property shall, at a minimum, separate for recycling paper, paperboard, cardboard, and clean and rinsed metal, glass and plastic containers. The materials that are separated for recycling shall be stored
      in bins, dumpsters, or other containers that are not used for the simultaneous storage of solid waste and recyclable materials. The owner may provide through a lease agreement for an occupant to be responsible for separating these materials for
      recycling in which case the occupant shall also be responsible for meeting the requirements of this subsection. Notwithstanding the existence of such a lease agreement, the owner is responsible for complying with this regulation except where the
      Director determines that there are circumstances that warrant holding the occupant liable for compliance. The Director may issue a notice of violation to the occupant or to the owner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2022.2.</num>
    <text>REPEALED</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2022.3.</num>
    <text>Recyclable material shall be collected at least twice per month unless fewer collections have been previously approved in writing by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2022.4.</num>
    <text>A sufficient number of containers shall be provided to store such recyclables which may accumulate on the premises during the intervals between collections.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2022.5.</num>
    <text>All containers for recyclables shall be kept clean and in good repair.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 7470, 7478 (October 2, 1992); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11962, 11965 (December 17, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>