<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-9304</num>
  <heading>PROGRAM APPLICATION AND AWARD (ยง 14-9304)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>9304.1.</num>
    <text>The Partnership Program seeks to be as flexible as possible in order to protect and increase the supply of affordable housing.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>DCHA may award Housing Assistance Payment (HAP) Contracts periodically on a competitive basis under the Partnership Program through published announcements.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>DCHA will advertise for two or more times, at least one week apart, in a newspaper of general circulation for that DCHA will accept applications for assistance.</text>
    </level>
    <text>(ii) The deadline for applications shall be at least 30 days after the date of the last publication.</text>
    <text>(iii) The advertisement shall identify the estimated number of units that will be assisted.</text>
    <text>(iv) The advertisement will not state that applications will only be considered if submitted in response to the advertisement, as DCHA may also receive and consider from time to time applications for allocations of Partnership Program funding assistance
      under Sections 9304.2 and 9304.3 hereof on a non-competitive basis.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>In addition to applications in response to advertisements, DCHA may also request owners with properties in eligible areas of the District of Columbia to respond to the advertised announcement and submit an application for the Partnership Program
        subsidy for their property.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The advertisement shall identify the estimated number of units that will be assisted.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The advertisement will not state that applications will only be considered if submitted in response to the advertisement, as DCHA may also receive and consider from time to time applications for allocations of Partnership Program funding assistance
        under Sections 9304.3 and 9404.4 hereof on a non-competitive basis.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9304.2.</num>
    <text>If no advertised announcement is outstanding, an Owner of an eligible property may submit an application to DCHA. If the application meets the threshold criteria listed in Section 9307 of this Title, it may be eligible for an Agreement to enter into
      a Housing Assistance Payment (AHAP) contract. Such an application will be reviewed and considered either upon receipt or under Section 9304.3 below or held for competitive consideration along with any applications received in response to an advertised
      announcement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9304.3.</num>
    <text>DCHA may proceed, after review by the Board of Commissioners, to award a Housing Assistance Payment (HAP) contract without using a competitive process for an eligible property that is:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An existing or new property under a revitalization or development plan initiative of DCHA or a DCHA development subsidiary;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Losing an operating subsidy formerly provided from another source that is no longer available which would result in displacement of eligible low income households; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>In need of a rental subsidy in order to retain the housing as a resource for current and future eligible low income households.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9304.4.</num>
    <text>DCHA may, in its sole discretion award a Housing Assistance Payment (AHAP) contract to the Owner of an eligible property who is developing an existing or new property under a revitalization or development plan initiative of DCHA or DCHA&amp;#8217;s
      development subsidiary, DC Housing Enterprises. Such property must meet the threshold criteria of Section 9307 of this Title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 5800 (June 21, 2002); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 974 (January 23, 2004) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 5016 (May 14, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>