<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-405</num>
  <heading>POLITICAL AND COMMUNITY EVENTS (§ 19-405)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>405.1</num>
    <text>405.1 The facilities and resources of the Authority shall not be used torovide any contribution, whether direct or indirect, cash or in-kind, to anyolitical party, political committee, candidate, or constituent servicesrogram.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.2</num>
    <text>405.2 The facilities and resources of the Authority shall not be used for anyvent (other than a convention event) of which a political party, politicalommittee, candidate or constituent services program is the host, organizer, oreneficiary, unless
      the rate to be paid for the event is at least equal to theate paid by for-profit clients for comparable events, but in no event less thanhe cost to the Authority for holding the event.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.3</num>
    <text>405.3 The terms “political party”, “political committee”,candidate”, and “constituent services program” as used in this sectionhall have the meanings ascribed to them by the election laws of the District ofolumbia at D.C. Official Code §§ 1-1101 et
      seq. and 1-1104 et seq.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.4</num>
    <text>405.4 Except as prohibited by Sections 405.1 and 405.2 of this chapter, theacilities and resources of the Authority may be used to provide direct orndirect support for community-related non-profit events, whether charitable orovernmental.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.5</num>
    <text>405.5 Before the Authority provides support for any community-relatedon-profit event pursuant to Section 405.4, the President and Chief Executivefficer or designee shall determine in writing that the amount and terms of suchupport further the mission
      of the Authority, for example, by enhancing itsbility to attract convention event, sports, entertainment and special eventookings or by promoting essential community relations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.6</num>
    <text>405.6 Except as prohibited by Sections 405.1 and 405.2, the resources of theuthority may be used to purchase tickets to community-related events and othervents at the Authority’s venues for distribution at less than theuthority’s purchase price to
      public officials or other persons who dousiness with the Authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.7</num>
    <text>405.7 Before the Authority purchases or distributes tickets pursuant to Section05.6, the General Counsel shall determine in writing that such purchase oristribution does not violate the laws of the United States or the District ofolumbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 29 DCR 259, 261 (January 15, 1982); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 3035 (April 18, 2003); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 8962 (June 14, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>