<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-404</num>
  <heading>CERTIFICATE OF OCCUPANCY AND PERMITS (§ 23-404)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>404.1.</num>
    <text>No license, except a Solicitor&amp;#8217;s license, Manager&amp;#8217;s license, or Caterer&amp;#8217;s license shall be issued to any person unless that person is the holder of a valid certificate of occupancy for the premises in which the business
      for which the license is sought is located, and is also the holder of all other licenses and permits required by law or regulation for that business.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>404.2.</num>
    <text>If a certificate of occupancy has been obtained, and the applicant for the alcoholic beverage license has duly applied for all other licenses and permits required by law or regulation for that business, the Board may, in its discretion but subject
      to all other requirements of this chapter, issue the alcoholic beverage license prior to the issuance of those other licenses and permits.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>404.3.</num>
    <text>The provisions of §§ 404.1 and 404.2 shall not apply to applications for Temporary licenses Class F or G, as long as the alcoholic beverages are sold and served in establishments that have a valid certificate of occupancy, and as long as the applicant
      for the license provides the Board with a statement from the owner of the establishment or the owner&amp;#8217;s duly authorized representative, consenting to the issuance of the license. A certificate of occupancy shall not be required for outdoor
      events or private residential homes used for non-commercial purposes. However, if alcoholic beverages are to be sold or served in any outdoor place (including but not limited to public parks, public streets or alleys), the application for the license
      shall particularly describe the place and the applicant shall provide the Board with a written statement indicating the owner&amp;#8217;s consent, or applicable public approval, if required.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>