<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-3000</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 15-3000)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3000.1.</num>
    <text>This chapter shall establish procedures to govern access to residential rental property by a cable television operator to install cable television facilities and equipment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3000.2.</num>
    <text>Subject to the provisions of this chapter, a cable television operator shall be obligated to provide a cable television service to any tenant within the operator&amp;#8217;s franchise territory requesting it.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3000.3.</num>
    <text>Owners of residential rental property occupied by tenants shall not interfere with the installation of cable television facilities on his or her property except to the extent permitted in §45a of the Cable Television Communications Act of 1981, D.C.
      Code §43-1844.1 (1981 Ed.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3000.4.</num>
    <text>No cable television operator may enter into any agreement with the owners, lessees, or persons controlling or managing buildings served by cable television, or do or permit any act that would have the effect of diminishing or interfering with existing
      rights of any tenant or occupant of the building to use or avail himself or herself of master or individual antenna equipment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3000.5.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in §3006 of this chapter, the owner of residential rental property shall not demand or accept payment from any cable television operator in exchange for permitting cable television service or facilities on or within his or her property
      or premises.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3000.6.</num>
    <text>All documents to be filed with the Office of Cable Television pursuant to this chapter shall be filed between the hours of 8:30 a.m. and 4:00 p.m. on or before the due date. No document shall be received for filing after that time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3000.7.</num>
    <text>The Office shall be open each business day except legal holidays.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3000.8.</num>
    <text>All documents shall be considered filed for purposes of this chapter when received by the Office during business hours set forth in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3000.9.</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise required by the Director, there shall be filed with the Office an original and two (2) copies of all documents submitted for filing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is § 45(a) of the Cable Television Communications Act of 1981, D.C. Law 4-142; added by §2(pp) of the Cable Television Communications Act of 1981 Clarification Amendment Act of 1983, D.C. Law
        5-36, D.C. Code § 43-1844.1 (1981 Ed.).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 7175 (September 30, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>