<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-1303</num>
  <heading>TRANSPORT OF BEVERAGES WITHIN THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA (ยง 23-1303)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1303.1.</num>
    <text>No licensee, or agent, employee, or servant of a licensee, shall transport into the District of Columbia any of the following in a vehicle unless that vehicle bears upon the exterior of both sides of the vehicle the name of the licensee and the kind
      and number of the licensee&amp;#8217;s beverage license in letters not less than three and one-half inches (3 1/2 in.) high:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>More than twelve (12) bottles of alcohol, spirits, or wine; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>More than forty-eight (48) bottles of beer.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1303.2.</num>
    <text>If more than twelve (12) containers of alcohol, spirits, or wine, or more than forty-eight (48) containers of beer, are transported in a vehicle not conforming with the requirements of ยง 1303.1, the person in charge of the transportation shall have
      in his or her possession a permit from the Board or a bill or memorandum issued by the seller of the alcoholic beverages, showing the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the seller;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The date of the sale; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The quantity and character of each beverage being transported.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1303.3.</num>
    <text>Upon demand by any police officer or duly authorized investigator of the Board, the person in charge of the transportation shall exhibit to the officer or investigator the permit, bill, or memorandum.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>