<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-1302</num>
  <heading>IMPORTATION OF ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES FOR PRIVATE USE AND CONSUMPTION (ยง 23-1302)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1302.1.</num>
    <text>Any person who becomes a resident of, or establishes a domicile in, the District of Columbia, may bring into the District of Columbia his or her own personal stock of alcoholic beverages, so long as the beverages are for his or her private use and
      consumption and so long as the importation of the beverages is in compliance with applicable laws and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1302.2.</num>
    <text>The provisions of ยง 1302.1 shall apply to embassies and diplomatic representatives of foreign countries.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1302.3.</num>
    <text>Prior to importing under this section any alcoholic beverages into the District of Columbia from outside of the United States, the individual seeking to do so shall submit a written request for an importation permit to the Board which contains the
      following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The type, brand, and quantity of each beverage to be imported;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The individual&amp;#8217;s out-of-state or foreign address and telephone number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The individual&amp;#8217;s permanent address and telephone number in the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A statement that the beverages are for personal use and consumption and will not be sold.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1302.4.</num>
    <text>The fee for an Importation Permit for alcoholic beverages imported pursuant to ยง 1302 for private use and consumption shall be fifty dollars ($50), paid by credit card, certified check, money order, business check, attorney&amp;#8217;s check, or personal
      check payable to ABRA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>