<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2802</num>
  <heading>EXAMINATION (ยง 17-2802)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2802.1.</num>
    <text>In order to be licensed to practice veterinary medicine, an applicant shall be required to receive passing scores on the District examination and the National Board Examination approved by the American Veterinary Medical Association (national examination),
      unless the Board waives the examination requirements pursuant to ยง2804.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2802.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall take the national examination approved by the American Veterinary Medical Association and the Board prior to taking the District examination. An applicant shall arrange for proof of the applicant&amp;#8217;s National Board score
      to be sent directly from the testing service to the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2802.3.</num>
    <text>The passing grade for the national examination shall be a score of a one and one-half (1 1/2) standard deviation below a converted score of seventy-five percent (75%).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2802.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant who has passed the national examination within the seven (7) year period prior to the date the application for a license is received by the Director shall not be required to retake that examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2802.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant who has passed the national examination more than seven (7) years prior to the date the application for a license is received by the Director shall retake that examination unless the Board, in its discretion, extends the period within
      which the examination results will be accepted with respect to an applicant who has heen actively practicing veterinary medicine.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2802.6.</num>
    <text>The Board shall hold the District examination at least once a year at a time and place determined by the Board in accordance with procedures established by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2802.7.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall submit an application to take the District examination at least forty-five (45) days prior to the date of the District examination. An applicant who has previously taken that examination shall submit such an application at least
      thirty (30) days prior to the date of a District examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2802.8.</num>
    <text>The District examination shall include questions on Radiology, Canine Medicine, Feline Medicine, Surgery, Clinical Pathology, Pharmacology, and other areas specified hy the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2802.9.</num>
    <text>The passing grade for the District examination shall be an average of seventy-five percent (75%). However, an applicant shall not receive a grade of less than seventy percent (70%) in more than two (2) areas of the examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2802.10.</num>
    <text>After receipt of the District examination results, an applicant may request permission from the Chairperson to review the applicant&amp;#8217;s examination papers, for the purpose of improving the applicant&amp;#8217;s performance upon reexamination.
      The request shall be made in writing in the same calendar year that the examination was taken. Nothing in this subsection permits an applicant to challenge the score that the applicant received on the examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2802.11.</num>
    <text>An applicant who passes the District examination, but fails the national examination, shall be required to retake and pass the national examination in the same calendar year that the applicant took the District examination. If the applicant fails
      to pass the national examination in the same calendar year, the applicant shall be required to retake the District examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2802.12.</num>
    <text>An applicant who fails the District examination but passes the national examination shall be required to reapply for and retake only the District examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 2226 (March 25, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>