<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2803</num>
  <heading>PRACTICE OF VETERINARY MEDICINE BY STUDENTS AND GRADUATES (ยง 17-2803)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2803.1.</num>
    <text>Only the following persons shall be authorized to engage in the supervised practice of veterinary medicine without a license:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Students who are fulfilling education requirements under section 8 of the Act, D.C. Code ยง2-2727(a)(1) (1987 Supp.); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Graduates whose first application for a license in the District of Columbia is pending.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2803.2.</num>
    <text>Only a supervisor shall be authorized to supervise the practice of veterinary medicine.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2803.3.</num>
    <text>A student or graduate may practice veterinary medicine only in accordance with the Act and this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2803.4.</num>
    <text>A student or graduate under this section shall not assume administrative or technical responsibility for the operation of a veterinary facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2803.5.</num>
    <text>Supervised practice by students shall take place under direct supervision. Supervised practice by graduates shall take place under direct or general supervision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2803.6.</num>
    <text>A person who has been denied a license or disciplined, or who has such action pending in the District of Columbia of another jurisdiction, shall not practice pursuant to this section unless authorized by the Board in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2803.7.</num>
    <text>A student or graduate shall identify himself or herself as such before practicing veterinary medicine.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2803.8.</num>
    <text>A supervisor is fully responsible for all practice by a student or graduate during the period of supervision and shall be subject to disciplinary action for any violation of the Act or this title by the student or graduate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2803.9.</num>
    <text>A student or graduate shall not receive compensation of any nature, directly or indirectly, from a client, except for a salary based on hours worked under supervision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2803.10.</num>
    <text>A student under this section shall not be employed or receive practical training for more than a period of six (6) months in a calendar year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2803.11.</num>
    <text>Upon notification of failure of the District examination, a graduate shall be terminated from employment and may not practice under this section under any other veterinarian in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2803.12.</num>
    <text>A supervisor shall notify the Board in writing immediately upon the employment or termination of the student or graduate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2803.13.</num>
    <text>A student or graduate shall be subject to all of the applicable provisions of the Act and this title. The Board may deny an application for a license or take other disciplinary action against the student or graduate who is found to have violated the
      Act or this title, in accordance with chapter 33 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2803.14.</num>
    <text>If the Board finds that a student or graduate has violated the Act or this title, the Board may, in addition to any other disciplinary actions permitted by the Act, revoke, suspend, or restrict the privilege of the student or graduate to practice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2803.15.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, the term &amp;#8220;Direct supervision&amp;#8221; means supervision in which a veterinarian is available on the premises and within immediate vocal communication of the supervisee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2803.16.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, the term &amp;#8220;General supervision&amp;#8221; means supervision in which the supervisor is available on the premises or by a communication device at the time the student or graduate is practicing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2803.17.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, the term &amp;#8220;Supervisor&amp;#8221; means a veterinarian licensed under the Act who is responsible for the supervision of a student or graduate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 2226, 2228 (March 25, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>