<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2814</num>
  <heading>STORAGE AND INVENTORY OF DRUGS (ยง 17-2814)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2814.1.</num>
    <text>Drugs shall be stored in the following manner:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Under conditions specified on the label of the original container, or as specified in the official veterinary medicine compendium;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>In accordance with applicable District and federal laws and regulations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Under secure conditions so as to prevent theft or diversion.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2814.2.</num>
    <text>Drug storage areas shall he secure and temperature controlled and shall be kept clean and orderly.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2814.3.</num>
    <text>The stock of drugs and biologicals shall he reviewed at reasonable intervals so that working stock, at the time of expiration, are removed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2814.4.</num>
    <text>A veterinarian shall take an inventory of all Schedule II, III, IV, and V drugs under the veterinarian&amp;#8217;s control every two (2) years and shall date and sign the inventory. The inventory shall indicate if it was made at the opening or closing
      of business and shall be kept on the premises where the drugs are stocked for three (3) years from the date of the inventory.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2814.5.</num>
    <text>A veterinarian shall keep Schedule II controlled substances in a locked area. Only a veterinarian shall have access to such drugs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2814.6.</num>
    <text>A veterinarian shall immediately report the theft or unusual loss of Schedule II, III, IV or V controlled substances to the Department and the United States Drug Enforcement Administration. The Director shall make such forms available without charge
      to all veterinarians.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 2226, 2236 (March 25, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>