<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2802</num>
  <heading>PURCHASE ORDERS (§ 19-2802)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2802.1.</num>
    <text>A purchase order is an offer by the Commission to buy goods and services upon specified terms and conditions, the aggregate amount of which does not exceed $25,000. Unless otherwise duly delegated, purchase orders must be signed by the CCO.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2802.2.</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, purchase orders shall be issued on a fixed-priced basis, exclusive of economic price adjustments or redetermination provisions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2802.3.</num>
    <text>Purchase orders shall be issued on a form prescribed by the CCO and shall specify the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The total quantity of goods or a description of the service ordered;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The total dollar amount, including any and all discounts; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The delivery date.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2802.4.</num>
    <text>The CCO may designate appropriate employees of the Commission to initiate purchase orders by unpriced purchase order, or requisition. All such unpriced purchase orders, or requisitions, shall specify as much of the information required by section
      2802.3 as practicable and shall be subject to approval by designated supervisory personnel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2802.5.</num>
    <text>With the written approval of the CCO, blanket purchase orders may be employed to fill anticipated, recurring needs where there is a wide variety of items in a broad class of goods that are generally purchased, but the exact items, quantities, and
      delivery requirements are not known in advance and may vary considerably.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2802.6.</num>
    <text>All blanket purchase orders shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A statement that the supplier will furnish goods or services, described in general terms, if and when requested during a specified period of time and within a stipulated total dollar amount;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A statement that the Commission is obligated only to the extent of the authorized purchases made pursuant to the order; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A statement that the prices to the Commission shall be as low or lower than those charged to the supplier’s most favored customer for comparable quantities under similar terms and conditions, in addition to any applicable discounts.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2802.7.</num>
    <text>A blanket purchase order shall terminate whenever:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The purchases thereunder equal the total dollar limitation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The stated quantity limitation has been supplied;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The stated term of the order expires; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>At any time the CCO, or his/her delegate, determines that termination is in the best interests of the Commission.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 7420, 7421-22 (October 9, 1998).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>