<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2800</num>
  <heading>PURPOSE AND APPLICATION (§ 19-2800)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2800.1.</num>
    <text>The following policies, rules and procedures governing the procurement, management and disposal of goods and services are hereby adopted by the District of Columbia Sports and Entertainment Commission (the “Commission”), notwithstanding, and in lieu
      of, the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, D.C. Law 6- 85, D.C. Code §§ 1- 1181.1, et seq. (1999 Repl.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2800.2.</num>
    <text>This chapter shall apply only to contracts or procurements initiated subsequent to the effective date hereof, unless otherwise agreed in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2800.3.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this chapter shall not be construed so as to invalidate, rescind or modify any pending or executory contracts of the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2800.4.</num>
    <text>This chapter shall not apply to the booking or scheduling of events at Commission facilities. The Commission shall, consistent with D.C. Code §§ 2- 4001 et seq., have the authority to exempt any other contract or contracts from this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2800.5.</num>
    <text>Where another statute or regulation is referenced in these Regulations, such reference shall be to the most recent version and any amendments or revisions to such statute or regulation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2800.6.</num>
    <text>If any provision of this chapter is deemed invalid, void or unenforceable by a court of competent jurisdiction, this chapter shall be construed as though such provision does not appear herein. Any such finding by a court of competent jurisdiction
      shall not affect the validity of any other section, paragraph or sentence of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is section 8(a)(12) of D.C. Law 10-152, the “Omnibus Sports Consolidation Act of 1994”, as amended, codified at D.C. Code § 2-4007(a)(12) (1999 Supp.).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 7420-21 (October 9, 1998).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>