<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2812</num>
  <heading>CAPABILITY OF BIDDERS AND OFFERORS (§ 19-2812)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2812.1.</num>
    <text>Each offeror shall submit information to the Board necessary to determine the offeror’s capability. In order to be determined responsible by the Board, each prospective contractor shall demonstrate that it has done the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Has adequate financial resources to perform the contract, or the ability to obtain them;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Is able to comply with the required or proposed delivery or performance schedule, taking into consideration all existing commercial and government business commitments;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Has a satisfactory performance record;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Has a satisfactory record of integrity and business ethics;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Has the necessary organization, experience, accounting and operational controls, and technical skills, or the ability to obtain them;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Has the necessary production, construction, and technical equipment and facilities, or the ability to obtain them; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Is not suspended, debarred, or otherwise ineligible to receive an award.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2812.2.</num>
    <text>If an offeror who otherwise would have been awarded a contract is found nonresponsible, a written determination of incapability stating the basis of the finding shall be prepared by the contracting officer and made a party of the procurement file.
      A copy of the determination shall be sent promptly to the incapable offeror.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 4081, 4094-95 (June 22, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>