<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2824</num>
  <heading>DEBARMENT OR SUSPENSION (§ 19-2824)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2824.1.</num>
    <text>A contractor shall be debarred or suspended from being awarded any Board contracts if the principal, or in the case of a corporation, any of its officers, directors, or shareholders holding a substantial interest, or in the case of a partnership,
      any of its partners, meets the following criteria:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Convicted for commission of a criminal offense arising from or incident to obtaining or attempting to obtain a private contract;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Convicted under District or federal statutes of embezzlement, theft, forgery, bribery, falsification or destruction of records, receiving stolen property, or any other offense indicating a lack of business integrity or business honesty which directly
        affects responsibility as a Board contractor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Convicted under District or federal antitrust statutes arising out of the submission of offers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Found by the CCO to be in violation of contract provisions of a character which is regarded by the CCO to be so serious as to justify debarment action;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Engaging in business activities which are contrary to the laws, rules, or regulations of the Government of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>In violation of the ethical standards stated in section 2824; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Determined by the CCO in writing to have committed a breach in professional ethical conduct of such a serious and compelling nature so as to affect responsibility as a Board contractor.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2824.2.</num>
    <text>A contractor or prospective contractor who has been notified of a proposed debarment action may request in writing that a hearing be held. The contractor’s or prospective contractor’s written request shall be delivered by certified mail to the CCO
      within ten (10) days of receipt by the contractor or prospective contractor of notice of the proposed action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2824.3.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall prepare a summary report of the proposed debarment action for the review of the General Manager. The General Manager shall hold a hearing within fifteen (15) days of receipt of the contractor’s or prospective contractor’s request for
      a hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2824.4.</num>
    <text>After consultation with the Corporation Counsel, the General Manager shall issue a final decision within twenty (20) days of the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 4081, 4110-11 (June 22, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>