<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2500</num>
  <heading>BOARD OF ACCOUNTANCY (ยง 17-2500)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2500.1.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this chapter are adopted by the District of Columbia Board of Accountancy (the Board) pursuant to its authority under Non-Health Related Occupations and Professions Licensure Act of 1998, effective April 20, 1999 (D.C. Law 12-261;
      D. C. Official Code ยง 47-2853.01 et seq. (2001)).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.2.</num>
    <text>The purpose of this chapter is to promote and protect the public interest by implementing the provisions of the Act, which provides for the licensing of certain practitioners of public accountancy and seeks to enhance the reliability of information
      which is used in financial transactions or for accounting for or assessing the financial status or performance of commercial, non-commercial, and governmental enterprises.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.3.</num>
    <text>The chairperson is authorized to sign all orders issued on behalf of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.4.</num>
    <text>A majority of the Board shall be in attendance at a meeting to constitute a quorum.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.5.</num>
    <text>A majority vote of those Board members present and voting is necessary for the Board to take any action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.6.</num>
    <text>The Board shall meet no less than four times per year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.7.</num>
    <text>The Board may meet in committees smaller than the full Board, but of not less than three members, for carrying out specific functions of the Board, provided that any actions of such smaller committees are ratified by the full Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4401 (April 30, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>