<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2511</num>
  <heading>CODE OF PROFESSIONAL CONDUCT[COLON] COMPETENCE AND TECHNICAL STANDARDS (§7-2511)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2511.1.</num>
    <text>A licensee shall not undertake any engagement for the performance of professional services that he or she cannot reasonably expect to complete with due professional competence, including compliance, where applicable, with the requirements of this
      section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2511.2.</num>
    <text>A licensee shall not permit his or her name to be associated with financial statements in a manner that implies that the licensee is acting as an independent public accountant with respect to those financial statements unless the licensee has complied
      with applicable generally accepted auditing standards.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2511.3.</num>
    <text>The Board considers statements on auditing standards issued by the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants and other pronouncements having similar generally recognized authority to be interpretations of generally accepted auditing standards.
      Departures from these statements shall be justified by anyone who does not follow them.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2511.4.</num>
    <text>A licensee shall not express an opinion that financial statements are presented in conformity with generally accepted accounting principles if the financial statements contain any departure from generally accepted accounting principles that has a
      material effect on the financial statements taken as a whole, except as provided in § 2511.5.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2511.5.</num>
    <text>A licensee may express an opinion that financial statements are presented in conformity with generally accepted accounting principles when the financial statements contain a departure from generally accepted accounting principles that has a material
      effect on the financial statements taken as a whole if the licensee can demonstrate that, by reason of unusual circumstances, the financial statements would otherwise have been misleading.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2511.6.</num>
    <text>When there is a departure from generally accepted accounting principles, the licensee’s report shall describe the departure, the approximate effects thereof, if possible, and the reasons why compliance with generally accepted accounting principles
      would result in a misleading statement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2511.7.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this chapter, generally accepted accounting principles are those principles defined by pronouncements issued by the Financial Accounting Standards Board and its predecessor and similar pronouncements issued by other Board approved
      entities having similar, generally recognized authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2511.8.</num>
    <text>In the performance of other accounting services, a licensee shall comply with all professional and technical standards generally recognized by the profession for the particular service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2511.9.</num>
    <text>A licensee, in the performance of professional services, shall not permit the use of his or her name in conjunction with any forecast of future transactions in a manner that may reasonably lead to the belief that the licensee vouches for the achievability
      of the forecast.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4401 (April 30, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>