<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2502</num>
  <heading>BOARD ACTION ON APPLICATIONS (§ 17-2502)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2502.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may review and take action on all applications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.2.</num>
    <text>The applicant shall have the burden of proving that he or she meets the required qualifications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.3.</num>
    <text>The Board may not presume qualifications not shown on the application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.4.</num>
    <text>The Board may disapprove an application that fails to provide the required information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.5.</num>
    <text>After giving notice and opportunity for a hearing, the Board may disqualify an applicant for either of the following reasons:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If the applicant has knowingly made or allowed to be made, directly or indirectly, any false or misleading statements in connection with his or her application; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the applicant has attempted to influence, directly or indirectly, any member of the Board in the discharge of the member&amp;#8217;s duties relating to an application.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.6.</num>
    <text>At the discretion of the Board, any applicant whose application has been disqualified may not reapply for a minimum of one (1) year from the date of disqualification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.7.</num>
    <text>Any licensee who has been requested by an applicant to submit to the Board evidence of the applicant’s experience and has refused to do so shall, upon request by the Board, explain in writing or in person the basis for the refusal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.8.</num>
    <text>The Board may require any licensee who has furnished evidence of an applicant’s experience to substantiate the information provided in the following manner:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Any applicant may be required to appear before the Board or its representative to supplement or verify evidence of experience; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Board may inspect documentation relating to an applicant’s claimed experience.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.9.</num>
    <text>The Director shall not issue a license or permit unless the applicant has been approved by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4401 (April 30, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>