<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-1210</num>
  <heading>DENIAL, REVOCATION, OR SUSPENSION OF BINGO, RAFFLE, AND MONTE CARLO NIGHT PARTYICENSES AND SUPPLIERS&amp;#8217; LICENSES (ยง 30-1210)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1210.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may deny any application for a license, or suspend for up to sixty (60) days, or revoke the license of any licensed organization or licensed supplier for any one of the following reasons:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If an applicant for a bingo, raffle or Monte Carlo night party license does not meet the requirements of ยง1200 or 1201;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If an applicant for a bingo, raffle or Monte Carlo night party license does not meet the requirements of ยง 1206;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If the applicant or licensed organization uses false or misleading information to obtain a license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>If the applicant, or licensed organization, or licensed supplier violates any applicable provisions of D.C. Official Code ยง3-1301 et seq. or this title;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Fraudulent or dishonest conduct in the operation of bingo, raffles and Monte Carlo night parties; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Other good cause.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1210.2.</num>
    <text>[RESERVED].</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1210.3.</num>
    <text>A license issued by the Board is not assignable or transferable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1210.4.</num>
    <text>A license issued by the Board shall remain in effect until the expiration date indicated on the license unless suspended or revoked by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1210.5.</num>
    <text>If the Board denies an application for a license or suspends or revokes a license, the applicant, the licensed organization or licensed supplier is entitled to a hearing in accordance with Chapter 3 of the Board&amp;#8217;s rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1210.6.</num>
    <text>An applicant denied a license, a licensed organization or supplier whose license is suspended or revoked shall receive a written notice of denial, suspension or revocation by certified mail, return receipt requested, stating the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The reason for denial, revocation or suspension;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The right to contest the denial, revocation or suspension at a hearing before the Board; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The right to be represented by counsel or any other person.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3788, 3800 (May 20, 1988) and 51 DCR 1684 (February 13, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>