<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-4013</num>
  <heading>RIGHT TURN ON RED (§ 18-4013)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4013.1.</num>
    <text>Right turns after coming to a full stop and yielding right-of-way to pedestrians and other vehicles shall be allowed when facing red traffic control signals, except at locations listed in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4013.2.</num>
    <text>Right turns by vehicles facing red traffic signals shall be prohibited at all times on all days of the week at the intersections listed in this subsection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4013.3.</num>
    <text>Right turns by vehicles facing a red traffic signal shall be prohibited during the hours from 7:00 a.m. to 7:00 p.m., on all days of the week at the intersections listed in this subsection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4013.4.</num>
    <text>Right turns on red will be prohibited at all intersection approaches with one (1) or more of the following characteristics:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Sight distance of vehicles approaching from the left is less than one of the following minimums:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Cross Street Speed Limit</text>
    <text>Minimum Sight Distance</text>
    <text>Cross Street Speed Limit</text>
    <text>Minimum Sight Distance</text>
    <text>20 mph</text>
    <text>120 feet</text>
    <text>40 mph</text>
    <text>270 feet</text>
    <text>25 mph</text>
    <text>150 feet</text>
    <text>45 mph</text>
    <text>320 feet</text>
    <text>30 mph</text>
    <text>190 feet</text>
    <text>50 mph</text>
    <text>360 feet</text>
    <text>35 mph</text>
    <text>220 feet</text>
    <text>55 mph</text>
    <text>410 feet</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The intersection has geometrical or operational characteristics which may result in unexpected vehicle or pedestrian conflicts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>There is significant crossing activity by children, elderly, or handicapped persons;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Significant pedestrian conflicts are expected due to a high volume of pedestrian crossings; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>There is an exclusive pedestrian “WALK” signal at the intersection.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>17 DCRR § 40.111, Special Edition (September 28, 1970); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 11028 (June 29, 1979), incorporating text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 9742, 9743 (April27, 1979); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 28 DCR 3205 (July 17, 1981), incorporating text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 1624 (April 10, 1981); and by Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 4479 (October 16, 1981), incorporating text of Proposed Rulemaking published
        et 28 DCR 3237. 3238 (July 17, 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>