<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>9-707</num>
  <heading>PERSONAL PROPERTY TAX EXEMPTION (ยง 9-707)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>707.1.</num>
    <text>The responsibility for establishing the right to exemption from the personal property tax shall rest upon the semipublic institution claiming the exemption.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.2.</num>
    <text>In order to establish a personal property tax exemption, the semipublic institution shall file an application with the Office showing the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The character of the organization;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The purpose for which it was organized;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The actual activities of the organization;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The sources of income of the organization;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Whether any of the income of the organization is credited to surplus or may inure to the benefit of any private shareholder or individual; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>All facts relating to its operation which affect its right to exemption.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.3.</num>
    <text>The following documents shall be attached to the application for a personal property exemption:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A copy of the charter or articles of incorporation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A copy of the by-laws of the organization;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The latest financial statement showing the assets, liabilities, receipts, and disbursements of the organization; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A copy of the ruling on its exemption status for federal income tax purposes from the Internal Revenue Service.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.4.</num>
    <text>The effective date for a personal property tax exemption granted shall be the July 1st following the date of the initial application request.&amp;#8221;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 6014, 6020 (August 5, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>