<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-107</num>
  <heading>OFFICERS (ยง 19-107)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>107.1</num>
    <text>107.1 The Officers of the Authority shall be a Chairperson, a Vice Chairperson, Treasurer, a President and Chief Executive Officer, a Chief Financial Officerf the Authority, a Secretary, an Assistant Secretary, and such other officerss may from time
      to time be deemed advisable by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.2</num>
    <text>107.2 Unless otherwise provided in the Act or these bylaws, officers shall behosen by a majority vote of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.3</num>
    <text>107.3 The Chairperson and Vice Chairperson shall be Members. The other Officersay, but need not, be Members. Any two or more offices may be held by the sameerson except the offices of Chairperson and Secretary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.4</num>
    <text>107.4 Unless otherwise provided by the Act or these bylaws, the Officers of theuthority shall hold their offices for such terms as shall be determined fromime to time by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.5</num>
    <text>107.5 Unless otherwise provided by the Act or these bylaws, the Officers of theuthority shall exercise such powers and perform such duties as shall bepecified by the Board and, if not inconsistent therewith, as are customarilyxercised by corporate
      officers holding such offices.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.6</num>
    <text>107.6 The Officers of the Authority shall hold office until their successorsre chosen and qualified. Unless otherwise provided in the Act or these bylaws,ny Officer of the Authority may be removed at any time by a majority of theembers in office,
      with or without cause, and any vacancy occurring in anyffice of the Authority may be filled by the vote of a majority of the Membersn office.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.7</num>
    <text>107.7 The Chairperson and such other Officers, employees and agents as may beuthorized by the Board may enter into and execute, on behalf of the Authority,ontracts, leases, debt obligations and all other forms of agreements ornstruments, whether under
      seal or otherwise, permitted by law, the Act andhese bylaws; except where such documents are required by law or the Act to betherwise signed and executed, or where the signing and execution thereof shalle exclusively delegated to some other Officer
      or agent of the Authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.8</num>
    <text>107.8 All checks, drafts or other orders for the payment of money shall beigned by such Officer or Officers or such other person or persons as the Boarday, from time to time, designate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 3816, 3820-21 (June 12, 1998); asmended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 10919, 10923 (November9, 2010); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 8953 (June 14,013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>