<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-109</num>
  <heading>CHIEF FINANCIAL OFFICER OF THE AUTHORITY (§ 19-109)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>109.1</num>
    <text>109.1 The Chief Financial Officer of the Authority shall perform all dutiesustomary to that office and, except as may be required in any instrument underhich any bonds are issued by the Authority, shall be responsible for allorporate funds and securities,
      and shall keep full and accurate accounts ofeceipts and disbursements in the books of the Authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>109.2</num>
    <text>109.2 The Chief Financial Officer of the Authority shall be responsible for theeposit of all monies or other valuable effects in the name of the Authority inuch depositories as shall be selected by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>109.3</num>
    <text>109.3 The Chief Financial Officer of the Authority or his or her delegate shallisburse the funds of the Authority in compliance with the provisions of the Actnd as may be ordered by the Board or its delegate, taking proper vouchers foruch disbursements,
      and shall periodically provide an account of theuthority’s transactions and the financial condition to the Chairperson andhe Board at its regular meetings or when the Board so requires.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>109.4</num>
    <text>109.4 The Assistant Chief Financial Officer of the Authority, if any beppointed, shall in the absence or disability of the Chief Financial Officererform the duties and exercise the powers of the Chief Financial Officer, andhall perform such other
      duties as the Board shall prescribe.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 3816, 3821-22 (June 12, 1998); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 10919, 10924 (November 19,010); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 8953 (June 14, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>