<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5416</num>
  <heading>STANDARDS OF CONDUCT (ยง 17-5416)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5416.1.</num>
    <text>A registered nurse shall adhere to the standards set forth in the &amp;#8220;Code of Ethics for Nurses&amp;#8221; as published by the American Nurses Association, as they may be amended or republished from time to time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5416.2.</num>
    <text>A registered nurse shall respect the client&amp;#8217;s right to privacy by protecting confidential information unless obligated or allowed by law to disclose the information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5416.3.</num>
    <text>A registered nurse shall not accept or perform professional responsibilities which the nurse is not competent to perform.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5416.4.</num>
    <text>A registered nurse shall not, after accepting an assignment or responsibility for a client&amp;#8217;s care, and without giving adequate notice to the supervisor so that arrangements can be made for continuation of nursing care by others:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Unilaterally sever the established nurse-client relationship;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Leave a client for a length of time, or in a manner, that exposes the client unnecessarily to risk of harm; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Leave a nursing assignment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5416.5.</num>
    <text>A registered nurse shall know, recognize, and maintain professional boundaries of the nurse-client relationship.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5416.6.</num>
    <text>A registered nurse shall report unsafe nursing practice by a nurse that he or she has reasonable cause to suspect has exposed or is likely to expose a client unnecessarily to risk of harm as a result of failing to provide client care that conforms
      to the minimum standards of acceptable and prevailing professional practice. The registered nurse shall report such conduct to the appropriate authority within the facility, or to the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5416.7.</num>
    <text>A registered nurse shall provide nursing services, without discrimination, regardless of the age, disability, economic status, gender, national origin, race, religion, or health problems of the client served.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 8613 (September 3, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>