<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-3322</num>
  <heading>FEES FOR CERTIFICATION, PERMITTING, AND ACCREDITATION (ยง 20-3322)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3322.1.</num>
    <text>Initial and renewal certification fees for the disciplines of lead-based paint inspector, risk assessor, abatement supervisor, and lead project designer shall be set at three hundred fifty dollars ($350), for both initial certification and each subsequent
      renewal, unless the course completion certificate provided to DDOE as part of the certification application process is not from a DDOE-accredited training provider, in which case the fee shall be four hundred fifty dollars ($450).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3322.2.</num>
    <text>The certification fee for a lead abatement worker, renovator, and dust sampling technician shall be set at one hundred dollars ($100), for both initial certification and each subsequent renewal, unless the course completion certificate provided to
      DDOE as part of the certification process is not from a DDOE-accredited training provider, in which case the fee shall be one hundred fifty dollars ($150).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3322.3.</num>
    <text>The certification fee for either a renovation firm or business entity shall be set at three hundred dollars ($300), for both initial certification and each subsequent renewal, though no such certification is needed if the renovation firm or business
      entity provides documentation of current certification status issued by the EPA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3322.4.</num>
    <text>The certification fee for a renovation firm or business entity seeking simultaneous certification as both a renovation firm and as a business entity certified to perform lead-based paint activities shall be set at five hundred fifty dollars ($550),
      for both initial certification and each subsequent renewal, though no such certification is needed if the renovation firm or business entity provides documentation of current dual certification status issued by EPA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3322.5.</num>
    <text>The fee for a lead abatement permit is fifty dollars ($50), plus three percent (3%) of the total agreed-upon contract price for the lead abatement portion of the work, provided the total cost of the permit shall not exceed $500.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3322.6.</num>
    <text>The fee for a renovation permit is fifty dollars ($50), plus two percent (2%) of the total agreed-upon contract price for the portion of the work that encompasses the specific activities listed in ยง 3310.1(a), provided the total cost of the permit
      shall not exceed $500.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3322.7.</num>
    <text>Initial, refresher course, and renewal accreditation fees are as follows, apply regardless of the language in which the course is taught, are capped not to exceed a total cost of five thousand dollars ($5,000) per training provider for any given accreditation
      application to DDOE, and are valid for three (3) years of accreditation:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Initial training course accreditation fee schedule:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Lead-Based Paint Inspector: $850</text>
    <text>Risk Assessor: $850</text>
    <text>Abatement Worker: $850</text>
    <text>Abatement Supervisor: $850</text>
    <text>Lead Project Designer: $500</text>
    <text>Renovator: $850</text>
    <text>Dust Sampling Technician: $500</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Refresher training course accreditation fee schedule:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Lead-Based Paint Inspector: $650</text>
    <text>Risk Assessor: $650</text>
    <text>Abatement Worker: $650</text>
    <text>Abatement Supervisor: $650</text>
    <text>Project Designer: $300</text>
    <text>Renovator: $650</text>
    <text>Dust Sampling Technician: $300</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Renewal of initial training course accreditation fee schedule:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Lead-Based Paint Inspector: $600</text>
    <text>Risk Assessor: $600</text>
    <text>Abatement Worker: $600</text>
    <text>Abatement Supervisor: $600</text>
    <text>Project Designer: $400</text>
    <text>Renovator: $600</text>
    <text>Dust Sampling Technician: $400</text>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Renewal of refresher course accreditation fee schedule:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Lead-Based Paint Inspector: $500</text>
    <text>Risk Assessor: $500</text>
    <text>Abatement Worker: $500</text>
    <text>Abatement Supervisor: $500</text>
    <text>Project Designer: $250</text>
    <text>Renovator: $500</text>
    <text>Dust Sampling Technician: $250</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3322.8.</num>
    <text>All certification, permitting, and accreditation fees shall be subject to periodic revision, as deemed advisable by DDOE.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3322.9.</num>
    <text>DDOE shall assess a twenty-five dollar ($25) fee to provide a replacement certification card or accreditation letter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10909 (July 26, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>