<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-3307</num>
  <heading>CERTIFICATION OF INDIVIDUALS[COLON] SPECIFIC REQUIREMENTS (§ 20-3307)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3307.1.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § 3312.1, the following disciplines are required to be certified by DDOE before performing a renovation, a clearance examination, or any lead-based paint activity except for interim controls, in a dwelling unit or child-occupied
      facility built before 1978:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Risk Assessor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Lead-Based Paint Inspector;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Abatement Worker;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Abatement Supervisor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Certified Renovator;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Dust Sampling Technician; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Lead Project Designer.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3307.2.</num>
    <text>Except as provided under § 3308, an applicant for certification seeking to engage in lead-based paint activities as a lead-based paint inspector, risk assessor, dust sampling technician, lead abatement worker, supervisor, or lead project designer,
      shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Submit an application to DDOE by mail, online, or in person, demonstrating that the individual meets all requirements of this section for the particular discipline for which certification is sought;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Complete an EPA- or DDOE-accredited course in the appropriate discipline and receive a course completion certificate from the training provider;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Pass the third-party certification exam offered by DDOE, if one is required in the appropriate discipline;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Pass the DDOE-administered exam, if one is required, that tests the applicant’s knowledge of the District’s relevant legal requirements pertaining to the relevant discipline; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Pay DDOE the appropriate certification fee required under § 3322.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3307.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant for certification as a lead-based paint inspector shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Successfully complete an accredited initial training course for lead-based paint inspectors and provide a course completion certificate from a</text>
    </level>
    <text>training provider that is either EPA-accredited, DDOE-accredited, or accredited by an EPA-approved state; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Provide the following set of information, unless provided with a DDOE waiver for this requirement, based upon a DDOE determination that other alternative prior work experience submitted instead by the applicant for consideration is sufficiently
        comparable:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A list of twenty (20) different addresses where the applicant has assisted in lead-based paint inspections with a certified lead-based paint inspector, which shall include the following information:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Address of each property, including unit number if applicable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Type of activities conducted at each property, such as an X- Ray Fluorescence Analyzer (“XRF”) survey, paint chip sampling, dust sampling, or soil sampling;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Date that each activity took place, and name of certified lead-based paint inspector the applicant assisted with each activity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Detailed description of how the applicant assisted; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>A signed and dated reference by each certified lead-based paint inspector that the applicant assisted, confirming that based on the assistance the applicant provided, the applicant is knowledgeable about and capable of conducting lead-based paint
        inspections and adhering to federal, state, and local regulations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3307.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant for certification as a risk assessor shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Successfully complete an accredited initial training course for lead-based paint inspectors and an initial training course for risk assessors, and provide course completion certificates from a training provider that is either EPA-accredited, DDOE-accredited,
        or accredited by an EPA approved state, and provide documentation of one (1) of the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A bachelor&amp;#8217;s degree and one (1) year of experience in a related field, such as lead, asbestos, or other environmental hazard identification or remediation work, or in construction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An associate’s degree and two (2) years of experience in a related field, such as lead, asbestos, or other environmental hazard identification or remediation work, or in construction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A high school diploma or its equivalent, and at least three (3) years of experience in a related field, such as lead, asbestos, or other environmental hazard identification or remediation work, or in construction; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Certification as an industrial hygienist, professional engineer, or registered architect, or as another environmental or construction related professional; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Demonstrate that the applicant’s skills are directly transferable to the job activities a risk assessor is typically engaged in, and provide the following set of information, unless provided with a DDOE waiver for this requirement, based upon a
        DDOE determination that other alternative prior work experience submitted instead by the applicant for consideration is sufficiently comparable:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A list of ten (10) different addresses where the applicant has conducted work while certified as a lead-based paint inspector, which shall include the following information:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Address of each property, including unit number if applicable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Type of activity conducted at each property, such as an XRF survey, paint chip sampling, dust sampling, or soil sampling;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Date each activity took place; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Signature of supervisor or other senior management who confirms that each activity being vouched for took place as described by the applicant.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3307.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant for certification as an abatement supervisor shall demonstrate that he or she has skills directly transferable to the job activities for a supervisor, based upon:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>At least one (1) year of experience as a certified lead-based paint abatement worker; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>At least two (2) years of experience in a related field, such as lead, asbestos, or environmental hazard identification or remediation work, or in construction.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3307.6.</num>
    <text>An applicant for certification as a lead project designer shall provide documentation of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A bachelor’s degree in engineering, architecture, or a related profession, and one (1) year of experience in building construction and design or a related field; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>At least four (4) years of experience in building construction and design.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3307.7.</num>
    <text>An applicant for certification as a renovator shall successfully complete the EPA-accredited renovator course and be certified by EPA as a renovator, or successfully complete the DDOE-accredited renovator course.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3307.8.</num>
    <text>An applicant for certification as a dust sampling technician shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Successfully complete the DDOE-accredited dust sampling technician course;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Document completion of the course by submitting a certificate to DDOE; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Pass a DDOE-administered exam that tests the applicant’s knowledge of the District’s relevant legal requirements pertaining to dust sampling technicians.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3307.9.</num>
    <text>An abatement worker applicant need not provide prior experience or education documentation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3307.10.</num>
    <text>An individual who successfully completes a DDOE-accredited lead-based paint inspector or risk assessor course may take a DDOE-accredited refresher dust sampling technician course in lieu of the initial training required by § 3307.8(a) to become a
      dust sampling technician.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3307.11.</num>
    <text>A certification issued to an individual by DDOE as a lead-based paint inspector, risk assessor, lead project designer, abatement worker, or supervisor under this section shall expire two (2) years from the date of issuance, and a certification for
      renovator or dust sampling technician shall expire five (5) years from the date of initial issuance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10909 (July 26, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>