<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-1000</num>
  <heading>PROHIBITED DEPOSITS[COLON] GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 24-1000)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1000.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall throw, cast, deposit, drip, scatter, or leave; or cause to be thrown, cast, laid, deposited, scattered, or left in or upon any street, avenue, alley, highway, footway, sidewalk, parking, or other public space in the District of Columbia;
      any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Dirt, mud, ashes, gravel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Trees, sawdust, shavings, hay, straw;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Offal, vegetable matter, garbage;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Coal, cinders;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Paper or refuse matter of any kind; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Any dead animal or putrescible matter of any sort.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.2.</num>
    <text>No person shall kindle or set on fire any combustible material upon any paved sidewalk or roadway.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.3.</num>
    <text>No person shall shake, beat, or otherwise treat carpets, rugs, floor coverings, garments, clothes, linings, covers, furniture, or other articles in such a manner as to cause dust to settle upon other premises or upon any street, avenue, park, square,
      road, or reservation in the District of Columbia within two hundred feet (200 ft.) of any house used for human habitation, occupation, or assembly.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.4.</num>
    <text>No person shall deposit, place, sift, shake, or otherwise treat ashes or other rubbish in any manner that causes dust to settle on other premises.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.5.</num>
    <text>No person shall cause or permit to flow, or cast or cause to be cast, dropped, or spilled upon or into any vacant lot, open space, street, avenue, alley, highway, footway, sidewalk, parking, or other public space in the District of Columbia, any foul
      drainage or foul matter of any kind; nor shall any person carry or transport on, over, or through any vacant lot, open space, street, avenue, alley, highway, footway, sidewalk, parking, or other public space, any filth, offal, or offensive matter
      without a permit from the Director of the D.C. Department of Human Services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.6.</num>
    <text>Owners of lots abutting upon streets, avenues, or alleys, or upon public parking or other public space, in the District of Columbia, and which are above grade, shall protect the lots so as to prevent dirt, sand, or gravel, or any bushes, trees, or
      like things from falling or being washed upon the public parking in front of the lots, or upon the sidewalks, streets, or alleyways adjacent to the lots.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.7.</num>
    <text>No person shall throw or place, or cause to be thrown or placed, any stones, gravel, earth, or other substance or material into any canal in the District of Columbia; or into the feeders, basins, or other works of any canal; or upon the towpath of
      any canal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.8.</num>
    <text>Any person who fails to comply with this section shall be subject to civil sanctions provided in the Litter Control Administration Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-100; D.C. Code §6-2901 et seq.), and shall be subject to a fine of
      not less than five hundred dollars ($500) and not more than one thousand ($1,000) for the first offense. Continued or repeated failure to comply with this section shall be grounds for suspension or revocation of a solid waste collector&amp;#8217;s
      license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is An Act approved January 26, 1887, 24 Stat. 368, ch. 49, §1, D.C. Code §1-1-315; §412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, as amended, 87 Stat.
        790, Pub.L. No. 93-198, D.C. Code §1-227(a) (1992 Repl. Vol.).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 3, §§1, 2, 5, 9, 20, Article 25, §11 of the Police Regulations (May 1981); as amended by §10 of the District of Columbia Abandoned and Junk Vehicle Removal Amendment Act of 1989, D.C. Law 8-24, 36 DCR 4575, 4581, June 30, 1989.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>