<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-1001</num>
  <heading>EXCAVATION AND CONSTRUCTION (ยง 24-1001)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1001.1.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section shall apply to persons engaged in or having charge or control of, or who may be engaged in or have charge or control of conveying material to or from, any of the following activities:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Excavating;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Repairs to structures or grounds; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Construction.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1001.2.</num>
    <text>No person subject to the provisions of this section shall deposit, or permit to be deposited, in any manner, any earth, clay, mud, sand, gravel, or other material upon the surface of any street, alley, avenue, highway, footway, sidewalk, parking,
      or other public space, either by placing, spilling, dropping, or tracking from the wheels of vehicles, or from the feet of animals, or otherwise.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1001.3.</num>
    <text>If any earth, clay, mud, sand, gravel, or other material is deposited on a public space, a person whose duty it is under this section to prevent a deposit shall promptly remove it.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1001.4.</num>
    <text>All macadamized or broken-stone roadways adjacent to excavations, or traversed vehicles either in the process of conveying material from an excavation or in returning to the place of excavation from the place of deposit, shall be covered with planking
      as may be required to prevent any mud, earth, clay, or other material from the excavation or from the place of deposit from reaching the surface of the roadway.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1001.5.</num>
    <text>Earth and rubbish from excavations, or building debris or material used in the construction of buildings, may be placed or permitted to lie on public space, as now authorized by the Building Regulations of the District of Columbia, or as may be authorized
      by permit previously obtained from the Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 3, ยง1 of the Police Regulations (May 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>