<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-1002</num>
  <heading>VACANT LOTS AND OPEN SPACES (ยง 24-1002)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1002.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall throw or deposit, or cause to be thrown or deposited, on any vacant lot or open space in the District any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Sawdust, shavings, vegetable matter, weeds;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Paper, rubbish, litter, garbage;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Offal, dead animal or putrescible matter of any sort;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>An abandoned vehicle, or any other solid waste refuse as defined in 21 DCMR ยง799.1; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any other thing that is injurious to public health.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.2.</num>
    <text>No deposit shall be permitted to remain on a vacant lot or open space.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.3.</num>
    <text>The owner or owners of any lot, lots, or square of ground in the District of Columbia, or their agents, who let their lot, lots, or square for any circus or other exhibition, shall, within twenty-four (24) hours after the exhibition leaves, clear
      and remove waste paper and deposits of all kinds from the lot, lots, or square, to the satisfaction of the Director, Department of Public Works.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.4.</num>
    <text>This section shall not apply to deposits of substances not injurious to health on any place designated by the Mayor as a public dump, where permission to make deposits is granted by the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 3, ยง2 of the Police Regulations (May 1981); as amended by ยง4 of the District of Columbia Solid Waste Regulations Amendment Act of 1989, D.C. Law 8-31, 36 DCR 4750, 4753 (July 7, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>