<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-1502</num>
  <heading>FARES (§ 18-1502)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1502.1</num>
    <text>1502.1 The fares to board a DC Circulator bus shall be as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Persons between the ages of five (5) and sixty-four (64): One dollar ($1.00)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Persons sixty-five (65) years of age and older: Fifty cents (50¢)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Persons who present a valid Metro Access card: Free of charge</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.2.</num>
    <text>A person sixty-five (65) years of age and older may pay the fare established in § 1502.1 (b) upon presenting the DC Circulator bus driver or fare collector with valid photo identification or a valid Medicare card.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.3.</num>
    <text>Passes that permit unlimited daily, three-day, weekly, monthly, or yearly use of the DC Circulator may be sold as follows:</text>
    <text>Daily Pass $ 3.00</text>
    <text>Three-Day Pass $ 7.00</text>
    <text>Weekly Pass $ 11.00</text>
    <text>Monthly Pass $ 40.00</text>
    <text>Yearly Pass $ 450.00</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.4.</num>
    <text>Except for children under the age of five (5) years old and uniformed District， Capitol, and National Park Service police officers, no person shall board a DC Circulator bus without:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Depositing the applicable fare into the bus fare box;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Touching the target point of the bus fare reader with a funded rechargeable fare card;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Presenting a valid DC Circulator pass;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Displaying a valid DC Circulator, Metrobus, or Metrorail pass, WMATA student farecard, or MetroAccess Card; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Displaying a transfer from a bus, train, or other vehicle upon the execution of an agreement between the Department and the owner or operator of such vehicle regarding the use of transfers.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>[REPEALED]</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>D.C. Act 16-554 published at 53 DCR 10235 (December 29, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking Published at 57 DCR 7902, 7903 (August 27, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>