<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1012</num>
  <heading>PENALTIES FOR VIOLATION (§ 21-1012)
    <text>Violation of any of the requirements of this chapter, except for Sections 1007,008.1, 1008.5, and 1009, shall subject a retail establishment to the penaltieset forth in this Chapter.</text>
    <text>If the Director of the District Department of the Environment (“Director”)etermines that a violation of this chapter covered by subsection 1012.1 hasccurred, the Director shall issue a warning notice to the retail establishmentor the initial violation.</text>
    <text>If the Director determines that an additional violation of this chapter hasccurred after a warning notice has been issued for an initial violation, theirector shall issue a notice of infraction and shall impose a penalty againsthe retail establishment.</text>
    <text>The penalty imposed by the Director shall not exceed the following, for eachiolation that occurs after the issuance of the warning notice:</text>
    <text>One hundred dollars ($100) for the first violation in a calendar year;</text>
    <text>Two hundred dollars ($200) for the second violation in a calendar year;</text>
    <text>and</text>
    <text>Five hundred dollars ($500) for the third and each subsequent violation in</text>
    <text>a calendar year.</text>
    <text>No more than one (1) penalty shall be imposed upon a retail establishment within seven (7) calendar day period.</text>
    <text>A retail establishment shall have fifteen (15) calendar days after the date that notice of infraction is issued to pay the penalty.</text>
    <text>The penalty shall double after fifteen (15) calendars days if the retailstablishment:</text>
    <text>Does not pay the penalty; or</text>
    <text>Fails to respond to a notice of infraction by either denying or objecting in</text>
    <text>writing to the infraction or penalty.</text>
    <text>A recipient may request a hearing pursuant to instructions contained in theotice of infraction.</text>
    <text>Hearings or adjudications of violations under this Chapter shall be conductedursuant to the Office of Administrative Hearings Establishment Act of 2001,ffective March 6, 2002 (D.C. Law 14-76; D.C. Official Code §§ 2-1831.01 eteq.).</text>
    <text>Source: Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 7208, 7214 (August 13, 2010).</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>