<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-1002</num>
  <heading>BOARD MEETINGS (ยง 28-1002)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1002.1.</num>
    <text>All meetings of the Board shall be conducted according to Robert&amp;#8217;s Rules of Order, Newly Revised, except to the extent that those rules may be inconsistent with any of the provisions contained in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.2.</num>
    <text>The Chairperson may appoint a parliamentarian to advise the Board on parliamentary matters.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.3.</num>
    <text>All meetings of the Criminal Justice Supervisory Board and its committees shall be open to the public; provided, that the Board or a committee may resolve into executive session upon two-thirds (2/3) vote of the Board or two-thirds (2/3) vote of the
      members of the committee who are present.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.4.</num>
    <text>An agenda shall be circulated to Board members at least ten (10) days prior to a Board meeting. The Chairperson or a member may add additional matters to the agenda with the consent of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.5.</num>
    <text>For those meetings at which an application for a subgrant award is being considered, notice of time, place, and agenda of the Board meeting shall be made public through appropriate notices and the local media.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.6.</num>
    <text>Non-members of the Board who wish to address the Board shall make their requests known to the Chairperson before the beginning of the Board meeting at which they wish to speak. The Chairperson or the Board may grant the request to be heard for a specific
      time period, or may refer the matter to the appropriate committee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.7.</num>
    <text>The Board shall meet no less frequently than quarterly at the times determined by the Executive Committee or its Chairperson, or upon the written request of ten (10) members of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.8.</num>
    <text>A public written record of all meetings of the Board and meetings of Board committees shall be maintained.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.9.</num>
    <text>Proxy voting shall not be permitted at Board meetings. All members of the Board shall be expected to attend meetings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.10.</num>
    <text>If a member cannot attend a meeting, he or she shall notify the Chairperson or the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.11.</num>
    <text>A quorum shall consist of fifty percent (50%) plus one (1) of the total membership of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.12.</num>
    <text>All decisions of the Board shall be by a majority vote of those members voting except as may otherwise by provided in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 1111, 1112-13 (March 14, 1980).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>