<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-1007</num>
  <heading>ANNUAL PROGRAM ANNOUNCEMENT (ยง 28-1007)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1007.1.</num>
    <text>The Planning Committee shall be responsible for developing an annual program announcement consistent with the plan which shall be submitted for review and approval of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1007.2.</num>
    <text>The program announcement shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Clearly define program areas and specific projects for which funding is contemplated;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Specify the range of eligible applicants for each project area. Projects shall be designated closed (one (1) eligible applicant) or competitive (two (2) or more eligible applicants) depending on the nature of the project and the priorities in the
        plan;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Identify for competitive program and project categories, the types of technical assistance to be provided by OCJPA and the extent of allowable program development effort by OCJPA staff;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Specify the amount of funding available, the maximum number of projects to be awarded in each category, and the grant period for which funds will be available; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Delineate special conditions and requirements that must be addressed for an application to be eligible for consideration. Special conditions and requirements may include any program element (such as requiring cooperative agreements or special target
        group involvement) deemed necessary for implementation of the applicable portion of the annual plan in accordance with applicable priorities and objectives.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1007.3.</num>
    <text>The program announcement, when approved, shall serve as the basis for application preparation and as a basis for provision of program development assistance by the OCJPA. In addition, the program announcement shall be the basis for initial programmatic
      review of project applications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 1111, 1115-16 (March 14, 1980).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>REFERENCES IN TEXT</heading>
      <text>The OCJPA, referred to in section 1007 above, was abolished by section 301 of D.C. Law 9-145, the &amp;#8220;Omnibus Budget Support Act of 1992.&amp;#8221; See Editor&amp;#8217;s Note under section 1000 of this chapter for information regarding
        the transfer of OCJPA&amp;#8217;s duties and functions to other offices within the Executive Office of the Mayor.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>