<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-1005</num>
  <heading>COMPREHENSIVE PLAN (ยง 28-1005)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1005.1.</num>
    <text>The Planning Committee shall have responsibility for the development of a recommended annual plan and other planning documents that may be appropriate for submission to the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1005.2.</num>
    <text>The Planning Committee shall consult with the following, as required by the Crime Control Act of 1976, as amended:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Judicial Planning Committee (the &amp;#8220;JPC&amp;#8221;); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Juvenile Justice Advisory Group (the &amp;#8220;JJAG&amp;#8221;).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1005.3.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to modify or amend the planning processes developed by the JPC and the JJAG under the Crime Control Act of 1976, as amended.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1005.4.</num>
    <text>In order to ensure that the development of the plan proceeds in accordance with the wishes of the Board, development of the plan shall require approval by the Board with respect to each of the following stages:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A preliminary statement of priorities, goals, and objectives;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A statement of primary strategies to be utilized in realizing goals and objectives with illustrations and explanation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A statement of areas of program activity consistent with the provisions of ยง 1005.4(a) and (b);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A statement of priorities for improvement of the criminal and juvenile justice systems in the District and recommended allocation of resources (including financial and technical assistance), with justifications for the allocation of resources among
        competing strategies and program areas and among the potentially eligible grantees (such as public vs. private and citywide vs. neighborhood based); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A timetable and work plan for implementation, oversight, consultation with the JPC and the JJAG, and evaluation of the plan and progress pursuant to the plan.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1005.5.</num>
    <text>The statement required by ยง 1005.4(d) shall incorporate past commitments and previous plans with multi-year implications and future multi-year commitments implicit in the present and proposed plans.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1005.6.</num>
    <text>The Planning Committee shall be responsible for submitting each item set forth in ยง 1005.4 to the Board in accordance with a schedule that has been submitted to and approved by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 1111, 1113-14 (March 14, 1980).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>