<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-1000</num>
  <heading>OFFICERS AND DUTIES (§ 28-1000)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1000.1.</num>
    <text>The officers of the Criminal Justice Supervisory Board (also referred to in this chapter as &amp;#8220;the Board&amp;#8221;) shall consist of a Chairperson and a Vice Chairperson.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.2.</num>
    <text>The Chairperson shall be appointed by the Mayor and the Vice Chairperson shall be chosen by the Board from among its members.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.3.</num>
    <text>In this chapter, any reference to the Chairperson shall also refer to the Vice Chairperson under circumstances where the Chairperson is unable to act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.4.</num>
    <text>The Chairperson shall preside at all meetings of the Criminal Justice Supervisory Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.5.</num>
    <text>The Chairperson shall appoint a Vice Chairperson of the Executive Committee and the chairpersons and members of all standing and ad hoc committees of the Board, with the consent of the Board, except as otherwise provided in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.6.</num>
    <text>The order of business for the Board shall be determined by the Chairperson.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.7.</num>
    <text>The Executive Committee shall be composed of the Chairperson of the Board, the Chief Judge of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals, the Chairperson of the Juvenile Justice Advisory Group, the Chairperson of the Committee on the Judiciary of the
      Council of the District, and two (2) other non-government members selected by the Chairperson with the approval of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.8.</num>
    <text>The Executive Committee shall meet on the call of the Chairperson of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.9.</num>
    <text>Between meetings of the Board, the Executive Committee may exercise all powers delegated to the Board, except as otherwise provided in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.10.</num>
    <text>The Director of the Office of Criminal Justice Plans and Analysis (also referred to in this chapter respectively as &amp;#8220;the Director&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;OCJPA&amp;#8221;) (or the head of any successor office) shall ensure the provision
      of necessary staff services to the Board, and shall serve as the Executive Director of the Board.</text>
    <text>By Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 2001-185, dated December 19, 2001, the Office of Policy Research and Development was established in the Executive Office of the Mayor and Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 93-34, dated April 1, 1992, which established the Office of
      Policy and Evaluation, was rescinded. Pursuant to paragraph 4 of Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 2001-185, &amp;#8220;all positions, personnel, property, records and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds of the Office of Policy
      and Evaluation [were] transferred to the Office of Policy Research and Development.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is D.C. Law 2-107, the &amp;#8220;Criminal Justice Supervisory Board Act of 1978&amp;#8243; (codified as amended at D.C. Official Code §§ 3-901 et seq. (2001).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 1111 (March 14, 1980).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR&amp;#8217;S NOTE</heading>
      <text>Pursuant to section 301 of D.C. Law 9-145, the &amp;#8220;Omnibus Budget Support Act of 1992,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;the functions of the Office of Criminal Justice Plans and Analysis, established pursuant to section 4(a) of the Criminal Justice
        Supervisory Board Act of 1978 . . . and all positions, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available to or to made available relating the functions of the Office of Criminal Justice Plans
        and Analysis [were] transferred to the Mayor&amp;#8217;s Office of Policy and Program Evaluation. . . .&amp;#8221;</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>