<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-1011</num>
  <heading>APPEALS[COLON] GENERAL (ยง 28-1011)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1011.1.</num>
    <text>An applicant for an action grant under the provisions of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968, as amended, and the Juvenile Justice Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974, as amended, who has been denied all requested LEAA funds to conduct
      a project for which funds are available, may appeal the grant request decision to the Criminal Justice Supervisory Board or to an Appeals Committee of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1011.2.</num>
    <text>The Office of Criminal Justice Plans and Analysis shall notify each applicant in writing of the reasons for denial. The notification shall be consistent with requirements set forth in ยง 303(a)(15) of the Crime Control Act of 1968, as amended, and
      the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974, as amended.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1011.3.</num>
    <text>Subgrant applicants shall have the right to withdraw or revise their appeals at any time prior to the final Board decision. The withdrawal or revisions shall not act as a bar to resubmission of the application for reconsideration by the Board at some
      later date.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1011.4.</num>
    <text>Appeals shall be taken by subgrant applicants upon written notice from the Office of Criminal Justice Plans and Analysis setting forth the reasons for disapproval of the application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1011.5.</num>
    <text>Appeals shall be taken within twenty (20) days of the dispatch of written notice by the Office of Criminal Justice Plans and Analysis. Appeals shall be in writing and shall set forth the reasons and grounds for the appeal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1011.6.</num>
    <text>Grounds for appeal may include one (1) or both of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An error of procedure occurred; and/or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Board&amp;#8217;s decision was based on a substantive error of fact.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1011.7.</num>
    <text>Denial of requests because of insufficient LEAA funds may not be appealed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1011.8.</num>
    <text>Applicants filing appeals desiring to present a personal appeal shall make that request to the Office of Criminal Justice Plans and Analysis in the written appeal and shall indicate the name of the person who shall present the appeal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1011.9.</num>
    <text>If the Criminal Justice Supervisory Board or an Appeals Committee desires to hear a supporting oral appeal, the applicant shall be notified of the time and place of the oral presentation by the Office of Criminal Justice Plans and Analysis.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 1111, 1118-19 (March 14, 1980).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR&amp;#8217;S NOTE</heading>
      <text>Pursuant to Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 2000-149, dated October 3, 2000, the Justice Grants Administration, Office of the Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice, &amp;#8220;is the sole Agency responsible for carrying out the provisions of the Juvenile
        Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974, as amended, 88 Stat. 1109.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>REFERENCES IN TEXT</heading>
      <text>The Office of Criminal Justice Plans and Analysis, referred to in section 1011 above, was abolished by section 301 of D.C. Law 9-145, the &amp;#8220;Omnibus Budget Support Act of 1992.&amp;#8221; See Editor&amp;#8217;s Note under section 1000 of
        this chapter for information regarding the transfer of OCJPA&amp;#8217;s duties and functions to other offices within the Executive Office of the Mayor.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>