<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6319</num>
  <heading>UNUSUAL INCIDENTS (ยง 29-6319)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6319.1.</num>
    <text>In this section, an &amp;#8220;unusual incident&amp;#8221; is an event that is significantly different from the regular routine or established procedure of the resident, the independent living program, or any person relevant to the resident.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6319.2.</num>
    <text>Unusual incidents include but are not limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The death of a resident;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The death of a staff member while on duty or at the independent living program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The attempted suicide of a resident or staff member;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A resident&amp;#8217;s suspension or expulsion from school or an alternative educational program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A resident is missing or has absconded;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A resident&amp;#8217;s alleged delinquent or criminal behavior, including but not limited to the possession or use of controlled substances, or weapons;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A resident is the victim of alleged delinquent or criminal behavior;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>A staff member&amp;#8217;s actual or alleged possession of a controlled substance, actual or alleged use of a controlled substance, or appearance of being under the influence of a controlled substance while on duty or at the independent living program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>A staff member&amp;#8217;s dereliction of duty, unlawful or improper behavior, or fraud;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>A resident&amp;#8217;s injury, trauma, or illness requiring treatment at a hospital;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>A violation of a resident&amp;#8217;s rights as set forth in this Chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Any physical altercation involving a resident or staff member;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Any sexual contact involving a resident who is less than eighteen (18) years of age;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>Any sexual contact between a resident and a staff member;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>Misuse of a resident&amp;#8217;s funds;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(p)</num>
      <text>An outbreak of a communicable disease;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(q)</num>
      <text>An incident requiring the services of the fire or police departments;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(r)</num>
      <text>An automobile accident involving residents or staff on duty;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(s)</num>
      <text>Destruction of government property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(t)</num>
      <text>Any contact or visit, whether announced or unannounced, by the media or high-level government officials;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(u)</num>
      <text>A loss of any utilities, including but not limited to power, water, or sewage;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(v)</num>
      <text>Any condition which results in the independent living program&amp;#8217;s closure; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(w)</num>
      <text>Any other occurrence or event which substantially interferes with a resident&amp;#8217;s health, welfare, living arrangement, or well-being, or in any way places a resident at risk.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6319.3.</num>
    <text>The independent living program shall report all unusual incidents to CFSA and the contracting entity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6319.4.</num>
    <text>Except as provided by ยง 6319.5, the report shall be made orally as soon as possible, but in no event later than twenty-four (24) hours, and in writing no later than the next business day.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6319.5.</num>
    <text>An independent living program shall report alleged child abuse, neglect, or other risk to a resident&amp;#8217;s health and safety in accordance with ยง 6304.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6319.6.</num>
    <text>If a resident is missing or has absconded, the independent living program shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Notify the law enforcement agency in the jurisdiction in which the resident resides and the contracting entity within one (1) hour after learning that a resident is missing or absconding; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Inform the law enforcement agency and the contracting entity immediately upon the resident&amp;#8217;s return to the independent living program.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6319.7.</num>
    <text>The independent living program shall establish and implement a written plan for the reporting of unusual incidents.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 1591 (February 22, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>