<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6308</num>
  <heading>ANNUAL LICENSE RENEWAL (§ 29-6308)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6308.1.</num>
    <text>An applicant for renewal of an annual license shall submit the application to CFSA at least two (2) but not more than three (3) months prior to the expiration of the current annual license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6308.2.</num>
    <text>The application for renewal of an annual license shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A report of any changes in the information required by § 6307, including copies of any applicable documents;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A report of any major changes contemplated for the coming year;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Documentation of compliance with §§ 6323.20 &amp;#8211; 6323.22 concerning the health of and medical examinations for prospective and existing staff;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Documentation of compliance with § 6324 concerning criminal records checks;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Documentation of compliance with § 6325 concerning child protection register checks;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>An annual financial statement (including, but not limited to, a cash flow statement, income statement and balance sheet), audited or unaudited, prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles (GAAP);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A copy of the independent living program&amp;#8217;s budget; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Copies of insurance information required under § 6316.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6308.3.</num>
    <text>CFSA shall review an application for annual license renewal and either grant or deny the application or grant a provisional or restricted license, within sixty (60) days of receipt of the completed application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6308.4.</num>
    <text>CFSA shall notify an applicant in writing of the decision to grant or deny an annual license renewal, or to grant a provisional or restricted license. The notice shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A statement of the grounds for the decision; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An explanation of the right to and the method of requesting a fair hearing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6308.5.</num>
    <text>If CFSA decides to grant the renewal, it shall issue the license within two (2) business days of its decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 1591 (February 22, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>