<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6309</num>
  <heading>LICENSE MODIFICATION (ยง 29-6309)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6309.1.</num>
    <text>CFSA may modify a license at any point during the licensing year upon request by the independent living program or on CFSA&amp;#8217;s own authority, provided that the modification is not deleterious to the residents&amp;#8217; health, safety, or
      welfare.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6309.2.</num>
    <text>A request for a modification made by an independent living program shall be made to CFSA, and shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be in writing, using a form provided by CFSA;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Set forth all relevant information concerning the specific modification sought and the reason for seeking the modification;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Contain any additional information required by CFSA; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Be accompanied by all relevant documentation and information.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6309.3.</num>
    <text>CFSA shall review a request for a license modification and either grant or deny the request within sixty (60) days of receipt of the completed request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6309.4.</num>
    <text>CFSA shall notify an applicant in writing of the decision to grant or deny a license modification. The notice shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A statement of the grounds for the decision; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An explanation of the right to and the method of requesting a fair hearing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6309.5.</num>
    <text>If CFSA decides to grant the license modification, it shall issue the modified license within two (2) business days of its decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 1591 (February 22, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>