<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6310</num>
  <heading>VARIANCE (ยง 29-6310)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6310.1.</num>
    <text>CFSA may approve a variance upon a showing by an independent living program of hardship and manifest public need, except that a variance may not be approved if it would be deleterious to residents&amp;#8217; health, safety, or welfare.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6310.2.</num>
    <text>A request for a variance shall be made to CFSA, and shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be in writing, using a form provided by CFSA;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Set forth all relevant information concerning the specific variance sought and the reason for seeking the variance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Set forth all relevant information concerning the alleged hardship and manifest public need that requires the variance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Include documentation sufficient to establish that granting the variance would not be deleterious to residents&amp;#8217; health, safety, or welfare;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Include documentation sufficient to establish that the independent living program would continue to comply with the intent of this Chapter if the variance were granted;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Contain any additional information required by CFSA; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Be accompanied by all relevant documentation and information.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6310.3.</num>
    <text>A variance shall remain in effect for the duration of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6310.4.</num>
    <text>CFSA shall review a request for a variance and either grant or deny the request within sixty (60) days of receipt of the completed request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6310.5.</num>
    <text>CFSA shall notify an applicant in writing of the decision to grant or deny a variance. The notice shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A statement of the grounds for the decision; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An explanation of the right to and the method of requesting a fair hearing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6310.6.</num>
    <text>A variance may not be issued to an independent living program owned or operated by the District of Columbia government.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6310.7.</num>
    <text>If CFSA decides to grant the variance, it shall issue the variance within two (2) business days of its decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 1591 (February 22, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>