<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6337</num>
  <heading>PROHIBITED AND ILLEGAL DEVICES AND SUBSTANCES (ยง 29-6337)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6337.1.</num>
    <text>Explosives, pyrotechnics, firearms, chemical weapons, non-chemical weapons, and other similar devices or substances are prohibited within the main facility and each residence. Nothing in this section shall be construed as prohibiting law enforcement
      authorities from bearing arms when they are present at a main facility or residence in conjunction with their official responsibilities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6337.2.</num>
    <text>Illegal substances are prohibited within the main facility and residences.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6337.3.</num>
    <text>An independent living program shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Prohibit the use and possession of alcohol by staff while in the main facility and each residence;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Prohibit the use and possession of alcohol by residents; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Maintain a no-smoking policy in the main facility and each residence.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6337.4.</num>
    <text>An independent living program immediately shall contact local law enforcement if there is a reasonable suspicion that a resident or staff member is in possession of a firearm or illegal substance, or has engaged in other criminal behavior, including
      usage or distribution of an illegal substance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6337.5.</num>
    <text>An independent living program shall have written policies and procedures for handling incidents involving prohibited and illegal devices and substances.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 1591 (February 22, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>