<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-1608</num>
  <heading>FILING OF PETITIONS AND SUPPLEMENTS (ยง 3-1608)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1608.1.</num>
    <text>Before the nominating petition is filed, all sheets which comprise the petition shall be assembled and serially numbered. The Board may refuse to accept any petition which has not been so assembled and so numbered.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1608.2.</num>
    <text>Each nominating petition when filed with the Board, shall be accompanied by a Declaration of Candidacy and Affidavit of Qualifications pursuant to Chapter 6 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1608.3.</num>
    <text>The individual who files the petition shall execute an affidavit attesting that to the best of his or her knowledge and belief, the petition being filed is complete and contains the legally required number of valid signatures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1608.4.</num>
    <text>The nominating petition, affidavit(s) and supplements, if any, shall be filed with the Board at its office no later than 5:00 p.m. on the date of the filing deadline required by law and announced by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1608.5.</num>
    <text>The petition may not be finally accepted by the Board unless the following occurs:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>There has been filed with the Board a Declaration of Candidacy and Affidavit of Qualifications executed in accordance with the provisions of this section and Chapter 6 of this title;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The person filing the petition executes an affidavit pursuant to the provisions of this section; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The petition is on a form provided by the Board and meets all the requirements of this section and of the Election Act; provided, that the Board, in its discretion, may waive any formal error.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1608.6.</num>
    <text>Any candidate who has met the requirements of this section may file petition supplements; Provided, that the supplements meet all other pertinent provisions of this section and are accompanied by an affidavit executed by the person filing the supplements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1608.7.</num>
    <text>The Board may reject any nominating petition that is confusing, misleading or does not conform to the requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 D.C. Reg. 8364, 8369 (December 15, 1989).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL NOTE</heading>
      <text>Prior to December 15, 1989, the Board of Elections and Ethics published Final Rulemaking notices at 27 D.C. Reg. 2763 (June 27, 1980), incorporating the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 27 D.C. Reg. 1929, 1950-51 (May 9, 1980); and at 29
        D.C. Reg. 2581-82 (June 18, 1982).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>