<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-1610</num>
  <heading>ORDER OF CONTESTS ON PRIMARY, GENERAL AND SPECIAL ELECTION BALLOTS (ยง 3-1610)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1610.1.</num>
    <text>The order of contests in any Primary, General or Special Election shall appear on the ballot in the following manner:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Electors for President and Vice President of the United States;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Delegate to the U.S. House of Representatives;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Mayor of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Chairman of the Council of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>At-Large Member of the Council of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Ward Member of the Council of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>President of the Board of Education;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>School District Member of the Board of Education; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Advisory Neighborhood Commissioner.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1610.2.</num>
    <text>The contests for the office of U.S. Senator and U.S. Representative may appear, in that order, on a ballot card separate from all other offices, until such time as the proposed state of New Columbia is admitted to the union.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1610.3.</num>
    <text>In any election following the admittance of the proposed state of New Columbia to the union, the contests for U.S. Senator and U.S. Representative shall appear first on the ballot, or immediately following the contest for Electors of President and
      Vice President of the United States in presidential election years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 D.C. Reg. 8364, 8370 (December 15, 1989); and further amended by Final Rulemaking published at 39 D.C. Reg. 7152 (September 18, 1992); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 48 D.C. Reg. 11722 (December 28,
        2001); and further amended by Final Rulemaking published at 49 D.C. Reg. 2737 (March 22, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>