<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-203</num>
  <heading>REGISTERED AGENT FOR NON-RESIDENT LICENSEES (§ 14-203)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>203.1</num>
    <text>203.1 An applicant or licensee that is the non-resident owner of at least one (1) rental unit in the District of Columbia shall appoint and continuously maintain a registered agent for service of process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>203.2</num>
    <text>203.2 The non-resident owner shall make the appointment by filing a written statement with the Director on a prescribed form.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>203.3</num>
    <text>203.3 The registered agent shall be an individual who is a resident of the District of Columbia or an organization incorporated in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>203.4</num>
    <text>203.4 If the licensee changes the agent, or if the name or address or any information about the agent changes after the licensee files the statement with the Director, the non-resident owner shall, within seven (7) business days of its occurrence,
      file a written statement notifying the Director of the change.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>203.5</num>
    <text>203.5 Pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 42-903(b)(2) (2010 Repl.), the Director shall serve as the registered agent for the non-resident owner if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A registered agent is not appointed under § 203.1; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The individual or organization appointed under § 203.1 ceases to serve as the resident agent and no successor is appointed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>203.6.</num>
    <text>Pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 42-903(d) (2010 Repl.), a non-resident owner of one (1) or more rental units in the District in violation of this section shall be subject to a penalty of three hundred dollars ($300).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>The Housing Regulations of the District of Columbia, 5G DCRR § 3102.3, Commissioners’ Order 55-1503 (August 11, 1955); as amended by section 4 of the Security Deposit Act, D.C. Law 1-48, 22 DCR 2823, 2828 (November 28, 1975); as replaced by Final
        Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 7487, 7490 (June 22, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>