<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-5700</num>
  <heading>APPLICABILITY (ยง 3-5700)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5700.1.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this chapter shall establish the procedures for filing financial disclosure forms and the limitations on honoraria pursuant to the authority set forth in the Subtitle D of the Government Ethics Act of 2011 (Act), Title II of the
      Board of Ethics and Government Accountability Establishment and Comprehensive Ethics Reform Amendment Act of 2011, effective April 27, 2012 (D.C. Law 19-124; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-1161.01 et seq. (2012 Supp.)).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5700.2.</num>
    <text>The Financial Disclosure Statement (FDS) form, prescribed by the Director of the Government Ethics (Director), shall be filed by the following public officials:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A candidate for nomination for election, or election, to public office;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Mayor, Chairman, and each member of the Council of the District of Columbia holding office under the Home Rule Act;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Attorney General;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A Representative or Senator elected pursuant to Section 4 of the District of Columbia Statehood Constitutional Convention Initiative of 1979, effective March 10, 1981 (D.C. Law 3-171; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-123 (2006 Repl.));</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A member of the State Board of Education;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A person serving as a subordinate agency head in a position designated as within the Executive Service;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A member of a board or commission listed in Section 2(e) of the Confirmation Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-142; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-523.01(e) (2006 Repl.)); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>A District of Columbia Excepted Service employee paid at a rate of Excepted Service 9 or above, or its equivalent, who makes decisions or participates substantially in areas of contracting, procurement, administration of grants or subsidies, developing
        policies, land use planning, inspecting, licensing, regulating, or auditing, or acts in areas of responsibility that may create a conflict of interest or appearance of a conflict of interest; and any additional employees designated by rule by
        the Ethics Board who make decisions or participate substantially in areas of contracting, procurement, administration of grants or subsidies, developing policies, land use planning, inspecting, licensing, regulating, or auditing, or act in areas
        of responsibility that may create a conflict of interest or appearance of a conflict of interest.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 2852 (March 8, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>