<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-413</num>
  <heading>SURETY BOND[SLASH]DEPOSIT (ยง 21-413)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>413.1.</num>
    <text>The owner or occupant shall post a surety bond or deposit, equal to not less than one-half (1/2) of the outstanding water, sewer, or groundwater sewer service charges, penalties, and interest owed at the time the request for administrative hearing
      is made.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>413.2.</num>
    <text>The requirement to post a surety bond or deposit shall not apply to an owner who occupies the single family house where the contested charges were incurred.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>413.3.</num>
    <text>The deposit shall be in the form of a certified check or money order. The deposit shall be placed in an escrow account and accrue interest. The interest rate shall be determined based on the Annualized Treasury Bill Yield Rate, which is published
      in nationally circulated newspapers, including the Washington Post and the New York Times. If more than one rate is published, the lowest rate shall be used.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>413.4.</num>
    <text>A surety bond shall accrue interest only if it is in a form that is equivalent to cash.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>413.5.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of the surety bond or deposit, the portion of the water and sewer charges being challenged shall not be subject to penalty or interest, and service shall not be terminated for non-payment of the contested charges, until a final decision
      has been rendered.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>413.6.</num>
    <text>The owner or occupant shall pay all charges not in dispute within thirty (30) days of the date that the bill for such charges is rendered.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 1300, 1311 (February 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 5358 (June 18, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>