<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-414</num>
  <heading>HEARING OFFICERS (ยง 21-414)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>414.1.</num>
    <text>Upon the filing of a request for hearing, the General Manager may conduct a hearing or assign a hearing officer (&amp;#8220;hearing officer&amp;#8221;) to the case. Thereafter, all motions and procedural requests shall be addressed to the hearing
      officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>414.2.</num>
    <text>No hearing officer shall conduct a hearing in a proceeding in which he or she is prejudiced or partial with respect to any owner or occupant, or where that officer has any interest in the matter pending for decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>414.3.</num>
    <text>No hearing officer shall have the authority to overrule any law or regulation of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>414.4.</num>
    <text>The hearing officer shall have the following powers:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>To give notice concerning hearings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>To administer oaths and affirmations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>To examine witnesses and to take testimony;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>To issue subpoenas and order the parties to submit documents or other evidence;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>To request that investigative reports be prepared by WASA in instances where the reports do not exist;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>To grant requests for discovery, if the discovery is necessary for the disposition of the appeal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>To rule upon offers of proof and to receive relevant evidence;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>To regulate the course and conduct of hearings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>To hold conferences, before or during a hearing, for the settlement or simplification of issues;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>To rule on motions and to dispose of procedural requests or similar matters;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>To issue final decisions as provided in this section or by law;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>To adjust the charges for water, sewer, and groundwater sewer service based upon facts adduced at hearings held pursuant to this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>To adjust the charges for groundwater sewer service based upon a challenge to a determination of practicability made pursuant to ยง 207; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>To take any other action authorized by this chapter, the Administrative Procedure Act, or by any other applicable statute, rule or regulation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published al 40 DCR 1300, 1312 (February 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 5358 (June 18, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>