<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-405</num>
  <heading>ADJUSTMENT FOR METER OR COMPUTATION ERRORS (§ 21-405)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>405.1.</num>
    <text>If the investigation discloses meter overread or faulty computation, adjustment(s) shall be made to reflect the correct charges, as indicated by the correct reading or corrected computations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.2.</num>
    <text>If the investigation reveals doubtful meter registration or possible meter malfunction, WASA shall remove the meter and test it.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.3.</num>
    <text>If the results of the tests under § 405.2 verify doubtful registration or meter malfunction, the water and sewer service bill shall be adjusted to equal the average consumption of water at the same premises for up to three (3) previous comparable
      periods for which records are available.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.4.</num>
    <text>If the results of the tests under § 405.2 verify doubtful registration or meter malfunction, and the investigation concerns groundwater sewer service, the groundwater sewer service bill shall be adjusted to equal the average groundwater meter registration
      at the same premises for up to three (3) previous comparable periods for which records are available.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.5.</num>
    <text>If records for up to three (3) comparable billing periods are not available, the bill shall be adjusted in accordance with the provisions of § 408.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 24 DCR 8315 (March 24, 1978), incorporating text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 24 DCR 6206, 6208 (January 27, 1978), 12 DCRR §§400.37.5(a) and 400.37.5(b); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 1300,
        1309 (February 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 5358 (June 18, 1999).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR&amp;#8217;S NOTE</heading>
      <text>Sections 405.1 to 405.3 issued under D.C. Act 2-112, Second Emergency Water and Sewer Bill Payment Act of 1977 expired on the 90th day following the effective date of the law. No permanent law was enacted</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>