<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-409</num>
  <heading>NOTICE OF INVESTIGATION RESULTS AND ADJUSTED BILLS (§ 21-409)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>409.1.</num>
    <text>After reviewing the report and making any adjustments to the water or sewer service charges, in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, the Authority shall mail written notice of the following to the owner or occupant:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The results of the investigation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the bill has been adjusted, an amended bill reflecting any adjustment(s) made.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.2.</num>
    <text>An owner or occupant may appeal the General Manager&amp;#8217;s decision by filing a petition for an administrative hearing within fifteen (15) calendar days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.3.</num>
    <text>The new date for payment of the original or adjusted bill, as set forth in the notice, shall not be less than fifteen (15) days after the mailing date of the notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.4.</num>
    <text>If the original bill was paid and an adjustment has been made, the amount of the overcharge shall be refunded to the party who paid the bill.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.5.</num>
    <text>The notice shall also inform the challenging party of the right to appeal the determination and bill (or amended bill) set forth in the notice, and shall set forth the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The requirements for filing the appeal under § 410.2; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If an appeal is filed, there will be no penalty or service cut-off for non-payment of the bill until the appeal has been considered and he or she has been notified in writing of the results of the appeal and a new date for payment</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 24 DCR 8315 (March 24, 1978), incorporating text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 24 DCR 6206, 6210 (January 27 1978), 12 DCRR §§400.37.6 and 400.37.7; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 1300, 1309
        (February 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 5358 (June 18, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 796(January 24, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>