<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-401</num>
  <heading>NOTICE OF RIGHT TO CHALLENGE BILLS, AND PRACTICABILITY AND IMMINENT THREATETERMINATIONS (§ 21-401)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>401.1.</num>
    <text>Each water, sewer, and groundwater sewer service bill shall contain a written statement advising the owner or occupant of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The owner or occupant may challenge the bill in accordance with the provisions of § 402;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Upon receipt of a challenge to a water, sewer and groundwater sewer service bill, WASA will investigate the bill;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If WASA finds the bill to be erroneous, it shall adjust the bill accordingly and refund any overcharge paid;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The owner or occupant will not be subject to any penalty, interest charge or termination of service for nonpayment of the disputed bill until the owner or occupant has been advised in writing of the results of the investigation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The owner or occupant will be notified in writing of the results of the investigation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>If the bill has not been paid, the owner or occupant will be notified in writing of the amount found to be due as a result of the investigation, and the date on which the bill shall be paid;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The owner or occupant may request a hearing in writing, within fifteen (15) days, if he or she is not satisfied with the decision of WASA; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The owner or occupant may request a written statement of billing, for the most recent eighteen (18) month billing and payment history of the account. Upon receipt of a written request, WASA shall prepare this statement of billing within thirty (30)
        days.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.2.</num>
    <text>Each determination of practicability made by the General Manager pursuant to § 207 of this title shall contain a written statement advising the owner or occupant of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The owner or occupant may challenge the determination in accordance with the provisions of § 402;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Upon receipt of a challenge to a determination of practicability, WASA will investigate the determination; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The owner or occupant will be notified in writing of the results of the investigation and the date and time of any hearing, if required.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.3.</num>
    <text>Each determination of practicability made by the General Manager pursuant to § 5403, each determination of imminent threat made by the General Manager pursuant to § 5405 and each denial, suspension or revocation of certification to test backflow preventers
      made by the General Manager pursuant to § 5408 shall contain a written statement advising the applicant or certificate holder of the following:</text>
    <text>a. The owner or owner&amp;#8217;s agent, applicant or certificate holder may challenge the denial, suspension or revocation of certification in accordance with the provisions of § 402; and</text>
    <text>b. The owner or owner&amp;#8217;s agent, applicant or certificate holder shall be notified in writing of the date and time of any hearing, if required.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 1300, 1307 (February 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 5358 (June 18, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 1743 (February 23, 2001).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL NOTE</heading>
      <text>Prior to February 12, 1993, the Department of Environmental Services published Final Rulemaking at 24 DCR 8315 (March 24, 1978), incorporating text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 24 DCR 6206, 6207 (January 27, 1978), 12 DCRR §400.37.3.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>