<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2500</num>
  <heading>ACCESSORY USES AND BUILDINGS (§ 11-2500)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2500.1.</num>
    <text>Any accessory use or accessory building shall be located on the same lot with the use or building to which it is accessory; provided, that required accessory parking space may be permitted on another lot where specifically permitted under other provisions
      of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.2.</num>
    <text>An accessory building shall be located only in a rear yard, except as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An accessory private garage may be located in a side yard pursuant to § 2300; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A pump island canopy and any kiosk adjacent to the pumps used exclusively as an attendant&amp;#8217;s shelter of a gasoline service station may be located in any open area of a lot not within twenty-five feet (25 ft.) of a Residence District unless
        separated therefrom by a street or alley.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.3.</num>
    <text>No more than thirty percent (30%) of the area of a required rear yard on any lot shall be occupied by accessory buildings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.4.</num>
    <text>An accessory building in any zone district shall not exceed one (1) story or fifteen feet (15 ft.) in height, except as provided in § 2500.5.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.5.</num>
    <text>In an R-1-A or R-1-B District only, an accessory private garage may have a second story used for sleeping or living quarters of domestic employees of the family occupying the main building.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.6.</num>
    <text>A two (2) story accessory building allowed under § 2500.5 shall not exceed twenty feet (20 ft.) in height and shall not be located within the required rear yard. It shall also be set back from all side lot lines for a distance equal to the minimum
      width of a required side yard in the district in which it is located.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.7.</num>
    <text>The height of an accessory building permitted by §§ 2500.4 or 2500.5 shall be measured from the finished grade at the middle of the side of the accessory building that faces the main building to the highest point of the roof of the building.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.8.</num>
    <text>An accessory building or structure shall not be erected on any lot prior to the time of construction of the main building to which it is accessory.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.9.</num>
    <text>An accessory building shall not obstruct light and ventilation required by other regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is the Zoning Act of 1938, approved June 20, 1938 (52 Stat. 797, as amended; D.C. Official Code §§ 6-641.01 to 641.15 (2001) (formerly codified at D.C. Code §§ 5-413 to 5-432 (1994 Repl. and
        1999 Supp.))).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE §§ 7502.1 through 7502.5 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958 (renumbered §§ 7601.1 through 7605.5 in the April 1981 edition of the Zoning Regulations); as amended by:</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 2818 (May 9, 1986); Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8524-25 (October 20, 2000); and Final
        Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 2742, 2747-48 (March 22, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>