<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2517</num>
  <heading>EXCEPTIONS TO BUILDING LOT CONTROL (OTHER THAN RESIDENCE DISTRICTS) (§ 11-2517)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2517.1.</num>
    <text>This section shall permit two (2) or more principal buildings or structures to be erected as a matter of right on a single subdivided lot that is not located in, or within twenty-five feet (25 ft.) of, a Residence District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2517.2.</num>
    <text>The number of principal buildings permitted by this section shall not be limited; provided, that the applicant for a permit to build submits satisfactory evidence that all the requirements of this chapter (such as use, height, bulk, and open spaces
      around each building), as provided by §§ 3202.2 and 3202.3 are met.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2517.3.</num>
    <text>If a principal building has no street frontage, as determined by dividing the subdivided lot into theoretical building sites for each principal building:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The front of the building shall be the side upon which the principal entrance is located;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Open space in front of the entrance shall be provided that is equivalent to the required rear yard in the zone district in which the building is located; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A rear yard shall be required.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2517.4.</num>
    <text>Where not in conflict with An Act to Regulate the Height of Buildings in the District of Columbia, approved June 1, 1910 (36 Stat. 452, as amended; D.C. Official Code §§ 6-601.01 to 6-601.09 (2001) (formerly codified at D.C. Code §§ 5-401 to 5-409
      (1994 Repl. and 1999 Supp.))), the height of a building governed by the provisions of this section, in all zone districts, shall be measured from the finished grade at the middle of the front of the building.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§ 7615 of the Zoning Regulations (April 1981); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 5847, 5850-5851 (August 11, 1989); and Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed
        Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8531-32 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>