<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2521</num>
  <heading>SOUTHWEST URBAN RENEWAL AREA (§ 11-2521)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2521.1.</num>
    <text>The following exceptions to development controls shall apply to specified properties located in the former Southwest Urban Renewal Area, an area geographically delineated and regulated for development by the District of Columbia Redevelopment Act
      of 1945, approved August 2, 1946 (60 Stat. 790, as amended; D.C. Official Code §§ 6-301.01 to 6-301.20 (2001) (formerly codified at D.C. Code §§ 5-801 to 5-820 (1994 Repl. and 1999 Supp.))), and the several Urban Renewal Plans adopted pursuant thereto,
      until the development controls expired in 1992 through 1996:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A lot in a W-1 District shall be permitted a maximum floor area ratio (FAR) of 2.0 for commercial or nonresidential uses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A lot in a W-1, R-3, R-5, or C-3 District shall be permitted to provide all or a portion of its parking requirements on a different lot; provided, that the required parking shall be located within three hundred feet (300 ft.) of any part of the
        lot that generates the parking requirements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>In a W-1 District, an addition to a hotel existing as of November 20, 1998 shall be permitted a maximum height of sixty-two feet (62 ft.) D.C. datum;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>In Square 536 in the C-3-C District, a building shall be permitted a maximum FAR of 8.0 and a lot occupancy of one hundred percent (100%); no rear or side yard requirement shall apply;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A building or structure that was built prior to November 20, 1998 that conformed to the height, area, and bulk provisions of the Urban Renewal Plans shall be considered a conforming structure under this title and in the event of fire, collapse,
        explosion, or act of God, may be built to its size as of November 20, 1998;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A building or structure that is constructed on a lot designated in the Urban Renewal Plan as P-1 through P-5 shall not exceed a height of twenty-two feet (22 ft.) above grade unless the Board of Zoning Adjustment, after public hearing, determines
        that the proposed height, bulk, and design are in harmony with existing uses and structures on neighboring property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>No development above grade shall be permitted on Lot 844 in Square 473 (the property designated P-6 in the Urban Renewal Plan for the Southwest Urban Renewal Area Project C). However, the density permitted on the property as a matter of right may
        be constructed elsewhere as transferable development rights (TDRs). These TDRs may be developed on property in the C-3-C District within TDR receiving zones; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>If part of the Waterside Mall property, comprising Lot 88 in Square 542 and Lot 60 in Square 499, is demolished so as to create a public right-of-way generally along the former right-of-way of 4th Street, S.W., so that the parts of the building
        to the east and west of right-of-way are no longer physically connected above grade, for zoning purposes all such improvements shall be deemed to be a single building.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 8184, 8187-88 (November 20, 1998); as corrected by Z.C. Order No. 807, Case No. 95-15/95-151, published at 46 DCR 1211, 1232 (February 12, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December
        8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8535-36 (October 20, 2000); and Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 9074, 9076 (October 4, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>