<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2502</num>
  <heading>PROJECTIONS INTO REQUIRED OPEN SPACES (§ 11-2502)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2502.1.</num>
    <text>Except for the projections and encroachments specified in this section and the exceptions in § 2503, every part of a required yard or court or other required open space shall be open and unobstructed to the sky.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.2.</num>
    <text>Cornices and eaves may project over any required yard or court for a distance not to exceed two feet (2 ft.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.3.</num>
    <text>Sills, leaders, belt courses, and similar ornamental or structural features may project over any required yard or court a distance not to exceed six inches (6 in.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.4</num>
    <text>2502.4 The ordinary projection of skylights above the bottom of a yard or court shall be permitted if placed so as not to obstruct light and ventilation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.5.</num>
    <text>Awnings serving a window, porch, or door may project into a required yard or open court for a distance not to exceed forty inches (40 in.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.6.</num>
    <text>An open or lattice-enclosed fire balcony or fire escape may project into a required yard or an open court for a distance not to exceed four feet (4 ft.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.7.</num>
    <text>A chimney, smokestack, or flue may project into any required rear yard, provided the horizontal section of the projection does not exceed five square feet (5 ft.2).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.8.</num>
    <text>A chimney, smokestack, or flue may project into any required side yard for a distance not to exceed two feet (2 ft.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.9.</num>
    <text>A self-contained room air conditioner may project into any required yard or court a distance not to exceed two feet (2 ft.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§§ 7503 et seq.. of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958 (renumbered §§ 7602.1 et seq. in the April 1981 edition of the Zoning Regulations); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by
        reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8526 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>