<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3330</num>
  <heading>DECISIONS OF A BOARD (ยง 17-3330)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3330.1.</num>
    <text>A board shall render a decision, in writing, no later than ninety (90) days after the date the hearing is completed, unless the Act listed in ยง 3300.1 provides for another period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3330.2.</num>
    <text>A board may, with the agreement of all parties, extend the period in which it is required to render a decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3330.3.</num>
    <text>A decision of a board adverse to a respondent shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Findings of fact;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Conclusions of law based upon the findings of fact and application of the laws;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An order; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A statement informing the respondent of the right to have the decision reviewed by the District of Columbia Court of Appeals, and the time within which judicial review is required to be sought according to the rules of that Court.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3330.4.</num>
    <text>A board, in addition to taking other disciplinary action, may revoke an expired license if the decision is based on conduct that occurred while the license was in effect.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3330.5.</num>
    <text>The chairperson of a board may sign an order, decision, or other document of the board on behalf of the board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3330.6.</num>
    <text>Within ten (10) days after a decision is rendered, a board shall serve a copy of the written decision upon the respondent, or the respondent&amp;#8217;s counsel of record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3330.7.</num>
    <text>A board shall issue its findings of fact, conclusions of law, and order in writing except when it determines that the interest of the health, safety, or welfare of the public require that the findings of fact, conclusions of law, or order of the board
      be issued orally.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3330.8.</num>
    <text>Oral findings of fact, conclusions of law, and an order issued in accordance in ยง 3330.7 are final and shall be recorded as final at the time they are communicated to the parties. Promptly thereafter, a board shall state its oral findings of fact,
      conclusions of law, and order in writing, and the chairperson shall sign the written decision and serve a copy on all parties or their attorneys of record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3330.9.</num>
    <text>A board may, on motion by a respondent, stay the imposition of an order pending appeal or reconsideration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3488, 3511 (May 13, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>