<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3309</num>
  <heading>REINSTATEMENT AFTER REVOCATION (ยง 17-3309)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3309.1.</num>
    <text>A person whose license to practice an occupation or profession has been revoked, or whose application for reinstatement has been denied, shall be ineligible to apply for reinstatement for a period of one (1) year from the date of the revocation or
      denial unless otherwise provided in the order of revocation or denial.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3309.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant for reinstatement under this section shall file an application with a board on the prescribed form and shall pay the required reinstatement fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3309.3.</num>
    <text>In addition to the requirements of ยง 3309.2, an applicant for reinstatement shall demonstrate fitness to resume practice by submitting evidence satisfactory to a board that the applicant has the integrity, competency, and knowledge of District and
      federal laws necessary to resume practice, and that the applicant&amp;#8217;s resumption of practice will not be detrimental to the public interest or the integrity of the applicant&amp;#8217;s occupation or profession.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3309.4.</num>
    <text>In making a determination pursuant to ยง 3309.3, a board may consider, among other factors, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The nature and circumstances of the conduct, or the mental or physical condition, for which the applicant&amp;#8217;s license was revoked;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s recognition and appreciation of the seriousness of any misconduct;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s conduct, or mental or physical condition, since the revocation, including steps taken by the applicant to remedy prior misconduct and prevent future misconduct, or to remedy the mental or physical condition;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The length of time that the applicant had practiced in the District or another jurisdiction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The length of time after expiration of the applicant&amp;#8217;s license that the applicant was not practicing either in the District or another jurisdiction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s present character; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s present qualification and competency to practice the occupation or profession.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3309.5.</num>
    <text>A board may require an applicant to complete specified educational or training requirements, in addition to any continuing education requirements, prior to or after reinstatement, to ensure that the applicant is competent to practice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3488, 3495 (May 13, 1088).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>