<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2002</num>
  <heading>NONCONFORMING USES WITHIN STRUCTURES (§ 11-2002)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2002.1.</num>
    <text>The restrictions set forth in this section and §§ 2003 and 2004 shall apply to nonconforming uses within structures, whether the structure is conforming or nonconforming.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2002.2.</num>
    <text>Where the nonconforming use occupies only a portion of the structure, the restrictions in this section and §§ 2003 and 2004 shall apply only to that part of the structure devoted to the nonconforming use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2002.3.</num>
    <text>A nonconforming use shall not be extended to portions of a structure not devoted to that nonconforming use at the time of enactment or amendment of this title, or to another structure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2002.4.</num>
    <text>Ordinary repairs, alterations, or modernizations may be made to a structure or portion of a structure devoted to a nonconforming use. Structural alterations shall not be allowed, except those required by other municipal law or regulation; provided,
      that structural alterations shall be permitted to a lawfully existing, nonconforming flat or apartment house located within a Residence District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2002.5.</num>
    <text>A structure devoted to a nonconforming use shall not be enlarged, except if the enlargement is to be devoted to a conforming use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2002.6.</num>
    <text>A new structure shall not be erected to house a nonconforming use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§ 7106.1 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 30 DCR 3922, 3925 (August 5, 1983); and Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text
        of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8496 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>