<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-215</num>
  <heading>EVIDENCE OF COVERAGE (ยง 7-215)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>215.1.</num>
    <text>Carriers shall provide the Office with evidence of coverage by filing a completed Notice of Workers&amp;#8217; Compensation Coverage as soon as possible after completion of arrangements to provide coverage, but no later than ten (10) working days
      after date of binder issued in the Mid-Atlantic Council region.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>215.2.</num>
    <text>An additional period of time not to exceed thirty (30) working days may be granted to carriers filing a Notice of Coverage where a binder has been issued in another jurisdiction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>215.3.</num>
    <text>Coverage shall become effective by the date indicated on the notice, which is the date on which a carrier becomes legally bound as to a risk.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>215.4.</num>
    <text>Notice shall be given in terms of coverage, not policy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>215.5.</num>
    <text>Notice shall be filed with the Office upon rewriting or renewal of coverage.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>215.6.</num>
    <text>The reason for notice shall be correctly indicated on the notice. Notice shall be filed on the prescribed form and defect as to form or contents shall render filing invalid, except as to coverage.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>215.7.</num>
    <text>Carriers desiring acknowledgement of filing of notice with the Office shall request return of receipt of certified mail from the U.S. Postal Service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>215.8.</num>
    <text>Agencies desiring a copy of notice shall be accommodated upon request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>215.9.</num>
    <text>Notice of ordinary coverage applicable to an employer who has two (2) or more establishments or job sites (Construction) in the District of Columbia shall be made on Supplemental Notice of Information form with respect to the parent company or home
      office, whether in or out of the District of Columbia, and shall be filed with the Office within sixty (60) days of coverage.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 3213 (June 3, 1994).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>