<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-259</num>
  <heading>TRANSMISSION OF THE OFFICIAL RECORD (ยง 7-259)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>259.1.</num>
    <text>Simultaneously with the issuance of the Notice of Application for Review under section 258.5 of these rules, the Clerk of the Board shall direct the custodian of the record to immediately forward to the Board the official evidentiary record of the
      case.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>259.2.</num>
    <text>The official record shall include the compensation order, the transcripts of all formal proceedings, exhibits, and other evidence of record, and any other such matters as shall be indicated.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>259.3.</num>
    <text>The &amp;#8220;custodian of the record&amp;#8221; is the individual responsible for the official records in the Administrative Hearings Division or the Office of Workers&amp;#8217; Compensation, depending on which entity issued the compensation order
      or final decision under appeal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>259.4.</num>
    <text>The custodian of the record shall certify and deliver to the Clerk of the Board the official record of the case within seven (7) working days of the date of issuance of the Notice of Application for Review.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>259.5.</num>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Working days&amp;#8221; is defined by 7 DCMR 299 as &amp;#8220;the District of Columbia Government business days, excluding Saturdays, Sundays and legal holidays.&amp;#8221;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>259.6.</num>
    <text>When the Clerk has received the official record of the case and the response from the party(ies) opposing the Application for Review, but in no event later than fifteen (15) working days from the date of receipt of the Application for Review, the
      Clerk of the Board shall certify to the Chief Administrative Appeals Judge that the appeal is perfected.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 8405 (September 9, 2005) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 11093 (December 23, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>