<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2010</num>
  <heading>DENIAL, SUSPENSION, AND REVOCATION OF LICENSES (§ 17-2010)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2010.1.</num>
    <text>The license of each private detective shall be subject to denial, suspension, or revocation for violation of any section of this chapter that is applicable to that license or business or for violation of any of the terms of D.C. Code, §47-2839, and
      upon any grounds set forth in regulation or statute, including, without limitation, any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Material misstatement in the application for license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Failure or refusal to comply with any statute or regulation governing the carrying on of the business of a private detective;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Conviction of false pretenses, larceny after trust, embezzlement, or any other offense involving (in the judgment of the Mayor) fraudulent conduct, arising out of or based on employment as a private detective; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Willful or fraudulent circumvention of any statute or regulation related to the conduct of the business of private detective.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2010.2.</num>
    <text>Whenever the Mayor proposes to deny, suspend, or revoke a private detective&amp;#8217;s license, the Mayor shall give the applicant or licensee notice which meets all of the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The notice shall be in writing and be signed by the Mayor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The notice shall state the ultimate facts constituting each violation or other basis for the action proposed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The notice shall indicate, where applicable, each provision of statute or regulation violated or not complied with;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The notice shall state the proposed adverse action; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The notice shall advise that the proposed action may be appealed as provided in § 2012, and of the time within which the appeal must be filed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Sections 12 and 13(a) of Regulation 70-30, approved July 9, 1970 (17 DCR 40), 5EE DCRR, §§ 4.1 and 4.2(a).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>