<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2000</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 17-2000)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2000.1.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this chapter, the term &amp;#8220;private detective&amp;#8221; means any person (whether self-employed or employed by others), firm, or corporation which is engaged in the business of, or advertises or represents himself, herself,
      or itself as being engaged in any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The business of detecting, discovering, or revealing crime or criminals;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The business of securing information for evidence relating to crime or criminals; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The business of discovering or revealing the identity, whereabouts, character, or actions of any person(s) or thing(s).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2000.2.</num>
    <text>The term &amp;#8220;private detective,&amp;#8221; as defined in §2000.1, shall not include persons who are employed as uniformed guards or uniformed security personnel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2000.3.</num>
    <text>No person shall be licensed as a private detective unless the Chief of Police of the Metropolitan Police Department of the District of Columbia or his or her designee (also referred to as the &amp;#8220;Chief of Police&amp;#8221;) certifies to the
      Mayor that the Chief of Police approves of the issuance of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2000.4.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in §2000.5, each license issued under this chapter shall be effective for one (1) license year beginning on November 1st of the year issued and continuing until the following October 31st.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2000.5.</num>
    <text>A license issued after the beginning of a license year shall date from the first day of the month in which the license is issued and shall expire on the next succeeding October 31st.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2000.6.</num>
    <text>No licensed private detective shall represent himself or herself, or engage in business as a private detective, under any name other than the name appearing on his or her license; Provided, that this provision shall not prevent the use of a trade
      name if that trade name is contained in the license application approved by the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2000.7.</num>
    <text>Any person who engages in business as a private detective without having a license then in effect shall be punished by a fine of not more than three hundred dollars ($ 300) or by imprisonment for not more than ninety (90) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is Paragraph 41(d) of Section 7 of An Act making appropriations to provide for the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1903, and for other purposes, approved
        July 1, 1902, 32 Stat. 590 (622), as amended by An Act approved July 1, 1932, 47 Stat. 550, ch. 366, D.C. Code §§ 47-2838 and 47-2844 (1987 Repl. Vol.).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Sections 1(c), 4, 5, 8, and 15 of Regulation 70-30, approved July 9, 1970 (17 DCR 40), 5EE DCRR, §§ 1.1(c), 2.3, 3.4, and 5.2.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>