<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2004</num>
  <heading>INVESTIGATION OF APPLICANTS AND LICENSEES (ยง 17-2004)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2004.1.</num>
    <text>The Mayor is authorized, in connection with consideration of license applications, and from time to time during the license year, to require an applicant for a license or a licensee to make available to the Mayor, during the regular business hours,
      any information that the Mayor considers necessary to determine or verify whether the applicant or licensee has violated or failed to comply with any provision of any statute or regulation relating to the obtaining or retention of a private detective&amp;#8217;s
      license or to the conduct of activities as a private detective.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2004.2.</num>
    <text>Investigation by the Mayor may include determination or verification of the identity of any person associated with the applicant or with any licensee in the private detective business, and the extent, if any, of that person&amp;#8217;s control, either
      directly or indirectly, of the applicant or over the business activities of the licensee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2004.3.</num>
    <text>The following shall be grounds for denial, suspension, or revocation of a license:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Failure to make requested information available to the Mayor or to furnish to the Mayor any information that the Mayor is authorized to request under this section; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Failure to furnish to the Mayor, or to permit the Mayor to make one (1) or more copies of records maintained by the applicant or licensee that the Mayor may specify.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 7 of Regulation 70-30, approved July 9, 1970 (17 DCR 40), 5EE DCRR, ยง 3.3.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>