<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-1006</num>
  <heading>DEALER&amp;#8217;S LICENSE (§ 16-1006)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1006.1.</num>
    <text>Each junk dealer or Class A dealer, or Class C dealer in secondhand personal property shall make application to the Mayor annually for license to conduct that business.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1006.2.</num>
    <text>The application shall be sent to the Chief of Police for a report on the character of the applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1006.3.</num>
    <text>Each application for a junk shop license shall be sent to the Commissioner of Public Health for a report on the surroundings where the business will be conducted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1006.4.</num>
    <text>Each application for a junk shop license where rags and similar fabrics are to be handled shall be sent to the Commissioner of Public Health and to the Fire Marshal for reports on the surroundings where the business is to be conducted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1006.5.</num>
    <text>The completed report(s) shall be sent to the Mayor for action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1006.6.</num>
    <text>Each applicant shall have three (3) sets of fingerprints taken by the Metropolitan Police Department. Fingerprints so furnished shall become a part of the application. An applicant who, within the past five (5) years, has received a District of Columbia
      business license after having submitted their fingerprints to the Metropolitan Police Department as a condition of receiving or renewing either a secondhand dealer business license or any other category of a District of Columbia business license
      shall be exempt from complying with this subsection and §§ 1006.7 and 1006.8.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1006.7.</num>
    <text>All of the partners in the case of a partnership, and the president, vice president, secretary, and treasurer of a corporation shall be required to comply with the provisions of § 1006.6. Fingerprints so taken shall be submitted to the Federal Bureau
      of Investigation, and to such other and further authorities as the Chief of Police may deem advisable, for comparison and record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1006.8.</num>
    <text>Any of the persons listed in §§ 1006.6 and 1006.7 who is not a legal resident of the District shall have his or her fingerprints taken by the Metropolitan Police Department or by the police department or comparable authority where he or she is a resident.
      Fingerprints, when taken by other than the Metropolitan Police Department, shall be attached to and accompanied by an affidavit of the authority taking the fingerprints which states that the fingerprints are the fingerprints of the applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 5 of Article 1 of the Police Regulations; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 11001, 11003 (September 21, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>