<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-1008</num>
  <heading>CLASS B DEALER REQUIREMENTS AND RESTRICTIONS (ยง 16-1008)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1008.1.</num>
    <text>It shall be unlawful for any person, firm or corporation primarily engaged in the business of dealing in new personal property in the District of Columbia to accept used personal property, other than motor vehicles, in trade or part payment for any
      merchandise without first obtaining a Class B secondhand dealer&amp;#8217;s license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1008.2.</num>
    <text>Each Class B secondhand dealer shall keep at his or her place of business a record of each transaction involving used personal property setting forth the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An accurate and complete description of the goods, article, or thing received in trade or part payment for other merchandise;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The date of receipt;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The name, sex, color, and address of the person from whom acquired; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the person, corporation, or firm which ultimately purchases or receives the property from the dealer.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1008.3.</num>
    <text>Whenever any secondhand personal property so acquired is to be sold at retail, is to be sent out of the District of Columbia, or is to be retained by the licensee for the licensee&amp;#8217;s own use, the licensee shall, not less than fifteen (15)
      days prior to selling the property, removing it from the District of Columbia, or using the property for personal purposes, deliver to the Chief of Police, on blank forms prescribed by the Mayors, a legible and correct transcript from the record
      required under this section relating to the property to be sold at retail, removed from the District of Columbia, or retained for use by the licensee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1008.4.</num>
    <text>All used personal property covered by this section shall be kept separate and distinct from other merchandise, and its character or identify shall not be changed or destroyed until after the expiration of fifteen (15) days from the time the required
      report has been made to the Chief of Police.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>