<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-1615</num>
  <heading>CONDUCT OF HEARING (ยง 17-1615)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1615.1.</num>
    <text>Every hearing shall be open to the public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1615.2.</num>
    <text>In connection with any hearing held pursuant to this chapter, the hearing examiner shall have the following powers:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>To request the Director to appoint a representative to present the Department&amp;#8217;s case at the hearing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>To administer oaths or affirmations to witnesses called to testify;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>To subpoena witnesses, relevant books, papers, and documents;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>To take testimony;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>To examine witnesses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>To rule on motions and objections;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>To direct the continuance of any case;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>To establish a timetable for the submission of proposed findings of fact, conclusions of law, and decision by the parties; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>To make proposed findings of fact and conclusions of law and to recommend a decision to the Director.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1615.3.</num>
    <text>The hearing examiner shall receive and consider any evidence or testimony. However, the hearing examiner shall exclude irrelevant, immaterial, or unduly repetitious evidence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1615.4.</num>
    <text>In any hearing resulting from the Director&amp;#8217;s contemplated action to deny licensure, the applicant for licensure shall have the burden of satisfying the hearing examiner of the applicant&amp;#8217;s qualifications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1615.5.</num>
    <text>In any hearing resulting from the Director&amp;#8217;s contemplated action to refuse to renew, to suspend, or to revoke a license, or to refuse to transfer or restore a license, to impose a fine, or to order restitution, the Department shall have
      the burden of proving that such action should be taken.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1615.6.</num>
    <text>In all hearings, a complete record shall be made of all evidence presented during the course of the hearing. Any party to the proceedings upon request shall be furnished with a copy of the record, or any part of the record, upon payment of the cost
      of producing or reproducing the record or part of the record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1615.7.</num>
    <text>The hearing examiner shall take all necessary steps to insure that all Department employees who are called by a party as witnesses are present for the hearing; Provided, that the party has submitted their names and titles in writing to the hearing
      examiner at least three (3) business days in advance of the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 3165, 3173 (May 15, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>