<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-3903</num>
  <heading>DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION (§ 15-3903)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3903.1.</num>
    <text>An energy utility shall not disclose any customer-specific information obtained in connection with the provision of regulated utility services except upon written consent of the utility customer. The consent form signed by the utility customer shall
      state the purpose of the disclosure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3903.2.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the limitations in subsection 3903.1, customer-specific information may be disclosed for lawful bill collection or credit reporting purposes, pursuant to a subpoena or request by a duly authorized law enforcement official, or pursuant
      to a lawful request authorized by local or federal law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3903.3.</num>
    <text>Any information provided by an energy utility to a core service affiliate(s) with respect to its electric or gas system, the marketing or sale of energy to customers or potential customers, or the delivery of energy to or on its system, shall be contemporaneously
      disclosed to all non-affiliated energy suppliers or potential non-affiliated energy suppliers on its system.</text>
    <text>Disclosure of such information must be published on the energy utility’s electronic bulletin board or equivalent mechanism used to communicate with licensed energy providers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3903.4.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the limitations in subsection 3903.3 above, an energy utility may disclose the following information without making the disclosure publicly available:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Information to an energy supplier, whether affiliated or non- affiliated, disclosed in the administration of a contract to supply Standard Offer Service;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Information to an energy supplier, whether affiliated or non- affiliated, concerning the energy supplier&amp;#8217;s customer that is necessary for the energy supplier to bill or provide services to its customers; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Information disclosed to the energy utility’s affiliate(s) required for the affiliate(s) to comply with federal and state laws and regulations, including those relating to financial reporting and corporate governance.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 1109, 1112 (February 4, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>