<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-206</num>
  <heading>SEWAGE ALLOWANCES FOR INDUSTRIAL AND COMMERCIAL USERS (§ 21-206)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>206.1.</num>
    <text>A commercial or industrial property may be eligible for a sewer allowance when the amount of water discharged into the District&amp;#8217;s sewer is less than the amount of water it receives from the District&amp;#8217;s water distribution system.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>206.2.</num>
    <text>The following two (2) methods shall be used to determine the extent and amount of the sewer allowance:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Metered Allowance: A sewer allowance will be granted to industrial and commercial users based on the total measured amount of water supplied by the District that does not enter the District&amp;#8217;s sewer system; Provided that the owner installs
        the necessary meters or devices, at no cost to the District, as indicated in this subsection:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A separate meter is installed to measure the amount of water used that will not be discharged in the District&amp;#8217;s sewer system;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>There is a security device that prevents tapping into the water supply; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A device is installed that recirculates the water supply or prohibits water from being discharged into or entering the District&amp;#8217;s sewer system, including runoff and wind-blown water; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Flat Allowance: Commercial and industrial properties that have recycling cooling systems will be granted a sewer allowance based on the number of gallons of water circulated per minute.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>206.3.</num>
    <text>The flat allowance shall be subtracted from the sewer service charge only during the period May 15th to October 15th of each year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>206.4.</num>
    <text>To extend the period for the flat allowance, property owners shall submit a written request and justification. The request must be approved by the Chief before it can go into effect.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>206.5.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of a written request for a sewer allowance, the Chief shall conduct an audit of the property to determine whether and the conditions under which, the property is eligible for a sewer allowance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>206.6.</num>
    <text>Owners of commercial and industrial properties shall be notified in writing whether the properties are eligible for a sewer allowance and the amount of any sewer allowance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>206.7.</num>
    <text>Commercial and industrial property owners shall allow the Bureau access to audit water use and to verify that the amount is not being discharged into the District&amp;#8217;s sewer system.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>206.8.</num>
    <text>During any period when the owner or occupant of eligible property fails to permit an audit under this section, all privileges associated with the sewer allowance shall be forfeited and the charges for sewer service shall be based on the full amount
      of water received by the property from the District water supply system.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 1300, 1301 (February 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 5358 (June 18, 1999).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL NOTE</heading>
      <text>Prior to February 12, 1993, the Department of Environmental Services published Final Rulemaking at 29 DCR 1822 (April 30, 1982); 12 DCRR §§500.1(l) &amp;#8211; (m), 504.1(a) &amp;#8211; (b) (October 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>