<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-202</num>
  <heading>MAINTENANCE AND REPAIR OF SEWER PIPES (§ 21-202)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>202.1.</num>
    <text>This section and §203 are promulgated in accordance with D.C. Code §6-405 (1995 Repl. Vol.), under authority set forth in D.C. Code §6-405(g) (1995 Repl. Vol.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.2.</num>
    <text>The Department shall maintain all public sewer pipes from the street sewers to the property line.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.3.</num>
    <text>If a portion of the structure (such as a porch, vault, or footing) projects beyond the property line, the Department shall maintain the sewer connection only to the outermost structural projection of the premises.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.4.</num>
    <text>All pipes and appurtenances on private property shall be maintained by and at the expense of the property owner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.5.</num>
    <text>When action is necessary to expedite or facilitate the maintenance of a sewer connection, the Department may perform maintenance or repair work on private property if agreed to in advance by the property owner. The cost of the work, including overhead
      expenses, shall be paid by the property owner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.6.</num>
    <text>Excavations in public space made and left open by the Department for the use or convenience of registered plumbers employed by private owners or other parties for the repair of sewer pipes or other sewer appurtenances, shall be promptly reported to
      the police division or precinct with jurisdiction over the area of excavation by telephone, and followed by written confirmation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 23, §7 of the Police Regulations; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 24 DCR 4651 (December 2. 1977), incorporating text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 24 DCR 3060, 3061 (October 21, 1977); 12 DCRR §§503.4(a)-(b), (October 1981);
        as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 5358 (June 18, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>