<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-201</num>
  <heading>TAMPERING AND OTHER. MISUSE OF PUBLIC SEWERS (§ 21-201)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>201.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall throw or deposit in or upon any public sewer or any trap, basin, inlet, grating, manhole, or other appurtenances of any public sewer in the District any sticks, stones, brick, coal, earth, gravel, dirt, mud, hay, straw, manure, rubbish,
      litter, sweepings, offal, vegetables, garbage, trees, shrubs, branches, twigs, leaves, papers, cinders, or refuse matter of any kind.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.2.</num>
    <text>The provisions of §201.1 shall not apply to matter discharged through a house sewer into a public sewer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.3.</num>
    <text>No person shall make or maintain any connection with any public sewer or public sewer appurtenance which could allow any hot, suffocating, corrosive, inflammable, or explosive liquid, gas, vapor, substance, or material of any kind to be conveyed into
      that sewer or sewer appurtenance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.4.</num>
    <text>No person shall cause to enter or flow into any public sewer or sewer appurtenance any hot, corrosive, suffocating, explosive, or inflammable liquid, gas, vapor, substance, or material of any kind.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.5.</num>
    <text>The provisions of §§201.3 and 201.4 shall not apply to water that is discharged from ordinary hot-water boilers or residences.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.6.</num>
    <text>No person shall break or damage any appurtenance of any public sewer or part of a public sewer appurtenance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.7.</num>
    <text>No person shall obstruct, impede, the flow of any public sewer or case that flow to be impeded or obstructed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.8.</num>
    <text>No person shall interfere with the free discharge or ventilation of a public sewer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.9.</num>
    <text>No person shall clog up any appurtenance of a public sewer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.10.</num>
    <text>Violation of any provision of this section shall be punishable, upon conviction, by fine not to exceed three hundred dollars ($300).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 3, §§12, 17 through and 19, and Article 30, §4 of the Police Regulations (May 1981); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 5358 (June 18, 1999).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR&amp;#8217;S NOTE</heading>
      <text>D.C. Law 6-76, Wastewater System Regulation Temporary Act of 1985, 32 DCR 6478 (November 15, 1985) repealed 21 DCMR §201. This Act expired on the 180th day following the effective date (January 25, 1986) of the law. D.C Law 6-95, Wastewater System
        Regulation Amendment Act of 1985 superseded the provisions of D.C. Law 6-76.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>