<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2801</num>
  <heading>ELIGIBILITY FOR LOANS AND GRANTS (§ 14-2801)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2801.1.</num>
    <text>Rehabilitation loans and grants may be made for residential properties within the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2801.2.</num>
    <text>[Deleted]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2801.3.</num>
    <text>In order to be eligible, a dwelling shall be in need of repair or rehabilitation to correct housing code violations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2801.4.</num>
    <text>Eligible residential properties shall include owner-occupied, single family properties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2801.5.</num>
    <text>Each applicant for an amortized or deferred loan shall meet the following conditions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An applicant shall not be able to qualify, as determined by DHCD, for the full loan amount required for the rehabilitation of his or her property from a private lending institution participating in the leveraging program or from a lending institution
        referred to the applicant by DHCD; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An applicant shall show evidence of capacity to repay the loan and shall meet reasonable credit standards.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2801.6.</num>
    <text>Applicants shall be eligible to receive grants as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>For grants of up to $ 30,000 to pay for modifications to a home to allow accessibility to mobility-impaired occupants, an applicant must provide physician&amp;#8217;s evidence of need on forms prescribed by the Department.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For grants to correct lead-based paint hazards, an applicant shall have lead-based paint hazards identified in the home by a certified lead-based paint risk assessor.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2801.7.</num>
    <text>Each applicant for loan or grant assistance shall show evidence of ownership by title, deed, recorded land installment contract, an executed contract of sale, or a purchase option.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2801.8.</num>
    <text>Each applicant shall agree to permit all inspections of the property as deemed necessary by DHCD to ensure the quality of rehabilitation work and compliance with D.C. laws and regulations, to make contractor payments, and to ensure continuing compliance
      with D.C. laws and regulations during the life of the loan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2801.9.</num>
    <text>Each applicant shall agree to sign DHCD&amp;#8217;s standard contract document for rehabilitation contract work and DHCD&amp;#8217;s standard loan and/or grant documents.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2801.10.</num>
    <text>Each applicant shall agree to receive counseling relating to his or her loan and/or grant prior to settlement. Counseling agencies have been identified by DHCD.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2801.11.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall not be permitted to settle on the loan unless the applicant has received counseling. A certificate shall be issued to each applicant upon completion of counseling.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2801.12.</num>
    <text>Each applicant shall acquire an applicant’s guide from DHCD.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2801.13.</num>
    <text>[Deleted]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2801.14.</num>
    <text>[Deleted]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 29 DCR 5394 (December 10, 1982); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 32 DCR 329 (January 18, 1985); as amended by Notice of Emergency Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 10182,10183 (November
        28, 2003); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 11061,11062 (December 3, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>