<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-2605</num>
  <heading>PENALTIES (ยง 20-2605)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2605.1.</num>
    <text>A manufacturer or wholesale dealer who knowingly fails to comply with the provisions of the Act or of this chapter shall be subject to a civil penalty not to exceed ten thousand dollars ($10,000) for each violation and not to exceed one hundred thousand
      dollars ($100,000) for all violations within a thirty (30) day period. Each day of violation shall constitute a separate offense. This penalty shall apply for a violation of D.C. Official Code ยง 7-1755(b) for each day after the sixtieth (60th) day
      of noncompliance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2605.2.</num>
    <text>A retail dealer who knowingly fails to comply with the provisions of the Act or of this chapter shall be subject to a civil penalty not to exceed five thousand dollars ($5,000) for each violation and not to exceed twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000)
      for all violations within a thirty (30) day period. Each day of violation shall constitute a separate offense.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2605.3.</num>
    <text>A manufacturer that knowingly makes a false certification under ยง 2603.1 shall be subject to a minimum civil penalty of seventy-five thousand dollars ($75,000) and a maximum civil penalty of two hundred and fifty thousand dollars ($250,000) for each
      knowing false certification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2605.4.</num>
    <text>The Chief, law enforcement personnel, or other duly authorized representatives of the Mayor may seize and take possession of cigarettes that do not bear proper markings as required by ยง 2603. Cigarettes seized pursuant to this subsection shall be
      turned over to the Attorney General for forfeiture to the District and destruction. Before cigarettes seized under this section are destroyed, the true holder of the trademark rights in the cigarette brand may inspect the cigarettes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 10012 (September 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>