<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>9-111</num>
  <heading>INFORMATION RETURNS (§ 9-111)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>111.1.</num>
    <text>Each person making payments of fixed or determinable income of six hundred dollars ($ 600) or more in the aggregate in any calendar year to a resident shall render a return of the payments for that year on or before February 28th of the following
      year, except as specified in §§ 111.2 and 111.9.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>111.2.</num>
    <text>Payments of the following character, although amounting to six hundred dollars ($ 600) or more during a calendar year, need not be reported in information returns:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Payments of income to non-residents;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Payments of income upon which District income tax has been withheld at the source;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Payments which, under the provisions of § 2(a) of Title 3 of the Act, do not constitute gross income to the recipient;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Payments by a broker to the broker&amp;#8217;s customers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any type payments made to corporations or financial institutions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Bills paid for merchandise, telegrams, telephone, freight storage, and similar charges;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Payments of rent made to real estate agents (but the agent must report payments to the landlord if the amount paid during the calendar year was six hundred dollars ($ 600); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Salaries and profits paid or distributed by a partnership to the individual partners.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>111.3.</num>
    <text>In order to make necessary a return of information, the income shall be fixed or determinable, it need not be annual or periodical.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>111.4.</num>
    <text>An amount is considered paid to the recipient when it is credited or set apart for the recipient without any substantial limitation or restriction on the time or manner of payment or condition under which payment is to be made.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>111.5.</num>
    <text>A return shall be made in each case on Form D-99, accompanied by Form D-96 showing the number of returns filed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>111.6.</num>
    <text>A copy of Federal Form 1099 or W-2 may be submitted instead of Form D-99.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>111.7.</num>
    <text>Form D-99 which has been approved by the Deputy Chief Financial Officer shall show the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the person making payments;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the recipient and the recipient&amp;#8217;s social security number. If the present address is unknown, the last known address shall be given; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The nature and total amount of the payments.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>111.8.</num>
    <text>If the District of Columbia agrees to participate in the combined Federal/State Information Reporting Program, a taxpayer complying with the Federal information requirements shall be deemed to have complied with the requirements for filing District
      information returns.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>111.9.</num>
    <text>Each person making payments of interest or dividends (as those terms are respectively defined in §§ 6042(b) and 6049(b) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954) of ten dollars ($ 10) or more in the aggregate in any calendar year to a resident shall render
      a return of the payments for that year on or before February 28th of the following year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order 56-1431 effective July 24, 1956, 16 DCRR §§ 304.2, 304.3 and 304.4; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 5393 (December 18, 1981), incorporating text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 4112 (September
        18, 1991); by Final Rulemaking published at 30 DCR 1922, 1933 (April 29. 1983); and by Final Rulemaking published at 32 DCR 1354, 1356 (March 8, 1985).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>