<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6502</num>
  <heading>EDUCATIONAL AND TRAINING REQUIREMENTS (§ 17-6502)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6502.1.</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, an applicant shall furnish proof satisfactory to the Board, in accordance with §504(i) of the Act, D.C. Code §2-3305.4(i) (1988), of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That the applicant has successfully completed an educational program in the practice of pharmacy and holds a Bachelor of Science or Doctor of Pharmacy degree from a school of pharmacy accredited by the American Council of Pharmaceutical Education
        (ACPE) at the time the applicant graduates; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That the applicant has successfully completed a pharmacy internship consisting of one of the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>One thousand (1,000) hours of pre-licensure professional practice in a program administered by a college of pharmacy accredited by ACPE at the time the applicant does the internship; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>One thousand five hundred (1,500) hours of independent pre-licensure professional practice under the supervision of a licensed pharmacist who uses the standards for pre-licensure professional practice described in §6502.2; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Two (2) rotations totaling six hundred and sixty (660) hours of prelicensure professional practice administered by a college of pharmacy accredited by ACPE at the time the applicant does the internship and five hundred and ten (510) hours of independent
        pre-licensure professional practice under the supervision of a licensed pharmacist who uses the standards for pre-licensure professional practice described in §6502.2.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6502.2.</num>
    <text>The Board shall give credit for independent pre-licensure professional practice required by §§6502.1(b)(2) and (3) if it meets the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Seventy percent (70%) of the work was spent performing the following pharmacy tasks:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Filling prescriptions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Compounding drugs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Evaluating prescriptions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Handling controlled substances;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Handling toxic drugs and substances;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Substituting generic drugs for brand name drugs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Storing and packaging drugs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Instructing patients;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Maintaining prescription records; and</text>
    </level>
    <text>(10) Handling veterinarian products;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A student who is enrolled in a school of pharmacy may be given credit only for hours of work performed during school breaks or vacations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Work performed in the following areas is subject to a maximum of five hundred (500) hours of credit:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Work-study in industry or government;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Research; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Community service projects;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Credit shall not be given for more than forty (40) hours of pre-licensure professional practice hours per week; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Credit for pre-licensure professional practice performed in the District of Columbia shall:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Not begin to accrue until the Board has registered the intern in accordance with the procedures set forth in § 6509 of this chapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Only be given for pre-licensure professional practice hours performed as part of a formalized internship program and under the supervision of the individual&amp;#8217;s assigned preceptor.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6502.3.</num>
    <text>For independent pre-licensure practice hours completed in the District of Columbia, the Board shall only give credit for the independent pre-licensure professional practice required by §§ 6502.1(b)(2) and (3) if it meets the requirements set forth
      in § 6502.2 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6502.4.</num>
    <text>For independent pre-licensure practice hours completed outside of the District of Columbia, the Board shall recognize the hours and apply the hours to the applicant&amp;#8217;s required total for licensure only if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The hours have been certified in writing by the Board of Pharmacy of the state in which they were obtained; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The hours were performed within two years from the date of the application for registration in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6502.5.</num>
    <text>Starting with the graduating class of 2014, in addition to the requirements of § 6502.1(b) of this chapter, each applicant for a pharmacist license shall submit proof of having completed an additional four hundred (400) hours of independent pre-licensure
      practice in a pharmacy setting with the emphasis being on the distribution of medicines and prescriptions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6243 (September 1, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 4330 (April 18, 2008); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11178 (November 26, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>