<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6507</num>
  <heading>LICENSE BY RECIPROCITY WITH WAIVER OF LICENSURE TRANSFER FORM (ยง 17-6507)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6507.1.</num>
    <text>Only applicants who were previously licensed in the District of Columbia to practice pharmacy may apply for licensure by reciprocity with waiver of licensure transfer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6507.2.</num>
    <text>To apply for a license by reciprocity with waiver of licensure transfer form, an applicant shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Submit a completed application to the Board on the required forms and include:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s social security number on the application. If the applicant does not have a social security number, the applicant shall:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Submit with the application a sworn affidavit, under penalty of perjury, stating that he or she does not have a social security number; and</text>
    </level>
    <text>(ii) Submit proof acceptable to the Board that he or she is legally authorized to be in the United States, such as a Certificate of Citizenship or Naturalization, Resident Alien Card, a valid foreign passport with a visa; or a work permit card from
      the Department of Homeland Security (I-766 or I-688B).</text>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Two (2) recent passport-type photographs of the applicant&amp;#8217;s face measuring two inches by two inches (2&amp;#8243; x 2&amp;#8243;), which clearly expose the area from the top of the forehead to the bottom of the chin; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>One (1) clear photocopy of a U.S. government-issued photo ID, such as a driver&amp;#8217;s license, as proof of identity.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Submit proof acceptable to the Board of previous licensure in the District of Columbia to practice pharmacy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Submit verification of current licensure in good standing in another state to practice pharmacy; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Pay all required fees.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6243, 6249 (September 1, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 4330 (April 18, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>