<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-2508</num>
  <heading>SPECIAL PERMITS (§ 18-2508)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2508.1.</num>
    <text>The Director, in his or her discretion, upon application in writing and good cause being shown, may issue a special permit in writing authorizing the applicant to operate or move a vehicle or combination of vehicles of a size or weight of vehicle
      or load, or both, exceeding the maximum size or weight specified in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.2.</num>
    <text>The application for a permit shall specifically describe the vehicle or vehicles and load to be operated or moved, the particular streets or highways for which a permit to operate is requested, and whether the permit is requested for a single trip
      or continuous operation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.3.</num>
    <text>A special permit issued under this section by the Director may establish seasonal or other limitations within which the vehicle(s) described may be operated on the streets or highways indicated, or otherwise to limit or prescribe conditions of operation
      of the vehicle or vehicles when necessary to avoid undue damage to the road foundations, surfaces, or other structures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.4.</num>
    <text>The Director may require such undertaking or other security as may be deemed necessary to compensate for any injury to any roadway or road structure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.5.</num>
    <text>Each permit shall be carried in the vehicle or combination of vehicles to which it refers and shall be open to inspection by any police officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.6.</num>
    <text>No person shall violate any of the terms or conditions of the special permit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Commissioners’ Order 274, 310/949 effective September 1, 1949, 17 DCRR §§ 155(e), (f) (October 19, 1970); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 3716, 3718 (June 20, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>