<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-752</num>
  <heading>MAXIMUM ALLOWABLE LEVELS OF EXHAUST COMPONENTS (§ 18-752)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>752.1.</num>
    <text>On or before January 1, 1996, the Director shall establish maximum allowable emission levels for components of motor vehicle exhaust emissions determined by the federal emission tests, as codified in title 40 CFR § 51.351, for light-duty motor vehicles
      weighing less than twenty-six thousand pounds (26,000 lbs.) net weight by model year. The maximum allowable emission levels will not exceed the fleet-wide performance criteria established by title 40 CFR § 51.351.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>752.2.</num>
    <text>On or before June 30, 1994, the Director shall establish test and quality assurance procedures for measuring exhaust emissions that are in compliance with the federal emissions test procedure as currently codified in title 40 CFR §§ 51.357 -51.359.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>752.3.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision in this Section, effective January 1, 2004, all vehicles 1996 or newer shall comply with federal On Board Diagnostic testing standards in effect on July 1, 2003, as published in the Code of Federal Regulations,
      Title 40, Chapter 1, Part 85.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>752.4.</num>
    <text>As necessary, the Director shall have authority to do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Supplement and amend the prescribed emission levels and testing methods;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Prescribe emission levels for additional components of motor vehicle exhaust emissions; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Prescribe emission levels for additional types of motor vehicles, including, but not limited to, medium duty or heavy-duty gasoline propelled or diesel-propelled vehicles.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>752.5.</num>
    <text>In establishing or amending the emission levels or test procedures, the Director shall consult with the Director of the Department of Environmental Services and shall comply with the notice provisions of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure
      Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>752.6.</num>
    <text>During the period January 1, 1995 through December 31, 1995, the Director shall test the exhaust emission levels of motor vehicles registered in the District in order to compile data on the exhaust emission levels of motor vehicles registered in the
      District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>752.7.</num>
    <text>The allowable exhaust emission levels for light-duty gasoline-propelled motor vehicles for Hydrocarbons shall be measured in parts per million (ppm) of exhaust gas measured.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>752.8.</num>
    <text>The allowable exhaust emission levels for light-duty gasoline-propelled motor vehicles for Carbon Monoxide shall be measured in percent of exhaust gas measured.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>752.9.</num>
    <text>Emission levels for Hydrocarbons and Carbon Monoxide are established for six (6) age groups of light-duty gasoline-propelled motor vehicles as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Motor vehicles of model year 1967 or older;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Motor vehicles of model year 1968 through model year 1970;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Motor vehicles of model year 1971 through model year 1974;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Motor vehicles of model year 1975 through model year 1979;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Motor vehicles of model year 1980; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1981 or newer.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>752.10.</num>
    <text>The allowable emission levels of Hydocarbons for these motor vehicle groups shall be as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1967 or older, emissions shall not exceed two thousand (2,000) ppm;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1968 through 1974, emissions shall not exceed one thousand two hundred fifty (1,250) ppm;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1971 through 1974, emissions shall not exceed one thousand two hundred (1,200) ppm;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1975 through 1979, emissions shall not exceed six hundred (600) ppm;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1980, emissions shall not exceed three hundred (300) ppm; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of mode year 1981 or newer, emissions shall not exceed two hundred twenty (220) ppm.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>752.11.</num>
    <text>The allowable emission levels of Carbon Monoxide for these motor vehicle groups shall be as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1967 or older, emission shall not exceed twelve and one half percent (12.5%);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>or motor vehicles of model year 1968 through 1970, emissions shall not exceed eleven percent (11%);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1971 through 1974, emissions shall not exceed nine percent (9%);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1975 through 1979, emissions shall not exceed six and one-half percent (6.5%);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1980, emissions shall not exceed one and one-half percent (1.5%); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1981 or newer, emissions shall not exceed one and two-tenths percent (1.2%).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>752.12.</num>
    <text>ALLOWABLE EMISSION standards established in §§ 752.7 &amp;#8211; 752.11 shall be used only for an idle exhaust emissions test.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>752.13.</num>
    <text>ALLOWABLE exhaust EMISSION standards established in §§ 752.14 &amp;#8211; 752.20 shall be used only for a transient exhaust emissions test.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>752.14.</num>
    <text>The allowable exhaust emission levels for spark-combustion powered motor vehicles for Hydrocarbons (HC) shall be measured in grams per mile (gm/mi) of exhaust gas measured.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>752.15.</num>
    <text>The allowable exhaust emission levels for spark-combustion powered motor vehicles for Carbon Monoxide (CO) shall be measured in grams per mile (gm/mi) of exhaust gas measured.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>752.16.</num>
    <text>The allowable exhaust emission levels for spark-combustion powered motor vehicles for Oxides of Nitrogen (NOx) shall be measured in grams per mile (gm/mi) of exhaust gas measured.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>752.17.</num>
    <text>Emission levels for Hydrocarbons, Carbon Monoxide, and Oxides of Nitrogen are established for nine (9) age groups of spark combustion powered motor vehicles as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1968 through model year 1972;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1973 through model year 1974;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1975 through model year 1976;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1977 through model year 1979;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1980;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1981 through model year 1982;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1983 through model year 1990;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1991 through model year 1993; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1994 or newer designated by The United States Environmental Protection Agency as “Tier 1” vehicles.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>752.18.</num>
    <text>The allowable emission levels of Hydrocarbons for these motor vehicle groups shall be as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1968 through model year 1972, emissions shall not exceed ten grams per mile (10 gm/mi);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1973 through model year 1974, emissions shall not exceed ten grams per mile (10 gm/mi);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1975 through model year 1976, emissions shall not exceed seven and one-half grams per mile (7.5 gm/mi);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1977 through model year 1979, emissions shall not exceed seven and one-half grams per mile (7.5 gm/mi);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1980, emissions shall not exceed two grams per mile (2.0 gm/mi);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1981 through model year 1982, emissions shall not exceed two grams per mile (2.0 gm/mi);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1983 through model year 1990, emissions shall not exceed two grams per mile (2.0 gm/mi);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1991 through model year 1993, emissions shall not exceed one and two-tenths grams per mile (1.2 gm/mi); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1994 or newer designated by The United States Environmental Protection Agency as “Tier 1” vehicles, emissions shall not exceed eight-tenth grams per mile (.8 gm/mi);</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>752.19.</num>
    <text>The allowable emission levels of Carbon Monoxide for these motor vehicle groups shall be as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1968 through model year 1972, emissions shall not exceed one hundred and fifty grams per mile (150 gm/mi);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1973 through model year 1974, emissions shall not exceed one hundred and fifty grams per mile (150 gm/mi);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1975 through model year 1976, emissions shall not exceed ninety grams per mile (90 gm/mi);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1977 through model year 1979, emissions shall not exceed ninety grams per mile (90 gm/mi);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1980, emissions shall not exceed sixty grams per mile (60 gm/mi);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1981 through model year 1982, emissions shall not exceed sixty grams per mile (60 gm/mi);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1983 through model year 1990, emissions shall not exceed thirty grams per mile (30 gm/mi);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1991 through model year 1993, emissions shall not exceed twenty grams per mile (20 gm/mi); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1994 or newer designated by The United States Environmental Protection Agency “Tier 1” vehicles, emissions shall not exceed fifteen grams per mile (15 gm/mi).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>752.20.</num>
    <text>The allowable emission levels of Oxides of Nitrogen for these motor vehicle groups shall be as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1968 through model year 1972, emission shall not exceed ten grams per mile (10 gm/mi);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1973 through model year 1974, emissions shall not exceed nine grams per mile (9.0 gm/mi);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1975 through model year 1976, emissions shall not exceed nine grams per mile (9.0 gm/mi);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1977 through model year 1979, emissions shall not exceed six grams per mile (6.0 gm/mi);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1980, emissions shall not exceed six grams per mile (6.0 gm/mi);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1981 through model year 1982, emissions shall not exceed three grams per mile (3.0 gm/mi);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1983 through model year 1990, emissions shall not exceed three grams per mile (3.0 gm/mi);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1991 through model year 1993, emissions shall not exceed two and one-half grams per mile (2.5 gm/mi); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>For motor vehicles of model year 1994 or newer designated by the United States Environmental Protection Agency as “Tier 1” vehicles, emissions shall not exceed two grams per mile (2.0 gm/mi).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 2 of the District of Columbia Exhaust Emission Inspection/Maintenance Program Amendments Act of 1980 D.C. Law 3-152,27 DCR 2907 (November 7, 1980), 32 DCRR § 6.803 (d); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 30 DCR 2571 (May 27, 1983);
        by Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 4119 (June 22, 1990); § 4(b) of the Motor Vehicle Biennial Inspection Amendment Act of 1993, 41 DCR 1014 (March 4, 1994); and by Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 3802, 3803 (June 17, 1994); as amended
        by Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 5967 (October 17,1997); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 8196 (October 3, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>