<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-743</num>
  <heading>MOTORCYCLE FACE SHIELDS (§ 18-743)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>743.1.</num>
    <text>The American National Standards Institute, Inc., Practice for Occupational and Educational Eye and Face Protection, Z87.1-1968, designated “Face Shields,” is adopted as the minimum standards for face shields required to be worn by operators and passengers
      on motorcycles.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>743.2.</num>
    <text>The test procedure for face shields shall refer to those standards which are applicable to all face shield devices and which are applicable to the following types of face shields being tested:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Impact resistance &amp;#8211; plastic-window face shield; Provided, that the face shield shall be tested while attached to a helmet and the harness of the helmet shall take the place of the crown strap;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Penetration resistance &amp;#8211; plastic-window face shield;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Visible transmittance &amp;#8211; plastic windows;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Flammability &amp;#8211; plastic windows; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Disinfection.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>743.3.</num>
    <text>In addition to the provisions of § 743.2, a face shield, other than one containing a wire screen window, shall be approved only if it meets the following specifications:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The edge of the face shield must be smooth, and if the edge is beveled, it must be dull-finished.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>It meets the window support and markings requirement of the specifications of the American National Standards Institute; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>It is equipped with visor snaps for attaching to the helmet and properly positioned for use when the motorcycle is in motion.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>743.4.</num>
    <text>Each face shield shall be permanently labeled with the manufacturer’s trade name and number, which must be the same trade name and number used in the approval application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 72-13 effective June 30, 1972, 32 DCRR §§ 6.508(a) &amp;#8211; (c), Special Edition.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>