<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-706</num>
  <heading>STOP LAMPS, TURN SIGNALS, AND REFLECTORS (§ 18-706)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>706.1.</num>
    <text>No motor vehicle, trailer, or semi-trailer manufactured or assembled before September 15, 1957, shall be operated in the District unless same is equipped with at least one (1) stop lamp meeting the requirements of § 713.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>706.2.</num>
    <text>No motor vehicle, trailer or semi-trailer manufactured or assembled on and after September 15, 1957, shall be operated in the District unless it is equipped with at least two (2) stop lamps meeting the requirements of § 713; except that truck tractors
      manufactured or assembled after September 15, 1957 but prior to January 1, 1968, motorcycles, and motorized bicycles shall be equipped with at least one (1) stop lamp meeting the requirements of § 713.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>706.3.</num>
    <text>No motor vehicle, trailer, or semi-trailer, manufactured or assembled on and after September 15, 1955, shall be operated in the District unless it is equipped with electric turn signals meeting the requirements of § 713.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>706.4.</num>
    <text>Motor driven cycles which attain a speed of thirty miles per hour (30 mph) or less in a distance of one (1) mile, motorized bicycles, and motorcycles shall be exempt from the requirements of § 706.3.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>706.5.</num>
    <text>All signal devices shall conform to the standards and specifications of the Society of Automotive Engineers applicable to such equipment current at the time such device is attached.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>706.6.</num>
    <text>Each new motor vehicle sold and operated upon a street or highway, other than a truck tractor, shall carry on the rear, either as part of the tail lamps or separately, two (2) red reflectors, except that each motorcycle and motorized bicycle shall
      carry at least one (1) reflector meeting the requirements of this section; and Provided, that vehicles of the type listed in § 707 shall be equipped with reflectors as specifically required in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>706.7.</num>
    <text>Each reflector shall be mounted on the vehicle at a height not less than fifteen inches (15 in.) or more than sixty inches (60 in.) measured asset forth in § 703.3, and shall be of such size and characteristics and so mounted as to be visible at night
      from all distances within three hundred feet (300 ft.) to fifty feet (50 ft.) from the vehicle when directly in front of lawful upperbeams of head lamps, except that visibility from a greater distance is required of reflectors on certain types of
      vehicles.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 72-13 effective June 30, 1972, 32 DCRR § 6.204, 6.205, Special Edition; as amended by Regulation No.74-17 effective June 29, 1974; and by §§ 2(p), (s) of the District of Columbia Motorized Bicycle Act, D.C. Law 1-110,23 DCR 4954 (January
        21, 1977).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>