<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-704</num>
  <heading>FOIA EXEMPTIONS FROM DISCLOSURE (ยง 15-704)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>704.1.</num>
    <text>The classes of records authorized to be exempted from disclosure under this chapter shall be the same as those provided in D.C. Code ยง1-1524 (1981 Ed.), as amended.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>704.2.</num>
    <text>Any reasonably separable portion of a record shall be provided to any person requesting the record after deletion of those portions which are exempt under this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>704.3.</num>
    <text>Any document filed under seal which is alleged by a party to contain proprietary information shall be deemed excepted from disclosure pursuant to D.C. Code ยง1-1524(a)(1) (1981 Ed.), unless the Commission, after notice to the affected party and opportunity
      to be heard, orders that D.C. Code ยง1-1524(a)(1) (1981 Ed.), does not apply. An application for reconsideration of an order shall act as a stay of the order pending reconsideration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>704.4.</num>
    <text>When alleged proprietary information is the subject of a FOIA request, the following procedures shall apply:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The General Counsel shall notify the requesting party that the information requested is alleged to be proprietary;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The General Counsel shall notify the party whose alleged proprietary information is the subject of a FOIA request, and inform the party of its right to file, within five (5) days of notification, the basis of its proprietary claim;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Within five (5) days of service of the party&amp;#8217;s basis of proprietary claim, the requesting party may file a response detailing why the requested information is not proprietary and why the information should be disclosed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Within ten (10) days of the date the response is required to be filed, the Commission shall issue an order regarding whether the alleged proprietary information is exempt from disclosure.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 7053, 7056 (November 14, 1986); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 2195 (April 3, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>