<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-705</num>
  <heading>FOIA FEES (§ 15-705)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>705.1.</num>
    <text>Charges for services rendered in response to FOIA requests shall be as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Searching for records, after the first hour, shall be one dollar and fifty cents ($ 1.50) per quarter hour (maximum of ten dollars ($ 10) for each request); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Fifteen cents (15￠) per page reproduction fee for each copy made.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.2.</num>
    <text>When a response to a request requires services or materials for which no fee has been established, the direct cost of the services or materials to the Commission may be charged, but only if the person making the request has been notified of the cost
      before it is incurred.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.3.</num>
    <text>Where an extensive number of documents are identified and collected in response to a request, and the person making the request has not indicated in advance his or her willingness to pay fees as high as are anticipated for copies of the document,
      the General Counsel shall inform the person that the documents are available for inspection and for copying at the established rate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.4.</num>
    <text>A charge of one dollar ($1) shall be made for each certification of true copies of Commission records.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.5.</num>
    <text>Search costs, not to exceed ten dollars ($10) for each request, may be imposed even if the requested record cannot be located.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.6.</num>
    <text>Fees shall be paid in full prior to the issuance of requested copies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.7.</num>
    <text>Remittances shall be in the form either of a personal check or bank draft on a bank in the United States, a postal money order, or cash. Remittance shall be made payable to the order of the D.C. Treasurer and mailed or delivered to the Secretary of
      the Commission. The Secretary shall not assume responsibility for cash which is lost in the mail.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.8.</num>
    <text>A receipt for fees paid shall be given only upon request. No refund shall be made for services rendered.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.9.</num>
    <text>The General Counsel may waive all or part of any fee when it is deemed to be either in the Commission&amp;#8217;s interest or in the interest of the public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 7053, 7056 (November 14, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>