<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-2401</num>
  <heading>LIMITED DUTY (ยง 7-2401)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2401.1.</num>
    <text>If the Director, in consultation with Police and Fire Clinic physicians, determines that a member, because of injury or other temporary medical disability is unable to perform the full range of duties, but is capable of effectively performing certain
      types of work within the department, and the prognosis is that the member will be able to perform a full range of duties after achieving maximum medical improvement, the Director may recommend to the Chief that the member perform work in a limited-
      duty status.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2401.2.</num>
    <text>The Director&amp;#8217;s recommendation shall not vest with the member a right to a limited duty position, and the Chief is not obligated to provide any member with a limited duty assignment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2401.3.</num>
    <text>Members in a limited-duty status shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Undertake in-service training as required by the Chief;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Not be permitted to work voluntary overtime; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Not accept or continue any off-duty employment without the specific approval of the Chief.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2401.4.</num>
    <text>No less than every 30 days, the Director shall evaluate members in a limited-duty status to evaluate their health status and to ensure that they are complying with their medical treatment plans.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2401.5.</num>
    <text>If at any time the Director, in consultation with Police and Fire Clinic physicians, determines that a member in a limited-duty status will be unable to perform the full range of duties after achieving maximum medical improvement, the Director shall
      recommend the member for disability retirement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 6450 (July 8, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>