<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-1403</num>
  <heading>FILING OF PETITIONS AND SUPPLEMENTS (§ 3-1403)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1403.1.</num>
    <text>Before the nominating petition is filed, all sheets which comprise the petition shall be assembled and serially numbered. The Board may refuse to accept any petition which has not been so assembled and numbered.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1403.2.</num>
    <text>A petition nominating a presidential candidate must be accompanied by an affidavit, signed personally by the presidential candidate, consenting to his or her name appearing on the ballot, except in the case where the party plan provides that delegates/alternates
      be listed on the ballot or on a handout provided to the voter, in which case, the presidential candidate shall file the affidavit required in § 1403.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1403.3.</num>
    <text>A petition nominating &amp;#8220;uncommitted&amp;#8221; (where the party plan does not provide for the listing of delegates/alternates on the ballot or on a separate handout to accompany the ballot) must be accompanied by an affidavit filed by the
      sponsor of the petition effort that he or she is a sponsor(s) of a petition drive to place uncommitted on the ballot, in lieu of the affidavits of the presidential candidate provided in §§ 1403.2 and 1403.4 (d) of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1403.4.</num>
    <text>In the case where the party plan provides that delegates/alternates be listed on the ballot or on a separate handout provided to the voter, a petition nominating a candidate for delegate or alternate to a National Party Convention may not be finally
      accepted by the Board for inclusion on the ballot until:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Each candidate for delegate/alternate has filed with the Board a Declaration of Candidacy executed in accordance with the provisions of this section and with Chapter 6 of this title;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The person filing the petition executes an affidavit pursuant to § 1401.7 of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The petition is on a form provided by the Board and meets all requirements of the provisions of this section and of the Election Act; provided, that the Board, in its discretion, may waive any formal error;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The petition is accompanied by an affidavit signed personally by the presidential candidate, consenting to his or her name appearing on the ballot, naming each convention delegate or alternate supported by the petition, and consenting to each delegate
        being listed on the ballot (or separate handout that is provided to the voter with the ballot) as committed to his or her candidacy; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The petition, if nominating “uncommitted,” is accompanied by a &amp;#8220;Delegate Slate Registration Form&amp;#8221; (in lieu of the affidavit provided by § 1403.4(d)), which provides the name, address, telephone number and signature of the individual
        who is authorized to represent the delegates/alternates in matters before the Board; and a complete listing of the candidates, and the office to which each seeks election.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1403.5.</num>
    <text>Any candidate who has met the requirements of this section may file petition supplements; Provided, that the supplements meet all other pertinent provisions of this section and that the filing deadline has not expired.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1403.6.</num>
    <text>The nominating petition, affidavits, and supplements, if any, shall be filed with the Board at its office no later than 5:00 p.m. on the filing deadline required by law and announced by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1403.7.</num>
    <text>The Board may reject any nominating petition that is confusing, misleading, or does not conform to the requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 43 D.C. Reg. 1350, 1352-53 (March 15, 1996).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>