<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-215</num>
  <heading>HEARINGS (ยง 29-215)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>215.1.</num>
    <text>Written and oral information regarding the right to file a complaint, how to request a hearing, and the method of filing a complaint shall be furnished by the Department to each applicant or recipient of any assistance, service, or license at the
      time of application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>215.2.</num>
    <text>Information on the right to file a complaint as described in ยง215.1 shall also be sent whenever the Department notifies the applicant or recipient in writing that the Department intends to take any action that may or will adversely affect the individual
      or the individual&amp;#8217;s benefits, including changes in or termination of those benefits.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>215.3.</num>
    <text>Written notice shall include notice of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That the applicant or recipient has the right to be represented by legal counsel or by any person who is not an employee of the District government;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That the individual may bring witnesses and present evidence in the individual&amp;#8217;s behalf; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>That the individual has the right to submit rebuttal evidence and: to conduct cross-examination that may be required for a full and true disclosure of the facts.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>215.4.</num>
    <text>Hearing procedures, entitled &amp;#8220;Administrative Review and Full Evidentiary Hearing Procedures for the Department of Human Services, Commission of Social Services, Vocational Rehabilitation Services Administration, Randolph-Sheppard Act, as
      amended by P.L. 93-516,&amp;#8221; shall be published separately by the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>DCRR Title 6C, as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 4611 (October 17, 1980).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>