<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-212</num>
  <heading>BLIND VENDORS COMMITTEE[COLON] MEMBERS AND ELECTIONS (ยง 29-212)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>212.1.</num>
    <text>The Department shall provide for the biennial election of a Blind Vendors Committee, which shall be fully representative of all blind vendors in the District program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>212.2.</num>
    <text>There shall be no test of eligibility for voting except licensing in the Program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>212.3.</num>
    <text>The election shall be conducted by mail. The return ballots shall be collected and held by a nongovernmental, nonprofit agency which shall bring the unopened ballots to an appointed place at a designated time, where they shall be opened and tabulated
      in the presence of all blind licensees who wish to attend.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>212.4.</num>
    <text>The Committee shall be composed of seven (7) members.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>212.5.</num>
    <text>Nominations for the Committee shall be conducted by mail. In order for a name to be placed on the ballot, the following conditions shall be met:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The vendor shall be nominated by at least ten percent (10%) of those eligible to vote in the election; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The nominated vendor shall have agreed to serve, if elected.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>212.6.</num>
    <text>Committee members shall serve for a term of two (2) years. There shall be no limit to the number of consecutive terms a vendor may serve.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>212.7.</num>
    <text>A vacancy occurring on the Committee shall be filled from among eligible vendors by a majority vote of the Committee. A member elected to fill a vacancy shall serve until the next election.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>DCRR Title 6C, as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 4611 (October 17, 1980).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>