<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-219</num>
  <heading>NOTICE AND RIGHT TO DUE PROCESS REMEDIES FOR BLIND VENDORS AND RSVFP TRAINEESECEIVING VOCATIONAL REHABILITATION SERVICES (§ 29-219)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>219.1.</num>
    <text>Pursuant to 34 C.F.R. § 361.57, each Vendor or RSVFP trainee shall be informed in writing, that he or she has the right to the following:</text>
    <text>To request an informal administrative review meeting, mediation or impartial due process hearing;</text>
    <text>To request an informal administrative review meeting, mediation or impartial due process hearing;</text>
    <text>The availability of the Client Assistance Program (“CAP”) to assist the applicant or consumer during the informal administrative review meeting, mediation or impartial due process hearing;</text>
    <text>To request a qualified interpreter, fluent in the primary language (including sign language) of the applicant/consumer or other methods of communication used by an individual due to his or her disability; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>To request auxiliary aids to ensure that communications with individuals with hearing, vision, or speech impairments are as effective as communications with others. &amp;#8220;Auxiliary aids&amp;#8221; include such services or devices as qualified
        interpreters, assistive listening headsets, television captioning and decoders, telecommunications devices for deaf persons (TDD&amp;#8217;s), videotext displays, readers, taped texts, brailed materials, and large print materials.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>219.2.</num>
    <text>A Vendor, RSVFP trainee, or his or her authorized representative shall receive written notification of his or her due process remedies, at the following times as applicable:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>At the time of application;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Assignment to an order of selection category;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Development of an IPE;</text>
    </level>
    <text>Upon reduction, suspension, and/or termination (including case closure) of any determination concerning the furnishing or denial of vocational rehabilitation services; or</text>
    <text>At the time of licensure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 8538 (December 9, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 4612, 4621 (May 28, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>