<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-221</num>
  <heading>REQUEST FOR INFORMAL ADMINISTRATIVE REVIEW MEETING[SLASH]NOTICE TIMELINESS (§9-221)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>221.1.</num>
    <text>A request for an informal administrative review meeting must be submitted in writing, within ten (10) business days, of the determination that affected the provision of vocational rehabilitation services. The time limits in this section may be extended
      by the Chief, Office of Quality Assurance and Federal Compliance, when good cause is shown by one party or at the request of both parties. This request must be addressed to:</text>
    <text>Office of Quality Assurance and Federal Compliance</text>
    <text>Attention: Chief</text>
    <text>Department on Disability Services, Rehabilitation Services Administration</text>
    <text>1125 15th Street, NW, 9th Floor</text>
    <text>Washington, D.C. 20005</text>
    <text>(202) 442-8670 (Voice or Relay)</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>221.2.</num>
    <text>Within five (5) business days after the request is received, the Chief of the Office of Quality Assurance and Federal Compliance (“OQAFC”) will do the following:</text>
    <text>Forward the request to the Chief of the DSB; and</text>
    <text>Send a written notification to the Vendor/RSVFP trainee stating the date, time and location of the informal administrative review meeting. Notification shall be in an Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA) compliant format, including:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>in the medium of the applicant or consumer’s choice, including large print, Braille, tape, disk; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>provided via e-mail and/or U.S. Priority Mail with Delivery Confirmation requested.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>221.3.</num>
    <text>[Repealed]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 8538 (December 9, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 4612, 4623 (May 28, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>