<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-208</num>
  <heading>PROMOTION AND TRANSFER COMMITTEE (§ 29-208)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>208.1.</num>
    <text>A Promotion and Transfer Committee shall act on behalf of the licensing agency for the purpose of applying the provisions of §207.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.2.</num>
    <text>The Committee shall be composed of a representative selected by each of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Blind Vendors Committee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The nominee organizations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The licensing agency.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.3.</num>
    <text>The Committee shall meet at a mutually agreeable time, at least semi-annually, and shall evaluate pertinent data in order to determine the number of performance rating points to be allocated to each vendor, in accordance with §§207.11 through 207.13.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.4.</num>
    <text>The total number of points awarded for performance, combined with the points accumulated for seniority, shall fix the vendor&amp;#8217;s position in order of eligibility for promotion and transfer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.5.</num>
    <text>The Committee shall also meet as often as is necessary to ensure full consideration of every proposed promotion or transfer. Full consideration may include a re-evaluation of the work demands of a given vending facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.6.</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise specified in this chapter, the decisions of the Promotion and Transfer Committee shall be decided by majority vote.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.7.</num>
    <text>The decisions of the Committee in regard to ratings shall be considered final.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>DCRR Title 6C, as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 4611 (October 17, 1980).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>