<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-9200</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 29-9200)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>9200.1.</num>
    <text>The purpose of this chapter is to establish limitations for reimbursement by the Medicaid program for provider preventable conditions. These rules shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Identify Provider Preventable Conditions (PPCs) which shall be included in the Department of Health Care Finance (DHCF) payment adjustment policy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Identify providers subject to the DHCF’s PPC payment adjustment policy; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Establish procedures for providers to self-report the occurrence of PPCs in their claims systems.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9200.2.</num>
    <text>Subject to the requirements set forth in Section 2702 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act of 2010 (the Act), approved March 23, 2010 (Pub. L. No. 111-148; 124 Stat. 119; 42 C.F.R. §§ 434, 438, and 447), the DHCF’s PPCs payment adjustment
      policy shall include all of the PPCs included in Medicare’s inpatient hospital payment adjustment regulations and any subsequent updates or revisions promulgated under section 1886(d)(4)(D) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. § 1395ww).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9200.3.</num>
    <text>The list of PPCs which are subject to payment adjustments by the DHCF under the District of Columbia’s Medicaid program shall include Health Care Acquired Conditions (HCACs) and Other Provider Preventable Conditions (OPPC).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9200.4.</num>
    <text>DHCF’s PPC payment adjustment policy shall apply to all hospital claims for dates of discharge on or after July 1, 2012.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9200.5.</num>
    <text>For non-hospital providers, the payment adjustment policy shall apply to all claims for services rendered on or after July 1, 2012.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9200.6.</num>
    <text>DHCF’s PPC payment adjustment policy shall also apply to the terms of the contracts entered into by Managed Care Organizations (MCOs) and the District of Columbia. The MCO’s payment policies must comply with the DHCF’s PPC payment adjustment policy.
      MCOs must ensure that their payment policies prohibit reimbursement to its providers for any amount expended when providing medical assistance for PPCs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 14960 (December 21, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>