<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-4358</num>
  <heading>BID BONDS, PROPOSAL BONDS, AND OTHER SECURITY (ยง 19-4358)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4358.1.</num>
    <text>The CCO may require bid bonds, proposal bonds, and other security in connection with any solicitation, regardless of whether any payment or performance security will be required under the contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4358.2.</num>
    <text>When the Library&amp;#8217;s independent cost estimate for a construction contract is over one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000), the CCO shall require a Security Bond in the Invitation for Bids.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4358.3.</num>
    <text>The CCO may require a Security Bond when the Library&amp;#8217;s independent cost estimate for a construction project is less than one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4358.4.</num>
    <text>When a Security Bond is required, the solicitation shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A statement that a Security Bond is required;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A statement that the Security Bond shall be effective for as long as the bid is required to remain effective;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Instructions to allow bidders to determine the amount of the required Security Bond.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4358.5.</num>
    <text>If a solicitation is cancelled, or if a bidder is permitted to withdraw a bid prior to award due to a mistake in the bid, the CCO shall take no action against the Security Bond.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4358.6.</num>
    <text>Security bonds shall be required in circumstances when only one bid or proposal is received, or when sole source procedures are utilized.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 493 (January 18, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>