<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-4301</num>
  <heading>AUTHORITY AND RESPONSIBILITY OF THE OFFICE OF THE CHIEF CONTRACTING OFFICER (ยง9-4301)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4301.1.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director/Chief Librarian of the Library shall be the Procurement Executive (PE). The Chief Business Officer of the Library shall be the Chief Contracting Officer (&amp;#8220;CCO&amp;#8221;).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4301.2.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall serve as the Library&amp;#8217;s chief procurement officer and shall be responsible for the Library&amp;#8217;s overall procurement program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4301.3.</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise provided herein the CCO may delegate in writing to one or more staff contracting officers any authority conferred on the CCO by these regulations, and the CCO shall include in any such delegation clear written instructions on the
      limitation of the delegated authority. Such delegation shall remain in effect unless and until the CCO modifies or revokes the delegation in writing. Delegation of contracting authority shall automatically be revoked for staff contracting officers
      whose employment with the Library is terminated through attrition or other form of termination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4301.4.</num>
    <text>Any Library official designated as a contracting officer shall not be delegated contracting authority greater than that of the CCO.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4301.5.</num>
    <text>Only the CCO or other Library contracting officer is authorized to enter into contracts, terminate contracts or contractually bind the Library. A contracting officer may bind the Library only to the extent of their written delegated authority by the
      CCO under subsection 4301.3.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4301.6.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall be responsible for developing all procurement policies and procedures unique to the procurement of supplies, services, materials and construction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4301.7.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall develop a procurement manual of internal procedures and instructions which shall conform to this chapter and that governs the internal functions of the Office of the CCO. The procurement manual shall be developed within 120 days of the
      effective date of these regulations and shall be approved by the Library Board of Trustees before becoming effective.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4301.8.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the CCO or other library contracting officer may procure supplies, services or construction from District of Columbia or Federal Supply Schedules to the extent permitted by the Schedules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 493 (January 18, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>