<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-4356</num>
  <heading>CONTRACTING FOR SERVICES (§ 19-4356)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4356.1.</num>
    <text>The Library may obtain services from professional, non-professional, expert and consulting personnel on an individual or organizational basis when essential to the Library&amp;#8217;s operations or when the services would achieve maximum effectiveness
      of operations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4356.2.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall ensure that the applicable provisions of the Service Contract Act of 1965 (41 U.S.C. §§351-358) and any applicable wage determinations are incorporated in accordance with federal regulations into all solicitations for
      services, to include services required by Section 4305 for simplified procurements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4356.3.</num>
    <text>Contracting for services shall not apply to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Personnel appointments and advisory committees;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Personal service contracts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Construction or architect-engineer services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Interagency governmental or cooperative agreements where the work is being performed by District, Federal or State employees or employees through cooperative agreements.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Services obtained under contracts below the simplified procurement threshold and services incidental to supply contracts also are excluded from the requirements of this section, except where the Service Contract Act of 1965 (41 U.S.C. §§351-358)
        and any applicable wage determinations are required.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4356.4.</num>
    <text>The Library shall ensure good management practices and contract administration techniques are used regardless of the contracting method.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4356.5.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall ensure the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Requirements for services are clearly defined and appropriate performance standards are developed so that the agency&amp;#8217;s requirements can be understood by potential offerors and that performance in accordance with contract terms and conditions
        will meet the agency&amp;#8217;s requirements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Service contracts are awarded and administered in a manner that will provide the Library its supplies and services within budget and in a timely manner; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Specific procedures are in place before contracting for services to ensure that inherently governmental functions are performed by District personnel.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4356.6.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall develop policies and procedures for procuring services for performance-based contracting within 12 months from the date these rules are finalized.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 493 (January 18, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>