<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-4342</num>
  <heading>COMPETITIVE SEALED BIDS FOR CONSTRUCTION (ยง 19-4342)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4342.1.</num>
    <text>An IFB for construction shall allow a reasonable time for bidders to prepare and submit their bids, but in no event less than ten (10) days after the initial solicitation is issued and publicized.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4342.2.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall publicize the IFB in accordance with Section 4302.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4342.3.</num>
    <text>In determining what is a reasonable time, the CCO shall consider the construction industry and the time necessary for bidders to inspect the site, obtain subcontract agreements, examine data concerning the work and prepare estimates based on plans
      and specifications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4342.4.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall ensure that each IFB includes the following information when applicable:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The appropriate wage determination as issued by the U.S. Department of Labor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The scope of the proposed construction project;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The period of performance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Information concerning any facilities, such as utilities, office space, and warehouse space, to be furnished during the construction period;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Arrangements for bidders to inspect the site and examine the data concerning performance of the work;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Any special qualifications or experience requirements that will be considered;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Any special instructions concerning bids, alternate bids, and award; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Any instructions concerning reporting requirements.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4342.5.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall send IFB&amp;#8217;s to prospective bidders upon request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 493 (January 18, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>