<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-4399</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 19-4399)
    <text>When used in this Chapter, the following words and terms shall have the meaningsscribed:</text>
    <text>Best and Final Offer (BAFO) &amp;#8211; An offeror&amp;#8217;s final proposal revisionontaining its best technical and price/cost offer as revised followingegotiation of the offeror&amp;#8217;s original proposal.</text>
    <text>Bidder &amp;#8211; A firm or individual who submits a bid in response to annvitation for Bids or a Request for Quotations.</text>
    <text>Bond &amp;#8211; A written instrument executed by a bidder or contractor and aecond party (the &amp;#8220;surety&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;sureties&amp;#8221;), to assureulfillment of the principal&amp;#8217;s obligations to a third party (the obligeer
      Library), identified in the bond. If the principal&amp;#8217;s obligations areot met, the bond assures payment, to the extent stipulated, for any lossustained b the obligee.</text>
    <text>Brand Name Description &amp;#8211; A description that identifies a product by itsrand name and model or part number or other appropriate nomenclature by whichhe product is offered for sale.</text>
    <text>Claim &amp;#8211; A written demand or written assertion by one of the contractingarties seeking, as a matter of right, the payment of money in a sum certain,he adjustment or interpretation of contract terms, or other relief arisingnder or relating
      to a contract. A claim arising under a contract is a claimhat can be resolved under a contract clause that provides for the relief soughty the claimant; provided that a written demand or written assertion by theontractor seeking the payment of money
      exceeding one hundred thousand dollars$ 100,000) is not a claim under this Chapter until certified as required byection 4380.8</text>
    <text>Commercial Item &amp;#8211; Any item, other than real property, that is used by theeneral public for other than governmental purposes and that has been sold,eased, or licensed to the general public.</text>
    <text>Competitive Process &amp;#8211; The process of obtaining offers (including bids anduotes) from two or more sources for products or services so that the desiredtems may be obtained at the lowest overall cost or best value.</text>
    <text>Contracting Officer &amp;#8211; A person with the authority to enter into,dminister and/or terminate contracts. Contracting Officers sign contracts onehalf of the Library and bear the legal responsibility for contracts. Onlyhose personnel with the
      requisite background and experience are designated asibrary Contracting Officers.</text>
    <text>Consent to Subcontract &amp;#8211; The CCO&amp;#8217;s written consent for the primeontractor to enter into a specific subcontract.</text>
    <text>Construction &amp;#8211; The process of altering, repairing or improving an existingr building a new facility.</text>
    <text>Contracts Review Committee &amp;#8211; A committee appointed by the President of theoard of Library Trustees for the purpose of considering appeals from decisionsade by the Executive Director/Chief Librarian regarding claims, debarment anduspensions,
      protests and disputes. The Committee shall include five (5) votingembers: the President, three other Board members, and the Executiveirector/Chief Librarian. Decisions shall be made by a majority vote.</text>
    <text>Corporate Surety &amp;#8211; A corporation licensed under District insurance lawshich, under its charter, has legal power to act as surety for others.</text>
    <text>Contracting Officer&amp;#8217;s Technical Representative (COTR) &amp;#8211; The personesponsible for the technical aspects of a requirement including monitoringontractor performance.</text>
    <text>Debarment &amp;#8211; Action taken by the CCO to exclude a contractor from Libraryontracting and approved subcontracting for a specified period of time.</text>
    <text>Delivery Order &amp;#8211; An order for supplies placed against establishedontracts which have been awarded by the Library. The price, terms andonditions have been previously agreed upon in a master contract, leaving onlyhe quantity of supplies and
      the place of delivery to be determined.</text>
    <text>Executed &amp;#8211; Transactions that are agreed to and signed by both parties.</text>
    <text>Full and Open Competition &amp;#8211; The competitive process where all responsibleources are permitted to compete for a contract award.</text>
    <text>Individual Surety &amp;#8211; A person who is liable for the entire penal amount ofhe bond.</text>
    <text>Informal Hearing &amp;#8211; A hearing with no formal rules of evidence, which maye performed by written correspondence.</text>
    <text>Insurance &amp;#8211; A contract that provides that, for a stipulated consideration,he insurer undertakes to indemnify the insured party against risk of loss,amage, or liability resulting from an unknown or contingent event.</text>
    <text>Limited Competition &amp;#8211; The process when full and open competition has beenustifiably waived but a select number of offers are solicited and evaluated.imited competition pertains to the negotiation procurement process.</text>
    <text>Local, Small, Disadvantaged Business Enterprise &amp;#8211; A firm or individualertified by the Department of Small and Local Business Development as a local,mall or disadvantaged business enterprise.</text>
    <text>Market Research &amp;#8211; Collecting and analyzing information about capabilitiesithin the market to satisfy Library requirements.</text>
    <text>Mentor-Protégé Program &amp;#8211; A program designed to encourage approvedentors to provide various forms of assistance to eligible protégéarticipants for the purpose of enhancing local, small and disadvantagedusiness enterprises participating in
      Library procurement opportunities.</text>
    <text>Minor Informality or Irregularity &amp;#8211; A minor error or irregularity that iserely a matter of form and not of substance. It also pertains to somemmaterial defect in an offer that can be corrected or waived without beingrejudicial to other offerors.</text>
    <text>Notice of Intent to Award &amp;#8211; A written notice to the apparent awardeedvising of intent to award the contract contingent upon the execution ofequired bonds and the formal contract, and the obtaining of all necessarypprovals.</text>
    <text>Offeror &amp;#8211; A firm or individual who submits a proposal in response to aequest for Proposals. The terms &amp;#8220;bidder&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;offeror&amp;#8221;re sometimes used interchangeably in the procurement process.</text>
    <text>Payment Bond &amp;#8211; A bond that ensures payment as required by law to allersons supplying labor or material in the performance of work required by theontract.</text>
    <text>Performance Bond &amp;#8211; A bond that secures performance and fulfillment of theontractor&amp;#8217;s obligations under the contract.</text>
    <text>Penal Sum or Penal Amount &amp;#8211; The amount of money specified in a securityor a percentage of the bid price in a bid security) as the maximum payment forhich the surety is obligated.</text>
    <text>Plans and specifications &amp;#8211; Drawings, text, and other descriptions of thehysical or functional characteristics required for and preliminary to theontract or construction project.</text>
    <text>Protest &amp;#8211; A claim by an interested party that the solicitation or theward of the contract or the failure to award the contract was or is contrary toaw and that the action or inaction by the Library affects the direct economicnterests of
      the interest party.</text>
    <text>Purchase Order &amp;#8211; An instrument used to contract for supplies and servicesor simplified procurements up to $ 100,000, except as required by Section 4313.</text>
    <text>Request for Proposals (RFPs) &amp;#8211; An instrument used in negotiatedrocurements to communicate the Library&amp;#8217;s requirements to prospectivefferors and to solicit proposals. The term solicitation is used interchangeablyith RFP.</text>
    <text>Request for Qualifications &amp;#8211; An instrument used to solicit qualificationsrom interested sources with the intent of pre-qualifying those sources toarticipate in a future solicitation.</text>
    <text>Request for Quotations &amp;#8211; An instrument used to procure supplies andervices within the simplified procurement threshold up to $ 100,000.</text>
    <text>Requisition &amp;#8211; The document used to formally initiate a request for therocurement of supplies or services for simplified or major acquisitions.</text>
    <text>Simplified Procurement &amp;#8211; A requirement for supplies or services for $00,000 or less.</text>
    <text>Sole Source &amp;#8211; Supplies or services that are available form only oneource. Sole source procurements must be fully documented and justified.</text>
    <text>Statement of Work &amp;#8211; The section of the contract and solicitation thatescribes the actual work to be accomplished when Competitive Sealed Proposalsre used.</text>
    <text>Subcontract &amp;#8211; A contract between a prime contract (or a subcontractor) and subcontractor to furnish supplies or services for performance of a part of arime contract or another subcontract, including, but not limited to, purchaserders, and
      changes and modifications to purchase orders. A subcontract alsoeans a joint venture or teaming arrangement.</text>
    <text>Subcontractor &amp;#8211; A supplier, distributor, vendor, or firm that furnishesupplies or services to or for a prime contractor or another subcontractor.</text>
    <text>Task Order &amp;#8211; An order for services placed against established contractshich have been awarded by the Library or other authorized source of supply. Therice, terms and conditions have been previously agreed upon in a masterontract, leaving
      only the quantity of services and the place of performance toe determined.</text>
    <text>Technical Evaluation &amp;#8211; The process that is used to evaluate technicalroposals submitted by offerors in response to a Library solicitation.</text>
    <text>Technical Evaluation Panel &amp;#8211; A group of individuals who are responsibleor evaluating the technical proposals submitted by offerors.</text>
    <text>Termination for Convenience &amp;#8211; The exercise of the Library&amp;#8217;s right toartially or wholly terminate contractor performance when it is in theibrary&amp;#8217;s interest.</text>
    <text>Termination for Default &amp;#8211; Exercise of the Library&amp;#8217;s right toartially or wholly terminate contractor performance because ofontractor&amp;#8217;s actual or anticipated failure to perform its contractualbligations.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 493 (January 18, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>