<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2100</num>
  <heading>HOUSING UNITS ELIGIBLE FOR LEASE IN-PLACE (§ 14-2100)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2100.1.</num>
    <text>DCHA may contract with housing providers to assist families who are otherwise eligible for program assistance under a lease in-place program; provided, that the units are in substantial compliance with the housing code.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2100.2.</num>
    <text>The program outlined in this chapter shall be separate and discrete from the program outlined in chapter 18 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2100.3.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this chapter shall prevent an applicant on the waiting list, as described in chapter 18, from receiving assistance in a unit in which he or she currently resides; provided, that the unit meets other applicable program requirements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is the Rental Housing Act of 1985, D.C. Law 6-10, D.C. Official Code §§ 42-3501.01 et seq. (2001).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 4472, 4485 (June 23, 1989).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR’S NOTE</heading>
      <text>The rules relating to the Tenant Assistance Program were originally adopted by the Director of the Department of Housing and Community Development. Under Part IIA(f) and B(2) of Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1987, D.C. Official Code, Vol. 3, 385
        (2001), all functions relating to the administration of the Tenant Assistance Program were transferred from the Director of the Department of Housing and Community Development (“DHCD”) to the Director of the Department of Public and Assisted Housing
        (“DPAH”). D.C. Law 10-243, the “District of Columbia Housing Authority Act of 1994,” abolished the Department of Public and Assisted Housing (DPAH) and established the District of Columbia Housing Authority (DCHA) as a corporate body and legal
        instrumentality of the government of the District of Columbia. D.C. Law 13-105, the “District of Columbia Housing Authority Act of 1999,” repealed D.C. Law 10-243 and re-established the DCHA as an independent authority of the District government
        and the successor in interest to the former housing authority. Accordingly, the term “Director” in chapters 17 through 21 of this title refers to the Director of the DCHA.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>