<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-405</num>
  <heading>NOTICE OF OPTION SELECTED (ยง 15-405)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>405.1.</num>
    <text>After the utility has received all of the tenants&amp;#8217; Preliminary Election Postcards or after the expiration of the ten (10) day waiting period (whichever comes first), the utility shall advise all tenants of the option selected by the majority
      of the tenants for payment of utility service to the building.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.2.</num>
    <text>If no option is selected by a majority, the option selected by a plurality of the tenants shall prevail.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.3.</num>
    <text>Any option selected shall be practicable under this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.4.</num>
    <text>If the utility company does not find the selected option to be practicable, it shall state its reasons in the notice and advise the tenants of their right to appeal the decision to the Commission within ten (10) working days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.5.</num>
    <text>Where sixty percent (60%) or more of the tenants have elected the individual metering option, the utility company shall immediately begin, at its own expense, the preparation of a Statement of Practicability for the master-metered building in question.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.6.</num>
    <text>When the Statement of Practicability has been prepared, the utility company shall send to each tenant in the building a notice detailing the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The determination made by the utility company whether it is practicable to offer tenants the opportunity to assume prospective service in their own name, the basis of that determination, and the nature of the service which could be offered. If the
        utility company has determined that the installation of individual meters is feasible, the notice shall include the condition that individual metering shall only be available if within ten (10) days from the delivery of this Statement of Practicability,
        all of the tenants elect to have individual meters installed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The cost to the tenant of installing an individual meter, if feasible, and the basis of the cost determination; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The tenant&amp;#8217;s right to appeal the utility company&amp;#8217;s determination of practicability to the Public Service Commission.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.7.</num>
    <text>The notice shall first be approved by the Public Service Commission and shall be sent by registered mail or hand-delivered to each apartment unit where a tenant&amp;#8217;s name is known. The notice shall also be sent to all tenants by regular mail
      and published in a newspaper of general circulation in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 3329, 3335 (July 24, 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>