<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-1500</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 1-1500)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1500.1.</num>
    <text>Section 7(a)(1) of D.C. Law 6-19 the “District of Columbia Public Records Management Act of 1985” (“Act”) provides that any record created or received by the District in the course of official business is the property of the District. Except as provided
      by law or in these regulations, such records shall not be destroyed, sold, transferred, or disposed of in any manner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1500.2.</num>
    <text>Any person who misuses, mutilates, or destroys public records shall be subject to the penalties provided in the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1500.3.</num>
    <text>This chapter shall be administered by the Administrator, the Archivist, the Records Manager, the Chief of the Library of Governmental Information, or by other subordinate officials of the Office of Public Records who are designated by them.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1500.4.</num>
    <text>The Administrator may obtain the services of experts and consultants in the fields of records management and archives and related fields, in accordance with applicable personnel or contracting regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1500.5.</num>
    <text>The Administrator shall be the only official authorized to accept a subpoena duces tecum or other legal demand for records or donated historical material in the custody of the Archives.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1500.6.</num>
    <text>Access to records stored in the Records Center or other approved storage depository shall be controlled by the District agency that transferred the records.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 7001 (October 30, 1987).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is section 3(e) of D.C. Law 6-19, the “District of Columbia Public Records Management Act of 1985,” as amended, D.C. Code §§ 1-2901 et seq. (1999 Repl.).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>