<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-5316</num>
  <heading>CHANGES IN FAMILY COMPOSITION (§ 14-5316)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5316.1.</num>
    <text>The Family shall request DCHA approval to add a new Family member, with the exception of the addition of a Family member as a result of birth, adoption, foster placement or court-awarded custody. However, in all circumstances the Family is required
      to notify DCHA of the addition in accordance with chapter 84 of this chapter of the DCMR.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5316.2.</num>
    <text>Requests to add adult Family members are subject to DCHA’s eligibility requirements at chapter 51 of this title of the DCMR.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5316.3.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall only consider a request to add an adult to the Family composition under the following circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>  Marriage;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the adult is to be added as a live-in aide; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>As a reasonable accommodation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5316.4.</num>
    <text>Before DCHA’s approval can be finalized, the Family shall obtain the owner’s written approval to add a new Family member or a live-in aide.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5316.5.</num>
    <text>If the owner declines to approve the addition of a new adult Family member, the Family will be issued a transfer voucher. The new member will be added to the Family composition once the Family member has moved into a new unit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5316.6</num>
    <text>5316.6 DCHA shall not add any Family members who claim citizenship or eligible immigration status to the household until a social security number is provided and verified.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 7890, 7897 (June 29, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>