<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-5325</num>
  <heading>GENERAL POLICIES FOR ANNUAL INSPECTIONS (§ 14-5325)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5325.1</num>
    <text>5325.1 Units shall be inspected for adherence to Housing Quality Standards at least once during a fiscal year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5325.2</num>
    <text>5325.2 If the tenant or owner complains that the unit does not meet Housing Quality Standards, DCHA shall conduct a complaint inspection. The staff has to inspect only the items that the Family or owner are complaining about, but if other violations
      are noticed during the inspection, the staff shall also note those items and require the owner or Family to repair the violations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5325.3.</num>
    <text>The owner or Family shall be given time to correct the failed items.</text>
    <text>There are two (2) guidelines to use:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If the items endangers the Family&amp;#8217;s health or safety using the emergency items list at § 5325, the owner or Family shall be given twenty-four (24) hours to correct the violation after being notified; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For all other cited deficiencies, the owner or Family shall be given thirty (30) days to correct the item(s).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5325.4.</num>
    <text>Minor violations that are listed as “Passed with Comments” on the inspection report shall not be re-inspected on site. Instead the tenant and owner will be given a self-certification form whereby they can certify that the violations have been repaired.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If the Family does not repair those minor violations that are attributable to the Family, the Family will not be approved for a transfer voucher except in emergency circumstances as set forth in § 8500.1; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the owner does not repair those minor violations that are attributable to the owner, the owner will not be approved for an annual rent increase.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 7890, 7908 (June 29, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>