<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-5310</num>
  <heading>CHANGES IN FAMILY SHARE AND HOUSING ASSISTANCE PAYMENTS (§ 14-5310)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5310.1.</num>
    <text>Changes in the Family’s TTP and the HAP payment shall be processed in accordance with the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Family shall report within thirty (30) days any changes in income, Family composition, or other circumstances that may result in a change in the Family TTP;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the Family reported in a timely manner:</text>
    </level>
    <text>If the reported change results in an increase of the Family’s share of rent, the effective date of increase shall be the first of the month following a thirty (30) days’ notice of increase to the Family and landlord; or</text>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the reported change results in a decrease of the Family’s share of rent, the effective date of the decrease shall be the first of the month after the change has been reported; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If the Family failed to report the change in a timely manner:</text>
    </level>
    <text>If the change results in an increase of the Family’s share of rent, the effective date shall be the first of the month following the change in Family income or composition; or</text>
    <text>If the change results in a decrease in the Family’s share of rent, then DCHA shall not apply the change retroactively and the effective date of the change shall the first of the month following the Family’s report of the change.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5310.2.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall notify the owner and the Family of any changes in the Family share and HAP by mailing a notice that includes the new amount and effective date of the change in payment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 7890, 7894 (June 29, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>