<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-5333</num>
  <heading>FAMILY MOVES (§ 14-5333)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5333.1.</num>
    <text>Except as noted in this subsection, families may move in accordance with chapter 85 of this title of the DCMR.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5333.2.</num>
    <text>Each Family shall give notice to move in accordance with chapter 85 of this title of the DCMR.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5333.3.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall not approve requests to move a Family more than once in a twelve (12) month period unless one of the exceptions apply:</text>
    <text>A victim or Family seeks to move under the protections enumerated in the VAWA;</text>
    <text>DCHA terminates the HAP contract with the owner; or</text>
    <text>The move is necessary to grant a request for a reasonable accommodation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5333.4.</num>
    <text>Families may only request a Voucher transfer briefing if the Family:</text>
    <text>Has lived in their unit for at least a year;</text>
    <text>Deleted.</text>
    <text>Has not been terminated or is not currently being recommended for termination;</text>
    <text>Is in good standing with the lease in the current unit (no outstanding rent or tenant-responsible utility bills); and</text>
    <text>Does not have any current tenant-caused HQS violations in their existing unit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5333.5.</num>
    <text>If the request is timely and granted, a Family shall only receive one (1) transfer voucher and one (1) transfer briefing between every biennial recertification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5333.6.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding § 5334.4, Families who qualify for emergency transfer vouchers shall be issued a transfer voucher if one (1) or more of the following conditions apply:</text>
    <text>The family has demonstrated a need based on the protections for victims of intrafamily violence as explained in § 4907;</text>
    <text>DCHA has terminated the HAP contract with the Family’s landlord;</text>
    <text>The Owner has initiated eviction proceedings against the Family;</text>
    <text>Emergency transfer was granted after request from the OAG as a matter of safety; or</text>
    <text>If DCHA determines that the family voucher size is too large, and the family is not within the first year of tenancy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5333.7.</num>
    <text>Requests for transfer vouchers made within six (6) months before or after the month of biennial recertification shall be denied unless the Family either:</text>
    <text>requests the transfer voucher at the first or second biennial recertification appointment; or</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>qualifies for one (1) of the emergency conditions as stated in § 5334.6.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 7890, 7913 (June 29, 2012); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 11004, 11005 (September 21, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>