<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-712</num>
  <heading>PUB CRAWLS (ยง 23-712)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>712.1.</num>
    <text>A promoter/organizer of a &amp;#8220;Pub Crawl&amp;#8221; shall be required to obtain Board approval. The promoter/organizer shall submit an application to hold the &amp;#8220;Pub Crawl&amp;#8221; on a form provided by the Board at least six (6) weeks
      prior to the scheduled date of the event. For purposes of this section a &amp;#8220;Pub Crawl&amp;#8221; shall be defined as an organized group of establishments within walking distance which offer discounted alcoholic drinks during a specified
      time period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>712.2.</num>
    <text>At least six (6) weeks prior to the scheduled date of the event, the event organizer/promoter must provide the Metropolitan Police Department and the Board with a written description of the event to include but not be limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>the names and addresses of all the establishments which are expected to participate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>the geographic area where the event will take place;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>the anticipated number and maximum number of participants;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>the actual hours of the event;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>the operational and security plan; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>the location of the designated registration area(s).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>712.3.</num>
    <text>The operational and security plan shall include but not be limited to the name and number of security personnel contracted for the event; a plan for the control of underage drinking; and the method to be used for checking participant identification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>712.4.</num>
    <text>The promoter/organizer must post at any designated registration area, the ABC Board approved operations and security plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>712.5.</num>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Pub Crawls&amp;#8221; may not promote excessive drinking and shall not include unlimited amounts of drinks for one price (all you can drink).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>712.6.</num>
    <text>Literature describing &amp;#8220;responsible drinking practices&amp;#8221; must be available at all designated registration points.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>712.7.</num>
    <text>All advertising/promotional materials for &amp;#8220;Pub Crawls&amp;#8221; must:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>include a statement that &amp;#8220;You must be 21 or older to participate&amp;#8221;;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>promote the use of public transportation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>include the plan for a designated driver program for the event.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>712.8.</num>
    <text>Establishments who are required by law to serve food, must have food available for purchase during the hours of the &amp;#8220;Pub Crawl.&amp;#8221;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>712.9.</num>
    <text>No establishment with more than two primary tier offenses in a two-year period may participate in a &amp;#8220;Pub Crawl.&amp;#8221;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>712.10.</num>
    <text>The Board shall make a decision whether to approve a completed &amp;#8220;Pub Crawl&amp;#8221; application within three weeks of its submission. Board approval shall not be required for a &amp;#8220;Pub Crawl&amp;#8221; containing less than 200 participants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>