<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-201</num>
  <heading>POLITICAL ACTIVITY OF MEMBERS AND EMPLOYEES OF THE BOARD (ยง 3-201)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>201.1.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in this section, nothing in this chapter shall be construed as prohibiting the members or employees of the Board from doing any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Exercising the right to vote at any election conducted in the District of Columbia or elsewhere;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Signing any nominating, initiative, referendum or recall petition; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Attending candidate forums.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.2.</num>
    <text>No member or employee of the Board shall do any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be a candidate or nominee for any elected office;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Hold any office in any political party or political committee; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Participate in the activities of or contribute to any political committee of any candidate for District office or for or against any ballot measure in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.3.</num>
    <text>A member or employee of the Board shall not engage in any activity, including attending political dinners, fundraisers, parties, meetings or conferences which would imply support of or opposition to a local candidate or group of candidates for office,
      as defined in ยง 9900, a local political party or political committee, or an initiative, referendum, or recall measure to appear on the ballot in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final rulemaking published at 28 D.C. Reg. 1726 (April 17, 1981) incorporating text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 28 D.C. Reg. 684, 691 (February 13, 1981); as amended by Notice of emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 7686
        (August 20, 2010) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11107 (November 26, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>