<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-1505</num>
  <heading>FILING OF PETITIONS AND SUPPLEMENTS (ยง 3-1505)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1505.1.</num>
    <text>When filed with the Board, a nominating petition shall be accompanied by a &amp;#8220;Declaration of Candidacy and Affidavit of Qualifications.&amp;#8221; The Board may refuse to accept nominating petitions of individuals who fail to submit this declaration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1505.2.</num>
    <text>Before the nominating petition is filed, all sheets which comprise the petition shall be assembled and serially numbered. The Board may refuse to accept any petition until it has been so assembled and so numbered.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1505.3.</num>
    <text>To be accepted for filing, a petition nominating candidates for presidential electors, shall, in addition to the requirements of this section, be accompanied by an affidavit signed personally by the presidential and vice presidential candidates which
      contains the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Names of the presidential electors supported by the petition;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Written consent, by the presidential and vice presidential candidates, to each presidential elector listed on the petition as being pledged to them; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A statement that the presidential and vice presidential candidates are the duly selected nominees of that party.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1505.4.</num>
    <text>A petition nominating candidates for presidential electors, pursuant to Chapter 10 of Title 1, D.C. Code (2006 Repl.), (relating to nomination from parties where a candidate has not been elected President) may not be finally accepted by the Board
      for inclusion on the ballot unless the nominating candidates meet the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>There has been filed with the Board a Declaration of Candidacy and Affidavit of Qualifications executed in accordance with the provision of this section and with Chapter 6 of this title;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The person filing the petition executes an affidavit pursuant to the provisions of this section; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The petition is on a form provided by the Board and meets all the requirements of the provisions of this section and of the Election Act; Provided, that the Board, in its discretion, may waive any formal error.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1505.5.</num>
    <text>Any candidate who has met the requirements of this section may file petition supplements, providing the supplements meet all other pertinent provisions of this section and are accompanied by an affidavit executed by the person filing them.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1505.6.</num>
    <text>The nominating petition, affidavit, and supplements, if any, shall be filed with the Board at its office no later than 5:00 p.m., of the filing deadline required by law and announced by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1505.7.</num>
    <text>The Board may reject any nominating petition that is confusing, misleading or does not conform to the requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 27 D.C. Reg. 2763 (June 27, 1980), incorporating the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 27 D.C. Reg. 1929, 1943 (May 9, 1980); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 29 D.C. Reg. 1223, 1224 (March 19, 1982);
        as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 30 D.C. Reg. 5289, 5305 (October 14, 1983); and further amended by Final Rulemaking published at 35 D.C. Reg. 2006, 2019 (March 11, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>