<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-1501</num>
  <heading>NOMINATION OF CANDIDATES BY PETITION (ยง 3-1501)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1501.1.</num>
    <text>The front of each page of the nominating petition shall contain the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The names of the candidates for President and Vice President;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name of the political party with which they are affiliated;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The names, addresses, and registration number of the three (3) candidates for presidential electors; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A statement indicating that any registered voter, regardless of party affiliation, may sign the petition; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A statement that only the names of the candidates for President and Vice President will be listed on the ballot.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1501.2.</num>
    <text>The back of each page of the petition shall contain the name, address, and telephone number of the person circulating the petition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1501.3.</num>
    <text>No nominating petition form shall be issued by the Board until the information required by ยง 1501.1 has been placed in all appropriate spaces on the petition form.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1501.4.</num>
    <text>If a candidate is not affiliated with any political party, each nominating petition form issued by the Board on his or her behalf shall indicate that he or she is &amp;#8220;Independent.&amp;#8221;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1501.5.</num>
    <text>[Deleted] 43 D.C. Reg. 1108 (March 1, 1996).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 D.C. Reg. 2006, 2018-19 (March 11, 1988); and further amended by Final Rulemaking published at 43 D.C. Reg. 1078, 1108 (March 1, 1996).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL NOTE</heading>
      <text>Prior to March 11, 1988, the Board of Elections and Ethics published Final Rulemaking notices at 27 D.C. Reg. 2763 (June 27, 1980), incorporating the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 27 D.C. Reg. 1929, 1941-42 (May 9, 1980).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>