<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-605</num>
  <heading>CONSTRUCTION, FIRE SAFETY, FENCING, DRIVEWAYS, AND PAVING (§ 24-605)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>605.1</num>
    <text>605.1 Parking facilities shall at all times comply with the fire preventionaws and regulations of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>605.2</num>
    <text>605.2 No frame structure shall be erected, constructed, or maintained upon anyurface parking lot or ground that is more than forty square feet (40 ft.2) inrea. Any such structures shall comply with District Construction Codesequirements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>605.3</num>
    <text>605.3 No license shall be issued for any surface parking lot or ground abuttingublic space, not including public alleys, unless the division line between theublic space and the surface parking lot or ground is marked by the coping orence required
      under this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>605.4</num>
    <text>605.4 The coping or fence required under this section for surface parking lotshall be built entirely on private property and the licensee shall apply for theecessary permitting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>605.5</num>
    <text>605.5 Coping shall consist of a regulation eight inch (8 in.) coping made ofoncrete.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>605.6</num>
    <text>605.6 Fencing shall be of an approved design, not less than two feet six inches2 ft. 6 in.) in height; and may be made of cable, bar, wire, or chainonstruction with concrete, iron, pipe, or wood posts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>605.7</num>
    <text>605.7 Failure to erect or maintain the coping or fence for surface parking lotsequired under this section shall be a violation of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>605.8</num>
    <text>605.8 All curb cuts and driveways shall meet the specifications of and beermitted by the District Department of Transportation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>605.9</num>
    <text>605.9 Businesses abutting on one (1) street shall be limited to two (2)riveways, and businesses abutting on two (2) or more streets shall be limitedo three (3) driveways.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>605.10</num>
    <text>605.10 Lots and grounds paved with impervious material shall be graded androvided with approved drains so that no drainage will flow across the sidewalk.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>605.11</num>
    <text>605.11 No paving on public space shall be done without first obtaining permitrom the District Department of Transportation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 28, §§2(c) &amp;#038; (d) of the Police Regulations (1981) (asections 605-608); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 7303September 4, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>