<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-610</num>
  <heading>PARKING FACILITY ATTENDANTS (§ 24-610)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>610.1</num>
    <text>610.1 Except as permitted in § 610.2, any person employed to park or supervise the parking of automobiles in a parking facility, or who parks or supervises the parking of automobiles in a parking facility, must possess a parking facility attendant’s
      license and pay a license fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>610.2</num>
    <text>610.2 The owner or operator of a parking facility, or the owner’s duly authorized agent, may employ an individual who does not hold a parking facility attendant’s license, but who does hold a valid motor vehicle operator’s license, to park or supervise
      the parking of automobiles for not more than seventy-two (72) hours before the submission by the attendant of an application to the Director, and upon the issuance by the Director of a receipt prescribed in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>610.3.</num>
    <text>Each license shall be valid for two (2) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>610.4</num>
    <text>610.4 The licensee shall carry the license issued under this section on his or her person at all times while engaged in the licensed occupation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>610.5</num>
    <text>610.5 The licensee shall exhibit his or her license on demand to any customer of the parking lot, or to any authorized representative of the District government.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>610.6</num>
    <text>610.6 The license issued to any individual may be revoked at any time in accordance with the terms of D.C. Official Code § 47-2844 (2001).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>610.7</num>
    <text>610.7 No person shall be issued a parking facility attendant’s license unless he or she possesses a valid motor vehicle operator’s license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>610.8</num>
    <text>610.8 No person shall operate a motor vehicle under the authority of a parking facility attendant’s license unless the person also has been issued, and has in his or her possession at the time of operating the motor vehicle, a valid motor vehicle
      operator’s license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>610.9</num>
    <text>610.9 While providing parking facility services, each licensee shall wear a uniform that identifies the licensee as working for a parking lot company.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 28, §§5(a), (b), (d) &amp;#038; (e) of the Police Regulations (1981) (as section 615); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 7303 (September 4, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>