<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-611</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION FOR PARKING FACILITY ATTENDANTS LICENSE (§ 24-611)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>611.1</num>
    <text>611.1 Any individual desiring a parking facility attendant’s license shall correctly provide, upon a form prescribed by the Director, the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The applicant’s full name and address;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The applicant’s color of hair and eyes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The applicant’s date of birth and sex;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The number and date of expiration of the applicant’s motor vehicle operator’s license; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A statement of whether the applicant has ever been convicted of a felony or misdemeanor.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>611.2</num>
    <text>611.2 Each applicant shall include with his or her application a copy of the applicant’s police record from the jurisdiction in which he or she resides on the date of the application, which is certified by the chief of police of that jurisdiction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>611.3</num>
    <text>611.3 On receipt of the application, the Director shall issue to the applicant a receipt, certifying that the application has been received.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>611.4</num>
    <text>611.4 Upon the approval of the application by the Director, the Director shall issue to the applicant a license for two (2) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>611.5</num>
    <text>611.5 When an applicant for a parking attendant’s license has submitted his or her application and has been issued the receipt by the Director, as provided for in this section, that receipt shall have the full force and effect of a license until the
      Director either issues the license or denies the application. The Director may require additional information or documentation necessary to determine the applicant’s fitness to receive a license and may deny a license to an applicant who fails to
      provide the required information or supporting documentation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>611.6.</num>
    <text>In addition to those grounds otherwise outlined by law or regulation, the Director shall have the authority to deny, revoke, or suspend the license if the applicant or licensee:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Fails to meet or maintain the qualifications for licensure as outlined in this chapter; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the Director finds that the applicant or licensee shows a disregard for safety, property, welfare of an individual, or the general public, or is otherwise unfit to work as a parking lot facility attendant.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 28, §§5(b) &amp;#038; (c) of the Police Regulations (1981) (as section 616); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 7303 (September 4, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>