<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-308</num>
  <heading>GLOVER PARK MORATORIUM ZONE (§ 23-308)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>308.1.</num>
    <text>No new retailer’s license class A, CT, CN, CX, DN, DT, or DX shall be issued for a period of three (3) years from the effective date of this section in the area that extends approximately one thousand two hundred feet (1,200 ft.) in all directions
      from 2436 Wisconsin Avenue, N.W., Washington, D.C. 20007. The number of class CR retailer’s licenses permitted in this area shall not exceed fourteen (14). This area shall be known as the Glover Park Moratorium Zone.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>308.2</num>
    <text>308.2 The Glover Park Moratorium Zone is more specifically described as beginning at Tunlaw Road and Fulton Street; East on Fulton Street to Wisconsin Avenue; South on Wisconsin Avenue to Edmunds Street; East on Edmunds Street to Massachusetts Avenue;
      Southeast on Massachusetts Avenue to Observatory Circle; Southeast around Observatory Circle to Calvert Street; West on Calvert Street to Wisconsin Avenue; Southeast on both sides of Wisconsin Avenue to 35th Street; South on 35th Street to Whitehaven
      Parkway; West on Whitehaven Parkway to 37th Street; North on 37th Street to U Street; West on U Street to a point of intersection of Huidekoper Place and W Street; West on W Street to 39th Street; North on 39th Street to Davis Place; East on Davis
      Place to Tunlaw Road; North and Northwest on Tunlaw Road to Fulton Street.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>308.3.</num>
    <text>All hotels, whether present or future, shall be exempt from the Glover Park Moratorium Zone.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>308.4</num>
    <text>308.4 Nothing in this section shall prohibit the Board from approving the transfer of ownership of a retailer’s license class A, CT, CN, CR, CX, DN, DT, or DX within the Glover Park Moratorium Zone that was in effect or for which an application was
      pending prior to the effective date of this section, subject to the requirements of Title 25 of the D.C. Official Code and this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>308.5</num>
    <text>308.5 Nothing in this section shall prohibit the Board from approving the transfer of a license from a location within the Glover Park Moratorium Zone to a new location within the Glover Park Moratorium Zone.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>308.6</num>
    <text>308.6 A license holder outside the Glover Park Moratorium Zone shall not be permitted to transfer its license to a location within the Glover Park Moratorium Zone.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>308.7.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall prohibit a valid protest of any transfer or change of a license class.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>308.8</num>
    <text>308.8 The moratorium shall have a prospective effect and shall not apply to any license granted prior to the effective date of this section or to any application for licensure pending on the effective date of this section.</text>
    <text>This section shall expire three (3) years after the date of publication of the notice of final rulemaking.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 3824 (April 15, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking published
        at 56 DCR 2948 (April 17, 2009); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 2161 (February 22, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>