<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-1401</num>
  <heading>NOTICE OF KNOWN OR SUSPECTED THIRD-PARTY LIABILITY (§ 29-1401)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1401.1.</num>
    <text>Any individual or institutional health-care provider that bills the District for health-care assistance furnished to a beneficiary shall provide the Department with written notice of any known or suspected third-party liability as soon as the health-care
      provider acquires knowledge of or suspects the existence of such liability.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1401.2.</num>
    <text>The written notice shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The beneficiary’s name, address, social security number, and Medicaid recipient number, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and telephone number of the other person(s) involved in the incident, if any; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A description of the incident causing the injury or illness, including the date and location.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1401.3.</num>
    <text>A beneficiary, or if represented, the beneficiary’s attorney, shall provide the Department with written notice of any known or suspected third-party liability before taking any steps to recover damages or costs arising from an incident involving the
      third party.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1401.4.</num>
    <text>The written notice shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The beneficiary’s name, address, social security number, and Medicaid recipient number, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and telephone number of the beneficiary’s attorney, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and telephone number of the third party;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and telephone number of the third party’s attorney, if known;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and telephone number of the third party’s insurer, if known;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and telephone number of beneficiary’s insurer, if known; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A description of the incident causing the injury or illness, including the date and location.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1401.5.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of a written notice of known or suspected liability of a third party pursuant to §§1401.1, 1401.2, 1401.3, and 1401.4, the Department shall immediately send a copy of the written notice to the Corporation Counsel, together with information
      concerning the dollar amount or monetary value of health-care assistance provided to or paid for on behalf of the beneficiary by the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1401.6.</num>
    <text>If the beneficiary separately institutes a proceeding against or settlement negotiations with a third party, the beneficiary or if represented, the beneficiary’s attorney shall inform the third party that the District also has a claim, and shall give
      the Corporation Counsel written notice of the action or settlement negotiations, by personal service or certified mail, within twenty (20) calendar days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1401.7.</num>
    <text>If a court proceeding has been instituted, proof of timely notice shall be filed with the court.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 1320 (March 7, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>