<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-807</num>
  <heading>INDIVIDUAL TREATMENT AND THERAPEUTIC PLANS (ยง 29-807)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>807.1.</num>
    <text>Copies of individual treatment and therapeutic plans shall be filed in the patient records.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>807.2.</num>
    <text>The treatment and therapeutic plans shall include, but are not limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A written assessment of the patient&amp;#8217;s current mental condition, signed and dated by the physician;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Diagnosis by the physician, such as listed in the American Psychiatric Association&amp;#8217;s Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, or other professionally acceptable source;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The names of the mental health professional and physician involved in the approval and direction of the treatment plan;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A statement of the patient&amp;#8217;s specific complaints, including the limitations and abilities, specific problems, and specific needs of the patient;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A statement of the specific goals of the patient and other significant factors in seeking treatment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A notation of the role of the patient in determining specific goals of the treatment program to include whether or not the patient is in accord with these goals;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A projected timetable for the achievement of both short and long term goals;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The name and title of the mental health professionals responsible for implementation and monitoring of the treatment plan showing one (1) mental health professional as responsible for supervising the implementation of the plan, integrating the various
        aspects of the program, and ensuring the recording of progress notes; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The name and title of other staff who shall participate in carrying out the treatment plan.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking adopted at 29 DCR 264 (January 15, 1982).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>