<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2119</num>
  <heading>BICYCLE PARKING SPACES (ยง 11-2119)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2119.1.</num>
    <text>Bicycle parking spaces shall be provided for office and retail and service uses, except for retail and service uses in the C-3-C, C-4, and C-5 (PAD) Districts. For office uses in the C-4 and C-5 (PAD) Districts, bicycle parking spaces shall be provided
      as if the building or structure were located in a C-3-C District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2119.2.</num>
    <text>The number of bicycle parking spaces provided shall be at least equal to five percent (5%) of the number of automobile parking spaces required under ยง 2101.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2119.3.</num>
    <text>Bicycle facilities shall have convenient access from the building or structure and street or other bicycle right-of-way and shall be clean, secure, well-lit, and located within a building or structure, either on the ground floor, basement, or first
      cellar level.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2119.4.</num>
    <text>All bicycle parking spaces required under ยง 2119.1 shall be a minimum of two feet (2 ft.) in width and six feet (6 ft.) in length.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2119.5.</num>
    <text>An aisle five feet (5 ft.) in width shall be provided between rows of bicycle parking spaces and the perimeter of the area devoted to bicycle parking.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2119.6.</num>
    <text>If a room or common locker not divided into individual spaces is used to meet these requirements, twelve square feet (12 ft.2) of floor area shall be considered the equivalent of one (1) bicycle parking space. Where manufactured metal lockers or racks
      are provided, each locker or stall devoted to bicycle parking shall be counted as one bicycle parking space.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2119.7.</num>
    <text>[DELETED]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2119.8.</num>
    <text>Signs shall be posted stating where bicycle parking spaces are located in each building or structure where bicycle parking spaces are required. The signs shall be located in a prominent place at each entrance to the building or structure. The sign
      shall have a white background, with black lettering that is no less than two inches (2 in.) in height.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2119.9.</num>
    <text>For a building or structure existing on March 1, 1985, one percent (1%) of the amount of required parking spaces may be converted to bicycle parking spaces of appropriate size.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2119.10.</num>
    <text>For a marina or yacht club within the W-0 District, one suitably designed and sited bicycle rack parking space shall be provided for each ten (10) berths or mooring spaces, in a location that is secure and convenient to the principal structure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2119.11.</num>
    <text>For a boathouse within the W-0 District, one suitably designed and sited bicycle rack parking space shall be provided for each 2,000 gross square feet of gross building area, in a location that is secure and convenient to the principal structure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 6585, 6609 (December 28, 1984); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8504-05 (October
        20, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 3440 (April 2, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 6358 (July 8, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>