<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2103</num>
  <heading>EXCEPTIONS TO THE SCHEDULE OF REQUIREMENTS[COLON] DOWNTOWN URBAN RENEWAL AREA§ 11-2103)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2103.1.</num>
    <text>Within the Downtown Urban Renewal Area, parking spaces required for all uses need not be provided if adopted, public law or municipal regulation prohibits a curb cut on the street on which the lot faces and there is no other alternative access to
      the lot through a street or alley.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2103.2.</num>
    <text>Within the Downtown Urban Renewal Area, the Board of Zoning Adjustment is hereby authorized in accordance with the requirements of § 3104 for special exceptions to reduce or eliminate the amount of parking spaces required for all uses and to approve
      parking plans for buildings or structures to provide all the required parking spaces in an off-site collective parking facility; provided, that the provisions of §§ 2103.3 through 2103.6 are satisfied.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2103.3.</num>
    <text>Parking spaces may be reduced if other adopted public law, policy, or municipal regulation requires or recommends that the street not be broken with a curb cut and there is no other alternative access to the lot through a street or alley.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2103.4.</num>
    <text>The Board shall give consideration to the:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Nature and location of the structure;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Maximum number of students, employees, guests, customers, or clients that can reasonably be expected to use the proposed building or structure at one (1) time;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Amount of traffic congestion existing or that the building or structure can reasonably be expected to create in the neighborhood;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Quantity of existing public, commercial, or private parking, other than curb parking, on the property or in the neighborhood that can reasonably be expected to be available when the building or structure is in use; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Proximity to public transportation, particularly Metrorail stations, and quality of public transportation service in the area, or a ride-sharing program approved by the D. C. Department of Transportation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2103.5.</num>
    <text>If the applicant relies on a ride-sharing program, the applicant shall demonstrate to the Board that the program shall continue as long as the use continues.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2103.6.</num>
    <text>Prior to taking final action on an application, the Board shall refer the application to the D.C. Departments of Transportation and Housing and Community Development for review and report.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 6585, 6596 (December 28, 1984); Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8499 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>