<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2118</num>
  <heading>RULES OF INTERPRETATION (§ 11-2118)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2118.1.</num>
    <text>For the purpose of this chapter, the rules of interpretation set forth in this section shall apply.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2118.2.</num>
    <text>Where individual seats are not provided, each eighteen inches (18 in.) of benches or other similar seating shall be considered as one (1) seat.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2118.3.</num>
    <text>The number of teachers or employees shall be computed on the basis of the greatest number of persons to be employed at any one period during the day or night, including persons having both full-time and part-time employment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2118.4.</num>
    <text>In computing the number of parking spaces required, that portion of the gross floor area or cellar area devoted to parking spaces, loading berths, loading platforms, service/delivery loading spaces, and vehicular access to parking spaces, may be excluded.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2118.5.</num>
    <text>In the case of mixed uses, the parking spaces required shall be the sum of the requirements for the various individual uses computed separately in accordance with § 2101. Parking spaces for one use shall not be considered as providing the required
      parking spaces for any other use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2118.6.</num>
    <text>Whenever calculations based on the schedule set forth in § 2101 result in a fractional space, any fraction under one-half shall be disregarded and any fraction of one-half or over shall require one (1) parking space.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2118.7.</num>
    <text>No parking spaces are required for buildings or structures with a gross floor area and cellar floor area less than the minimum sizes specified in the schedule established by § 2101. However, for buildings or structures containing more than one (1)
      commercial use where the first three thousand square feet (3,000 ft.2) of gross floor area and cellar floor area do not require parking, this exemption shall apply to the combined gross floor area and cellar floor area contained in the building
      or structure and shall be pro-rated between the separate uses.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2118.8.</num>
    <text>In the case of parking reductions allowed under §§ 2102 through 2105, 2107, 2108, and 2117.9(c), no more than one (1) parking reduction shall be permitted. A reduction granted under one (1) section shall be considered a reduction for all such sections.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2118.9.</num>
    <text>Except where otherwise indicated, whenever the word &amp;#8220;all&amp;#8221; is followed by the words &amp;#8220;parking spaces&amp;#8221; in the same sentence, the parking requirements as specified shall apply to all parking spaces, whether or not
      the spaces are required by this chapter. The requirements shall also apply to both accessory parking spaces and parking spaces that are constructed as a principal use unless otherwise specified.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2118.10.</num>
    <text>No parking shall be provided that restricts vehicular access to and from gasoline pumps from any point of access to the gasoline service station.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 6585, 6608 (December 28, 1984); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 2818, 2819 (May 9, 1986); and Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the
        text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8504 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>