<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6005</num>
  <heading>NATIONAL EXAMINATION AND CERTIFICATION (ยง 17-6005)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6005.1.</num>
    <text>In addition to the requirements in ยง 6001 and ยง 6004, to qualify for a certificate to practice as a clinical nurse specialist in the District of Columbia, an applicant shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be currently certified as a clinical nurse specialist by the American Nurses Credentialing Center (ANCC) or any nationally recognized certifying body accepted by the Board; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Submit evidence indicating satisfactory completion of at least a three (3) credit hour pharmacology and clinical management of drug therapy or pharmacotherapeutics course, or completion of at least a thirty (30) contact hour pharmacology and clinical
        management of drug therapeutics course or pharmacotherapeutics course within the last five (5) years as it relates to the clinical nurse specialists&amp;#8217; scope of practice.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6005.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall submit proof of having obtained a passing score on the ANCC certification examination by arranging to have official written certification of the certified copy of the examination results, sent to the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6005.3.</num>
    <text>A national certification program acceptable to the Board shall provide:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A scope of practice statement that reflects the standards of specialized and advanced nursing practice the area of certification;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An approval process for the formal programs of study in the area of certification which shall:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be based on measurable objectives that relate directly to the scope of practice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Include theoretical and clinical content directed to the objectives; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Be equivalent to at least one academic year preceptorship which is part of the formal program and shall be included as part of the academic year. Current practice in the area of certification will not be accepted as a substitute for the formal program
        of study.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An examination in the area of certification which shall:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Measure the theoretical and clinical content denoted in the score of practice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Be developed in accordance with generally accepted standards of validity and reliability; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Be opened only to registered nurses who have successfully completed the program of study referred to in paragraph (b) of this section.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A certification maintenance program.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6005.4.</num>
    <text>The passing score on the certification examination shall be the passing score established by the certifying body administering the examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6005.5.</num>
    <text>The Board shall issue and update a list of nationally recognized certifying bodies accepted by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6005.6.</num>
    <text>Failure to maintain recertification as a clinical nurse specialist shall result in the loss of license status as a clinical nurse specialist.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 11771 (December 27, 2002); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 3129 (March 25, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 3129 (March 25, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>