<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6099</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 17-6099)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6099.1.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this chapter, the following terms have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Act &amp;#8211; Health Occupation Revision Act of 1985 (&amp;#8220;Act&amp;#8221;), effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code $8 3-1201.01 et seq.).</text>
    <text>Applicant &amp;#8211; a person applying for a license to practice as a clinical nurse specialist under this chapter.</text>
    <text>Board &amp;#8211; the Board of Nursing, established by ยง 204 of the Act, D.C. Official Code ยง 3-1202.04.</text>
    <text>Certificate &amp;#8211; a certificate to practice as a clinical nurse specialist under this chapter.</text>
    <text>Clinical practice &amp;#8211; the routine application of the principles of clinical nurse specialist to the diagnosis and treatment of disease and the maintenance of health.</text>
    <text>Graduate &amp;#8211; an individual who has graduated from a post-basic nursing education program for preparation to practice as a clinical nurse specialist.</text>
    <text>Nationally recognized certifying body &amp;#8211; is one that offers a national certification examination in the specialty area of advanced nursing practice, utilizes standards and principles of the American Board of Nursing Specialties (ABNS), and
      provides a mechanism for evaluating continued competency in the speciality area of nursing practice.</text>
    <text>Supervisor &amp;#8211; means a certified clinical nurse specialist who is responsible for the supervision of a student, graduate, or applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6099.2.</num>
    <text>The definitions in ยง 4099 of chapter 40 of this title are incorporated by reference into and are applicable to this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 11771 (December 27, 2002); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 7228 (July 23, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>