<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2022</num>
  <heading>ELIGIBILITY CRITERIA (§ 29-2022)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2022.1.</num>
    <text>In order to be eligible for assistance under this program, an applicant shall meet the following criteria.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2022.2.</num>
    <text>The applicant shall be a resident of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2022.3.</num>
    <text>The applicant shall be eligible for health insurance benefits which he or she will lose because he or she cannot continue to work due to disability, but which can be continued if the applicant pays the monthly health insurance premium.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2022.4.</num>
    <text>The applicant’s anticipated household income for the next twelve (12) months, including the month of application for assistance under this program, may not exceed five hundred percent (500%) of the federal annual poverty income level for a household
      of the same size.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2022.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant’s liquid assets may not exceed five thousand dollars ($5,000) at the time of application for assistance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2022.6.</num>
    <text>For purposes of §2022.5, the term “liquid assets” shall be defined as cash, or property owned by the applicant which can be converted into cash, for use in his or her personal support and maintenance and including, but not limited to, stocks, bonds,
      savings accounts, and certificates of deposit; “liquid assets”, however, shall not be construed to include the applicant’s primary place of residence, automobile, household or personal belongings, or cash value of life insurance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2022.7.</num>
    <text>The applicant shall provide written certification from a physician that he or she has been diagnosed as having Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome (AIDS).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 38 DCR 4360, 4361 (July 12, 1991).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>