<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-1327</num>
  <heading>GEORGIA AVENUE COMMERCIAL OVERLAY DISTRICT (GA) (ยง 11-1327)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1327.1.</num>
    <text>The Georgia Avenue Commercial (GA) Overlay District applies to all properties zoned C-2-A and/or C-3-A along both sides of Georgia Avenue, N.W., from the north side of the intersection of Georgia Avenue and Kenyon Street to the south side of the intersection
      of Georgia Avenue and Varnum Street.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1327.2.</num>
    <text>The provisions of the GA Overlay shall not apply to public schools.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1327.3.</num>
    <text>In addition to the purposes in ยง 1300, the purposes of the GA Overlay District are to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Implement the objectives of the Georgia Avenue &amp;#8211; Petworth Metro Station Area and Corridor Plan, approved by the Council of the District of Columbia on July 7, 2006 (Res. 16-686; 53 DCR 5444);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Implement the goals of the Great Streets Framework Plan for 7th Street &amp;#8211; Georgia Avenue, published by the District Department of Transportation and dated 2006;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Encourage additional residential uses along the Georgia Avenue corridor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Encourage improved commercial uses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Provide uniform building design standards;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Set guidelines for development review through PUD and special exception proceedings; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Encourage vertically-mixed uses (ground floor commercial and residential above) within a quarter mile of the Georgia Avenue &amp;#8211; Petworth Metrorail Station along Georgia Avenue, from Park Road to Shepherd Street.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 0747, 0751 (January 25, 2008); as corrected by Errata Notice published at 58 DCR 4314, 4315 (May 20, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>