<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-1320</num>
  <heading>H STREET NORTHEAST NEIGHBORHOOD COMMERCIAL OVERLAY DISTRICT (HS) (§ 11-1320)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1320.1</num>
    <text>1320.1 The H Street Northeast Neighborhood Commercial Overlay District (HS) applies to all lots fronting onto H Street, N.E. from 2nd Street to 15th Street, N.E. and zoned C-2-A, C-2-B, C-2-C, C-3-A, or C-3-B, as well as: Square 1026, Lots 65, 66,
      100, 101, 102, 103, 173, 177, 835, and 836; lots within Squares 1027 and 1049 fronting onto Maryland Avenue, N.E. or 14th Street, N.E.; Reservations 15P, 15Q, 15R, and 213; and all of Square 1050.</text>
    <text>The Overlay is divided into three (3) sub-districts affecting the following squares:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>H Street Northeast Overlay Housing Sub-district (HS-H) encompasses properties fronting on H Street, N.E. in Squares 751, 752, 776, 777, 808, 809, 832, 833, 858, and 859 from 2nd to 7th Streets, N.E.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>H Street Northeast Overlay Retail Sub-district (HS-R) encompasses properties fronting on H Street, N.E. in Squares 889, 890, 911, 912, 933, 958, 959, 981, and 982 from 7th to 12th Streets, N.E.; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>H Street Northeast Overlay Arts Sub-district (HS-A) encompasses properties fronting on H Street, N.E. in Squares 1003, 1004, 1026, 1027, 1049N, and 1049 from 12th to 15th Streets, N.E., as well as: Square 1026 lots 65, 66, 100, 101, 102, 103, 173,
        177, 835, and 836; lots within Squares 1027 and 1049 fronting onto Maryland Avenue, N.E. or 14th Street, N.E.; Reservations 15P, 15Q, 15R, and 213; and all of Square 1050.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1320.2</num>
    <text>1320.2 In addition to the purposes in § 1300, the purposes of the HS Overlay District are to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Implement the policies and goals of the Comprehensive Plan and the H Street, N.E. Strategic Development Plan as approved by the Council of the District of Columbia on February 17, 2004 (R15-460);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Encourage residential uses along the H Street, N.E. corridor, particularly provisions of affordable units and reuse of upper floors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Encourage the clustering of uses into unique destination districts along the corridor, specifically a housing district from 2nd Street to 7th Street, N.E.; a neighborhood-serving retail shopping district from 7th Street to 12th Street, N.E.; and
        an arts and entertainment district from 12th Street to 15th Street, N.E.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Establish design guidelines for new and rehabilitated buildings that are consistent with the historic character and scale of the Overlay District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Encourage the reuse of existing buildings along the corridor; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Encourage residential uses, the reuse of existing buildings, and the redevelopment of those portions of Squares 1026, 1027, 1049, and 1050 within the Overlay but not fronting H Street.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1320.3.</num>
    <text>For purposes of § 1302, the designated use area shall include any lot within the HS Overlay District that fronts on H Street, N.E. In addition to the ground floor uses designated by § 1302.2, the following uses are also designated in each Sub-district:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>HS-H Sub-district: Residential Uses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>HS-R Sub-district:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Candy store;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Computer store;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Delicatessen;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Fabric store;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Health or exercise studio;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Ice cream parlor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Plant store or nursery;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Secondhand or consignment store;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Shoe store;</text>
    </level>
    <text>(10) Video rental and sales; and</text>
    <text>(11) Other similar personal/consumer service establishment or retail use; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>HS-A Sub-district: Any use listed in §1323.2.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1320.4.</num>
    <text>The following buildings, structures, and uses are permitted only by special exception if approved by the Board of Zoning Adjustment, in accordance with the standards specified in §§ 3104 and 1325 of this Title.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Any use requiring a special exception in the underlying zone, except a new gasoline service station;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Accessory parking spaces located off-site from the principal use;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Fast food establishment or food delivery service provided:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>No part of the lot on which the use is located shall be within twenty-five feet (25 ft.) of a Residence District, unless separated therefrom by a street or alley;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If any lot line of the lot abuts an alley containing a zone district boundary line for a Residence District, a continuous brick wall at least six feet (6 ft.) high and twelve inches (12 in.) thick shall be constructed and maintained on the lot along
        the length of that lot line;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any refuse dumpsters shall be housed in a three (3) sided brick enclosure equal in height to the dumpster or six feet (6 ft.) high, whichever is greater. The entrance to the enclosure shall include an opaque gate and shall not face a Residence District;
        and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>This use shall occupy no more than twenty-five percent (25%) of the linear street frontage within the HS Overlay District as measured along the lots that face the designated roadway;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Funeral, mortuary, or undertaking establishment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Parking garage; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Construction of a new building or enlargement of the gross floor area of an existing building by fifty percent (50%) or more, if located on a lot that has six thousand square feet (6,000 sq. ft.) or more of land area.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1320.5.</num>
    <text>The following uses are prohibited:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Automobile and truck sales;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Automobile laundry;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Boat or marine sales;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Gasoline service station;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Outdoor storage of any materials; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Parking lot.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1320.6.</num>
    <text>The provisions of § 1302.5 shall not apply to the HS Overlay District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1320.7.</num>
    <text>For purposes of §1303.2, the designated roadway within the HS Overlay Districts shall be H Street, N.E.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 1708, 1711 (March 10, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 9393 (September 28, 2007); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 10347, 10356 (December 9, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>