<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-1328</num>
  <heading>DESIGN REQUIREMENTS (GA) (§ 11-1328)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1328.1.</num>
    <text>The design requirements of §§ 1328.2 through 1328.11 shall apply to any lot in the GA Overlay District for which a building permit was applied for after December 11, 2006.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1328.2.</num>
    <text>Buildings shall be designed and built so that not less than seventy-five percent (75%) of the street wall at the street level shall be constructed to the property line abutting the street right-of-way. Buildings on corner lots shall be constructed
      to all property lines abutting public streets.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1328.3.</num>
    <text>In the GA/C-2-A Zone District, seventy percent (70%) lot occupancy shall be permitted for mixed use buildings that include residential use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1328.4.</num>
    <text>On-grade parking structures with frontage on Georgia Avenue, N.W. shall provide not less than sixty-five percent (65%) of the ground level frontage as commercial space.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1328.5.</num>
    <text>Each building on a lot that fronts on Georgia Avenue, N.W. shall devote not less than fifty percent (50%) of the surface area of the street wall at the ground level to entrances to commercial uses or to the building&amp;#8217;s main lobby, and to
      display windows having clear or clear/low emissivity glass. Decorative or architectural accents do not count toward the fifty percent (50%) requirement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1328.6.</num>
    <text>Security grilles over windows or doors shall have no less than seventy percent (70%) transparency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1328.7.</num>
    <text>Each commercial use with frontage on Georgia Avenue, N.W. shall have an individual public entrance directly accessible from the public sidewalk.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1328.8.</num>
    <text>Buildings shall be designed so as not to preclude an entrance every forty feet (40 ft.) on average for the linear frontage of the building, excluding vehicular entrances, but including entrances to ground floor uses and the main lobby.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1328.9.</num>
    <text>The ground floor level of each building or building addition shall have a uniform minimum clear floor-to-ceiling height of fourteen feet (14 ft.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1328.10.</num>
    <text>Buildings subject to § 1328.9 shall be permitted an additional five feet (5 ft.) of building height over that permitted as a matter-of-right in the underlying zone.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1328.11.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding 11 DCMR § 2116.2, off-street surface parking shall be permitted in rear yards only.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 0747, 0752 (January 25, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>