<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-1309</num>
  <heading>EIGHTH STREET SOUTHEAST NEIGHBORHOOD COMMERCIAL OVERLAY DISTRICT (ES) (§1-1309)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1309.1.</num>
    <text>The Eighth Street Southeast Neighborhood Commercial (ES) Overlay District is applied to a compact geographic area along Eighth Street, S.E., near the entrance to the Navy Yard, comprising those properties zoned C-3-A in Squares 906, 907, 929, and
      930.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1309.2.</num>
    <text>In addition to the purposes set forth in § 1300, the purposes of the ES Overlay District are to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Encourage and allow new business and office development in close proximity to the Navy Yard, with emphasis on firms that will conduct business with the Navy, as well as neighborhood-serving retail and service businesses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Allow and encourage medium density commercial development, in the interest of securing economic development, while restricting building heights to a low level so as to respect the historic scale of buildings and the entrance to the adjacent Navy
        Yard; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Provide for safe and efficient pedestrian movement by reducing conflicts between pedestrian and vehicular traffic, so as to improve access to retail and other businesses in the area.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1309.3.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of § 1302, the designated area shall include any lot within the ES Overlay District that fronts on Eighth Street, L Street, M Street, or Potomac Avenue, S.E.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1309.4.</num>
    <text>For purposes of § 1302.5, restaurants, fast food establishments, and prepared food shops, shall be subject to the following limitations: these uses shall occupy no more than fifty percent (50%) of the linear street frontage within the ES Overlay District,
      as measured along the lots that face designated roadways in the ES Overlay District of which up to half (1/2) of the fifty percent (50%) of the linear street frontage shall only be occupied by fast food establishments.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1309.5.</num>
    <text>For purposes of § 1303.2, the designated roadways within the ES Overlay District shall be Eighth Street, M Street, and Potomac Avenue.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1309.6.</num>
    <text>The maximum permitted height for any building or structure in the ES Overlay District shall be forty-five feet (45 ft.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1309.7.</num>
    <text>The maximum permitted gross floor area for permitted commercial and residential uses in the ES Overlay District shall be 3.0 FAR.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 8290-91 (October 15, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8446-47 (October
        20, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 9393 (September 28, 2007); as corrected by Errata Notice published at 58 DCR 4314, 4315 (May 20, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>