<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-1304</num>
  <heading>SPECIAL EXCEPTIONS (NC) (ยง 11-1304)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1304.1.</num>
    <text>Exceptions from the requirements of this chapter shall be permitted only as a special exception, if approved by the Board of Zoning Adjustment after public hearing, in accordance with ยง 3104, and subject to the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The excepted use, building, or feature at the size, intensity, and location proposed will substantially advance the stated purposes of the NC Overlay District and the particular NC Overlay District, and will not adversely affect neighboring property,
        nor be detrimental to the health, safety, convenience, or general welfare of persons residing or working in the vicinity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Exceptional circumstances exist, pertaining to the property itself or to economic or physical conditions in the immediate area, that justify the exception or waiver;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Vehicular access and egress are located and designed so as to minimize conflict with principal pedestrian ways, to function efficiently, and to create no dangerous or otherwise objectionable traffic conditions; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Board may impose requirements pertaining to design, appearance, signs, size, landscaping, and other such requirements as it deems necessary to protect neighboring property and to achieve the purposes of the NC Overlay District and the particular
        overlay district.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1304.2.</num>
    <text>This section shall not operate to allow any exception to the height or floor area ratio limits of any NC Overlay District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 7616, 7619 (November 3, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8444 (October
        20, 2000); as corrected by Errata Notice published at 58 DCR 4314 (May 20, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>