<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-1306</num>
  <heading>CLEVELAND PARK NEIGHBORHOOD COMMERCIAL OVERLAY DISTRICT (CP) (§ 11-1306)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1306.1.</num>
    <text>The Cleveland Park Neighborhood Commercial (CP) Overlay District is applied to a compact geographic area surrounding the Cleveland Park Metrorail Station and within the Cleveland Park Historic District, comprising those lots zoned C-2-A in Squares
      2218, 2219, 2222, 2068, 2069, and 2082.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.2.</num>
    <text>In addition to the purposes in § 1300, the purposes of the CP Overlay District are to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Provide for safe and efficient pedestrian movement by reducing conflicts between pedestrian and vehicular traffic so as to improve access to retail services, the Metrorail station, and other uses in the area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Encourage compatibility of development with the purposes of the Historic Landmark and Historic District Protection Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-144, as amended; D.C. Code §§ 6-1101 to 6-1115 (formerly codified at D.C. Code §§
        5-1001 to 5-1015 (1994 Repl. &amp;#038; 1999 Supp.))); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Provide for retention of existing housing within the CP Overlay District so as to help meet the need for affordable housing and to enhance pedestrian activity, safety, and consumer support for businesses in the commercial area.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.3.</num>
    <text>For purposes of § 1302, the designated use area shall include any lot within the CP Overlay District that fronts on Connecticut Avenue or Macomb, Newark, Ordway, or Porter Streets.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.4.</num>
    <text>For purposes of § 1303.2, the designated roadway within the CP Overlay District shall be Connecticut Avenue.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.5.</num>
    <text>In the CP Overlay District, no dwelling unit or rooming unit in existence as of October 1, 1987, shall be converted to any nonresidential use or to a transient use as hotel or inn; provided, that this restriction shall not apply to the ground floor
      of the building; that is, that floor that is nearest in grade elevation to the sidewalk.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.6.</num>
    <text>The maximum permitted height for any building or structure in the CP Overlay District shall be forty feet (40 ft.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.7.</num>
    <text>The matter-of-right floor area ratio in the CP Overlay District shall be 2.0, not more than 1.0 of which may be occupied by nonresidential uses.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.8.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the requirements of §§ 1306.6 and 1306.7, developments that are subject to the requirements of Chapter 26 Inclusionary Zoning may use the following modifications to the CP Overlay’s height, lot occupancy, and floor area ratio restrictions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The maximum building height shall not exceed forty-five (45) feet;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The lot occupancy shall not exceed seventy-five percent (75%); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The floor area ratio shall not exceed 2.4 FAR.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 7616, 7620 (November 3, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 2609 (March 14, 2008); as corrected by Errata Notice published at 58 DCR 4314 (May 20, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>