<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-3199</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 27-3199)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3199.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Confidential information &amp;#8211; proprietary information.</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; the Director of the Office of Contracting and Procurement or the District of Columbia Chief Procurement Officer.</text>
    <text>Invention &amp;#8211; any device, process, design, or other discovery that is or may be patentable or otherwise protectable under Title 35 of U.S. Code.</text>
    <text>Nonprofit organization &amp;#8211; a domestic university or an organization of higher education or an organization of the type described in section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 (26 U.S.C. 501(c)) and exempt from taxation under 26
      U.S.C. 501(a), or any domestic nonprofit scientific or educational institution.</text>
    <text>Royalties &amp;#8211; payments for the use of a patented invention, copyrighted material, or other proprietary information or data under a license granted by the owner.</text>
    <text>Proprietary information &amp;#8211; information, including trade secrets, data, formulas, patterns, compilations, programs, devices, methods, techniques, or processes, that have the following characteristics:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>It derives independent economic value, actual or potential, from not being generally known to, and not being readily ascertainable by proper means by, other persons who can obtain economic value from its disclosure or use; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>It is the subject of efforts that are reasonable under the circumstances to maintain its secrecy.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1623 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>