<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-3110</num>
  <heading>RIGHTS TO COPYRIGHTED MATERIAL AND PROPRIETARY INFORMATION (ยง 27-3110)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3110.1.</num>
    <text>The Director shall prescribe standard contract provisions governing rights to copy-righted material and proprietary information under District contracts for inclusion in solicitations and contracts, in accordance with the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3110.2.</num>
    <text>A contracting officer may acquire title to, or obtain or limit access to, copyrighted materials, materials subject to copyright protection, and proprietary information developed under or used in the performance of contracts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3110.3.</num>
    <text>When necessary for the evaluation of bids or proposals, a contracting officer may include a request for proprietary information and data in a solicitation, in accordance with the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3110.4.</num>
    <text>In order to protect the property rights and economic interests of contractors and prospective contractors, the Director shall develop written procedures for safeguarding and limiting access to all types of proprietary information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3110.5.</num>
    <text>The procedures issued by the Director shall provide limited access to proprietary information developed or used under a contract. Unless otherwise provided by the Director, access shall be limited to District employees who are directly involved with
      the performance of the contract or who otherwise need access in order to properly perform their duties in connection with the contract or the items or services provided under the contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3110.6.</num>
    <text>The physical security of proprietary information shall be ensured by the use of procedures designed to limit physical access, restrict copying or other forms of duplication, and limit transfer of proprietary information to unauthorized persons.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1620 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>