<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-402</num>
  <heading>REQUESTS FOR RECORDS (ยง 1-402)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>402.1.</num>
    <text>A request for a record of an agency may be made orally or in writing and shall be directed to the particular agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>402.2.</num>
    <text>Although oral requests may be honored, a requester may be asked to submit in writing a request for records.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>402.3.</num>
    <text>A written request may be mailed, faxed or e-mailed to the agency Freedom of Information Officer, or agency head in the absence of a designated Freedom of Information Officer. The outside of the envelope or the subject line of the fax or e-mail shall
      state: &amp;#8220;Freedom of Information Act Request&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;FOIA Request&amp;#8221;. In addition, a request shall include a daytime telephone number, e-mail address or mailing address for the requester.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>402.4.</num>
    <text>A request shall reasonably describe the desired record(s).Where possible, specific information regarding names, places, events, subjects, dates, files, titles, file designation, or other identifying information shall be supplied.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>402.5.</num>
    <text>Where the information supplied by the requester is not sufficient to permit the identification and location of the record by the agency without an unreasonable amount of effort, the requester shall be contacted and asked to supplement the request
      with the necessary information. Every reasonable effort shall be made by the agency to assist in the identification and location of requested records.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 24 DCR 6211, 6212 (January 27, 1978); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 52, 53 (January 7, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>