<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-1011</num>
  <heading>COMPLIANCE CERTIFICATION (ยง 20-1011)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1011.1.</num>
    <text>For each control period, the AAR for the budget source shall submit to the Administrator an annual compliance certification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1011.2.</num>
    <text>The AAR shall submit the compliance certification by the allowance transfer deadline (December 31) of each year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1011.3.</num>
    <text>The compliance certification shall contain, at a minimum:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Identification of the budget source, including name, address, name of AAR and NATS account number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A statement whether emissions data have been submitted to the Administrator pursuant to the procedures established in ยง 1009 and conforming to the Administrator&amp;#8217;s requirements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A statement whether the budget source operated in compliance with the allowances allocated for the control period, including those obtained through transfer by the allowance transfer deadline, and holds sufficient allowances in its compliance account
        for the control period, as of the allowance transfer deadline, to equal or exceed the recorded emissions for the control period;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A statement of certification whether the monitoring plan that governs the budget source was maintained to reflect actual operation of the budget source;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A statement of certification that all emissions from the budget source were accounted for, either through the applicable monitoring or through application of the appropriate missing data procedures; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A statement to indicate whether there were any changes in the method of operation of the budget source or the method of monitoring the budget source during the current year.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1011.4.</num>
    <text>The Director reserves the right to verify compliance by whatever means necessary, including:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Inspecting facility-operating records;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Obtaining information on allowance deduction and transfers from NATS;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Obtaining information on emissions from NETS;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Testing emission monitoring devices; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Requiring a budget source to conduct emissions testing under the supervision of the Director.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by final rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8646(October 10, 2000); as amended by final rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9686 (December 8, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>