<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-402</num>
  <heading>NON-DISCRIMINATION AND EQUITABLE SERVICES (ยง 7-402)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>402.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall, on the grounds of race, color, religion, national origin, sex, age, marital status, personal appearance, sexual orientation, family responsibilities, physical handicap, matriculation, political affiliation or belief be discriminated
      against, or denied employment as a participant, administrator, staff-person, in connection with any program under the Act, except that where the Act specifies or limits the age range of the eligible population.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>402.2.</num>
    <text>YES, the Department, Contractors, Vendors, Recipients, Sub-Recipients under the Act shall comply with the following laws:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Human Rights Law, Title 34 of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Titles VI, VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Equal Pay Act;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Rehabilitation Act;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Title IX of the Education Amendments Act of 1972; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Other applicable non-discrimination laws.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>402.3.</num>
    <text>All programs, to the maximum extent feasible, shall contribute to the elimination of sex stereotyping. YES, in planning its program activities, shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Recruit for, and encourage, female entry, through such means as training, into occupations with skill shortages where women represent less then twenty-five percent (25%) of the labor force;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Recruit for, and encourage, male entry, through such means as training, into occupations with skill shortages where men represent less than twenty-five percent (25%) of the labor force; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Contribute to the maximum extent feasible to the removal of barriers to the mobility of the handicapped.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>402.4.</num>
    <text>No person shall be denied training or employment in any program because of artificial barriers to employment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>402.5.</num>
    <text>YES shall analyze and re-evaluate job descriptions and qualification requirements at all levels of employment, including civil service requirements and practices relating thereto, with a view toward removing artificial barriers to employment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>402.6.</num>
    <text>Where tests or selection procedures have an adverse impact on any race, sex, or national origin group, the tests or selection procedures shall be validated as to job relatedness.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>402.7.</num>
    <text>Tests or selection procedures which have been validated shall not be considered to be an artificial barrier to employment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>402.8.</num>
    <text>YES shall establish procedures to ensure against discrimination and foster equal employment opportunity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>402.9.</num>
    <text>YES shall assign EEO responsibility to an individual or staff, or if this is not practicable, explain why in the Master Plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>402.10.</num>
    <text>Members of the eligible populations shall be provided maximum feasible opportunities for employment in the administration of programs, including staff positions in which they will have opportunities for occupational training and career advancement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>402.11.</num>
    <text>YES shall make special efforts to recruit and hire staff which will reflect the make-up of the population of the area by age, race, sex and national origin, and shall take corrective action if staff composition varies significantly from this goal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>