<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-418</num>
  <heading>PREVENTION OF FRAUD AND PROGRAM ABUSE (ยง 7-418)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>418.1.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, &amp;#8220;Fraud&amp;#8221; includes knowing-or the reckless misrepresentation of facts which induces reliance on such misrepresentation to the detriment of a second party, particularly those misrepresentations affecting
      the use, expenditure, receipt of or entitlement to funds made available by the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>418.2.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, &amp;#8220;abuse&amp;#8221; encompasses any improper conduct in violation of YES Program interests, agreements, controlling policies, regulations, or statutes which may or may not constitute fraud.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>418.3.</num>
    <text>All administrators, participants, recipients, sub-recipients, members of councils, Advisory Boards, shall avoid personal conflict of interest and appearance of conflict of interest in the allocation of funds and in the conduct of contracting/procurement
      activities involving funds provided under the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>418.4.</num>
    <text>No funds shall be paid to any non-District or Federal individual, institution or organization to conduct an evaluation of any program or component if the individual, institution or organization is associated with that program or component as a consultant,
      technical advisor, employee or other compensable capacity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>418.5.</num>
    <text>No officer, employees, or agent of YES or any recipient or sub-recipient shall solicit or accept gratuities, favors or anything of monetary value from any actual or potential youth participant, contractor, vendor or sub-recipient.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>418.6.</num>
    <text>Strict accounting procedures shall be utilized to maintain the discretion and integrity of various finding codes, sources and accounts of monies provided under the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>