<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-607</num>
  <heading>COMMISSION OVERSIGHT OF PROGRAM IMPLEMENTATION (ยง 27-607)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>607.1.</num>
    <text>If the Commission determines that an agency&amp;#8217;s proposed sheltered market program is unsatisfactory or that an agency is not fulfilling its commitment under an approved program, the Commission may make specific recommendations to the agency
      with regard to the agency&amp;#8217;s program or program implementation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>607.2.</num>
    <text>If the Commission determines that an agency&amp;#8217;s sheltered market program goal is too low or is not being met, the Commission may require the agency to give at least thirty (30) days advance notice to the Commission of the solicitation of bids
      on the open market for any contract in the amount of twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000) or more.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>607.3.</num>
    <text>If the Commission determines that an agency&amp;#8217;s sheltered market procurement program goal is too low or is not being met, the Commission may require that, prior to the establishment of specifications for any procurement contract in the amount
      of $2,000 or more, an agency shall inform the Commission whether the contract will be placed in the sheltered market.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>607.4.</num>
    <text>If the agency has not determined whether the contract will be placed in the sheltered market, the Commission may make a recommendation for placement and provide the names of certified contractors to the agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>607.5.</num>
    <text>If an agency does not place a contract in the sheltered market pursuant to a Commission recommendation under this section, the agency shall provide the Commission with a written explanation for placing the contract in the open market.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>607.6.</num>
    <text>If the Commission determines that an agency&amp;#8217;s sheltered market program goal is too low or is not being met, the Commission may order that a portion of the agency&amp;#8217;s contracts be reserved for placement in the sheltered market program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>607.7.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall inform the Mayor of all determinations, recommendations, and orders issued pursuant to this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 26 DCR 2771, 2778 (December 21, 1979).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>