<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-8903</num>
  <heading>NOTICE OF HEARING AND RIGHTS TO DOCUMENTS (§ 14-8903)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8903.1</num>
    <text>8903.1 Requests for an Informal Hearing shall follow the following guidelines:</text>
    <text>Requests for an Informal Hearing or extension of time to request an Informalearing shall be reduced to writing.</text>
    <text>DCHA may assist participants in reducing requests for an Informal Hearing orxtension of time to request an Informal Hearing to writing to comply with §903.1(a).</text>
    <text>Any assistance provided by DCHA to reduce a request to writing shall not beeemed the provision of legal advice to the participant.</text>
    <text>Participants shall either mail via first class mail or personally deliver toCHA’s Office of Fair Hearings their request for an Informal Hearing orequest for an extension of time to request an Informal Hearing. If personallyelivered, DCHA shall provide
      a receipt to the participant noting that theequest for an Informal Hearing was received and the date it was received.</text>
    <text>If the request for an Informal Hearing is mailed to DCHA, the request shall beostmarked within thirty-five (35) calendar days from:</text>
    <text>the postmark date of DCHA&amp;#8217;s notification under § 8902; or</text>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>the notice of an action or determination by DCHA.</text>
    </level>
    <text>If the request for an Informal Hearing is personally delivered to DCHA, theequest must be received by DCHA’s Office of Fair Hearings within thirty-five35) calendar days from:</text>
    <text>the postmark date of DCHA&amp;#8217;s notification under § 8902; or</text>
    <text>the date of the issuance of the notice of a challenged action.</text>
    <text>Requests to reschedule an Informal Hearing shall be subject to the followingonditions:</text>
    <text>Either party may request to reschedule an Informal Hearing for the conveniencef the party up to three (3) calendar days prior to the first scheduled Informalearing date, with or without a showing of good cause.</text>
    <text>Either party may request to reschedule an Informal Hearing any time prior to theirst scheduled Informal Hearing date or prior to any subsequent hearing date,nly if the requesting party can demonstrate good cause and if delay will notesult in harm
      or prejudice to the other party.</text>
    <text>Notwithstanding the paragraph above, the Office of Fair Hearings will reschedulen Informal Hearing as a reasonable accommodation if the participant canemonstrate that a disability prevented them from rescheduling within therescribed time periods.</text>
    <text>Once a timely request for an Informal Hearing has been filed, the Housingssistance Payments (HAP) will continue to the current landlord in accordanceith the current HAP contract in effect at the time of the request for annformal Hearing until a final
      determination is made in accordance with thishapter.</text>
    <text>If a participant has not submitted a timely request for an Informal Hearing per 8903.1, but still desires an Informal Hearing to be held, the participantust file a “Good Cause Hearing” request. The Good Cause Hearing requesthall explain the reason
      or reasons that the participant failed to comply withhe requirements of § 8903.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8903.2</num>
    <text>8903.2 Good Cause Hearings shall follow the following guidelines:</text>
    <text>A participant can only request a Good Cause Hearing if the participant has beenerminated from the Housing Choice Voucher Program.</text>
    <text>If the Office of Fair Hearings receives an Informal Hearing request that doesot comply with the deadlines in § 8903.1, the Office of Fair Hearings willotify the participant in writing of the right to request a Good Cause Hearing.</text>
    <text>Any Good Cause Hearing Request received more than sixty (60) calendar days afterhe date of the issuance of the notice pursuant to § 8903.2(a) shall be denieds untimely and barred.</text>
    <text>If the Office of Fair Hearings does not schedule a Good Cause Hearing withinhirty (30) calendar days of the participants’ timely request, then DCHA shallutomatically reinstate any relevant benefits retroactive to the date ofermination, pending the
      issuance of a decision following a Good Cause Hearing.</text>
    <text>The sole issue for determination in the Good Cause Hearing shall be whether thearticipant had good cause for failing to timely request an Informal Hearing.</text>
    <text>In determining whether the participant has demonstrated good cause, the Hearingfficer shall consider the following factors:</text>
    <text>Whether and when the participant received notice of the challenged DCHAetermination, action, or inaction; and</text>
    <text>Any mitigating circumstances related to the untimely filing of the request forn Informal Hearing, including but not limited to circumstances related to thearticipant’s disability, incapacity, or an emergency affecting thearticipant or a member of
      the participant’s household.</text>
    <text>At the Good Cause Hearing, the Hearing Officer shall not hear evidence orddress the merits of the participant’s underlying challenge to the DCHA’sction, inaction or determination. The Hearing Officer shall only considervidence regarding the timeliness
      of the request and the factors listed in §903.2(f) at the Good Cause Hearing.</text>
    <text>In the event that the Hearing Officer hears the merits of the underlyinghallenged DCHA action or determination, either party may request the Executiveirector or his/her designee to vacate the Hearing Officer’s decision andeschedule the Good Cause
      Hearing with another impartial Hearing Officer inccordance with the provisions above.</text>
    <text>The Hearing Officer shall make his or her best effort to render a decision onhe good cause showing on the same day that the Good Cause Hearing is held, buthall render a decision no more than three (3) business days after the Goodause Hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8903.3</num>
    <text>8903.3 The following process for scheduling and issuing Informal Hearing andood Cause Hearing notification letters shall apply:</text>
    <text>When the Office of Fair Hearings receives a timely written request for annformal Hearing or a Good Cause Hearing the following provisions apply:</text>
    <text>The Office of Fair Hearings shall mail a letter notifying the participant of theate and time of the Hearing within fifteen (15) calendar days of the postmarkate of the hearing request if the hearing request is mailed to the Office ofair Hearings,
      or within fifteen (15) calendar days of the receipt if theearing request is hand-delivered to the Office of Fair Hearings.</text>
    <text>The Office of Fair Hearings notification letter shall also be mailed to anyepresentative of the participant who is identified by name and address on theequest for the Hearing or who has entered his or her appearance since then.</text>
    <text>The Office of Fair Hearings shall deliver a letter notifying the DCHA Office ofeneral Counsel of the date and time of the Hearing within fifteen (15) calendarays of the postmark date of the hearing request.</text>
    <text>The date of the hearing shall be no sooner than fifteen (15) calendar days ando later than thirty (30) calendar days after the postmark date of the Office ofair Hearings letter notifying the participant of the date and time of theearing.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>All notification letters for Hearings shall contain:</text>
    </level>
    <text>The date and time of the Hearing;</text>
    <text>The location of the Hearing;</text>
    <text>The participant’s right to bring evidence, witnesses, and legal or otherepresentation at the participant’s expense;</text>
    <text>The right to view, or have their counsel or other representative view, subjecto a timely request under § 8903.4 any documents in the participant&amp;#8217;sile, or any evidence in the possession of DCHA, upon which DCHA based theroposed action, inaction
      or determination, or that DCHA intends to rely on athe Hearing;</text>
    <text>The right to obtain, subject to a timely request under Section 8903.4, a copy ofocuments or evidence in the possession of DCHA prior to the Hearing and noticehat DCHA shall provide the copies pursuant to § 8903.4; and</text>
    <text>The participant must provide to the Office of the General Counsel copies of anyocuments or evidence the participant intends to use at the Hearing at leasthree (3) business days prior to the scheduled Hearing.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If DCHA provides evidence that it mailed the notice via first class mail inhe ordinary course of business to the participant’s address of record and theotice was not returned to DCHA, then the participant shall be presumed to haveeceived the notice.
        The participant bears the burden of rebutting thisresumption by providing sufficient evidence that the notice was not received.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8903.4</num>
    <text>8903.4 The following rules shall apply to the Production of Documents:</text>
    <text>DCHA shall make copies of requested documents for the participant. DCHA shallrovide the first seventy-five (75) such pages to the participant at no chargend shall charge twenty-five (25) cents per page for each page in excess ofeventy-five (75). If
      the documents are provided electronically or on a CD,CHA is authorized to charge for the cost of the CD and the total number ofages produced electronically.</text>
    <text>Upon request by a participant or its representative to review and/or copy anyocuments in the participant&amp;#8217;s file, DCHA shall make such documentsvailable to the participant, or its representative for review and/or copyingither within twenty-one
      (21) calendar days of the request or seven (7) calendarays prior to the Informal Hearing date, whichever is sooner.</text>
    <text>In no case shall the participant, or its representatives, be allowed to remove aile from DCHA&amp;#8217;s office.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 7193, 7195-97 (July 26,002); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 13170 (September 20,013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>