<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-1209</num>
  <heading>CONTRACT ADMINISTRATION (§ 27-1209)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1209.1</num>
    <text>1209.1 The contracting officer may appoint a contract administrator for each contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1209.2.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer may delegate the following functions to a contract administrator:</text>
    <text>Prepare a clear and concise statement of work;</text>
    <text>Determine the allowability, suspension, or disapproval of costs;</text>
    <text>Approve or disapprove contractor invoices;</text>
    <text>Review and approve or disapprove a contractor’s requests for payments under progress payments or performance-based payment structures;</text>
    <text>Take action to recover overpayments from the contractor;</text>
    <text>Perform production support, oversight, and status reporting, including timely reporting of potential and actual slippages in contract delivery schedules;</text>
    <text>Advise the contracting officer of any actual or potential labor disputes;</text>
    <text>Ensure contractor compliance with contractual quality assurance requirements;</text>
    <text>Ensure contractor compliance with contractual safety requirements;</text>
    <text>Perform surveillance to assess compliance with contractual terms for schedule, cost, and technical performance in the areas of design, development and production;</text>
    <text>Report to the contracting officer any inadequacies noted in the specifications;</text>
    <text>Ensure timely submission of required reports;</text>
    <text>Monitor contractor compliance with specifications or other contractual requirements;</text>
    <text>Prepare evaluations of contractor performance in accordance with chapter 22 of this title; and</text>
    <text>Any other function relating to contract administration not expressly reserved by these rules to the contracting officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1407 (February 26, 1988); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 9071 (September 27, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 11077,
        11078 (December 23, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>