<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-1599</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 31-1599)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1599.1.</num>
    <text>The words and phrases in this chapter shall have the meanings set forth below:</text>
    <text>Applicant – An individual, partnership or corporation seeking a dome light installation business license from the Commission.</text>
    <text>Commission – The DC Taxicab Commission.</text>
    <text>Dome light– An instrument or device approved by the Commission which is attached to the top of a licensed taxicab to illuminate the assigned taxi number and display a taxi’s availability For Hire.</text>
    <text>Dome light installation business – Any business which engages, in whole or in part, in the manufacture, sale (whether of new or used equipment), installation, repair, or adjustment of taxi dome lights for use on any licensed taxi vehicle in the District
      of Columbia including any business which engages in whole or in part in the installation of taxicab cruiser lights.</text>
    <text>Dome light installation business owner – An individual, partnership, or corporation licensed by the Commission to own and operate a dome light installation business.</text>
    <text>Driver – A person licensed by the Commission to drive a licensed DC taxicab in the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Mailing address – The address designated by an applicant or licensee for the receipt of all notices and correspondence from the Commission. Unless otherwise approved in advance, the mailing address of a dome light installation business licensee shall
      be the street address of the business.</text>
    <text>Owner – An individual, partnership, limited liability company, or corporation licensed by the Commission to own and operate a taxicab or taxicabs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 14019 (December 7, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>