<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-1502</num>
  <heading>DOME LIGHT INSTALLATION BUSINESS LICENSE &amp;#8211; GENERAL REQUIREMENTS (ยง1-1502)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1502.1.</num>
    <text>The application for the initial and renewal dome light installation business license shall be filed on a form provided by the Office of Taxicabs and shall contain a sworn and notarized statement that the information contained therein is true under
      penalty of perjury.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.2.</num>
    <text>License Application Requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An individual applicant for a dome light installation business license shall:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Provide proof of identity in the form of a valid photo identification issued by the United States, any state or territory thereof, or any political subdivision of such state or territory; and a valid, original social security card;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Be at least eighteen (18) years of age; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Be of good moral character as reflected by the outcome of the report required in paragraph (d) of this subsection and in accordance with the guidelines in ยง 1001.12 of this title.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An applicant that is a partnership shall provide the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A certified copy of the partnership certificate from the jurisdiction where the principal place of business is located.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Each partner must satisfy the requirements for individual applicants set forth in ยง 1502.2(a).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An applicant that is a corporation shall provide the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A certified copy of its certificate of incorporation with a filing receipt issued by the Mayor, if incorporated less than one (1) year from the date of the license application or a certificate of good standing; or if incorporated more than one (1)
        year from the date of the license application, or if not a District of Columbia corporation, a copy of the certificate of incorporation, filing receipt, and authority to do business within the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A list of its officers and shareholders, including names, residence addresses, telephone numbers, and percentage of ownership interest of each shareholder; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A certified copy of the minutes of the organizational meeting at which the current officers were elected.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Each of the following persons shall be fingerprinted, for purposes of securing criminal history records from the Federal Bureau of Investigation:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Each individual applicant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Each partner of a partnership applicant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Each officer or shareholder of a corporate applicant; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Each person who has provided funds either individually, or as a principal of a partnership or corporation, whether such funds were provided by gift, loan, or otherwise, in connection with the operation of the dome light installation business, unless
        such provider is a licensed bank or loan company. The applicant shall pay any processing fees required by the Office of Taxicabs or the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The Commission shall have the right to reject the proposed name of any dome light installation business that is substantially similar to any name in use by another dome light installation business licensee.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Each license expires two (2) years from the date of issuance.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 14019 (December 7, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>