<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-1529</num>
  <heading>DOME LIGHT INSTALLATION BUSINESS – SALE OF DOME LIGHTS (§ 31-1529)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1529.1.</num>
    <text>A dome light installation business owner shall only sell and install dome lights that have been approved by the Commission for use in a District of Columbia licensed taxicab.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1529.2.</num>
    <text>A dome light installation business owner shall not sell a dome light for use in a taxicab licensed by the Commission unless a valid vehicle license from the Commission is presented.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1529.3.</num>
    <text>A dome light installation business owner shall not sell a dome light for use in a Commission licensed vehicle unless the installation, testing and certification of the dome light/vehicle assembly is performed by the dome light installation business
      licensee or an employee thereof.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1529.4.</num>
    <text>A dome light installation business owner shall report to the Commission, within seven (7) days, all sales, trades or exchanges of dome lights by the licensed dome light installation business on a form prescribed by the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1529.5.</num>
    <text>A dome light installation business owner shall inform all purchasers in writing, before the sale takes place, of any and all restrictions imposed by the dome light manufacturer or dome light installation business licensee regarding the testing, repairs,
      and installation of the dome light.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1529.6.</num>
    <text>A dome light installation business owner shall remove, deface, or otherwise void the validity of the certification sticker upon receipt of a dome light purchased, exchanged, or accepted in trade by the dome light installation business licensee, and
      shall report such decertification to the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1529.7.</num>
    <text>The certification sticker must conform to all specifications established by the Commission and bear the name of the Chairperson of the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1529.8.</num>
    <text>All installations of dome lights in taxicabs licensed to operate in the District of Columbia must be in accordance with specifications which have been filed with and approved by the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1529.9.</num>
    <text>No change in the method of installation shall be made unless the installation method has been filed with and approved by the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 14019 (December 7, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>