<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-301</num>
  <heading>GENERAL AUTHORITY OF THE ADMINISTRATOR OF DOCUMENTS (ยง 1-301)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>301.1.</num>
    <text>The Administrator of the Office of Documents and Administrative Issuances is vested with authority to administer generally the provisions of this chapter, the provisions of the Documents Act, and the applicable provisions of the Administrative Procedure
      Act (D.C. Code ยง2-501 et seq.), as amended, in accordance with the provisions of D.C. Official Code, ยง2-612 (2006 Repl.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.2.</num>
    <text>The Administrator is authorized to promulgate rules and procedures for the implementation of the Documents Act and applicable provisions of the Administrative Procedure Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.3.</num>
    <text>The Administrator is responsible for the supervision, management, and direction of the District of Columbia Office of Documents and Administrative Issuances, under the supervision of the Secretary of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.4.</num>
    <text>The Administrator is authorized to adopt editorial standards for the submission of documents for publication in the District of Columbia Register and the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations, including requirements for standardized organization,
      numbering, format, grammar, and other matters of style.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.5.</num>
    <text>With the exception of acts and resolutions adopted by the Council of the District of Columbia, the Administrator is authorized to reject for publication any document that fails to comply substantially with the publication requirements and standards
      set forth in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.6.</num>
    <text>The Administrator is authorized to incorporate by reference the text of documents in the D.C. Register or D.C. Municipal Regulations, in accordance with the provisions of the Documents Act and this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.7.</num>
    <text>The Administrator is required to certify the promulgation, adoption, or enactment of all documents published by the Office of Documents and Administrative Issuances. The Administrator is authorized to obtain the assistance of the Office of the Attorney
      General, the officer designated by the Chairperson of the Council, or agency legal counsel in determining whether a document should be certified for publication.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.8.</num>
    <text>The Administrator is required to provide instruction for promulgators of documents in the matters set forth in this chapter, including preparation and submission of documents, publication standards, and other areas that will assist the promulgators
      in complying with the requirements of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 9855, 9856 (May 4, 1979); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 4091, 4092 (September 18, 1981); and Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 271, 273 (January 9, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>