<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4911</num>
  <heading>SCOPE OF PRACTICE (ยง 17-4911)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4911.1.</num>
    <text>A physician assistant may, in accordance with this chapter and the Act, perform health care tasks that are consistent with sound medical practice, when delegated by their supervising physician(s) and the service is within the physician assistant&amp;#8217;s
      skills, forms a component of the physician&amp;#8217;s scope of practice, and the physician assistant is provided supervision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4911.2.</num>
    <text>A written delegation agreement that lists delegated functions, practice sites, and supervisors must be signed by the supervising physician(s) and the physician assistant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4911.3.</num>
    <text>Physician assistants may pronounce the death of patients under their care and authenticate with their signature any form that may be authenticated by a supervising physician, consistent with the permission granted by their supervisors, if such is
      specifically included among the permitted responsibilities outlined in the delegation agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4911.4.</num>
    <text>Physician assistants shall be considered the agents of their supervising physician(s) in the performance of all practice-related activities including, but not limited to, the ordering of diagnostic, therapeutic, and other medical services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4911.5.</num>
    <text>Each time a physician assistant provides care for a patient and enters his or her name, signature, initials, or computer code on a patient&amp;#8217;s record, chart, or written order, the physician assistant shall also enter the name of the supervising
      physician responsible for the patient.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4911.6.</num>
    <text>When a physician assistant transmits an oral order, he or she shall also state the name of the supervising physician responsible for the patient.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4911.7.</num>
    <text>A physician assistant may perform health care tasks and medically related services at any location where the supervising physician(s) can provide appropriate oversight and/or review of the physician assistant&amp;#8217;s actions related to the provision
      of such services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4911.8.</num>
    <text>Physician assistants licensed in the District shall keep their license available for inspection at their primary place of business and shall, when engaged in their professional activities, identify themselves as physician assistants by introduction
      and by identification badge with clearly visible lettering with their name and title &amp;#8220;Physician Assistant&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;PA-C&amp;#8221;.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4911.9.</num>
    <text>A physician assistant may give medical orders to health professionals, consistent with the policies of a hospital or health care facility where the orders are to be executed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 8263, 8268 (December 8, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 8489, 8490 (August 31, 2007); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 4201 (March 22, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>