<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4907</num>
  <heading>APPROVED CONTINUING EDUCATION PROGRAMS AND ACTIVITIES (ยง 17-4907)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4907.1.</num>
    <text>The Board, in its discretion, may approve continuing education programs and activities that contribute to the knowledge, skills, and professional performance and relationships that a physician assistant uses to provide services to patients, the public
      or the profession and that the other requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4907.2.</num>
    <text>The Board may approve continuing medical education programs and activities for Category 1 credit that are as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Sponsored, co-sponsored, or accredited by:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The American Academy of Physician Assistants (AAPA);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Accreditation Council for Continuing Medical Education (ACCME);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The American Osteopathic Council on Continuing Medical Education (AOACCME);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The American Academy of Family Physicians (AAFP); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A state medical society; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Designated:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Category 1 by the AAPA;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>American Medical Association Physician&amp;#8217;s Recognition Award (AMA/PRA) Category 1 by the ACCME;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Category 1 by the AOACCME; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Prescribed credit by the AAFP.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4907.3.</num>
    <text>A physician assistant may show proof of meeting the above continuing medical education requirements by providing evidence of current certification by the National Commission on Certification of Physician Assistants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4907.4.</num>
    <text>The Board may approve continuing education programs and activities for Category 2 credit that are as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Limited in content to the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Public health administration;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The basic medical sciences; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The discipline of clinical medicine; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Comprised of one of the following activities:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Grand rounds;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Teaching rounds;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Seminars;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Lectures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Conferences;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Medical teaching;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Patient care review;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Publication or presentation of an article related to practice as a physician assistant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Workshops;</text>
    </level>
    <text>(10) Courses of instruction, including self-instruction;</text>
    <text>(11) Reading literature published primarily for readership by health care practitioners;</text>
    <text>(12) Teaching health professionals, as long as such teaching is not a major professional responsibility of a physician assistant; or</text>
    <text>(13) Written and practical examination, including self-assessment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4907.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall have the burden of verifying whether a program or activity is approved by the Board pursuant to this section prior to attending the program or engaging in the activity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 8263, 8266 (December 8, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 8486 (August 31, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>