<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-941</num>
  <heading>MEDICAID BIRTH CENTER SERVICES AND REIMBURSEMENT (§ 29-941)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>941.1.</num>
    <text>These rules establish standards governing Medicaid reimbursement for the delivery of services provided to Medicaid beneficiaries at freestanding birth centers located in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>941.2.</num>
    <text>A freestanding birth center, eligible for Medicaid reimbursement shall be:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Licensed in accordance with the Health-Care and Community Residence</text>
    </level>
    <text>Facility, Hospice and Home-Care Licensure Act of 1983, effective February 24, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-48; D.C. Official Code, §§ 44-501, et seq. (2005 Repl. &amp;#038; 2012 Supp.)) and implementing rules; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Enrolled by DHCF as a Medicaid provider of birth center/maternity center services.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>941.3.</num>
    <text>Services eligible for Medicaid reimbursement provided at a freestanding birth center shall be delivered by a:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Physician licensed in accordance with the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revisions Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code §§ 3-1201 et seq. (2007 Repl. &amp;#038; 2012 Supp.));</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Pediatric Nurse Practitioner who is licensed as a registered nurse pursuant to the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revisions Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code §§ 3-1201 et seq. (2007 Repl. &amp;#038;
        2012 Supp.)), and certified by the National Board of Pediatric Nurse Practitioners or the Pediatric Nursing Certification Board (PNCB);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Family Nursing Practitioner who is licensed as a registered nurse pursuant to the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revisions Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code §§ 3-1201 et seq. (2007 Repl. &amp;#038;
        2012 Supp.)) and credentialed as a Family Nurse Practitioner- Board Certified (FNP-BC);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Nurse Midwife who is licensed as an advanced practice registered nurse pursuant to the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revisions Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code §§ 3-1201 et seq. (2007 Repl. &amp;#038;
        2012 Supp.)), and certified by the American Midwifery Certification Board (AMCB); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Certified Professional Midwife who is certified pursuant to the American Midwifery Certification Board (AMCB).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>941.4.</num>
    <text>Services eligible for Medicaid reimbursement provided at a freestanding birth center shall be provided:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>To beneficiaries in an outpatient setting;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>By a facility that is not a part of a hospital; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>By or under the direction of a physician.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>941.5.</num>
    <text>Services eligible for Medicaid reimbursement provided at a freestanding birth center shall consist of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Routine ante-partum care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Delivery; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Postpartum care.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>941.6.</num>
    <text>Medicaid reimbursement for routine ante-partum care in any trimester shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Initial and subsequent medical history;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Physical examination;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Recording of fetal heart tones;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Recording of weight and blood pressure;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Routine chemical urinalysis; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Maternity counseling.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>941.7.</num>
    <text>Medicaid reimbursement for delivery services shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Admission history and physical examination;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Management of uncomplicated labor; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Vaginal delivery.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>941.8.</num>
    <text>Medicaid reimbursement for postpartum care shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Mother’s postpartum check within six (6) weeks after birth;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Newborn screening test which consists of a screening panel which shall include, but not be limited to:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Phenylketonuria (PKU);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Congenital Adrenal Hyperplasia (CAH);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Congenital hypothyroidism;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Hemoglobinopathies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Biotinidase deficiency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Maple Syrup Urine Disease (MSUD);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Homocystinuria; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Galactosemia.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A well baby check or newborn assessment to include two separate screenings for a newborn on two separate dates of service.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>941.9.</num>
    <text>Medicaid reimbursement for services for normal, uncomplicated pregnancies shall be limited to fourteen (14) ante-partum visits. These visits shall occur in the following manner:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Monthly visits up to twenty-eight (28) weeks gestation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Thereafter, biweekly visits up to thirty-six (36) weeks gestation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Thereafter, weekly visits until delivery.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>941.10.</num>
    <text>In order to be eligible for Medicaid reimbursement, additional birth center visits, beyond the requirements set forth in § 941.9 shall be deemed medically necessary and require prior authorization.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>941.11.</num>
    <text>Reimbursement rates for birth centers and practitioners delivering birth center services shall be published on the DHCF website at www.dhcf.dc.gov.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>941.99.</num>
    <text>DEFINITIONS</text>
    <text>For purposes of this chapter, the following terms shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Ante-partum care &amp;#8211; Care delivered to a pregnant patient during the period before childbirth.</text>
    <text>Gestation &amp;#8211; The period of development in the uterus from conception until birth.</text>
    <text>Outpatient &amp;#8211; A patient who receives medical treatment without being admitted to a hospital.</text>
    <text>Postpartum care &amp;#8211; Care delivered to a patient shortly after childbirth.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 2042 (March 7, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 6703 (August 15, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 7832 (September 19, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published
        at 55 DCR 2858 (March 21, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 15526 (November 8, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>