<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-1103</num>
  <heading>MEETINGS OF THE BOARD (ยง 1-1103)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1103.1.</num>
    <text>The Chairperson of the Board shall preside at all meetings of the Board at which he or she is present and shall perform such other duties as may be required of him or her by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1103.2.</num>
    <text>The Vice-Chairperson of the Board shall, in the absence of the Chairperson, preside at meetings of the Board and shall perform such other duties as may be required of him or her by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1103.3.</num>
    <text>Meetings of the Board may be called at the discretion of the Chairperson or at the request of any two Members. At least forty-eight (48) hours in advance of each meeting of the Board, notice shall be given to each Member.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1103.4.</num>
    <text>Notice of a meeting of the Board shall specify the date, time and place of the meeting. The notice may be delivered by methods including, but not limited to, telephone, email, government mail or announcement at a previous meeting. A Member may waive
      notice of any meeting by written statement filed with the Secretary. Attendance at a meeting also shall constitute a waiver of notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1103.5.</num>
    <text>The Board shall convene within sixty (60) days of receipt of a notice of a violation to investigate the causes of the violation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1103.6.</num>
    <text>Meetings of the Board shall be closed except to those requested to attend or as otherwise specified in these Guidelines.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 7968 (August 13, 2004) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 4402 (May 11, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>