<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-1310</num>
  <heading>ADMINISTRATION AND ENFORCEMENT (ยง 16-1310)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1310.1.</num>
    <text>The Director shall perform the functions vested in the Mayor by the Act, unless the Act or this chapter specifically requires performance of a function by a District official other than the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1310.2.</num>
    <text>The Director may investigate or direct an appropriate investigation of any information contained in an application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1310.3.</num>
    <text>Either the Director or the Chief of Police may cause investigation to be made of any registrant or other person whom the Director or Chief of Police has probable cause to believe is engaging in charitable solicitation in violation of the Act or this
      chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1310.4.</num>
    <text>If the Chief of Police knows or has probable cause to believe that a violation of the Act or this chapter has been or is being committed, the Chief shall take or cause to be taken appropriate action to enforce the Act or this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1310.5.</num>
    <text>The Director shall maintain a file of persons entitled to exemption under ยง 4(b) of the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1310.6.</num>
    <text>Any person claiming exemption from the provisions of the Act under ยง 4(c)(2) of the Act [D.C. Official Code ยง 44-1703(c)(2) (2001 Ed.)], on the grounds that the person is soliciting exclusively among the membership of the soliciting agency, shall,
      if required by the Director or the Chief of Police, furnish information to the Director or the Chief of Police to show that the individuals solicited or to be solicited are in fact members or employees of the soliciting agency. Upon request, the
      person shall also furnish a copy of the soliciting agency&amp;#8217;s charter and by-laws.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1310.7.</num>
    <text>Any person soliciting contributions, or believed to be soliciting contributions, shall, upon demand by the Director or Chief of Police, display his or her solicitor information card. If the person is employed by an exempt person, he or she shall display
      sufficient evidence to support the contention that the solicitation is exempt.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>