<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-1305</num>
  <heading>ISSUANCE OR DENIAL OF CERTIFICATES OF REGISTRATION (ยง 16-1305)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1305.1.</num>
    <text>Upon the filing of an application, the Director may investigate or cause to be investigated the statements contained in the application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1305.2.</num>
    <text>The Director is authorized to deny a certificate of registration to an applicant if, upon investigation, the Director has reason to believe that one or more of the following facts exist:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That the applicant has failed to complete the application;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That the application contains false or misleading information; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>That the application does not disclose sufficient information as required by the Act or this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1305.3.</num>
    <text>Each certificate of registration shall bear the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the registrant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The number of the certificate, as assigned by the Director;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The date of issuance and the expiration date;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A statement that the certificate does not constitute an endorsement by the District of Columbia, or by any officer or employee of the District, of the purpose of or the person conducting the solicitation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Other information or conditions that the Director may require.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1305.4.</num>
    <text>A certificate of registration shall be valid for the length of time stated on the certificate but in no event for more than one (1) year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1305.5.</num>
    <text>Duplicates of certificates of registration shall be made available to the registrant, upon written request, at a cost of one dollar ($ 1) for each duplicate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1305.6.</num>
    <text>No person shall use or display any certificate of registration after the certificate has expired or has been suspended or revoked.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>