<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-1306</num>
  <heading>SOLICITOR INFORMATION CARDS (§ 16-1306)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1306.1.</num>
    <text>Each registrant and each applicant for a certificate of registration shall make application to the Director for the number of solicitor information cards that will be required to conduct the solicitation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.2.</num>
    <text>At the request of persons exempt under §§ 4(b), (c), and (d) of the Act, the Director shall issue to them identification cards to be distributed to each solicitor employed by that exempt person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.3.</num>
    <text>Solicitor information cards shall be supplied at cost.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.4.</num>
    <text>Each solicitor information card shall be serially numbered and shall bear following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the solicitor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The number of certificate of registration under the authority of which the solicitor solicits contributions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The name of the registrant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The dates within which solicitations may be made;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A statement that the card does not constitute an endorsement of the solicitation by the District of Columbia, or by any officer or employee of the District; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Other information or conditions that the Director may require.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.5.</num>
    <text>The Director may, in his or her discretion, issue solicitor information cards with the names of the solicitors omitted. If the cards are issued without names, the names of the solicitors shall subsequently be furnished to the Director at the Director&amp;#8217;s
      request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.6.</num>
    <text>The Director may, in connection with any request for solicitor information cards, require the registrant to submit a list in triplicate of the names and addresses of the persons for whom the cards are being requested, and the Director may either prepare
      or cause to be prepared a solicitor information card for each name appearing on the list, or the Director may serially number the names of the list and issue like-numbered cards to the registrant, for completion in accordance with the requirements
      of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.7.</num>
    <text>No registrant to whom the Director issues serially numbered cards against a serially numbered list of names shall issue any card to any person other than the person indicated on the list of names by the same number as that appearing on a card.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.8.</num>
    <text>No registrant issued a completely filled-out solicitor information card shall distribute the card to any person other than the person named on the card.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.9.</num>
    <text>No person other than the person whose name appears on the solicitor information card shall be issued that card or be authorized to use the card by a person whose name does not appear on the card, even if the person is employed by a registrant to make
      solicitations, shall be a violation of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.10.</num>
    <text>Each registrant shall be responsible for carrying out and securing compliance with the provisions of this section and § 1307. Failure or refusal of any registrant or solicitor to comply with the provisions of these sections shall be grounds for the
      suspension or revocation of the certificate of registration issued to the registrant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>