<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2105</num>
  <heading>TERMINATION OF ORDERS (ยง 27-2105)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2105.1.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer may terminate for default an order placed under a District term contract in accordance with chapter 37 of this title and the terms of the contract. The contracting officer may terminate for default any order placed under federal
      schedule contract in accordance with the terms of the contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2105.2.</num>
    <text>The Director, shall be notified in writing within ten (10) working days when a contracting officer has declared a schedule contractor in default or fraud is suspected.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2105.3.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer may terminate for the convenience of the District an order placed under a District term contract in accordance with chapter 37 of this title and the terms of the contract. The contracting officer may terminate for the convenience
      of the District an order placed under a federal supply schedule in accordance with the terms of the contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2105.4.</num>
    <text>Before the contracting officer terminates for convenience an order placed under a District term contract, the contracting officer shall attempt to enter into a no-cost termination agreement with the contractor. All disputes shall be resolved in accordance
      with chapter 38 of this title and the terms of the contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2105.5.</num>
    <text>Before the contracting officer terminates for convenience an order placed under a federal schedule contract, the contracting officer shall attempt to enter into a no-cost termination agreement with the contractor. All disputes shall be resolved in
      accordance with the terms of the federal schedule contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1519 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>