<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2103</num>
  <heading>DISTRICT TERM CONTRACTS AND FEDERAL SUPPLY SCHEDULES (ยง 27-2103)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2103.1.</num>
    <text>The Director shall ensure that each agency is informed of the availability of goods and services under District term contracts and federal supply schedules, and the requirements for purchasing from each of these sources under ยง2100 and this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2103.2.</num>
    <text>The use of District requirements contracts shall be mandatory for all District agencies listed under the contract as using agencies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2103.3.</num>
    <text>The use of District indefinite quantity contracts shall be mandatory to the extent of the minimums stated in those contracts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2103.4.</num>
    <text>Except as required by ยง2100.1, the use of federal supply schedules shall be mandatory when the contracting officer determines that both of the following apply:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The goods or services on the federal schedule will meet the District&amp;#8217;s minimum requirements; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The federal schedule price is lower than the price that can be obtained with a new contract.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2103.5.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall procure from federal supply contracts or District term contracts by placing purchase orders directly with the contractor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2103.6.</num>
    <text>When goods or services are available under a District requirements contract, a contracting officer shall not do either of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Solicit bids, proposals, quotations, or otherwise test the market solely for the purpose of seeking alternative sources to the requirements contract; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Request formal or informal quotations from other contractors for the purpose of making price comparisons.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2103.7.</num>
    <text>When the requirements of the ordering agency are less than the minimum order limitation, or are in excess of the maximum order limitation provided in the applicable federal supply schedule, use of the schedule shall not be mandatory.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1517 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>