<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-3401</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION PROCESS (ยง 20-3401)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3401.1.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this program, applications shall be accepted one time per fiscal year. However, if additional funds become available during that same fiscal year, announcements shall be published in the D.C. Register to announce the deadline for
      accepting applications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3401.2.</num>
    <text>To solicit the broadest participation, applicants may only apply for one grant during the fiscal year. The period of the grant activity shall be no longer than one hundred eighty (180) days from the start of the grant award.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3401.3.</num>
    <text>Any individual or organization within the District of Columbia may apply for financial support to carry out an innovative energy conservation demonstration activity or activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3401.4.</num>
    <text>Applications shall be accompanied by a District of Columbia Energy Extension Service Energy Conservation Demonstration Awards Program Request Form.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3401.5.</num>
    <text>Applicants shall submit the original and five (5) copies of the Grant Request Form and Application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3401.6.</num>
    <text>All applicants shall submit their request for grant funding to the D.C. Energy Extension Service of the D.C. Office of Energy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3401.7.</num>
    <text>The D.C. Office of Energy shall give public notice through the D.C. Register, local media, and other sources of the availability of the program, and of the deadlines for submitting applications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3401.8.</num>
    <text>The EES Energy Conservation Demonstration Awards Program Request Form shall state the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the applicant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and telephone number of the contact person; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The amount of the grant funds requested.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3401.9.</num>
    <text>The following information shall be included in the application:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Preface: Information about the applicant including, but not limited to, background or structure, personnel, tax status, history of related activities and associations with other groups, and overall capabilities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>One page summary of project: Including the need for project, purpose and objectives, community benefits, relationship to the District EES Program and any other relevant community programs or groups;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Technical description of the project: Including the &amp;#8220;what, when, where, how, and why&amp;#8221; of the project, services to be offered or products to be produced, progress chart, what, if any, activities will continue beyond the period
        of the grant, and, if related to other work, a brief description of the relationship;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Qualifications of key personnel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Cash or in-kind services which the applicant will provide toward the proposed activity; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Description of applicant&amp;#8217;s budgetary needs, including (as relevant to the activities pertinent to the grant application) the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Salaries (specify full or part-time, duration of employment, and salary of each individual);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Related salary cost (fringe benefits, etc.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Postage;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Consultant or contractual service;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Supplies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Duplicating and printing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Rent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Travel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Telephone; and</text>
    </level>
    <text>(10) Applicant&amp;#8217;s contribution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3401.10.</num>
    <text>Within three (3) weeks after the announced application deadline, the Program Manager shall send the applicant a letter acknowledging receipt of the application and noting any deficiencies in the application or additional information required.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3401.11.</num>
    <text>If the application is complete, the letter shall give the estimated date by which a final decision will be made.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3401.12.</num>
    <text>Questions concerning the status of an application shall be directed to the Program Manager.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 7991 (December 14. 1990)</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>