<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-7999</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 17-7999)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7999.1.</num>
    <text>As used in this chapter, the following terms shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Applicant – a person applying for a license to practice speech-language pathology under this chapter.</text>
    <text>Board – the Board of Audiology and Speech-Language Pathology.</text>
    <text>Clinical fellow – a person who is completing the clinical fellowship requirements set forth under 17 DCMR § 7903.</text>
    <text>Clinical fellow supervisor – a person who is the supervisor of a clinical fellow.</text>
    <text>Direct supervision – supervision in which the supervisor is immediately available on the premises and within vocal communication either directly or by a communication device.</text>
    <text>Dual licensure renewal – renewal of both an audiology and a speech-language pathology license in the District of Columbia, within the same renewal period.</text>
    <text>General supervision – supervision in which the supervisor is available to the person supervised, either in person or by a communications device.</text>
    <text>Good cause – serious illness of the applicant, the death or serious illness of a member of the applicant’s immediate family, or other cause sufficient to the Board.</text>
    <text>Graduate student – a person enrolled in a Master’s or Doctoral degree program in speech-language pathology.</text>
    <text>Practice of speech-language pathology – means the application of principles, methods, or procedures related to the development and disorders of human communication, including any condition, whether of organic or non-organic origin, that impedes the
      normal process of human communication including disorders and related disorders of speech, articulation, fluency, voice, oral, or written language; auditory comprehension and processing; oral, pharyngeal or laryngeal sensorimotor competencies; swallowing;
      auditory or visual processing; auditory or visual memory or cognition; communication; and assisted augmentative communication treatment and devices. The term “practice of speech language pathology” also includes the planning, directing, supervising,
      and conducting of a habilitative and rehabilitative counseling program for individuals or groups of individuals who have, or are suspected of having, disorders of communication, and any service in speech-language pathology including prevention,
      identification, evaluation, consultation, habilitation or rehabilitation, instruction or research. The practice of speech-language pathology may include pure-tone air conduction hearing screening, screening of tympanometry, and acoustic reflex screening,
      limited to a pass-or-fail determination for the identification of individuals with other disorders of communication and may also include aural habilitation or rehabilitation, which means the provision of services and procedures for facilitating
      adequate auditory, speech, and language skills in individuals with hearing impairment. The practice of speech-language pathology does not include the practice of medicine or osteopathic medicine, or the performance of a task in the normal practice
      of medicine or osteopathic medicine by a person to whom the task is delegated by a licensed physician.</text>
    <text>Clinical fellowship- the experience required by Section 7903 of these regulations.</text>
    <text>Supervisor – a speech-language pathologist who is qualified pursuant to Section 7903.7 and who is providing general supervision to an individual completing the clinical fellowship requirements, or a speech language pathologist who is qualified pursuant
      to § 7912.9 and who is providing direct supervision to a graduate student under § 7912.</text>
    <text>Supervisee- an individual who is completing the clinical fellowship requirements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7999.2.</num>
    <text>The definitions in § 4099 of Chapter 40 of this title are incorporated by reference into and are applicable to this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 7314 (September 4, 2009); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 14806 (October 18, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>