<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-7906</num>
  <heading>CONTINUING EDUCATION REQUIREMENTS (§ 17-7906)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7906.1.</num>
    <text>This section shall apply to renewal, reactivation, or reinstatement of a license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7906.2.</num>
    <text>This section shall not apply to applicants for an initial license by examination, reciprocity, or endorsement, nor shall it apply to applicants for the first renewal of a license granted by examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7906.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant for renewal of a license, who is not subject to Subsection 7906.4, shall submit proof of having completed twenty (20) hours of approved continuing education hours during the two (2) year period preceding the date the license expires,
      including one (1) hour of ethics. The hours must be related to speech-language pathology.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7906.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant for dual licensure renewal shall submit proof of having completed thirty (30) hours of approved continuing education hours during the two year period preceding the date the license expires, including one (1) hour in ethics. Of the thirty
      (30) hours, the applicant shall have completed at least five (5) hours in both the audiology and speech-language pathology disciplines. The intent of this paragraph is likewise shared by, and may be cross-referenced with, Subsection 7808.4 of Chapter
      78 of Title 17 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations, which govern the continuing education requirements of audiologists.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7906.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant for reinstatement of a license shall submit proof of having completed ten (10) hours of continuing education for each year during which the license was not valid, provided that:</text>
    <text>If an applicant seeks to be licensed more than five (5) years after the date that the applicant’s license expires, the applicant shall meet the requirements for obtaining an initial license; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>In order to reinstate a license, an applicant for reinstatement must have met all continuing education requirements for the licensure period immediately prior to the expiration of the license in addition to ten (10) hours for each year the applicant
        was unlicensed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7906.6</num>
    <text>7906.6 An applicant for reactivation of a license shall submit proof of having completed twenty (20) hours of continuing education per renewal period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7906.7</num>
    <text>7906.7 A license is not valid until it is renewed or reinstated.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7906.8</num>
    <text>7906.8 A holder of an expired or sanctioned license shall only be eligible to apply for renewal or reinstatement of the sanctioned or expired license by meeting any legal and regulatory requirements applicable to the expired license in addition to
      the requirements set forth in any applicable order of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7906.9</num>
    <text>7906.9 The Board shall periodically conduct a random audit of at least ten percent (10%) of its active licensees to determine continuing education compliance. Any licensee selected for the audit shall return the completed continuing education compliance
      audit form and all supporting documentation to the Board within thirty (30) days of receiving notification of the audit. Failure to comply with the continuing education requirements may subject the licensee to disciplinary action by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 7314 (September 4, 2009); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 14810 (October 18, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>