<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-7907</num>
  <heading>CONTINUING EDUCATION PROGRAMS AND ACTIVITIES (§ 17-7907)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7907.1</num>
    <text>7907.1 A continuing education hour shall be valid only if it is part of arogram or activity approved by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7907.2</num>
    <text>7907.2 The Board may approve a continuing education program if it meets theollowing criteria:</text>
    <text>It is current in its subject matter;</text>
    <text>It has been developed and will be taught by qualified individuals; and</text>
    <text>The program provider submits for the Board’s review, no less than thirty (30)ays prior to the date of the presentation, the following documentation:</text>
    <text>A copy of the official program or syllabus;</text>
    <text>The presentation title;</text>
    <text>The date of the presentation;</text>
    <text>The contact hours or credits awarded for the presentation; and</text>
    <text>The type of audience for which the program is intended.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7907.3</num>
    <text>7907.3 The Board shall accept for credit, programs or activities conducted byhe following organizations (provided that the applicant submits verification ofttendance):</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Speech-Language Hearing Association of the District of Columbia orimilar speech-language hearing association of another state;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The American Academy of Audiology;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The American Speech-Language Hearing Association (ASHA) and its approvedontinuing education providers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>An accredited provider of The Accreditation Council on Continuing Medicalducation of the American Medical Association offering Category I continuingedical education;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The International Association of Continuing Education and Training (IACET)nd its authorized providers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A health care organization accredited by the Joint Commission onccreditation of Healthcare Organizations (JCAHO); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The International Hearing Society.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7907.4</num>
    <text>7907.4 The Board may accept for credit the following activities:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A course given at an accredited college or university;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A seminar or workshop;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An educational program given at a conference;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>In-service training;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Serving as a presenter or speaker at a conference, seminar, workshop, orn- service training; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Publishing an article in a professional journal or publication of a book or chapter in a book or publication of a book review in a professional journalelated to audiology or speech-language pathology.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7907.5</num>
    <text>7907.5 The Board may, in its discretion, approve additional continuingducation programs and activities that contribute to the growth of professionalompetence in the practice of audiology or speech-language pathology and meethe other requirements of
      this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7907.6</num>
    <text>7907.6 The Board shall not grant credit for work done in the course of aenewal, reinstatement, or reactivation applicant’s normal occupation orncident to the performance of his or her regular duties, such as teachingourses, research, or course preparation
      in the case of a teacher or professor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7907.7</num>
    <text>7907.7 A renewal, reinstatement, or reactivation applicant shall have theurden of verifying whether a program is approved by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7907.8</num>
    <text>7907.8 A renewal, reinstatement, or reactivation applicant shall proveompletion of required continuing education hours by submitting upon request theollowing information with respect to each program:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the provider of the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name of the program, its location, a description of the subject matterovered, and the names of the instructors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The dates on which the applicant attended the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The hours of credit claimed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Verification by the course provider or accreditor of completion, byignature, stamp, or official transcript in the case of accreditors.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 7314 (September 4, 2009); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 14810 (October 18, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>