<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2410</num>
  <heading>DENIAL OR REVOCATION OF LICENSES (§ 17-2410)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2410.1.</num>
    <text>The Mayor may refuse to issue a commission to an applicant or may remove a notary public from office upon determining that the action is necessary in view of the conditions and restrictions as provided in this chapter and by law, as well as upon written
      complaints received by the Secretary of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2410.2.</num>
    <text>A notice, in writing, of a determination to deny or revoke a commission shall be given by the Mayor to the person concerned.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2410.3.</num>
    <text>The notice of determination shall explain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The nature of and grounds for the action;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The right of the person concerned to be heard on the matter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The finality of the decision to deny or revoke a commission unless the person concerned requests a hearing on the matter by filing a petition for review with the Mayor.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2410.4.</num>
    <text>A petition for review shall be sent by certified letter to the Secretary of the District of Columbia (See §2400.7) within twenty (20) days after service of the notice to deny or revoke a license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2410.5.</num>
    <text>The petition for review shall be signed by the petitioner and shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A request for review of the decision of the Mayor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A statement of why the petitioner believes the decision of the Mayor was in error; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If the petitioner will be represented by legal counsel, the name, address, and telephone number of that legal counsel</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§§ 20.1, 20.2, 20.3, and 20.4 of Regulation No. 73-13, approved May 24, 1973, 19 DCR 1147, 1148 (June 11, 1973), 25 DCRR §§ 20.1, 20.2, 20.3, and 20.4.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>