<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2407</num>
  <heading>CERTIFICATION (AUTHENTICATIONS) OF NOTARIES PUBLIC (§ 17-2407)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2407.1.</num>
    <text>The Secretary of the District of Columbia shall issue certifications (authentications) of seals and signatures of notaries appointed in the District of Columbia pursuant to section 588 of An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia,
      approved March 3, 1901 (31 Stat. 1279; D.C. Official Code § 1-1201), and this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2407.2.</num>
    <text>The Secretary of the District of Columbia shall issue certifications of the signatures of the District of Columbia governmental officials who are required to sign documents of public records. The certifications shall be as follows:</text>
    <text>A Certificate: For documents that will be used within the United States, generally for interstate commerce.</text>
    <text>Department Head Certificate: For documents that require the signature of an agency head (or his or her designee) and the official seal of the agency.</text>
    <text>Apostille: For documents destined for countries that are parties to the Hague Convention.</text>
    <text>Foreign Certificate: For documents destined for countries that are not parties to the Hague Convention.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2407.3.</num>
    <text>A fee of fifteen dollars ($15) per certificate shall be charged for the issuance of certifications under this section.</text>
    <text>(June 11, 1973), as added by § 302 of District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1983, D.C. Law 5-14;</text>
    <text>as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 43 DCR 3365 (June 30, 1995); as amended by Final</text>
    <text>Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 5052 (June 11, 2010); as amended by the Fiscal Year 2011</text>
    <text>Budget Support Act of 2010, effective September 24, 2010 (D.C. Law 18-223), published at 57</text>
    <text>DCR 6242, 6259 (July 23, 2010).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§§ 1.7(a) and 1.7(b) of Regulation No. 73-13, approved May 24, 1973, 19 DCR 1147</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>