<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-7103</num>
  <heading>SCOPE OF PRACTICE BY REGISTERED DANCE THERAPISTS (ยง 17-7103)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7103.1.</num>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Dance therapy&amp;#8221; is the psychotherapeutic use of movement which furthers the physical and emotional integration of the individual.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7103.2.</num>
    <text>The terms &amp;#8220;dance therapy&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;dance/movement therapy&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;movement&amp;#8221; therapy&amp;#8221; have the same meaning and may be used interchangeably.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7103.3.</num>
    <text>As used in this section &amp;#8220;Dance Therapy Practice&amp;#8221; means treatment service delivery in clinical, residential, community, or private practice settings where the therapist will:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Observe, assess and record the movement behavior and the client&amp;#8217;s level of functioning (including mental and emotional processes and their manifestation) on a nonverbal movement level;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Communicate with the client through movement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Plan and implement appropriate therapeutic intervention based on clearly defined treatment goals consistent with the education and training of their profession, including but not limited to working toward the goals of: bodily integration, enhancing
        communicative behavior, enhancing social interaction and awareness and expression of feelings by clients served;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Periodically evaluate, record, and report the client&amp;#8217;s response to the dance therapy treatment provided; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Perform all the above in accordance with the Code of Ethical Practice and all credentialling requirements established by the American Dance Therapy Association.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7103.4.</num>
    <text>A person registered to practice dance therapy under this chapter may employ the theories and techniques of the profession, (including &amp;#8220;dance therapy practice&amp;#8221;) to aid in the restoration and rehabilitation of the mental and physical
      functions of their clients in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7103.5.</num>
    <text>A person registered to practice dance therapy pursuant to this chapter shall practice within the permissible scope of practice allowed by his or her credentialled status with the American Dance Therapy Association as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An individual who is credentialled by the American Dance Therapy Association as a &amp;#8220;Dance Therapist Registered&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;DTR&amp;#8221; is qualified for entry into the profession and may be employed as a dance therapist within
        a clinical residential or community setting;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An individual who is credentialled by the American Dance Therapy Association as a member of the &amp;#8220;Academy Dance Therapists Registered&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;ADTR&amp;#8221; is qualified for the advanced level of dance therapy practice
        including the right to train dance therapists, teach, provide supervision and engage in private practice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An individual who is credentialled as a &amp;#8220;DTR&amp;#8221; but who is not credentialled as an ADTR may not train dance therapists, teach, provide supervision or engage in private practice.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 6010 (September 14, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>