<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-801</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION FOR CERTIFIED BUSINESS ENTERPRISE STATUS (§ 27-801)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>801.1</num>
    <text>801.1 An applicant for certification with the Department shall submit aompleted application that is signed and sworn to by the applicant, settingorth the basis for certification as a CBE, accompanied by documentationequested by the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.2</num>
    <text>801.2 An applicant for certification, along with the application, shall alsoubmit documentation that includes, but is not limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Business documentation, including articles of incorporation, by-laws,ertificates of good standing, stock voting rights, minutes of organizationaleetings, partnership agreements, profit sharing agreements, buy-out rights,oint venture agreements,
        tax returns, and annual reports;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Stock options or other ownership options which are outstanding, evidence ofoans or other debts between owners, evidence of loans or other debts betweenwners and third parties which are related to the business, and identificationf trusts affecting
        the finances or control of the business;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Copies of current financial or operating statements, including balanceheets, income statements, statements of retained earnings, and statements ofash flows, being current up to the ninety-day period prior to the applicationate, along with federal
        and District of Columbia and/or applicable state taxeturns for the past three most recent years;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Type, quantity, and value of equipment owned;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Bonding limit, name of bonding company, sources of letters of credit, otherources of capital and other financing, and trade references;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Experience of firm owners and managers in areas such as supervision;ccounting, bookkeeping, and other recordkeeping; use of suppliers; and use ofquipment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Lease or ownership information for every property at which the applicantaintains an office;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>A list of all employees, including name, home address, and the office tohich he or she reports; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Any other documentation the Department may require.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.3</num>
    <text>801.3 An applicant may also be required to demonstrate compliance with theequirements of the Act, this chapter, and other laws of the District ofolumbia. In furtherance of such demonstration, the applicant shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Permit the Department to enter and conduct an on-site inspection of thepplicant&amp;#8217;s business premises;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Provide the Department, during the on-site inspection, with immediate accesso any records or area of the premises that the Department deems necessary toeview to determine whether the applicant is in compliance with the Act andhese regulations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Provide any other information the Department deems necessary to evidenceompliance with the Act and these regulations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.4</num>
    <text>801.4 An applicant currently certified as a CBE seeking an upgrade shall submito the Department an upgrade application that is signed and sworn to by thepplicant and shall provide additional information and/or documentationndicating the applicant’s
      qualifications for the upgrade, which may includeut not be limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A detailed resume of all individuals that the Department is to consider;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Transcript from a university or other institution indicating education orraining in an area related to the upgrade; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any other information requested by the Department.</text>
    </level>
    <text>.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 9052 (December 4, 1992); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 8439 (October 23, 2009),ncorporating by reference text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5622,623 (July 10, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>