<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-835</num>
  <heading>AGENCY CERTIFIED BUSINESS ENTERPRISES SUBCONTRACTING (§ 27-835)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>835.1.</num>
    <text>When determining whether a prime contractor has willfully breached a subcontracting plan under section 2348 of the Act, the Department shall consider:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Notification of the Department by the prime contractor prior to the</text>
    </level>
    <text>breach;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The prime contractor’s efforts at replacing the subcontractor with another subcontractor certified by the Department in the same categories;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Changes in the business operation or certification of the subcontractor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Changes in economic conditions from the time the plan was developed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The extent of the breach.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>835.2.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding § 835.2, failure to achieve at least ninety percent (90%) of the identified subcontracting expenditure shall create a rebuttable presumption of a willful breach.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>835.3</num>
    <text>835.3 Contracting officers seeking a waiver or modification of the subcontracting requirements of sections 2346 and 2350 of the Act shall submit to the Director a written request detailing the reasons that support waiver or modification, including
      the efforts of the contracting officer to secure CBE involvement, particularly SBEs. Such a request shall be submitted prior to the acceptance of bids or proposals.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 9052 (December 4, 1992); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 8439 (October 23, 2009), incorporating by reference text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5622, 5648 (July 10, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>