<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-826</num>
  <heading>DECISIONS (§ 27-826)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>826.1</num>
    <text>826.1 The Commission shall issue a decision in writing no later than ninety90) days after a hearing record is closed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>826.2</num>
    <text>826.2 A decision of the Commission that is adverse to an applicant orespondent shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Findings of fact;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Conclusions of law;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An order; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A statement informing the applicant or respondent of the right to have theecision reviewed by the District of Columbia Court of Appeals and the timeithin which a petition for judicial review is required to be submitted by theules of that Court.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>826.3</num>
    <text>826.3 The Commission shall serve a copy of the decision on the applicant orespondent and the Assistant Attorney General of record in the matter within ten10) days of the date the Commission issues the decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>826.4</num>
    <text>826.4 If a Commission decision is wholly or partially based on official noticef a material fact that is not on the record, the applicant or respondent andhe Assistant Attorney General of record in the matter may oppose the taking offficial notice
      in a motion for reconsideration submitted to the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>826.5</num>
    <text>826.5 The Commission’s decision may modify the period of time which bars aubmission of an application or respondent for certification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>826.6</num>
    <text>826.6 A respondent who has been denied the renewal of a certificate or whoseertificate has been revoked shall not be eligible to receive any preferencesor being a CBE or be awarded any SBE set-aside contracts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 9052 (December 4, 1992); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 8439 (October 23, 2009),ncorporating by reference text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5622,641 (July 10, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>