<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-832</num>
  <heading>AGENCY PROCUREMENT PLAN (§ 27-832)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>832.1</num>
    <text>832.1 One month prior to the beginning of each fiscal year, each agency shallubmit to the Department the agency&amp;#8217;s procurement plan as described inection 832.5 for the fiscal year, on a form designated by the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>832.2</num>
    <text>832.2 Failure of an agency to submit, timely or otherwise, a procurement planor the fiscal year shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be reported to the City Administrator within 30 days after the start of theiscal year; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Require the agency to request written authorization from the Department tolace any solicitation, including but not limited to, Requests for Proposals“RFPs”), Invitations for Bids (“IFBs”), Requests for Qualifications“RFQs”), and Calls for Expressions
        of Interest, on the open market untilhe plan is filed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>832.3</num>
    <text>832.3 The report of the failure of an agency to submit a procurement plan forhe fiscal year, an increase in the agency’s set-aside, or the failure of theepartment to provide an agency allocation letter shall not eliminate theequirement for the agency
      to submit a procurement plan to the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>832.4</num>
    <text>832.4 The Director may consider the quarterly reports submitted by the agencyor the previous fiscal year in determining the increased set-aside for thegency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>832.5</num>
    <text>832.5 An agency procurement plan shall specifically set forth the followingnformation for the fiscal year covered by the plan:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Contracts or procurements that the agency intends to award;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Contracts or procurements that the agency has set-aside for SBEs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A description of the contract or procurement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Whether the contract or procurement is a new or existing contract orrocurement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The anticipated start and end date for each procurement; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Particular dollar amounts relating to the procurements specified in each ofhe above paragraphs of this subsection.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>832.6</num>
    <text>832.6 If an agency cannot include with its procurement plan all of thenformation required by this section, it shall submit with its plan a statementnd supporting documentation which establishes good cause for the failure, asell as a request for an
      extension of time for submission of the requirednformation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>832.7</num>
    <text>832.7 If an agency&amp;#8217;s procurement plan sets forth SBE expendituresursuant to paragraphs 832.5(f) and (g) that are below the required programoals set forth in section 2341 of the Act, the agency shall submit with itslan a request for an adjustment
      of program goals and supporting documentationhich establishes good cause for the requested adjustment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>832.8</num>
    <text>832.8 The Department shall notify an agency in writing of its approval orejection of an agency&amp;#8217;s procurement plan within two months of its receiptf the plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>832.9</num>
    <text>832.9 The Department shall include in any notification of rejection of angency&amp;#8217;s procurement plan the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Deficiencies in the plan and a requirement that the deficiencies beemedied within a stated time period;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Information that the failure of the agency to comply with the notice mayesult in Department enforcement action pursuant to section 2352 of the Act;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Requirements that the agency submit supporting documentation relating tohe required elements of the plan as appropriate; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Recommendations for correcting the deficiencies in the plan, includingttendance at meetings with the Department.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 9052 (December 4, 1992); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 8439 (October 23, 2009),ncorporating by reference text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5622,644 (July 10, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>