<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-834</num>
  <heading>AGENCY SET-ASIDE AND PREFERENCE PROGRAM IMPLEMENTATION (§ 27-834)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>834.1</num>
    <text>834.1 When an entire solicitation has been placed in the SBE set-asiderogram, the solicitation shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>State that it is a set-aside for certified small business enterprisefferors under the provisions of the Act; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Require that responses include a copy of the SBE’s letter ofertification.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>834.2</num>
    <text>834.2 Once a solicitation has been placed in the SBE set-aside market asequired by sections 2344 and 2345 of the Act, the agency shall not remove itrom the set-aside market unless:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>At least one attempt to solicit bids or proposals for the procurement inhe SBE set-aside market has failed to produce a responsive bid or proposal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>There is no SBE that qualifies for the procurement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The prices of the bids or proposals are 12% or more above the likely pricen the open market; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The removal is authorized by law.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>834.3</num>
    <text>834.3 Each agency shall provide to the Department, if requested, the followingypes of procurement records:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Small purchase sources;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Term contracts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Blanket purchases orders;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Repetitive or recurring procurement; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>GSA Schedule procurement.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>834.4</num>
    <text>834.4 If an agency with independent contracting authority or the Office ofontracting and Procurement (“OCP”) intends to place a solicitation on thepen market for a contract or procurement of $100,000 or less, the agency or OCPhall provide a written
      notice to the Department as soon as practicable that thegency intends to exclude the contract or procurement from its set-asiderogram. The written notice shall include, at a minimum, a description of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The steps taken to identify SBEs that may be able to provide the goods orervices; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The information contained in the written determination(s) required underection 2344 or 2345 of the Act.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 9052 (December 4, 1992); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 8439 (October 23, 2009),ncorporating by reference text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5622,647 (July 10, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>