<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-813</num>
  <heading>BID AND PROPOSAL PREFERENCES FOR JOINT VENTURES (ยง 27-813)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>813.1</num>
    <text>813.1 Bid and proposal preferences shall be assigned by the Department uponertification of a joint venture as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>For joint ventures in which all venturers are CBEs, the joint venture shalle assigned: the points allotted to the majority CBE; or if there is no majorityBE, then the managing CBE; plus up to four (4) points for any CBE whoseercentage of ownership
        in the joint venture is greater than thirty-five percent35%) and less than or equal to fifty percent (50%); plus two (2) points forny CBE whose percentage of ownership in the joint venture is greater thanwenty percent (20%) and less than or equal
        to thirty-five percent (35%). Theotal number of points allotted to the joint venture shall not exceed twelve12).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For joint ventures in which there are non-CBE participant(s), if theercentage of ownership of the CBE(s) in the venture is:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>More than fifty percent (50%) of the joint venture and the CBE(s) has(have)ore than 50% control and collectively receive more than fifty percent (50%) ofhe profits of the joint venture, the joint venture shall receive the pointsllotted to the majority
        CBE;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Greater than or equal to thirty-five percent (35%) and less than or equalo fifty percent (50%), the joint venture shall receive up to four (4) points;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Greater than or equal to twenty percent (20%) and less than or equal tohirty-five percent (35%), the joint venture shall receive two (2) points; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Less than twenty percent (20%), the joint venture shall receive zero (0)oints.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The percentage of ownership of each venturer shall be determined based on,ut not limited to, the defined financial contribution and benefit, the workerformed, the allocation of profits and fees, management control, and the laborontribution.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 9052 (December 4, 1992); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 8439 (October 23, 2009),ncorporating by reference text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5622,633 (July 10, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>