<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-811</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION FOR JOINT VENTURES (§ 27-811)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>811.1</num>
    <text>811.1 An applicant for certification as a joint venture shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Submit an executed copy of the applicant’s joint venture agreement whichust:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Specify in reasonable detail the purpose of the joint venture, includinghe specific procurement, solicitation, or project the applicant wishes to beertified to perform;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Identify the parties to the joint venture and define their respectivebligations, rights, and responsibilities, including the management structure,ontrol of the joint venture, financial contributions, bonding requirements,ervice and labor contributions,
        revenue or fees for services or labor, andistribution of profits;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Demonstrate that one of the joint venturers is a CBE or an applicant forBE certification;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Provide for the establishment and administration of a separate bank accountn the name of the joint venture into which all funds received will be depositednd through which all expenses will be paid, and which requires all withdrawalsnd deposits to
        be approved by the CBE member of the joint venture managementommittee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Contain an itemized description of all major equipment, facilities, andther resources to be furnished by each participant in the joint venture with aetailed schedule of costs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Contain a provision indicating that the CBE’s interest in the jointenture shall not be reduced or diluted;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Contain a provision indicating that the CBE’s financial risk isommensurate with its percentage interest in the joint venture;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Contain a provision indicating that the joint venture agreement is theontrolling agreement between the parties regarding interest, ownership,ontrol, responsibilities, duties, and functions of the parties and the jointenture agreement shall prevail
        if there is any conflict between the jointenture agreement and any other agreement between the parties;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Specify the responsibilities of the parties in at least the areas ofegotiations with the owners, subcontract negotiation, contract and subcontracterformance; and</text>
    </level>
    <text>(10) Indicate that the CBE shall perform services of the joint, receive profitsf the joint venture, provide labor hours required of the joint venture, orerform other work for the joint venture as approved by the Department that ist a minimum equal
      to its percentage of ownership interest in the joint venture.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Submit additional information that must:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Inform the Department of whether the CBE has relinquished its ownershipnterest in any joint venture within the one-year period prior to thepplication date; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Demonstrate that each participant in the joint venture has the competencend expertise necessary to perform the type of work in connection with which thepplicant wishes to be certified.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Submit all other agreements between the parties regarding the operations ofhe joint venture;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Submit the most current audited financial statement for the non-CBEarticipant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Submit its certified payroll upon request; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Permit the Department to enter and conduct an onsite inspection ore-inspection of the applicant&amp;#8217;s business premises.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>811.2</num>
    <text>811.2 An application for joint venture certification may be submitted to andeviewed by the Department simultaneously with an application for certificationf one or more of the individual venturers as a CBE.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>811.3</num>
    <text>811.3 The Department may deny certification of any joint venture whose jointenture agreement lacks any of the provisions in § 811.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>811.4</num>
    <text>811.4 The joint venture shall make its records available to the Department atny time deemed necessary by the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>811.5</num>
    <text>811.5 The Commission may revoke the certification of a joint venture forailure to comply with the Act and these regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>811.6</num>
    <text>811.6 Upon receipt of an application for certification as a joint venture, theepartment will follow the process outlined in § 806.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 9052 (December 4, 1992); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 8439 (October 23, 2009),ncorporating by reference text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5622,631 (July 10, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>