<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-810</num>
  <heading>PROVISIONAL CERTIFICATION (§ 27-810)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>810.1</num>
    <text>810.1 An applicant seeking provisional certification shall submit the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A request in writing to the Department for a provisional certification;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A copy of the solicitation or other contract or procurement opportunity indicating the date upon which a response to the solicitation is due; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A completed application, including all supporting documentation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>810.2</num>
    <text>810.2 In considering whether to certify an applicant, the Department shall examine information submitted under § 810.1(b) and (c) and preliminarily verify, based on the documentation and without conducting a site visit, that the applicant complies
      with the Act and these regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>810.3.</num>
    <text>If an applicant that receives a provisional certification is selected for a District of Columbia contract or procurement and the provisional preference points are outcome determinative, the contract or procurement official must immediately inform
      the Department. The Department shall complete its investigation and site visit to confirm the applicant’s qualifications for certification prior to award. The Department shall inform the District contract or procurement official regarding its final
      decision before the award.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>810.4.</num>
    <text>A provisional certification shall be effective for forty-five (45) business days or until the Department makes a decision regarding the business enterprise under § 810.3, whichever is a shorter period of time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 9052 (December 4, 1992); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 8439 (October 23, 2009), incorporating by reference text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5622, 5630 (July 10, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>