<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-833</num>
  <heading>AGENCY PROGRAM REPORTS (§ 27-833)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>833.1</num>
    <text>833.1 Quarterly reporting periods are as follows: October 1 through December1, January 1 through March 31, April 1 through June 30, and July 1 througheptember 30.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>833.2</num>
    <text>833.2 Each agency shall submit quarterly reports on Department forms withinhirty (30) days after the end of each quarter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>833.3</num>
    <text>833.3 If an agency cannot include with a quarterly report all the informationequired by the Act, it shall submit with the report a statement and supportingocumentation which establishes good cause for the failure as well as the mannernd time in which
      the agency will submit the required information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>833.4</num>
    <text>833.4 If an agency&amp;#8217;s quarterly report indicates that the agency is noturrently meeting its SBE contracting and procuring requirements under section341 of the Act and its procurement plan, the agency shall submit with itseport:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The explanation for the contracting shortfall; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The specific steps it will take to remedy the shortfall, along withupporting documentation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>833.5</num>
    <text>833.5 The Department shall notify an agency in writing of any deficiencies inhe agency&amp;#8217;s quarterly report within thirty (30) days of its receipt ofhe report.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>833.6</num>
    <text>833.6 If an agency&amp;#8217;s quarterly report contains deficiencies, theepartment’s notification under § 833.5:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Shall identify the deficiencies in the report and require that theeficiencies be remedied within a stated time period;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>May require that the agency submit supporting documentation relating to theequired elements of the report; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>May include recommendations concerning how best to remedy the deficienciesn the report, including attendance at meetings with the Department.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 9052 (December 4, 1992); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 8439 (October 23, 2009),ncorporating by reference text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5622,646 (July 10, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>