<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-844</num>
  <heading>EQUITY AND DEVELOPMENT PARTICIPATION RESTRICTIVE COVENANT (ยง 27-844)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>844.1.</num>
    <text>If there is a transfer of title to any District-owned land that will become part of a Covered Project, the Department may require that a restrictive covenant be filed on that land requiring compliance with the Equity Participation and Development
      Participation requirements of the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>844.2.</num>
    <text>A restrictive covenant requiring compliance with the Equity Participation and Development Participation shall run with the land and otherwise remain in effect until released by the Department following the completion of construction of and the issuance
      of certificates of occupancy for the Covered Project. A release of the restrictive covenant shall be executed by the Department only after either the Developer and the Equity and Development Participants submit a sworn certification together with
      documentation demonstrating to the satisfaction of the Department that, or the Department otherwise determines that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Development Participants received at least 20% of the development fees for the Covered Project based on the final development expenditures for such Covered Project; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Equity Participant has maintained at least a 20% ownership interest in the Sponsor Entity in the Covered Project throughout its development.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 9052 (December 4, 1992); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 8439 (October 23, 2009), incorporating by reference text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5622, 5652 (July 10, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>