<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-1601</num>
  <heading>SEALING OF PREMISES (§ 16-1601)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1601.1.</num>
    <text>If any premises are primarily used to operate a massage establishment or health spa without a basic business license or engage in activity that violates any provision of D.C. Official Code §§ 22-2701, 22-2705 through 22-2707, or 22-2710 through 22-2712,
      the Director may order the sealing of the premises, or portion of the premises, for up to sixty (60) days, in accordance with the provisions of D.C. Official Code § 2-1801.06.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1601.2.</num>
    <text>An order issued by the Director pursuant to § 1601.1 shall be accompanied by findings of fact and conclusions of law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1601.3.</num>
    <text>A finding that the premises are primarily used to engage in activity that violates D.C. Official Code §§ 22-2701, 22-2705 through 22-2707, or 22-2710 through 22-2712 may be based, among other things, on a totality of the circumstances at the premises,
      including, but not limited to, the presence of furnishings or sexually-oriented items that are more suited for prostitution than for lawful commercial use of the premises.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1601.4</num>
    <text>1601.4 During the period of time that the premises, or portion of the premises, are ordered sealed pursuant to § 1601.1, any unauthorized entry at the premises shall be grounds for the Director to extend the order sealing the premises for up to an
      additional one hundred eighty (180) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1601.5</num>
    <text>1601.5 For a period of one hundred eighty (180) days after the lifting of an order sealing the premises, or portions of the premises, any further use of the premises to operate a massage establishment or health spa without a license or engage in activity
      that violates any provision of D.C. Official Code §§ 22-2701, 22-2705 through 22-2707, or 22-2710 through 22-2712 shall be grounds for the Director to order the sealing of the premises for a new period of up to one hundred eighty (180) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 8837 (November 13, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>