<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-1316</num>
  <heading>TRANSCRIPTS OF HEARINGS (ยง 24-1316)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1316.1.</num>
    <text>Transcripts of the hearing proceedings may be ordered through the Department of Public Works on a form prescribed for that purpose by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1316.2.</num>
    <text>The costs for transcript(s) of the hearing record shall be borne by the respondent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1316.3.</num>
    <text>Fees for transcripts shall be at a rate set by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1316.4.</num>
    <text>Transcripts may be ordered upon payment of a deposit, the amount of which shall be set by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1316.5.</num>
    <text>When the cost of the transcript has been determined to be less than the amount of the transcript deposit, the amount by which the deposit exceed the cost of the transcript shall be refunded.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1316.6.</num>
    <text>When the cost of the transcript is determined to exceed the amount of the transcript deposit, the respondent shall be notified in writing of the balance due for preparing the transcript. The balance due shall be paid within fifteen (15) days of notification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1316.7.</num>
    <text>If the respondent fails to make a payment when due as required by this section or if any check offered to make payment is dishonored, the request for the transcript shall be dismissed, and the deposit shall not be refunded.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1316.8.</num>
    <text>Changes in the official transcript shall be made only when the transcript involves errors of substance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1316.9.</num>
    <text>A motion to correct a transcript shall be filed with the Chief Hearing Examiner and the other party within ten (10) days after receipt of the transcript by a party.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1316.10.</num>
    <text>If no objections to the motion are filed within ten (10) days after the filing of the motion, the transcript may, upon the approval of the Chief Hearing Examiner, be changed to reflect the corrections.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1316.11.</num>
    <text>If objections to a motion to correct a transcript are received, the motion and objection shall be submitted to the reporter or transcriber by the Chief Hearing Examiner with a request to compare the transcript with the stenographic or other record
      of the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1316.12.</num>
    <text>After receipt of the transcriber&amp;#8217;s report, an order shall be entered by the Chief Hearing Examiner settling the record and ruling on the motion.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 7807, 7822 (December 4, 1987); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 6055, 6057 (September 14, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>