<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2122</num>
  <heading>HEARINGS (§ 17-2122)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2122.1.</num>
    <text>A person on whom notice has been served pursuant to § 2120 and § 2121 may file a written demand for a hearing with the Office of Administrative Hearings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2122.2.</num>
    <text>If notice was served personally, the demand for hearing shall be filed within twenty (20) calendar days from the date on which the notice was served.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2122.3.</num>
    <text>If the notice was served other than personally, the demand for hearing shall be filed within twenty-four (24) calendar days from the date on which it was served (including the date it was mailed, if served in accordance with § 2121.2(c)).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2122.4.</num>
    <text>Filing the demand for hearing shall not in itself stay enforcement of the action of the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2122.5.</num>
    <text>The Mayor may grant, or the Office of Administrative Hearings may order, a stay upon appropriate terms.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2122.6.</num>
    <text>Each applicant or security officer shall be entitled to a hearing within twenty-one (21) days of demand.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2122.7.</num>
    <text>Each hearing shall provide full procedural safeguards to the officer or applicant, including the right to be represented by his or her own legal counsel and the right to confront and cross-examine witnesses.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2122.8.</num>
    <text>A record shall be kept of the proceedings of each hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§5.3 of the Regulation Establishing Standards for Certification and Employment for Security Officers, Reg. No. 74.31, approved December 1, 1974, 21 DCR 1203 (December 13, 1974); as amended by D.C. ACT 16-465 published at 53 DCR 6726 (August 18,
        2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>