<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2199</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 17-2199)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2199.1.</num>
    <text>The following definitions shall apply to terms used in this chapter:</text>
    <text>Campus security department &amp;#8211; A division of a university campus that provides security services for the protection of students, faculty, staff, and visitors while they are on campus.</text>
    <text>Certification &amp;#8211; The permission that must be granted by the Mayor before a person can lawfully be employed as a security officer in the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Certification card &amp;#8211; A card issued by the Mayor to an individual certified as a security officer.</text>
    <text>Chief of Police &amp;#8211; The Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department of the District of Columbia or his or her designated agent.</text>
    <text>Employer &amp;#8211; Unless the context implies otherwise, a person, firm, corporation, or other private organization providing security services exclusively in connection with the affairs of the one business organization that employs them.</text>
    <text>Firm &amp;#8211; A partnership, corporation, or other private entity employing security personnel.</text>
    <text>Firm member &amp;#8211; A partner of a partnership, or an officer or secretary of a corporation, or a director of a private entity employing security personnel.</text>
    <text>License &amp;#8211; Unless the context requires otherwise, a license issued by the Mayor to conduct a business to provide security services.</text>
    <text>Licensed security agency &amp;#8211; A person or entity that is licensed by the Mayor to conduct a business that provides security services.</text>
    <text>Mayor &amp;#8211; The Mayor of the District of Columbia or the Mayor&amp;#8217;s agent or designee.</text>
    <text>Private detective agency &amp;#8211; A person, firm, or corporation which is licensed as a private detective agency under D.C. Official Code ยง 47-2839 and Chapter 20 of this title to provide private detective services for a fee or other consideration.</text>
    <text>Security agency &amp;#8211; A person or entity who conducts a business that provides security services.</text>
    <text>Security services &amp;#8211; Any activity that is performed for compensation by a security officer or special police officer to protect an individual or property, except as otherwise provided in this chapter.</text>
    <text>Supervision &amp;#8211; Release from incarceration, and the conclusion of any court-ordered parole, probation, or supervision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>ยง1.1 of the Regulation Establishing Standards for Certification and Employment for Security Officers, Reg. No. 74-31, approved December 1, 1974, 21 DCR 1203 (December 13, 1974); as amended by D.C. ACT 16-465 published at 53 DCR 6726 (August 18,
        2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>