<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2124</num>
  <heading>SECURITY AGENCY LICENSE (ยง 17-2124)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2124.1.</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, an individual or a firm shall be licensed by the Mayor as a security agency before the individual or firm may conduct or solicit to engage in a business that provides security services in the District
      of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2124.2.</num>
    <text>An individual or a firm may qualify for a license as a security agency. If the applicant is a firm, the firm shall appoint a firm member as the representative member to make the application on behalf of the firm.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2124.3.</num>
    <text>No applicant shall be licensed as a security agency unless the Chief of Police of the Metropolitan Police Department, or his or her designee, certifies to the Mayor that the Chief of Police approves of the issuance of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2124.4.</num>
    <text>Each individual or firm applying for a license shall submit to the Mayor, under oath, any information that the Mayor may require to assist in determining whether granting the license will be in the public interest.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2124.5.</num>
    <text>Application for a license to engage in business as a security agency shall be made to the Mayor on a form prescribed by the Mayor, to include the documents required by this chapter, and shall be accompanied by the license fee required by law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2124.6.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a security agency license shall pay to the District an application fee of $500, if the applicant is an individual, or $1,000, if the applicant is a firm.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2124.7.</num>
    <text>If the applicant is an individual, the application form provided by the Mayor shall require the name of the applicant, the age of the applicant, the address of the applicant, and the current and previous employment of the applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2124.8.</num>
    <text>If the applicant is a firm, the application form provided by the Mayor shall require a list of all of the firm members, and for each firm member, the same information required regarding an individual applicant under ยง 2124.7.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2124.9.</num>
    <text>For all applicants, the application form shall require:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The address of the applicant&amp;#8217;s proposed principal place of business and of each proposed branch office;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any trade or fictitious name that the applicant intends to use while conducting the business of the security agency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The submission of a facsimile of any trademark that the applicant intends to use while conducting the business of the security agency; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>As the Mayor considers appropriate, any other information to assist in the evaluation of an individual applicant, or if the applicant is a firm, any firm member.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2124.10.</num>
    <text>If the applicant is an individual, the application form shall be signed, under oath, by the individual. If the applicant is a firm, the application form shall be signed, under oath, by the representative member, as the representative member, and by
      all the other firm members.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2124.11.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a license shall submit with the application form a bond in accordance with the requirements of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2124.12.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a license who intends to employ at least five (5) individuals as security guards shall submit with the application proof of liability insurance, as required under this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Amended by D.C. ACT 16-465 published at 53 DCR 6726 (August 18, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>