<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2100</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 17-2100)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2100.1.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this chapter, the term &amp;#8220;security officer&amp;#8221; means any person privately employed to do any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Prevent the theft, misappropriation, or concealment of goods, wares, merchandise, money, bonds, stock certificates, or other valuable documents, papers, and articles;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Prevent damage to real or personal property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Prevent assaults, gate-crashing, or other disorders at meetings, events, or performances; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Prevent similar illegal occurrences.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2100.2.</num>
    <text>The term &amp;#8220;security officer&amp;#8221; includes the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Uniformed individuals employed by a security agency or other employer for any of the purposes set forth in § 2100.1; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Uniformed individuals privately employed as guards, watchpersons, patrol service personnel for specified property, security technicians, security officers, and other similar positions.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2100.3.</num>
    <text>The term &amp;#8220;security officer&amp;#8221; does not include any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Persons commissioned as special police officers under the second paragraph of the section &amp;#8220;FOR METROPOLITAN POLICE&amp;#8221; of An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for
        the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred, and for other purposes, approved March 3, 1899 (30 Stat. 1057; D.C. Official Code § 5-129.02);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Persons working in their official capacity as employees of the federal government;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Members of the Metropolitan Police Department or the public police force of any other jurisdiction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Persons working as armored car guards; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Persons commissioned as campus police officers under the second paragraph of the section &amp;#8220;FOR METROPOLITAN POLICE&amp;#8221; of An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for
        the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred, and for other purposes, approved March 3, 1899 (30 Stat. 1057; D.C. Official Code § 5-129.02), as regulated by Chapter 12 of Title 6A of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2100.4.</num>
    <text>Each certification for a security officer issued under this chapter, except temporary certification cards issued under § 2109 and certifications whose expiration dates have been extended under § 2100.5, shall be effective for 2 years. The expiration
      date shall be shown on the certification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2100.5.</num>
    <text>If a security officer has been retained by a new security agency or employer for the 90-day transition employment period required by section 3 of the Displaced Workers Protection Act of 1994, effective April 26, 1994 (D.C. Law 10-105; D.C. Official
      Code § 32-102), training requirements for certification imposed by this chapter shall be tolled for the duration of the 90 days. If a security officer&amp;#8217;s certification is scheduled to expire during the 90-day period, the expiration date
      for the certification shall be extended until 14 days after the expiration of the 90-day period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2100.6.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in D.C. Official Code § 47-2839a, violation of any provision of this chapter shall be punishable by a fine of up to three hundred dollars ($ 300) or by imprisonment for up to ninety (90) days, in addition to the possible denial,
      suspension, or revocation of certification under the provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2100.7.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this chapter shall supersede any other District of Columbia regulations to the extent of any conflict with those regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred, and for other purposes,
        approved March 3, 1899 (30 Stat. 1057, ch. 422, D.C. Code § 4-114 (1981)).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§§1.1(f), 3.1, 3.3 and 6.1 of the Regulation Establishing Standards for Certification and Employment for Security Officers, Reg. No. 74-31, approved December 1, 1974, 21 DCR 1203 (December 13, 1974), as amended by §2 of the Security Officer Licensing
        Facilitation of 1977, D.C. Law 2-29, 24 DCR 1451 (August 19, 1977), and §27 of the End of Session Technical Amendments Act of 1984, D.C. Law 5.159, 32 DCR 30 (January 4, 1985); as amended by D.C. ACT 16-465 published at 53 DCR 6726 (August 18,
        2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>