<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2113</num>
  <heading>BADGES, PATCHES, AND EMBLEMS (§ 17-2113)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2113.1.</num>
    <text>No security officer shall wear or carry a metal or metallic-appearing badge.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2113.2.</num>
    <text>A distinctive cloth badge worn on a security officer&amp;#8217;s left breast is permitted if the prior written permission of the Mayor is obtained.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2113.3.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the corporate name of the security agency, the words &amp;#8220;police,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;United States,&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;District of Columbia,&amp;#8221; or abbreviations of those words, and the seals or insignias of
      the United States and the District of Columbia shall not be used on any badge, patch, emblem, or uniform.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2113.4.</num>
    <text>Uniforms bearing emblems and patches that meet the following requirements and restrictions shall be approved by the Mayor and shall be worn by security officers:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Shoulder shall be red in color, bear the name of the employer or security agency, and shall have white, clearly legible lettering;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name of the security agency or employer shall be spelled out in full on the patches;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Initials shall not be allowed, and abbreviations are permissible only with the prior written permission of the Mayor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Patches may bear a security agency or employer design insignia which has been approved in writing by the Mayor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Patches shall be of half-moon design;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Patches shall be three inches (3&amp;#8243;) high by five inches (5&amp;#8243;) wide;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A patch shall be worn on each shoulder of a shirt, blouse, jacket, or overcoat; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>A patch bearing the words &amp;#8220;Security Officer&amp;#8221; shall be worn on the right breast. This patch shall be four and one-half inches (4 1/2&amp;#8243;) long and one inch (1&amp;#8243;) high. This patch shall be red with white lettering.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2113.5.</num>
    <text>An employee may wear an appropriate designation of his or her rank (such as sergeant) on either or both sleeves. Chevrons shall be red in color with white piping. If the employee is of officer rank, he or she may wear the appropriate emblem on the
      collar or shoulders of the uniform shirt, jacket, or blouse.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2113.6.</num>
    <text>The word &amp;#8220;INSPECTOR,&amp;#8221; or an abbreviation of that word, shall not appear on any badge, patch, emblem, or uniform.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2113.7.</num>
    <text>A non-metal cap ornament that does not have a metallic appearance may be worn. It may carry the rank of the employee and shall bear the name of the security agency or employer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2113.8.</num>
    <text>Any deviation from the requirements of §§ 2113.4, 2113.5, 2113.6, or 2113.7 shall require the prior written approval of the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2113.9.</num>
    <text>The provisions of §§ 2113.4, 2113.5, 2113.6, and 2113.7 apply only to security officers. No other uniformed security personnel licensed, commissioned, or certified by the District shall wear badges, patches, or emblems that are red with white lettering,
      or that are not readily discernible from those badges, patches, and emblems.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2113.10.</num>
    <text>Each security officer shall take due care to prevent his or her badges, patches, and emblems from falling into the possession of any unauthorized person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§§4.3(a), 4.3(b), 4.3(c), and 4.4 of the Regulation Establishing Standards for Certification and Employment for Security Officers, Reg. No. 74.31, approved December 1, 1974, 21 DCR 1203 (December 13, 1974); as amended by D.C. ACT 16-465 published
        at 53 DCR 6726 (August 18, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>