<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-712</num>
  <heading>ISSUANCE OF LICENSES (§ 21-712)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>712.1.</num>
    <text>No collection vehicle license may be issued until the vehicle sought to be licensed has been inspected by the Mayor and found to comply with the requirements prescribed in §§709.1 through 709.4 and all fees assessed against the licensee in accordance
      with this chapter have been paid in full.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>712.2.</num>
    <text>Licenses shall date from the first (1st) Monday in March of each year and expire on the Saturday preceding the first (1st) Monday in March of the following year, but may be prorated in accordance with the provisions of paragraph 5 of §7 of An Act
      Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and three, and for other purposes, approved July 1, 1902 (32 Stat. 623; D.C. Code §47-2805
      (1990 Repl. Vol.)).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>712.3.</num>
    <text>The Director shall provide two (2) metal tags with each collection vehicle license issued indicating the collection vehicle license number.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>712.4.</num>
    <text>The metal tags provided with the license shall be affixed to each side of the body of the respective collection vehicle in such manner as to be clearly visible at all times.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>712.5.</num>
    <text>During the period of the validity of each license, the licensee shall notify the Director of any change in the information shown on the application within ten (10) days of the change.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE Regulation No. 71-21, approved June 29, 1971, 18 DCR 16 (July 12, 1971), 8 DCRR §8-3:606(e)-(g); as amended by §501 of the Revenue Act for Fiscal Year 1978, D.C. Law 1-124 (23 DCR 6336 (February 18, 1977): by Regulation No. 72.15, approved
        July 28, 1972; by §§2(d) and (e) of the Solid Waste Control Act of 1977, D.C. law 2-69, §8-3:</heading>
      <text>606(d), 24 DCR 6800, 6805 (February 17, 1978); and by §2 of the D C. Solid Waste Disposal Art of 1989 D.C. Law 8-16, 36 DCR 4155 (June 9, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>