<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-707</num>
  <heading>SOLID WASTE CONTAINERS (§ 21-707)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>707.1.</num>
    <text>After July 1, 1978, all containers sold, offered for sale or used in the District for the on-site storage and collection of solid wastes shall be of a design and manufacture approved by the Mayor in accordance with standards adopted by the National
      Sanitation Foundation of Ann Arbor, Michigan, or its equivalent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.2.</num>
    <text>All containers covered by this section shall have displayed on the container in a conspicuous location the appropriate symbol of compliance established by the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.3.</num>
    <text>If containers are used for the storage of rubbish, or a combination or rubbish and food waste (garbage), a sufficient number shall be provided to store such solid wastes which may accumulate on the premises during the usual interval between collections.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.4.</num>
    <text>Containers shall be kept clean and in good repair.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.5.</num>
    <text>Ashes shall be stored in metal containers. When stored in the open, the metal containers shall be covered.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.6.</num>
    <text>In addition to the applicable requirements of this section, the provisions of §708 shall apply to containers for solid wastes to be used by District residents entitled to residential municipal refuse collection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.7.</num>
    <text>Carry containers used for collection service shall be of a design and material approved by the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.8.</num>
    <text>At no time shall lightweight plastic bags that are designed to be used exclusively as liners be used solely for the storage of solid waste.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.9.</num>
    <text>Grease held for recycling or disposal shall be stored in a tightly-sealed metal drum with a capacity of not more than 55 gallons. The grease container and the area where the grease is stored shall be free of spilled grease. The grease container shall
      be stored not less than 4 feet from any other vertical object such as a wall, shelving, or wood fuel stacks.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.10.</num>
    <text>Commercial trash compactors shall be free of spilled waste at all times and shall be kept closed when not compacting waste.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.11.</num>
    <text>Commercial waste containers shall be constructed of heavy gauge metal with tightly-fitting lids constructed of either heavy gauge plastic or metal. Waste container lids shall be kept closed at all times other than when the container is being filled
      or emptied. Waste container lids shall be free of large gaps, cracks or holes. The area where the waste con-tainer is stored shall be kept free of spilled waste at all times. If the waste container is equipped with a drain plug, the plug shall be
      constructed of heavy duty plastic or metal and shall be kept in the drain hole until the filled container is trans-ported to its ultimate destination for emptying and disposal of its contents.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.12.</num>
    <text>Pet food and bird seed kept outside shall be stored in a rodent-proof container. Pet food and bird seed shall not be left to accumulate or remain on the ground after birds and pets have been fed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE Regulation No. 71-21, approved June 29, 1971, 18 DCR 16 (July 12, 1971), 8 DCRR §§8-3:603(c), (e)-(g) and 8-3:</heading>
      <text>604(c); as amended by Final Rulemaking (DES Order No. 90-94-01 (Rev.)) published at 18 DCR 869 (June 26, 1972) Supp. No. 1; by .§2(c) of the Solid Waste Control Act of 1977, D.C. Law 2-69, 24 DCR 6800 (February 17, 1978); and by §3(b) of the D.C.
        Solid Waste Regulations Amendment Act of 1989, D.C. Law 8.31, 36 DCR 4750 (July 7, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>