<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-1600</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 23-1600)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1600.1.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this chapter shall govern the following items: (a) Administrative review hearings, roll call hearings, or status hearings regarding the issuance, transfer, or renewal of a license, or the making of substantial changes to a licensee&amp;#8217;s
      business operations under authority of the Act; (b) Protest hearings regarding the issuance, transfer or renewal of a license, or the making of substantial changes to a licensee&amp;#8217;s business operations under authority of the Act; (c) Fact-finding
      hearings on any matter governed by the Act regarding an applicant for a license or a licensee; and (d) Show cause hearings, summary suspension hearings or summary revocation hearings regarding the revocation or suspension of a license issued under
      the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.2.</num>
    <text>The Board may, for good cause shown and in the interest of justice or to prevent hardship, waive any provision of this chapter which is not required by the Act in any proceeding after duly advising the parties of its intention to do so.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.3.</num>
    <text>The following hearings held before the Board shall be considered to be contested cases: (a) Protest hearings; (b) Show cause hearings; (c) Summary suspension or summary revocation hearings; (d) Cease and desist hearings; and (e) Safekeeping hearings</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.4.</num>
    <text>The following hearings held before the Board shall not be considered to be contested cases: (a) Fact-finding hearings; and (b) Moratorium hearings and other rulemaking hearings</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.5.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this chapter are intended to be consistent with the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act (D.C. Official Code §§ 2-501 et seq.). If there is any conflict between this chapter and the District of Columbia Administrative
      Procedure Act, the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act shall govern.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.6.</num>
    <text>If there is any conflict within this chapter, provisions of specific application shall supersede those of general application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>D.C. Code § 25-351</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>