<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-1607</num>
  <heading>ESTABLISHMENT OF GEOGRAPHIC BOUNDARIES (§ 23-1607)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1607.1.</num>
    <text>Upon recognition by the Board of a properly filed protest at a roll call hearing, the applicant shall be required to select one of the geographic areas listed below that the applicant proposes be considered in determining the appropriateness of the
      establishment. The applicant shall submit the proposed boundaries to the Board and the protestants no later than ten (10) calendar days after the roll call hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1607.2.</num>
    <text>Upon recognition by the Board of a properly filed protest at a roll call hearing, the applicant shall be required to select one of the geographic areas listed below that the applicant proposes be considered in determining the appropriateness of the
      establishment. The applicant shall submit the proposed boundaries to the Board and the protestants no later than ten (10) calendar days after the roll call hearing. The applicant shall be deemed to have selected the &amp;#8220;section&amp;#8221;
      geographic area if it fails to submit boundaries to the Board within the ten (10) calendar day period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1607.3.</num>
    <text>Any protestant may object to the area and boundaries proposed by an applicant by filing a written objection with the Board no later than thirty (30) calendar days after receipt of the applicant&amp;#8217;s proposed boundaries. The objection shall
      also be served on the applicant by any of the means set forth in § 1703. The objection shall state in detail the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The reasons for objecting to the boundaries proposed by the applicant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The boundaries proposed by the objector; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The reasons why the objector&amp;#8217;s boundaries should be adopted by the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1607.4.</num>
    <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s submission shall be served on the objector by any of the means set out in § 1703 and received by the Board no later than eight (8) calendar days after receipt of the applicant&amp;#8217;s submission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1607.5.</num>
    <text>Any objector or applicant who makes a submission to the Board pursuant to §§ 1607.1, 1607.2, 1607.3, or 1607.4, may forward written argument or documentary evidence to the Board in support of the boundaries he or she proposes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1607.6.</num>
    <text>The Board, pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 25-312(b), shall determine, on a case-by-case basis, the size of the area relevant for the appropriateness review. In making this determination, the Board shall consider the overall characteristics of the
      area, including population, density, and general commercial and residential activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1607.7.</num>
    <text>For the purpose of determining the appropriateness of a license, the geographic areas to be considered by the Board shall be measured pursuant to § 101.1 and shall be as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A &amp;#8220;locality,&amp;#8221; which shall be the immediate neighborhood of the establishment and whose boundary shall be at a distance of six hundred feet (600 ft.) from the establishment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A &amp;#8220;section,&amp;#8221; whose boundary shall be at an area larger than the immediate neighborhood and whose boundary shall be at a distance of twelve hundred feet (1,200 ft.) from the establishment; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A &amp;#8220;portion,&amp;#8221; whose boundary shall be at an area larger than a &amp;#8220;section&amp;#8221; and whose boundary shall be at a distance of eighteen hundred feet (1,800 ft.) from the establishment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1607.8.</num>
    <text>In determining the area to be considered, the Board shall consider the report of the Board&amp;#8217;s investigators concerning the overall characteristics of the alternative areas, including the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The population and density of the areas surrounding the establishment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The general commercial and residential activities in the areas surrounding the establishment; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Geographical factors, such as parks, rail lines, major thoroughfares, bodies of water, cemeteries, and unimproved or unused property, which may tend to define physically an area to be considered.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1607.9.</num>
    <text>In determining the area to be considered, the Board shall also consider the evidence and testimony of a party proposing a particular area of consideration, when the proposal is based on an assertion of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Historical patterns of commercial or residential activity leading to an identification of a given area as a distinct, generally-recognized neighborhood, or larger area; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any other reason not included in § 1607.2.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1607.10.</num>
    <text>The Board shall make a final decision on the boundaries without a hearing and based on the submissions received from the applicant and the objector.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1607.11.</num>
    <text>The Board&amp;#8217;s final decision shall be made and announced at the first status hearing for the application at issue.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by D.C. ACT 15-442 published at 51 DCR 6525 (July 2, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>