<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-501</num>
  <heading>VOTER REGISTRATION INFORMATION (§ 3-501)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>501.1.</num>
    <text>Upon written request, the Board shall provide to any person a list of the registered qualified electors of the District of Columbia or any ward, precinct or Advisory Neighborhood Commission Single-Member District (ANC SMD) therein.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.2.</num>
    <text>The Board may furnish selective lists according to party affiliation, date of registration, ward, precinct, or ANC SMD, voter history, or any other permissible category.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.3.</num>
    <text>The Board shall make requested voter registration information available to the public on electronic or magnetic medium, or on any media in use by the Board at the time of the request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.4.</num>
    <text>The following items of information contained in voter registration records are confidential and shall not be considered public information subject to disclosure to the general public:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Full or partial social security numbers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Dates of birth;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Email addresses or phone numbers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The identity of the voter registration agency at which the voter registered; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The residence and mailing addresses of any registered qualified elector whose residence address has been made confidential pursuant to §501.8.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.5.</num>
    <text>Complete voter registration records, including date of birth and social security numbers, shall be released to the District of Columbia Superior Court upon request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.6.</num>
    <text>Cumulative data based on the items of information listed in §501.4 may be publicly disclosed as long as information about any individual cannot be discerned from the disclosed data.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.7.</num>
    <text>A voter’s signature on registration records, either on a paper record or application or an electronically captured image, may be viewed by the public but may not be copied or traced except by Board officials for election administration purposes. Any
      such copy or tracing is not a public record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.8.</num>
    <text>A registered qualified elector’s address shall be considered public information until the registered qualified elector or his or her representative presents a copy of a court order to the Registrar directing the confidentiality of the qualified elector’s
      address. If the order is received more than forty-five (45) days before an election, the elector’s address shall be immediately removed from all voter records available for public inspection. If the order is received within forty-five (45) days
      of the election, the address shall be removed as soon as practicable but in no instance later than seven (7) days following an election. Any address made confidential pursuant to this subsection shall remain confidential for as long as the court
      shall order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 43 D.C. Reg. 1078, 1080 (March 1, 1996); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 D.C. Reg. 3267, 3270 (April 16, 2010); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 7 DCR 7690 (August
        20, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11111, 11114 (November 26, 2010); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Federal Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 10752 (December 16, 2012)[EXPIRED];as amended by Notice
        of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 941, 944 (February 10, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>