<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-515</num>
  <heading>CHANGES IN REGISTRATION[COLON] NAME (§ 3-515)
    <text>515 CHANGES IN REGISTRATION: NAME</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <num>515.1.</num>
    <text>A registered voter shall notify the Board in writing of a name change due to marriage, divorce, or by order of a court within thirty (30) days of the applicable event.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>515.2.</num>
    <text>The Board shall process name changes received pursuant to the monthly report furnished by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia in accordance with D.C. Official Code § 1-1001.07(k)(3) (2011 Repl.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>515.3.</num>
    <text>Prior to the thirtieth (30th) day preceding an election, a registered voter may give notice of change of name by:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Completing a change of name on a voter registration application;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Filing a change of name by signed letter or postal card which includes the following information;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Former and current name;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Address; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Date of birth;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Filing a change of name through the DMV or a voter registration agency (VRA) pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 1-1001.07(d) (2011 Repl.); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Completing any other form prescribed for this purpose by the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>515.4.</num>
    <text>On or after the thirtieth (30th) day preceding an election, a registered voter may change his or her name in-person at the Board’s office or a VRA. Requests for change of name other than those made in-person during the thirty (30) days that immediately
      precede and include the date of the election shall be held and processed after the election.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>515.5.</num>
    <text>The effective date of any change of name, for voter registration purposes, shall be the date that the notice of change is received by the Board, unless the notice of change of name is held and processed after the election, as described in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 43 D.C. Reg. 1078, 1089-90 (March 1, 1996); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 43 D.C. Reg. 1927 (April 12, 1996); and as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 D.C. Reg. 3267, 3284 (April 16, 2010); as
        amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 7 DCR 7690 (August 20, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11111, 11119 (November 26, 2010); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Federal
        Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 10752 (December 16, 2012)[EXPIRED];as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 941, 953 (February 10, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>