<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-513</num>
  <heading>VOTER REGISTRATION APPLICATION PROCESSING[COLON] AT THE POLLS, EARLY VOTINGENTERS, AND DURING IN-PERSON ABSENTEE VOTING (§ 3-513)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>513.1.</num>
    <text>A qualified elector may register during the in-person absentee voting period specified in § 717 of this title, at an early voting center designated by the Board, or on Election Day by appearing in person at the polling place for the precinct in which
      the individual maintains residence, by completing the Board’s official Voter Registration Application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>513.2</num>
    <text>513.2 Valid proof of residence is any official document showing the voter’s name and a District of Columbia home address. Acceptable forms of proof of residence include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A copy of a current and valid government-issued photo identification;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A copy of a current utility bill, bank statement, government check, paycheck; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A government-issued document that shows the name and address of the voter; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any other official document that shows the voter’s name and District of Columbia residence address, including leases or residential rental agreements, occupancy statements from District homeless shelters, and tuition or housing bills from colleges
        or universities in the District.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>513.3.</num>
    <text>Voters who fail to provide valid proof of residence during the in-person absentee voting period, at an early voting center, or on Election Day must provide such proof in order to complete registration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>513.4.</num>
    <text>Registered voters shall be permitted to submit notices of change of address or change of name during the in-person absentee voting period, at an early voting center, or at a polling place on Election Day.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>513.5.</num>
    <text>A registered voter shall not change his or her party affiliation status during the in-person absentee voting period, at an early voting center, or at a polling place on Election Day. Requests for change of party affiliation status received during
      the in-person absentee voting period, at an early voting center, or at a polling place on Election Day shall be held and processed after the election. A change in party affiliation status occurs when a voter:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Changes his or her party registration from one political party to another;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Changes his or her party registration from “no party (independent)” to a political party; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Changes his or her party registration from a political party to “no party (independent).”</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>513.6</num>
    <text>513.6 A voter registration application, or a notice of change of name, address, or party affiliation status, received pursuant to this section is considered to be received by the Board upon acknowledgement of receipt by the Board’s date-stamp. The
      date of receipt shall also be the effective date of registration or change of name, address, or party affiliation status.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 43 D.C. Reg. 1078, 1088 (March 1, 1996); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 D.C. Reg. 4738, 4740-41 (June 19, 2009); and as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 D.C. Reg. 3267, 3282 (April 16, 2010);
        as amended by Notice of Emergency and Federal Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 10752 (December 16, 2012)[EXPIRED];as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 941, 951 (February 10, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>