<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-521</num>
  <heading>CANCELLATION OF VOTER REGISTRATION[COLON] CHALLENGE AND REQUEST FOR ADDITIONS TOEGISTRATION ROLL (§ 3-521)
    <text>521 CANCELLATION OF VOTER REGISTRATION: CHALLENGE AND REQUEST FOR ADDITIONS TO REGISTRATION ROLL</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <num>521.1.</num>
    <text>Any duly registered voter may:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>&amp;#8220;Challenge&amp;#8221; the registration of any person whom the voter believes is fictitious, deceased, disqualified, or ineligible to vote on grounds other than a failure to give notice of a change of address; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>&amp;#8220;Request&amp;#8221; the addition of any person whose name has been erroneously omitted or cancelled from the registration roll.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>521.2</num>
    <text>521.2 The Board shall not accept a voter registration challenge or application for correction of the voter roll after the forty-fifth (45th) day preceding an election.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>521.3.</num>
    <text>During the period beginning on the ninetieth (90th) day before any election and ending on the forty-fifth (45th) day before any election, the Board shall expedite the process as further described in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>521.4.</num>
    <text>Requests for the correction of the voter roll or the challenge of the right to vote of any person named on the voter roll shall be in writing and shall include any evidence in support of the challenge that the registrant is not a qualified elector.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>521.5.</num>
    <text>The Board shall send notice to any person whose registration has been challenged, at the address listed on the Board’s record, along with a copy of any evidence filed in support of the challenge.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>521.6.</num>
    <text>The notice sent to a person whose registration has been challenged shall be sent to the address listed on the Board’s records, and shall include a statement that the registrant must respond to the challenge not later than thirty (30) days from the
      date of the mailing of the notice, or ten (10) days if the challenge is received between ninety (90) and forty-five (45) days from the election, or be cancelled from the voter roll.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>521.7.</num>
    <text>The Registrar shall make a determination with respect to the challenge, based on any evidence presented, within ten (10) days of receipt of the challenged registrant’s response, or three (three) days if the challenge is received between ninety (90)
      and forty-five (45) days from the election.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>521.8.</num>
    <text>After making a determination with respect to the challenge, the Registrar shall notify, by first class mail, both the challenged registrant and the person who filed the challenge.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>521.9.</num>
    <text>Within fourteen (14) days of the date that the chief voter registration official’s notice is mailed, or five (5) days if the challenge is received between ninety (90) and forty-five (45) days from the election, any aggrieved party may appeal the Registrar’s
      determination to the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>521.10.</num>
    <text>The Board shall conduct a hearing and issue a decision within thirty (30) days of receipt of the written appeal notice, or ten (10) days if the challenge is received between ninety (90) and forty-five (45) days from the election.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>521.11.</num>
    <text>With respect to a request for the addition of a person to the voter roll, if the Board’s records indicate that the omission or cancellation was proper, the Board shall send notice of its determination, by first-class (forwardable) mail, to both the
      individual named in the request and the person who filed the request. The notice shall advise both parties that the person whose name was removed from the registration roll is required to submit a new voter registration application in order to become
      registered.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 57 D.C. Reg. 3267, 3291 (April 16, 2010); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Federal Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 10752 (December 16, 2012)[EXPIRED];as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR
        941, 956 (February 10, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>