<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2299</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 14-2299)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2299.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this Chapter, the following words and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed below:</text>
    <text>Annual Income – annual income as defined in 24 C.F.R. § 5.609 as of [the date of publication of this Chapter in the D.C. Register].</text>
    <text>Area Median Income – the area median income for a household in the Washington Metropolitan Statistical Area as set forth in the periodic calculation provided by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development, adjusted for household
      size without regard to any adjustments made by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development for the purposes of the programs it administers. Adjustments of Area Median Income for household size shall be made in the same manner as
      is prescribed in section 2(1) of the Housing Production Trust Fund Act, effective March 16, 1989 (D.C. Law 7-202; D.C. Official Code §§ 42-2801(1)).</text>
    <text>Bedroom – a room with immediate access to an exterior window and a closet that is designated as a “bedroom” or “sleeping room” on construction plans submitted in an application for a building permit for an Inclusionary Development.</text>
    <text>Certifying Entity – means an entity certified by the Department of Housing and Community Development pursuant to § 2214.</text>
    <text>Eligible Capital Improvement – major structural system upgrades, special assessments, new additions, and improvements related to increasing the health, safety, or energy efficiency of an Inclusionary Unit. Such improvements generally include: (i)
      major electrical wiring system upgrades; (ii) major plumbing system upgrades; (iii) room additions; (iv) installation of additional closets and walls; (v) alarm systems; (vi) smoke detectors; (vii) removal of toxic substances, such as asbestos,
      lead, mold, or mildew; (viii) insulation or upgrades to double-paned windows or glass fireplace screens; and (ix) upgrade to Energy Star built-in appliances, such as furnaces, water heaters, stoves, ranges, dishwashers, and microwave hoods.</text>
    <text>Eligible Replacement and Repair Cost – in-kind replacement of existing amenities and repairs and general maintenance that keep an Inclusionary Unit in good working condition. Such improvements generally include: (i) electrical maintenance and repair,
      such as switches and outlets; (ii) plumbing maintenance and repair, such as faucets, supply lines, and sinks; (iii) replacement or repair of flooring, countertops, cabinets, bathroom tile, or bathroom vanities; (viii) non-Energy Star replacement
      of built-in appliances, including furnaces, water heaters, stoves, ranges, dishwashers, and microwave hoods; (ix) replacement of window sashes; (x) fireplace maintenance or in-kind replacement; (xi) heating system maintenance and repairs; and (xii)
      lighting system.</text>
    <text>For Sale Inclusionary Development – the portion of an Inclusionary Development that includes or will include Inclusionary Units that will be sold to Households.</text>
    <text>For Sale Inclusionary Unit – an Inclusionary Unit that will be or has been sold to a Household.</text>
    <text>Household – all persons who will occupy the Inclusionary Unit. A Household may be a single family, one (1) person living alone, two (2) or more families living together, or any other group of related or unrelated persons who share living arrangements.</text>
    <text>Inclusionary Development – a development subject to the provisions of the Inclusionary Zoning Program.</text>
    <text>Inclusionary Development Covenant – the Inclusionary Development Covenant described in § 2204.</text>
    <text>Inclusionary Development Owner – a person, firm, partnership, association, joint venture, or corporation, or government with a property interest in land or improvements that is or will be occupied by an Inclusionary Development, but excluding Inclusionary
      Unit Owners.</text>
    <text>Inclusionary Unit– a dwelling unit set aside for sale or rental to Low-Income or Moderate-Income Households as required by the Inclusionary Zoning Program.</text>
    <text>Inclusionary Unit Owner – a Household member or members that owns an Inclusionary Unit.</text>
    <text>Inclusionary Zoning Act – the Inclusionary Zoning Implementation Act of 2006, effective March 14, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-275; D.C. Official Code § 6-1041.01 et seq.).</text>
    <text>Inclusionary Zoning Program – all of the provisions of the Zoning Commission’s Inclusionary Zoning Regulations, the Inclusionary Zoning Act, and this Chapter.</text>
    <text>Ineligible Costs – means normal maintenance, general repair work, personal or decorative items or work, cosmetic enhancements, installations with limited useful life spans, and non-permanent fixtures not eligible for capital improvement credit as
      determined by the Department of Housing and Community Development. Such costs generally include: (i) cosmetic enhancements such as fireplace tiles and mantels, decorative wall coverings or hangings, window treatments (for example, blinds, shutters,
      and curtains), installed mirrors, shelving, and refinishing of existing surfaces; (ii) non-permanent fixtures, such as track lighting, door knobs, handles and locks, and portable appliances; and (iii) installations with limited useful life spans,
      such as carpet, painting of existing surfaces, and light bulbs.</text>
    <text>Low-Income Household – a Household with a total Annual Income equal to or less than fifty percent (50%) of the Area Median Income, adjusted for household size.</text>
    <text>Market Rate Unit – a unit in an Inclusionary Development that is not an Inclusionary Unit.</text>
    <text>Moderate-Income Household – a Household with a total Annual Income greater than fifty percent (50%) and less than or equal to eighty percent (80%) of the Area Median Income adjusted for household size.</text>
    <text>Notice of Availability – the notice required to be provided to the Department of Housing and Community Development by an Owner in accordance with § 2206.</text>
    <text>Owner – both an Inclusionary Development Owner and an Inclusionary Unit Owner.</text>
    <text>Rent and Price Schedule – the rent and price schedule published in the D.C. Register pursuant to § 103(b) of the Inclusionary Zoning Act (D.C. Official Code § 6-1041.03(b)).</text>
    <text>Rental Inclusionary Development – the portion of an Inclusionary Development that includes, or will include, Inclusionary Units that will be leased to Households.</text>
    <text>Rental Inclusionary Unit – an Inclusionary Unit that will be or has been leased to a Household.</text>
    <text>Tenant – a Household member or members that occupy a Rental Inclusionary Unit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 3907 (May 15, 2009); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 9295, 9321 (December 11, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>