<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2205</num>
  <heading>CERTIFICATES OF OCCUPANCY FOR INCLUSIONARY UNITS (§ 14-2205)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2205.1</num>
    <text>2205.1 An Inclusionary Development Owner shall obtain a certificate ofccupancy for each Inclusionary Unit in an Inclusionary Development or aertificate of occupancy for an Inclusionary Development that identifies andncludes each Inclusionary Unit
      in the Inclusionary Development.</text>
    <text>Prior to the issuance of a certificate of occupancy for an Inclusionary Unit ornclusionary Development, an Inclusionary Development Owner shall provide to theepartment of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs an update of all informationrovided in its application
      for a Certificate of Inclusionary Zoning Compliance,f there has been any substantive change to such information since the filing ofhe application. The Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs shall reviewhe updated information pursuant to the
      procedures set forth in § 2203.</text>
    <text>After the submission of the application for a certificate of occupancy, theepartment of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs shall inspect the Inclusionarynit or Inclusionary Development for compliance with the Certificate ofnclusionary Zoning Compliance
      and the Inclusionary Zoning Program.</text>
    <text>The Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs shall make good faith effortso complete its Inclusionary Zoning compliance inspection within seventeen (17)ays after receipt of the certificate of occupancy application.</text>
    <text>No certificate of occupancy for an Inclusionary Unit or Inclusionary Developmenthall be issued unless the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairsetermines that the Inclusionary Unit or Inclusionary Development is inompliance with the Certificate
      of Inclusionary Zoning Compliance and thenclusionary Zoning Program.</text>
    <text>The Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs may authorize third parties toertify the compliance of an Inclusionary Unit or Inclusionary Development withhe Certificate of Inclusionary Zoning Compliance and the Inclusionary Zoningrogram.</text>
    <text>Pursuant to the Rental Housing Act of 1985, as amended, if an Inclusionary Unitwner enters into a temporary lease of a For Sale Inclusionary Unit, annclusionary Unit Owner must register the Rental Inclusionary Unit as exempt,ursuant to § 42-3502.05(a)(1)
      of the D.C. Official Code, with the Rentalccommodations Division of the Department of Housing and Community Development.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 3907 (May 15, 2009); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 9295, 9302 (December 11, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>