<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2209</num>
  <heading>DISTRICT LOTTERY – REGISTRATION FOR LOTTERY (§ 14-2209)
    <text>In order to be eligible to participate in the District-conducted lottery for theurchase or rent of an Inclusionary Unit, a Household shall register with theepartment of Housing and Community Development.</text>
    <text>The Department of Housing and Community Development shall maintain at least thewo (2) following lottery registration lists:</text>
    <text>The District List, consisting of Households whose members live in, or at leastne (1) of whose members works in, the District of Columbia; and</text>
    <text>The Miscellaneous List, consisting of Households that do not qualify to belaced on the District List.</text>
    <text>A Household seeking to be placed on a registration list shall provide theollowing information to the Department of Housing and Community Development onuch form as may be prescribed by the Department of Housing and Communityevelopment:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and telephone number of the Household member who willerve as the principal contact for the Department of Housing and Communityevelopment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Household’s size and estimated annual income;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If the Household consists entirely of a person enrolled as a full-timetudent in a college or university, the annual income of the person’s parentr guardian; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>For each adult Household member:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Verification of current principal residence;</text>
    <text>If employed, verification of employment and the name and address of themployer;</text>
    <text>If a college or university student, and the annual income of his or her parentr guardian would qualify under the eligibility standards, verification ofatriculation; and</text>
    <text>Housing counseling certificate of completion.</text>
    <text>Registration shall become effective on the date the application for registrations, after review by the Department of Housing and Community Development,onsidered complete and shall expire two (2) years thereafter, unless renewedrior to expiration.</text>
    <text>The Department of Housing and Community Development shall notify each registrantf the date upon which their registration became effective and the date uponhich the registration will expire.</text>
    <text>An application to renew a registration shall indicate any change in anynformation that was required to be provided in the initial application.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 3907 (May 15, 2009); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 9295, 9307 (December 11, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>