<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2210</num>
  <heading>DISTRICT LOTTERY – CONDUCT OF LOTTERIES (§ 14-2210)
    <text>No later than seventeen (17) days after receiving a Notice of Availability forn Inclusionary Unit to be offered pursuant to a District lottery, theepartment of Housing and Community Development shall hold a lottery of thoseouseholds on the District
      List that meet the size and Annual Incomeequirements for the Inclusionary Unit as described in section § 2211.3.</text>
    <text>Unit size eligibility shall be determined based upon the following standards:</text>
    <text>Unit Size (Bedroom)</text>
    <text>Minimum</text>
    <text>Number of Persons in Unit</text>
    <text>Maximum</text>
    <text>Number of Persons in Unit</text>
    <text>0</text>
    <text>1</text>
    <text>1</text>
    <text>1</text>
    <text>1</text>
    <text>2</text>
    <text>2</text>
    <text>2</text>
    <text>4</text>
    <text>3</text>
    <text>4</text>
    <text>6</text>
    <text>4</text>
    <text>6</text>
    <text>8</text>
    <text>5</text>
    <text>8</text>
    <text>10</text>
    <text>6</text>
    <text>10</text>
    <text>12</text>
    <text>For each Inclusionary Unit, the Department of Housing and Community Developmenthall randomly select at least four (4) Households through a lottery from theistrict List. If fewer than four (4) Households on the District List meet theousehold size and
      Annual Income standards applicable to the Inclusionary Unit,he Department of Housing and Community Development shall hold a lottery fromhe Miscellaneous List in order to select at least four (4) Households whicheet the Household size and Annual
      Income standards applicable for thenclusionary Unit.</text>
    <text>The Households chosen shall then be ranked in the following order:</text>
    <text>Households residing in the District of Columbia, who shall then be ranked byhe length of time each has been on the District List;</text>
    <text>Households with at least one (1) member employed in the District of Columbia,ho shall then be ranked by the length of time each has been on the Districtist; and</text>
    <text>Households on the Miscellaneous List, who shall then be ranked by the length ofime each has been on the Miscellaneous List.</text>
    <text>If more than one (1) Household has been on the registration list for the sameeriod of time, their ranking shall be in the order in which the Households wereelected in the lottery.</text>
    <text>If none of the Households selected through a lottery purchase or rent thenclusionary Unit, the Department of Housing and Community Development shallontinue to hold lotteries pursuant to the procedures set forth in this sectionntil a Household purchases
      or leases the Inclusionary Unit or the Inclusionarynit is leased or sold; except, the Department of Housing and Communityevelopment may permit the rental or sale of the Inclusionary Unit to aousehold that is not registered for the lottery if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>More than six (6) months has passed since the Notice of Availability wasubmitted for the Inclusionary Unit and at least 2 lotteries have beenonducted;</text>
    </level>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <num>2210.7</num>
    <text>2210.7 With respect to each Household selected pursuant to a lottery under thisection, the Department of Housing and Community Development shall provide aotice under § 2211.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 3907 (May 15, 2009); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 9295, 9308 (December 11, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>