<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2200</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 14-2200)
    <text>The purpose of this Chapter is to implement the Zoning Commission’snclusionary Zoning Regulations (Title 11 DCMR, Chapter 26) and the Inclusionaryoning Act.</text>
    <text>Subject to certain exemptions, the Zoning Commission’s Inclusionary Zoningegulations mandate that, in applicable zone districts, Inclusionary Units berovided in new residential buildings of ten (10) or more dwelling units or whenhe construction of
      ten (10) or more dwelling units represents an expansion ofn existing building’s gross floor area by fifty percent (50%) or more.</text>
    <text>The Zoning Commission’s Inclusionary Zoning Regulations establish a formula toetermine the minimum and maximum amount of gross floor area that must beeserved for Inclusionary Units, but leave the establishment of maximum pricesnd rents for the Inclusionary
      Units to the Council and the Mayor.</text>
    <text>Subject to certain exceptions, the Inclusionary Zoning Act requires Inclusionarynits be sold or leased only to persons authorized by the Mayor at a price orent no greater than the maximum established by the Mayor.</text>
    <text>The Inclusionary Zoning Act also provides that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>No building permit shall be issued for an Inclusionary Development unlesshe Mayor approves a Certificate of Inclusionary Zoning Compliance and aovenant signed by the Owner of the Inclusionary Development</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>No certificate of occupancy for a Market Rate Unit in an Inclusionaryevelopment shall be issued unless the application includes a written statementigned by the Mayor and dated no earlier than six (6) months before the date ofhe application indicating
        that the Inclusionary Development is in complianceith the Inclusionary Zoning Program and the Certificate of Inclusionary Zoningompliance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A violation of the Inclusionary Zoning Program constitutes grounds for theevocation of any building permit and certificate of occupancy for the marketate portions of the Inclusionary Development.</text>
    </level>
    <text>This Chapter implements these aspects of the Inclusionary Zoning Act bystablishing, among other things:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The process and prerequisites for obtaining building permits andertificates of occupancy for Inclusionary Developments;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The process for selecting households for referral to the owner of annclusionary Unit; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The responsibilities of and limitations on Inclusionary Unit Owners andenants.</text>
    </level>
    <text>All timeframes established in this Chapter for an agency to take an action areuidelines only. An agency’s failure to act within a timeframe established inhis Chapter shall not constitute a default by the agency and shall not permitny person to take
      or refuse to take any action governed by the Inclusionaryoning Program.</text>
    <text>In computing a period of time specified in this Chapter, calendar days shall beounted unless otherwise provided.</text>
    <text>In computing a period of time specified in this Chapter, the day of the act,vent, or default after which the designated period of time begins to run shallot be included. The last day of the period of time so computed shall bencluded unless it is a
      Saturday, Sunday, or official District of Columbiaoliday, in which case the period of time shall run until the end of the nextay that is neither a Saturday, Sunday, nor official District of Columbiaoliday.</text>
    <text>When, under this Chapter, a person has the right or is required to perform anct within a prescribed period of time after the sending of or the date of aotice or other paper, and the paper or notice is sent by mail, three (3) dayshall be added to the
      prescribed period of time.</text>
    <text>In the event of a conflict between the provisions of this Chapter and therovisions of the Inclusionary Zoning Act or the Zoning Commission’snclusionary Zoning Regulations, the most stringent provision shall apply.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 3907 (May 15, 2009); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 9295, 9296 (December 11, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>