<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2206</num>
  <heading>NOTICE OF AVAILABILITY; HOUSING LOCATOR WEBSITE REGISTRATION (§ 14-2206)
    <text>The provisions of this section govern the process by which:</text>
    <text>The owner of a For Sale Inclusionary Development or a For Sale Inclusionarynit fulfills its obligation to notify the Department of Housing and Communityevelopment that an Inclusionary Unit is available for purchase; and</text>
    <text>The owner of a Rental Inclusionary Development fulfills its obligation tootify the Department of Housing and Community Development that an Inclusionarynit is available for lease.</text>
    <text>An Owner shall provide the notification described in § 2206.1 to the Departmentf Housing and Community Development by filing a written Notice of Availabilityn accordance with the provisions of this section.</text>
    <text>An Inclusionary Development Owner shall file the initial Notice of Availabilityor an Inclusionary Unit prior to the date of the certificate of occupancy finalnspection from the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs for thenclusionary Development
      or the Inclusionary Unit.</text>
    <text>An Owner of a Rental Inclusionary Unit shall file all subsequent Notices ofvailability no later than seventeen (17) days after a Tenant gives notice ofts intent to vacate the Inclusionary Unit, including a notice of intentrovided pursuant to § 2216.1,
      or the Owner becomes aware that the Tenant hasacated or will vacate the Inclusionary Unit, whichever is earliest.</text>
    <text>An Owner of a For Sale Inclusionary Unit shall file all subsequent Notices ofvailability at least forty-five (45) days before the date the Owner markets thenclusionary Unit to eligible Households or, if the Inclusionary Unit is to beffered pursuant
      to a lottery performed pursuant to § 2210, at leasthirty-five (35) days before the lottery.</text>
    <text>The Notice of Availability shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Inclusionary Unit’s street address and unit number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The estimated date upon which the Inclusionary Unit will be available forccupancy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>For each initial Notice of Availability for a For Sale or Rentalnclusionary Unit, a list of any optional or required upfront or recurring feesnd costs, including but not limited to condominium, cooperative, or homeownerssociation fees and fees or
        costs for amenities, services, upgrade options, orarking. For each such fee or cost, the following information shall berovided:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The amount of the fee or cost;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A description of the fee or cost and how it will be charged; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If applicable, the budget for the condominium, cooperative, or homeownerssociation, the condominium, cooperative, or homeowner association fee for eacharket Rate Unit and each Inclusionary Unit, and the formula by which such fees assessed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>For each subsequent Notice of Availability for a For Sale or Rentalnclusionary Unit, a list of any required upfront or recurring fees and costs,ncluding but not limited to condominium, cooperative, or homeowner associationees and fees or costs for
        amenities, services, upgrade options, or parking, andhe amount of each such fee or cost;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>For each subsequent Notice of Availability for a For Sale Inclusionary Unit,n itemized list of all capital improvements and upgrades made to thenclusionary Unit that the Owner wishes the Department of Housing and Communityevelopment to consider
        when establishing the Maximum Resale Price pursuant to 2218. The Inclusionary Unit Owner shall document each cost or value claimedith receipts, contracts, or other supporting evidence;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>For each subsequent Notice of Availability for a Rental Inclusionary Unit,he method by which a Household shall be selected for the rental or sale of thenclusionary Unit, which method shall be consistent with § 2208;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Such other information as may be required by the Department of Housing andommunity Development.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Within five (5) days after the Owner files a Notice of Availability, the Ownerhall register the Inclusionary Unit for which the Notice of Availability wasiled with the housing locator website established by the District pursuant tohe Affordable Housing
      Clearinghouse Directory Act of 2008, effective August 15,008 (D.C. Law 17-215; 55 DCR 5313).</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 3907 (May 15, 2009); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 9295, 9303 (December 11, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>