<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2216</num>
  <heading>RESPONSIBILITIES OF RENTAL INCLUSIONARY DEVELOPMENT OWNERS AND TENANTS (§4-2216)
    <text>No later than sixty (60) days before each anniversary of the first day of theease, a Household leasing a Rental Inclusionary Unit shall submit to thenclusionary Development Owner the following information and documents on orith such form as may be
      prescribed by the Department of Housing and Communityevelopment:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A statement as to whether the Tenant intends to renew the lease; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the Tenant states that he or she intends to renew the lease:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A certification that the Household continues to occupy the unit as itsrincipal residence;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The names of each person residing in the unit;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A Certification of Income, Affordability, and Household Size that meets theequirements of § 2213; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A Declaration of Eligibility that meets the requirements of § 2213.</text>
    </level>
    <text>A Rental Inclusionary Unit, shall have rider attached to the lease agreement.</text>
    <text>The rider shall contain, but shall not be limited to the following terms:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Tenant shall provide a Certification of Income, Affordability, andousing Size in accordance with § 2216.1;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Tenant shall provide a Declaration of Eligibility in accordance with §216.1;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Tenant shall maintain its eligibility for the Inclusionary Unit based onhe Tenant’s Household Size and Annual Income requirements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Tenant shall provide the information and documents required by § 2216.1ithin the time period specified by § 2216.1</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The Inclusionary Unit shall be the principal residence of all adult personsho occupy the Inclusionary Unit; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The Tenant shall not make intentional misrepresentations to the Departmentf Housing and Community Development or the Certifying Entity;</text>
    </level>
    <text>The Owner may, in the Owner’s discretion, extend the deadline established by 2216.1; provided, the deadline shall not be extended beyond the last day ofhe Tenant’s lease.</text>
    <text>If a Tenant is in violation of a lease agreement or rider, the Inclusionaryevelopment Owner shall provide to the Tenant a notice to vacate in accordanceith § 42-3505.01 of the D.C. Official Code.</text>
    <text>If a notice to vacate is provided pursuant to § 2216.4, the Inclusionaryevelopment Owner may permit the Household to continue to occupy the unit at theurrent rent for not less than three (3) and no more than six (6) months afterhe Inclusionary Unit
      Owner provides to the Tenant the notice to vacate.cceptance of rent during this period will not constitute a waiver of theiolation of the lease or another obligation of tenancy or void the notice toacate.</text>
    <text>An Inclusionary Unit Tenant shall not close on the purchase of residentialroperty before the Tenant has provided notice of the intent to terminate itsease of the Inclusionary Unit in accordance with the terms of the lease.</text>
    <text>The Inclusionary Development Owner shall not require payment of rent that isreater than the maximum allowable rent determined in accordance with§ 2207.2 and 2207.4.</text>
    <text>Annually within fifteen (15) days after the anniversary of the issuance date ofhe first certificate of occupancy for an Inclusionary Unit in a Rentalnclusionary Development, the Owner shall submit a report to the Department ofousing and Community
      Development setting forth the following information forhe entire Rental Inclusionary Development:</text>
    <text>The number of Rental Inclusionary Units, by bedroom count, that are occupied;</text>
    <text>The number of Rental Inclusionary Units, by bedroom count, that were vacateduring the previous twelve (12) months;</text>
    <text>For each Rental Inclusionary Unit vacated during the previous twelve (12)onths, the unit number of the unit that was vacated, the number of days thenit was vacant (or a statement that the unit is still vacant), and the date onhich a Notice of Availability
      was provided to the Department of Housing andommunity Development pursuant to § 2206;</text>
    <text>For each occupied Rental Inclusionary Unit, the names of all occupants, theousehold size, and the Household’s Annual Income as of the date of the mostecent Certification of Income, Affordability, and Housing Size;</text>
    <text>A sworn statement that to the best of the Owner’s information and knowledge,he Annual Income and size of each Household occupying each Rental Inclusionarynit complies with the size and income limits applicable to the Rentalnclusionary Unit; and</text>
    <text>A copy of each new and revised Certification of Income, Affordability, andousing Size provided in accordance with § 2216.1.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 3907 (May 15, 2009); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 9295, 9314 (December 11, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>