<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2207</num>
  <heading>DESIGNATION OF MAXIMUM PURCHASE PRICE OR RENT (§ 14-2207)
    <text>Within seventeen (17) days after the receipt of a Notice of Availability, theepartment of Housing and Community Development shall notify the Owner of theaximum purchase price or rent for each Inclusionary Unit listed in the Noticef Availability.</text>
    <text>Except as provided in § 2207.5, the initial maximum purchase price or rent forn Inclusionary Unit shall be the greater of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The purchase price or rent in the Rent and Price Schedule in place on theiling date of the application for the Certificate of Inclusionary Zoningompliance issued for the Inclusionary Development in which the Inclusionarynit is located; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The purchase price or rent in the Rent and Price Schedule in place on theiling date of the Notice of Availability for the Inclusionary Unit.</text>
    </level>
    <text>The maximum purchase price for all subsequent sales of an Inclusionary Unitwner shall be the Maximum Resale Price determined by the Department of Housingnd Community Development pursuant to § 2218.</text>
    <text>The maximum rent for all subsequent rentals shall be the rent set forth in theent and Price Schedule in place on the date that the Notice of Availability forhe Inclusionary Unit is filed.</text>
    <text>If the costs provided for a For Sale Inclusionary Unit in response to2206.6(d) exceed by ten percent (10%) or more the cost assumptions in thepplicable Rent and Price Schedule, the Department of Housing and Communityevelopment may lower the initial
      maximum purchase price to the extent needed toaintain the affordability standard set forth in § 103(a) of the Inclusionaryoning Act (D.C. Official Code § 6-1041.03(a)) and this Chapter.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 3907 (May 15, 2009); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 9295, 9305 (December 11, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>