<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4811</num>
  <heading>SCOPE OF PRACTICE (ยง 17-4811)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4811.1.</num>
    <text>A chiropractor who is licensed to practice in the District of Columbia under the provisions of this chapter may provide the following chiropractic services:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Locating, diagnosing, and analyzing subluxated vertebrae as follows:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>By x-ray of the spinal column;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>By physical examination; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>By employing other non-invasive procedures such as MRI and CAT scan;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Correcting vertebral subluxation displacement by applying specific localized force to the spine;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Advising patients about diet, exercise and stress;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Referring patients for specialized diagnostic testing, which may be necessary for chiropractic treatment or patient safety;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Referring patients to other healthcare practitioners as deemed necessary by the chiropractor; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Diagnosing and treating bodily articulations by means of manipulation or adjustments.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4811.2.</num>
    <text>A chiropractor who is certified by the Board to perform ancillary procedures pursuant to ยง 4803.3 may perform any physiotherapy for which the chiropractor has received specialized training at a program or institution listed in ยง 4807.1 as long as
      the physiotherapy is preparatory and complementary to chiropractic care.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 6658, 6663 (September 2, 1986); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 2747, 2750 (May 4, 1990); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 6820 (July 19, 2002); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 49 DCR 11237 (December 13, 2002); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 3955 (May 23, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 7946 (July 25, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>