<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4604</num>
  <heading>PRIMARY CASE MANAGER (ยง 29-4604)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4604.1.</num>
    <text>Each MCOTT client shall have an assigned Primary Case Manager who shall be responsible for the treatment relationship with the client on an ongoing basis.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4604.2.</num>
    <text>The Primary Care Manager shall be responsible for the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Maintaining up-to-date assessments and evaluations necessary for eligibility for MCOTT services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Participating in the treatment planning and monitoring of client progress in meeting the goals and objectives of the MCOTT client&amp;#8217;s ITP;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Locating, coordinating, and monitoring all necessary medical, social and psychiatric services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Assisting in the development and execution of a plan for assuring income maintenance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Assisting in the development of appropriate social networks;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Assisting with other activities necessary to maintain psychiatric stability in a community-based setting.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Assisting in the development of a plan for assuring continuing Medicaid coverage; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Documenting case management efforts in each MCOTT client&amp;#8217;s record.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4604.3.</num>
    <text>The Primary Case Manager shall have at least one other team member who shares in providing the case management services and who serves as a backup when the Primary Case Manager is not present.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 6122 (July 23, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>