<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4699</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 29-4699)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4699.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Assessment means the process used to evaluate a client&amp;#8217;s presenting problems with an accompanying description of the reported or observed conditions to the classification or diagnosis of the client&amp;#8217;s severe and persistent mental
      illness.</text>
    <text>Client means a person who has completed the admissions process and is receiving treatment and services from the Mobile Community Outreach Treatment Team.</text>
    <text>Commission for Mental Health Services or CMHS within the Department of Human Services, is responsible for administering services for mentally ill persons in the District.</text>
    <text>Comprehensive assessment means the organized process of gathering information to evaluate a client&amp;#8217;s mental health status and his or her treatment needs. The results of the comprehensive assessment are used to develop an individual treatment
      plan or service plan for the client.</text>
    <text>Individual supportive therapy means talk therapy that focuses on lessening distress and symptomatology and improving psychological defenses and role functioning as well as increasing and reinforcing the client&amp;#8217;s understanding of and participation
      in treatment and rehabilitative services.</text>
    <text>MCOTT Program means the Provider&amp;#8217;s comprehensive array of services staffed and organized to provide care for MCOTT clients.</text>
    <text>Medical Assistance Administration or MAA is the single state agency in the District&amp;#8217;s Department of Health responsible for administering the Medicaid program.</text>
    <text>Medication monitoring means the observation of the client to determine/identify beneficial effects and inadvertent or undesirable effects related to psycho tropic medications.</text>
    <text>Medication error means any error in prescribing or administering a specific medication, including errors in writing or transcribing the prescription or in obtaining and administering the correct medication, in the correct dosage, in the correct form
      and at the correct time.</text>
    <text>Mobile Community Outreach Treatment Team or MCOTT means a self-contained clinical team which assumes responsibility for directly providing needed treatment, rehabilitation and support services to identified clients with severe and persistent mental
      illness.</text>
    <text>Primary Case Manager means the MCOTT client&amp;#8217;s advocate, treatment plan and individual treatment team coordinator, and primary provider of individual supportive therapy and symptom management. He/she is also the first staff called on when
      the client is in crisis and is the primary support and educator to the individual client&amp;#8217;s family. The individual treatment team shares these tasks with the Primary Case Manager and is responsible to perform the tasks when the Primary
      Case Manager is absent.</text>
    <text>Psychotropic medication means any drug used to treat, manage or control psychiatric symptoms or disordered behavior, including but not limited to antipsychotic, antidepressant, mood stabilizing or antianxiety agents.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 6122 (July 23, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>