<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4608</num>
  <heading>ASSESSMENT AND TREATMENT PLANNING (ยง 29-4608)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4608.1.</num>
    <text>The Program Director, Assistant Director or Psychiatrist shall complete and document an initial evaluation promptly at the time of each client&amp;#8217;s admission to the MCOTT Program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4608.2.</num>
    <text>The MCOTT Program shall assign an Individual Treatment Team to each client. Such team shall consist of three to five members possessing a range of clinical and rehabilitation skills and which shall be assigned by the clinical coordinator within a
      week of the MCOTT client&amp;#8217;s admission to the MCOTT Program. The core members of this team shall be the Primary Case Manager, psychiatrist, and one clinical or rehabilitation staff who shall backup and share case coordination tasks and replace
      the Primary Case Manager when he/she is not working. The individual treatment team shall have: 1) continuous responsibility for the assessment of the client&amp;#8217;s individual status and needs; 2) development of the treatment plan with the client
      and his/her family; and 3) direction and provision of much of the client&amp;#8217;s treatment and rehabilitation skills. Individual treatment team members shall be assigned to take separate service roles with the client.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4608.3.</num>
    <text>The Program Director, psychiatrist and individual treatment members shall complete and document a comprehensive assessment within one (1) month of the client&amp;#8217;s admission to the MCOTT Program. The comprehensive assessment shall include, but
      not be limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Psychiatric symptomatology and mental status. Utilizing information derived from the evaluation, a psychiatrist or a clinical or counseling psychologist shall make a diagnosis listed in the American Psychiatric Association Diagnostic and Statistical
        Manual of Mental Disorders (DSM IV or most current version);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Psychiatric history, including compliance with and response to prescribed medical/psychiatric treatment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Medical, dental and other health needs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Extent and effect of drugs and/or alcohol use;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Housing situation and conditions of daily living;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Vocational and educational functioning;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Criminal record, including final dispositions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Social functioning; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Recent history of client&amp;#8217;s personal life.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4608.4.</num>
    <text>Each MCOTT Program shall develop an Individual Treatment Plan (&amp;#8220;ITP&amp;#8221;) for each client. The ITP shall be written and developed collectively by the Program Director, Primary Case Manager and psychiatrist to plan treatment and service
      interventions and to assign staff persons responsible for providing the services. The ITP shall include, but is not limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Assessment of the client&amp;#8217;s needs/problems; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Establishment of measurable long and short-term treatment goals.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 6122 (July 23, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>