<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4610</num>
  <heading>TREATMENT RECORDS (ยง 29-4610)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4610.1.</num>
    <text>Each MCOTT Program shall keep accurate treatment records reflecting the initial, comprehensive and ongoing assessments, initial and periodic treatment plans, and the ongoing progress of each MCOTT client. The MCOTT Program staff shall document all
      relevant data promptly at the time of its occurrence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4610.2.</num>
    <text>Each MCOTT Program shall keep accurate records reflecting the specific services offered to each client reimbursable under the District&amp;#8217;s Medicaid/MCOTT Provider Agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4610.3.</num>
    <text>All client services shall be documented in a manner consistent with the CMHS Policy 50000.450.IC &amp;#8220;Clinical Records.&amp;#8221;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4610.4.</num>
    <text>Each MCOTT Program shall maintain client treatment records that are confidential, complete, accurate and contain up-to-date information relevant to each MCOTT client&amp;#8217;s care and treatment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4610.5.</num>
    <text>Each MCOTT client&amp;#8217;s record shall include documentation of assessments, treatment plans and the nature and extent of services provided to clearly identify each client&amp;#8217;s treatment needs and services received in lay language.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4610.6.</num>
    <text>The Program Director shall maintain and secure client treatment records.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4610.7.</num>
    <text>Each MCOTT Program shall ensure that the client&amp;#8217;s records are held in a central location accessible to the MCOTT Program team.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4610.8.</num>
    <text>All records of care, treatment and supervision created under the MCOTT Program Standards shall be the property of CMHS.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4610.9.</num>
    <text>Each MCOTT client&amp;#8217;s record shall be kept in a locked room or file controlled by appropriate MCOTT Program staff. For purposes of record confidentiality, the disclosure of treatment information by the MCOTT is subject to all the provisions
      of applicable District and federal laws.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4610.10.</num>
    <text>Each MCOTT client&amp;#8217;s clinical record shall be available for review at all times to CMHS and MAA staff for monitoring the client&amp;#8217;s care under the Medicaid/MCOTT Provider Agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4610.11.</num>
    <text>Records of all MCOTT clients discharged from the MCOTT Program shall be turned over to CMHS staff within thirty (30) days of the date of discharge.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 6122 (July 23, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>