<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-1732</num>
  <heading>JUDICIAL REVIEW; RECORD ON APPEAL (ยง 17-1732)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1732.1.</num>
    <text>A party aggrieved by a final decision of the Director may seek review of the decision by the District of Columbia Court of Appeals in accordance with the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act (D.C. Official Code ยง 2-501 et seq.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1732.2.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt by the Director of a notice of appeal, the Director shall promptly acknowledge receipt.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1732.3.</num>
    <text>The Director shall compile, index, and transmit the originals or copies of all documents pertinent to the appeal, including the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A copy of the decision from which an appeal is taken;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A copy of any recommended or proposed decision and any exceptions thereto;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>All documents relied on by the Director, including any relevant documents timely submitted to the Director by the respondent or by other parties to the hearing; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A transcript or summary (in accordance with ยง 1730.3 of this chapter) of all testimony given or statements made during any hearings, conferences, or investigations concerning the matter in dispute conducted by the Director before the filing of the
        notice of appeal.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1732.4.</num>
    <text>The Director shall provide to all parties to the appeal a copy of the Director&amp;#8217;s index of the record on appeal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1732.5.</num>
    <text>The record may be shortened or summarized if, with permission of the court, all parties to the review proceedings so agree.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1732.6.</num>
    <text>The documents transmitted pursuant to this section, and any supplements thereto, shall be available for inspection by the parties at a location designated by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking at 50 DCR 9549 (November 14, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>