<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-1702</num>
  <heading>RENEWAL OF REGISTRATION AND LICENSURE (ยง 17-1702)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1702.1.</num>
    <text>An athlete agent may apply to renew a registration by submitting an application for renewal. The applicant must sign the application under the penalty of perjury and must contain all matters required in the original registration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1702.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant for renewal who is also registered, certified, or licensed in another jurisdiction and has submitted a renewal application in another State may, instead of submitting an application for renewal provided for by ยง 1701.1 of this chapter,
      submit a basic District of Columbia renewal application, a notarized copy of the other State&amp;#8217;s renewal application and a valid certificate of licensure from the other State if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The renewal application was submitted in the other State within the six (6) months preceding the filing of the renewal application in the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The information contained in the renewal application is substantially similar to that required by the District of Columbia application; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The renewal application for the other jurisdiction was signed by the applicant under the penalty of perjury.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1702.3.</num>
    <text>A certificate of registration or a renewal is valid for two (2) years or as otherwise provided in ยง 1702.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1702.4.</num>
    <text>The Director may change the renewal system to a system whereby a license expires on the last day of the month on the birth date of the applicant or the holder of the registration, or to another system, for the administrative convenience of the Director.
      The initial registration will be valid for the balance of the current renewal cycle. The Director will mail a renewal notice to the registrant three (3) months before the expiration date of the holder&amp;#8217;s current registration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1702.5.</num>
    <text>If the Director changes the renewal system under ยง 1702.4, in order to permit an orderly transition, the term of a license that is in effect on the date of the Director&amp;#8217;s determination may be extended up to three (3) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking at 50 DCR 9549 (November 14, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>