<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-1735</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 17-1735)
    <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the following terms have the meaningsscribed:</text>
    <text>Administrative Law Judge (ALJ) &amp;#8211; a Hearing Examiner authorized to hearases pursuant to the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civilnfractions Act of 1985, effective October 5, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-42; D.C. Officialode §§ 2-1801.01
      et seq.), or designated by the Director to hear a case.</text>
    <text>Agency contract &amp;#8211; an agreement in which a student-athlete authorizes aerson to negotiate or solicit on behalf of the student-athlete arofessional-sports-services contract or an endorsement contract.</text>
    <text>Applicant &amp;#8211; an applicant for a registration under the Uniform Athletegents Act of 2002, D.C. Law 14-107, and these rules.</text>
    <text>Athlete agent &amp;#8211; an individual who enters into an agency contract with atudent-athlete or, directly or indirectly, recruits or solicits atudent-athlete to enter into an agency contract. The term includes anndividual who represents to the
      public that the individual is an athlete agent.he term does not include a spouse, parent, sibling, grandparent, or guardian ofhe student- athlete or an individual acting solely on behalf of a professionalports team or professional sports organization.</text>
    <text>Athletic director &amp;#8211; an individual responsible for administering theverall athletic program of an educational institution or, if an educationalnstitution has separately administered athletic programs for male students andemale students, the
      athletic program for males or the athletic program foremales, as appropriate.</text>
    <text>Business day &amp;#8211; a day other than a Saturday, Sunday, legal holiday, or dayn which the department is officially closed.</text>
    <text>Contact &amp;#8211; a communication, direct or indirect, between an athlete agentnd a student-athlete, to recruit or solicit the student-athlete to enter inton agency contract.</text>
    <text>Day &amp;#8211; a calendar day</text>
    <text>Department &amp;#8211; the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; the Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatoryffairs and/or authorized agent.</text>
    <text>Endorsement contract &amp;#8211; an agreement under which a student-athlete ismployed or receives consideration to use on behalf of the other party any valuehat the student-athlete may have because of publicity, reputation, following,r fame obtained
      because of athletic ability or performance.</text>
    <text>Hearing Examiner &amp;#8211; any person appointed by the Director pursuant to theuthority granted under D.C. Official Code § 2-1801.01 et seq., to conductdministrative hearings under this chapter.</text>
    <text>Intercollegiate sport &amp;#8211; a sport played at the collegiate level for whichligibility requirements for participation by a student-athlete are establishedy a national association for the promotion or regulation of collegiatethletics.</text>
    <text>Legal holiday &amp;#8211; one of the following holidays:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>New Year&amp;#8217;s Day;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Martin Luther King, Jr.&amp;#8217;s, Birthday;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Washington&amp;#8217;s Birthday;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Memorial Day;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Independence Day;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Labor Day;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Columbus Day;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Veterans Day;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Thanksgiving Day;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Christmas Day; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Any other day designated as a legal holiday by the President, the Congress,r the Mayor or the Council of the District of Columbia, on the actual day theegal holiday is celebrated by the government of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Office of Investigations and Enforcement &amp;#8211; the investigative divisionithin the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
    <text>Party &amp;#8211; a respondent, the Corporation Counsel, the Director, or any othererson recognized as a party in a particular proceeding.</text>
    <text>Person &amp;#8211; an individual, corporation, business trust, estate, trust,artnership, limited liability company, association, joint venture, government,overnmental subdivision, agency, or instrumentality, public corporation, or anyther legal or
      commercial entity.</text>
    <text>Professional-sports-services contract &amp;#8211; an agreement under which anndividual is employed, or agrees to render services, as a player on arofessional sports team, with a professional sports organization, or as arofessional athlete.</text>
    <text>Record &amp;#8211; information that is inscribed on a tangible medium or that istored in an electronic or other medium and is retrievable in perceivable form.</text>
    <text>Registrant &amp;#8211; a person registered under this chapter.</text>
    <text>Registration &amp;#8211; registration as an athlete agent pursuant to this chapter.</text>
    <text>Respondent &amp;#8211; a person against whom an adverse action is contemplated,roposed, or taken.</text>
    <text>State &amp;#8211; a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puertoico, the United States Virgin Islands, or any territory or insular possessionubject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</text>
    <text>Student-athlete &amp;#8211; an individual, who engages in, is eligible to engage in,r may be eligible in the future to engage in, any intercollegiate sport. If anndividual is permanently ineligible to participate in a particularntercollegiate sport,
      the individual is not a student-athlete for purposes ofhat sport.</text>
    <text>Void &amp;#8211; of no legal force or effect.</text>
    <text>Voidable &amp;#8211; capable of being adjudged as having no legal force or effect.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking at 50 DCR 9549 (November 14, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>