<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-827</num>
  <heading>CONCESSION STANDS[COLON] CONSTRUCTION AND EQUIPMENT (ยง 24-827)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>827.1.</num>
    <text>All food stands shall be covered with wood, metal, flame-resistant canvas, or similar material approved by the Fire Chief.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>827.2.</num>
    <text>Food stands and mobile units shall be constructed and ready for inspection by the District at least one (1) day prior to Inauguration Day, unless a later time is authorized by the Concessions Committee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>827.3.</num>
    <text>A concession stand equipped with heating or cooking facilities shall be located not less than fifteen feet (15 ft.) from any reviewing stand.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>827.4.</num>
    <text>All lighting appliances shall be of a type approved by the Director of Housing and Community Development and the Fire Chief.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>827.5.</num>
    <text>Dry chemical fire extinguishers suitable for Class A, B, or C fires, with a minimum classification of 2A-10B:C, and bearing an Underwriters Laboratory label shall be available at each stand. The number and size of fire extinguishers to be available
      at each stand shall be approved by the Fire Chief.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>827.6.</num>
    <text>Each stand shall be equipped with one (1) or more metal trash containers with tight-fitting metal covers. The Fire Chief and the Director of Environmental Services shall determine what size the container or containers shall be to adequately accommodate
      the trash that results from the operations conducted or to be conducted in the stand.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Sections 20(d)-(f), (j)-(l) of the Presidential Inauguration Special Regulations and Rule of Interpretation Concerning Nonrevival of Statutes Act of 1982, D.C. Law 4-125, 29 DCR 2093 (May 21, 1982).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>