<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-801</num>
  <heading>SPECIAL INAUGURAL PROHIBITIONS (ยง 24-801)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>801.1.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section shall apply during the inaugural period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.2.</num>
    <text>No person shall, without proper authority, pass through, over, or under, or break down, cut, remove, injure, or destroy any rope or other barricade erected or placed by lawful authority; nor shall any person remove, injure, or in any way tamper with
      any light or sign placed upon any rope or barricade placed by lawful authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.3.</num>
    <text>No person shall intrude with any vehicle, stand, box, or obstruction of any kind into any area that is designated and properly marked by lawful authority, and contiguous to the route of any parade, ceremony, or unusual gathering of people, except
      as authorized by the Chief of Police.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.4.</num>
    <text>No person shall falsely represent, either directly or indirectly, that any program, medal, guidebook, or picture is the official souvenir program, medal, guidebook, or picture approved as such by the Inaugural Committee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.5.</num>
    <text>No person within the inaugural area shall give, sell, offer for sale, carry, or display, any imitation pistol, toy revolver, long gun, or other imitation weapon.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.6.</num>
    <text>No person shall, without proper authority, erect any support or stretch any conductor to illuminate any street, avenue, or alley, that is not in accordance with the terms and conditions of the permit as may be issued.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.7.</num>
    <text>No stove, torch, or open flame device for cooking, illuminating, or heating shall be used upon any street, alley, sidewalk, or reservation in the inaugural area, except in accordance with the provisions of ยง825 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Sections 5-7, 12, 14, 17 of the Presidential Inauguration Special Regulations and Rule of Interpretation Concerning Nonrevival of Statutes Act of 1982, D.C. Law 4-125, 29 DCR 2093 (May 21, 1982).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>