<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-899</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 24-899)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>899.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Chief of Police &amp;#8211; the Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department of the District of Columbia, as established by §1 of the Act relating to the D.C. Metropolitan Police (D.C. Code, §4-107), or the designated agent of the Chief of Police.</text>
    <text>Concessions Committee &amp;#8211; the Concessions Committee of the Inaugural Committee, or its designated agent.</text>
    <text>D.C. Sales and Use Tax Acts &amp;#8211; the D.C. Sales Tax Act approved May 27, 1949 (63 Stat. 112; D.C. Code §§47-2001 et seq.), and the D.C. Use Tax Act approved May 27, 1949 (63 Stat. 124; D.C. Code §§47-2201 et seq.).</text>
    <text>Director of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs &amp;#8211; the director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs of the District of Columbia, or the Director&amp;#8217;s designated agent.</text>
    <text>Director of Environmental Services &amp;#8211; the director of the Department of the Environmental Services of the District of Columbia, or the Director&amp;#8217;s designated agent.</text>
    <text>Director of Finance and Revenue &amp;#8211; the director of the Department of Finance and Revenue of the District of Columbia, or the Director&amp;#8217;s designated agent.</text>
    <text>Director of Housing and Community Development &amp;#8211; the director of the Department of Housing and Community Development of the District of Columbia, or the Director&amp;#8217;s designated agent.</text>
    <text>Director of Public Works &amp;#8211; the director of the Department of Public Works of the District of Columbia, or the Director&amp;#8217;s designated agent.</text>
    <text>Fire Chief &amp;#8211; the fire chief of the Fire Department of the District of Columbia, or the Fire Chief’s designated agent.</text>
    <text>Inaugural Area &amp;#8211; the Inaugural Area shall be bounded by the streets as designated below:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Beginning at the southeast corner of Second and E Streets, S.E., north along the east curb of Second Street, S.E. and N.E., to the northeast curb of Massachusetts Avenue, N.E.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Continuing northwest along the north curb of Massachusetts Avenue, N.E., to Union Station Plaza;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>West along the north side of Union Station Plaza to the northeast curb of Massachusetts Avenue, N.E.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Northwest along the north curb of Massachusetts Avenue, N.E., to the west curb of North Capitol Street;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>South along the west curb of North Capitol Street to the north curb of E Street, N.W.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>West along the north curb of E Street, N.W., to the east curb of Sixth Street, N.W.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>North along the east curb of Sixth Street, N.W., to the north curb of H Street, N.W.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>West along the north curb of H Street, N.W., to the east curb of Tenth Street, N.W.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>North along the east curb of Tenth Street, N.W., to the north curb of K Street, N.W.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>West along the north curb of K Street, N.W., to the northwest corner of Washington Circle at Twenty-third and K Streets, N.W.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>West along the north curb of K Street to the west boundary of Rock Creek Parkway;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>South along the west boundary of Rock Creek Parkway to the Potomac River;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Then south along the east bank of the Potomac River to a point due west of the south intersection of Independence Avenue and Ohio Drive, S.W.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>East along the south curb of Independence Avenue, S.W., to the southwest curb of Canal Street, S.W.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>Southeast along the southwest curb of Canal Street, S.W., to the south curb of E Street, S.E.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(p)</num>
      <text>East along the south curb of E Street, S.W., to the west curb of Second Street, S.E.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(q)</num>
      <text>Then back to the point of beginning.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Inaugural Committee &amp;#8211; shall have the meaning ascribed to it by §1 of the Presidential Inaugural Ceremonies Act, approved August 6, 1956 (70 Stat. 1049; D.C. Code §§1-1801 et. seq.).</text>
    <text>Inaugural Period &amp;#8211; shall have the meaning ascribed to it by §1 of the Presidential Inaugural Ceremonies Act, approved August 6, 1956 (70 Stat. 1049; D.C. Code §§1-1801 et seq.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 2 off the Presidential Inauguration Special Regulations and Rule of Interpretation Concerning Nonrevival of Statutes Act of 1982, D.C. Law 4-125, 29 DCR 2093 (May 21, 1982).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>