<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-825</num>
  <heading>CONCESSION STANDS[COLON] GENERAL REQUIREMENTS (§ 24-825)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>825.1.</num>
    <text>The provisions of §§825 through 830 shall apply during the inaugural period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>825.2.</num>
    <text>No person shall set up any stand or booth to sell, offer for sale, or distribute any fruit, food, lunches, candy, tobacco, drinks, or similar items on any street, avenue, alley, or public reservation at any point between the established building lines,
      without first having the operation and location of the stand or booth approved by the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Concessions Committee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Chief of Police;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Fire Chief;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Director of Environmental Services; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The D.C. Department of Public Works.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>825.3.</num>
    <text>The approval of the Secretary of the Interior, or his or her designated representative, shall be required in the case of sites on Federal reservations or grounds under the Secretary&amp;#8217;s jurisdiction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>825.4.</num>
    <text>Approval of the Concessions Committee shall be conditioned upon the agreement of the licensee to comply with the requirements for the construction, operation, and sanitation of food concession stands as are required by this chapter and other District
      regulations, and any other conditions the Concessions Committee may require.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>825.5.</num>
    <text>After a concessions stand or booth has been approved, a card or placard issued by the Director of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs shall be attached to it indicating that the location and operation of the stand or booth have been approved.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>825.6.</num>
    <text>Whenever the Director of Environmental Services has reason to believe that any food vendor, or the operation of any food stand or mobile food dispensing unit, creates an imminent danger to public health, the Director shall be authorized to require
      the food vendor, or the operator of the food stand or mobile food dispensing unit, to cease operating until the condition creating the imminent danger to public health is corrected to Director&amp;#8217;s satisfaction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>825.7.</num>
    <text>Concession stands shall be removed not later than forty-eight (48) hours after Inauguration Day.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>825.8.</num>
    <text>All other stands, booths, and temporary structures shall be removed by the date set by Inaugural Committee or Concessions Committee contracts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>825.9.</num>
    <text>If the person responsible for the erection of any stand, booth, or temporary structure has failed to remove the structure within the time specified by this section, the cost of removal, whether removal is by or under the authority of the Inaugural
      Committee or the District, shall be at the person&amp;#8217;s expense.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Sections 20(a), (q) &amp;#038; (r) of the Presidential Inauguration Special Regulations and Rule of Interpretation Concerning Nonrevival of Statutes Act of 1982, D.C. Law 4-125, 29 DCR 2093 (May 21, 1982).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>