<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-803</num>
  <heading>SPECIAL TRAFFIC REGULATIONS (§ 24-803)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>803.1.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section shall apply during the inaugural period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.2.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in §803.3, the Inaugural Area is declared a congested area; and no parking shall be permitted in the Inaugural Area on Inauguration Day, or until the signs prohibiting parking are removed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.3.</num>
    <text>The provisions of §803.2 shall not be applicable to the United States Capitol grounds, or to the streets and roadways on the Capitol grounds; except as specifically agreed to by the Joint Congressional Committee on Inaugural Ceremonies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.4.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in §803.5, within the Inaugural Area and on the highways designated in this chapter, no vehicle shall be parked or left standing except when actually taking on or discharging passengers; or, in the case of commercial vehicles, while
      actually loading or unloading merchandise. Commercial vehicles, when engaged in loading or unloading merchandise, shall stop or stand in a position parallel with the curb.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.5.</num>
    <text>The provisions of §803.4 shall not apply to taxicabs or sight-seeing vehicles that may occupy the stands established in the Inaugural Area for a period of five (5) days, including Inauguration Day. The provisions of §803.4 also shall not apply to
      any special stands as may be established within the Inaugural Area, except where the occupying of these stands will interfere with the formation or passage of any scheduled parade or ceremony, or with the free movement of traffic.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.6.</num>
    <text>The Chief of Police may temporarily close the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The streets and avenues included in the route of any parade;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The streets used for ceremony or for an unusual gathering of people in connection with any official inaugural activity; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any intersecting streets, avenues, alleyways, and abutting reservations that may be designated by the Chief of Police.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.7.</num>
    <text>The closing of streets shall be for that period of time the Chief of Police may deem necessary for the public&amp;#8217;s interest.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.8.</num>
    <text>If, during the period from three (3) days prior to and including Inauguration Day, it becomes necessary for the Director of Public Works to declare no parking on streets designated as snow emergency routes in compliance with 18 DCMR §2417, parking
      shall be prohibited on the following streets:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Both sides of C Street, S.E., from New Jersey Avenue to Third Street;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Both sides of E Street, S.E., from South Capitol Street to Third Street;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Both sides of F Street, N.W., from Twenty-first Street to Twenty-third Street;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Both sides of G Street, N.W., from Twenty-first Street to Twenty-third Street; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Both sides of H Street, N.W., from Twenty-first Street to Twenty-third Street.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.9.</num>
    <text>The Chief of Police may suspend or reroute the movement of all pedestrian and vehicular traffic; including, with the approval of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority, the operation of buses on any street, avenue, or highway in the District.
      The Chief of Police may also divert traffic in the manner and direction the Chief deems is in the public&amp;#8217;s interest.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 4, 27-29 of the Presidential Inauguration Special Regulations and Rule of Interpretation Concerning Nonrevival of Statutes Act of 1982, D.C. Law 4-125, 29 DCR 2093 (May 21, 1982).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>