<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-1605</num>
  <heading>BUILDINGS, STRUCTURES, AND USES ON SOUTH CAPITOL STREET (CG) (ยง 11-1605)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1605.1.</num>
    <text>The following provisions apply to new buildings, structures, or uses with frontage on South Capitol Street within the CG Overlay.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1605.2.</num>
    <text>Each new building or structure located on South Capitol Street shall be set back for its entire height and frontage not less than 15 feet, with the exception of a:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Buildings within Squares 649 and 651; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Replacement of an existing row dwelling within Squares 653 and 655; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Vertical addition to an existing row dwelling within Squares 653 and 655, not extending out into the South Capitol Street right-of-way and not exceeding 50% of the gross floor area of the original row dwelling.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1605.3.</num>
    <text>Any portion of a building or structure that exceeds 110 feet in height shall provide an additional one-to-one (1:1) step-back from the building line along South Capitol Street.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1605.4.</num>
    <text>No private driveway may be constructed or used from South Capitol Street to any parking or loading berth areas in or adjacent to a building or structure constructed after February 16, 2007.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1605.5.</num>
    <text>For each new building or structure located on South Capitol Street, a minimum of 60% of the street-wall shall be constructed on the setback line, with the exception of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Buildings within Squares 649 and 651 where a minimum of 60% of the street-wall shall be constructed to the South Capitol Street property line; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Replacement of or an addition to an existing row dwelling within Squares 653 or 655 in accordance with ยง 1605.2.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 1587-1592 (February 16, 2007); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 10292 (October 26, 2007); as corrected by Errata Notice published at 58 DCR 4314, 4315 (May 20, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>