<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-5001</num>
  <heading>DUTIES OF THE CHIEF MEDICAL EXAMINER&amp;#8217;S OFFICE (§ 28-5001)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5001.1.</num>
    <text>The CME and such other medical examiners as may be appointed, may administer oaths and affirmations and take affidavits in connection with the performance of their duties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5001.2.</num>
    <text>The CME, other medical examiners, and such other medical examiners as may be appointed, medicolegal investigators and toxicologists as he or she may appoint, may be authorized by the CME to teach medical and law school classes, to conduct special
      classes for law enforcement personnel and to engage in other activities related to their work.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5001.3.</num>
    <text>The CME and other medical examiners are authorized to determine with reasonable medical certainty the cause and the circumstances surrounding each death required to be investigated. To protect the integrity and autonomy of these death investigations,
      the following shall apply:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Neither the CME nor his/her agents or designees shall accept any money or other compensation, or benefit, either directly or indirectly, that could appear to create a potential conflict or influence over the death investigation.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Unless the Medical Examiner deems it necessary to determine the cause and manner of death, he/she shall not participate in any organ harvest procedure.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The physician performing an organ harvest shall immediately stop the procedure and notify the Medical Examiner if any unforeseen injury/trauma is discovered during the procedure.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The physician performing an organ harvest as described in paragraph (b), above, is required to provide a detailed description of the procedure in the Medical Examiner’s format to the Medical Examiner in accordance with D.C. Official Code § 5-1406(b).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5001.4.</num>
    <text>The Chief Medical Examiner shall investigate those types of death s enumerated in D.C. Official Code § 5-1405(b)(2001), which includes the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>All known or suspected unnatural deaths;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>All deaths occurring without medical attention within a period of ten (10) days prior to death;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>All deaths occurring within twenty four (24) hours of hospital admission.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 8922 (October 7, 2005), and as amended by NOTICE OF EMERGENCY AND PROPOSED RULEMAKING at 54 DCR 8843 (September 7, 2007) [EXPIRED].</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>