<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-1702</num>
  <heading>SLATE FORMATION (§ 3-1702)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1702.1.</num>
    <text>A slate of candidates, which wishes to be recognized as a slate, may be formed in the following instances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Where two (2) or more individual candidates have qualified by filing separate nominating petitions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Where a group of candidates have qualified by filing a single nominating petition; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Where a combination of individual candidates or groups of candidates have qualified by filing separate nominating petitions.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1702.2.</num>
    <text>The members of a slate shall file with the Board a &amp;#8220;Statement of Slate Registration,&amp;#8221; on a form provided by the Board, no later than 4:45 p.m. on the third (3rd) day after the deadline for filing petitions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1702.3.</num>
    <text>The &amp;#8220;Statement of Slate Registration&amp;#8221; shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name, address, telephone number and signature of the individual who is authorized to represent the slated candidates in matters before the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A complete listing of the candidates who are members of the slate and the office to which each seeks election;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A statement that each candidate gives his or her permission to be identified as a member of the slate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The slate name, which shall be sufficiently concise to permit the Board to print the name on the ballot on the same line with each candidate’s name; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The signatures and printed name of each of the candidates who are members of the slate; provided, that where candidates have qualified as a group, using a single nominating petition, all candidates listed on the petition must be signatories.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1702.4.</num>
    <text>Additions to slate composition or changes of slate names may be filed with the Board by the authorized representative as amendments to the original &amp;#8220;Statement of Slate Registration.&amp;#8221;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1702.5.</num>
    <text>Amendments to the original &amp;#8220;Statement of Slate Registration,&amp;#8221; shall be filed with the Board by the authorized representative and shall be on a form, provided by the Board, which shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The requested amendment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The signature of the slate’s authorized representative; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The signature(s) of any additional slate candidate(s), if applicable.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1702.6.</num>
    <text>Any candidate or a group of candidates that qualified for the ballot by filing a single nominating petition, may withdraw from a registered slate by filing with the Board a &amp;#8220;Statement of Slate Withdrawal.&amp;#8221;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1702.7.</num>
    <text>The &amp;#8220;Statement of Slate Withdrawal&amp;#8221; shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A statement that the individual candidate or group of candidates irrevocably withdraws from the slate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The signatures of each affected candidate; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The signatures of all candidates listed on the petition; provided, that the candidate(s) seeking withdrawal qualified by using a single nominating petition.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1702.8.</num>
    <text>Slated candidates shall not be disqualified from the ballot for any of the following reasons:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Where a candidate has withdrawn from a slate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Where a candidate has withdrawn from the ballot; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Where any candidate or a group of candidates, have been determined, by the Executive Director or his or her designee, to be ineligible to qualify as part of a slate.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1702.9.</num>
    <text>Amendments and statements of slate withdrawals shall be filed with the Board no later than 4:45 p.m. on the third (3rd) day after the deadline for filing nominating petitions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1702.10.</num>
    <text>Slated candidates may be voted upon as a slate or as individual candidates within each election contest.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 D.C. Reg. 2006, 2022-24 (March 11, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>