<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2601</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 11-2601)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2601.1.</num>
    <text>When used in the Chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Achievable bonus density &amp;#8211; The amount of the bonus density permitted under § 2604 that potentially may be utilized within a particular inclusionary development, notwithstanding constraints resulting from the physical characteristics of the
      land or restrictions imposed by District or federal laws and agencies.</text>
    <text>The Act &amp;#8211; the Inclusionary Zoning Implementation Amendment Act of 2006, effective Mar. 14, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-275; 54 DCR 880). References to the Act include any Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order, agency rule, or other administrative issuance promulgated
      pursuant to that legislation.</text>
    <text>Development, inclusionary &amp;#8211; a development subject to the provisions of this Chapter pursuant to § 2602.1.</text>
    <text>Development, off-site &amp;#8211; a development that accounts for all or part of an inclusionary development&amp;#8217;s requirements under this Chapter, if approved pursuant to § 2607.</text>
    <text>Eligible household &amp;#8211; one or more persons certified by the Mayor as being a low- or moderate-income household pursuant to the Act.</text>
    <text>Inclusionary unit &amp;#8211; a unit set aside for sale or rental to an eligible low- and moderate-income household as required by this Chapter or by order of the Board of Zoning Adjustment pursuant to § 2607.</text>
    <text>Low-income household &amp;#8211; a household of one or more individuals with a total annual income adjusted for household size equal to less than fifty percent (50%) of the Metropolitan Statistical Area median as certified by the Mayor pursuant to
      the Act.</text>
    <text>Mayor &amp;#8211; the Mayor of the District of Columbia, the Director of the agency or agencies delegated the authority to implement the Act, or the agency official or officials re-delegated such authority.</text>
    <text>Moderate-income household &amp;#8211; a household of one or more individuals with a total annual income adjusted for household size equal to between fifty-one percent (51%) and eighty percent (80%) of the Metropolitan Statistical Area median as certified
      by the Mayor pursuant to the Act.</text>
    <text>Purchase/rental schedule &amp;#8211; the most current schedule, published by the Mayor pursuant to the Act, establishing the maximum purchase prices and rents for inclusionary units.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 7013 (August 25, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 6943 (July 20, 2007); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 2604 (March 14, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>