<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2603</num>
  <heading>SET-ASIDE REQUIREMENTS (§ 11-2603)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2603.1.</num>
    <text>An inclusionary development for which the primary method of construction does not employ steel and concrete frame structure located in an R-2 through an R-5-B District or in a C-1, C-2-A, W-0 or W-1 District shall devote the greater of 10% of the
      gross floor area being devoted to residential use or 75% of the bonus density being utilized for inclusionary units.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2603.2.</num>
    <text>An inclusionary development of steel and concrete frame construction located in the zone districts stated in § 2603.1 or any development located in a C-2-B, C-2-C, C-3, CR, R-5-C, R-5-D, SP, USN, W-2, or W-3 Zone District shall devote the greater
      of eight percent (8%) of the gross floor area being devoted to residential use or fifty percent (50%) of the bonus density utilized for inclusionary units.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2603.3.</num>
    <text>Inclusionary developments located in R-3 through R-5-E, C-1, C-2-A, StE, W-0 and W-1 Districts shall set aside fifty percent (50%) of inclusionary units for eligible low-income households and fifty percent (50%) of inclusionary units for eligible
      moderate-income households. The first inclusionary unit and each additional odd number unit shall be set aside for low-income households.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2603.4.</num>
    <text>Developments located in CR, C-2-B through C-3-C, USN, W-2 through W-3, and SP Zone Districts shall set aside one hundred percent (100%) of inclusionary units for eligible moderate-income households.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2603.5.</num>
    <text>The Mayor or the District of Columbia Housing Authority shall have the right to purchase up to twenty-five percent (25%) of inclusionary units in a for-sale inclusionary development in accordance with such procedures as are set forth in the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2603.6.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding § 2603.5, nothing shall prohibit the Mayor or the District of Columbia Housing Authority to acquire title to inclusionary units in a for-sale inclusionary development if any of the following circumstances exist:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>There is a risk that title to the units will be transferred by foreclosure or deed-in-lieu of foreclosure, or that the units’ mortgages will be assigned to the Secretary of the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Title to the units has been transferred by foreclosure or deed-in-lieu of foreclosure, or the units’ mortgages have been assigned to the Secretary of the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2603.7.</num>
    <text>An inclusionary development of steel and concrete frame construction located in a StE District shall devote no less than eight percent (8%) of the gross floor area being devoted to residential use in a StE District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 7020 (August 25, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 2616 (March 14, 2008); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 4788, 4815 (June 3, 2011); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 60 DCR 4834 (March 29, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 5144 (April 5, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>