<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-1804</num>
  <heading>PERFORMANCE STANDARDS (§ 29-1804)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1804.1.</num>
    <text>The Department shall establish standards for grantees in making determinations of demonstrated performance prior to the award of grants and subgrants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1804.2.</num>
    <text>Determinations of demonstrated performance shall be in writing and take into consideration such matters as whether the applicant has:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Adequate financial resources or the ability to obtain them;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The ability to meet the program design specifications at a reasonable and</text>
    </level>
    <text>competitive cost, as well as the ability to meet performance goals;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A satisfactory record of past performance in the grant or subgrant subject area, including demonstrated quality of service delivery;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Documentation that the grantee has the legal status (i.e. business license, non-profit incorporation, etc.) to conduct business within the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A satisfactory record of integrity, business ethics, and fiscal accountability;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The necessary organization, experience, accounting and operational controls; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The technical skills to perform the work.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1804.3.</num>
    <text>In the alternative, the Department may determine that an applicant has demonstrated performance by an objective review of available documentation at the discretion of the Director. The rationale for any approvals of demonstrated performance by the
      alternative process shall be documented in writing and maintained in the Department’s records in accordance with Section 1815.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 481 (January 24, 1997); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 5614 (April 12, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 15243 (November 1, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>