<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-1803</num>
  <heading>EXCEPTED AWARDS (§ 29-1803)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1803.1.</num>
    <text>The Department may make a grant award on a sole source basis in appropriate circumstances as determined by the Director in his/her sole discretion that include, but are not limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The authorization for the award designates the grantee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The applicable law defines eligibility in such a way that there is only one eligible applicant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>There is a recognized coalition or group of service providers through which the broadest community participation may be obtained in serving the targeted clientele; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>When the services required by the Department are available from only one source and no other type of services will satisfy Department requirements.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1803.2.</num>
    <text>The Department may make a grant award as an earmark if the earmark is clearly authorized by legislation or Agreement that provides the grant funds.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1803.3.</num>
    <text>The Department shall make excepted awards in the same manner as competitive awards except that the Department need not use a review panel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1803.4.</num>
    <text>The Department shall prepare a written “sole source justification” memorandum signed by the Director explaining the circumstances that justified the absence of competition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1803.5.</num>
    <text>The sole source justification memorandum shall be maintained in the Department’s records in accordance with Section 1815.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 481 (January 24, 1997); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 5614 (April 12, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 15243 (November 1, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>