<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-1808</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION REVIEW (§ 29-1808)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1808.1.</num>
    <text>After the NOFA has been published and the RFA released, the Department shall appoint a review panel comprised of a minimum of three individuals.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1808.2.</num>
    <text>Each review panelist shall:</text>
    <text>Have knowledge and expertise in the objectives of the grant, the RFA and the administrative requirements mandated by the source of the funds; and</text>
    <text>Be free of any conflict of interest or the appearance of a conflict of interest as evidenced by a signed affidavit certifying that they have no personal or vested interest in the organizations that submitted applications in response to the RFA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1808.3</num>
    <text>1808.3 Review panelists who are employees of the District government may not be compensated and may only serve if they have written authorization from their supervisors to serve on a review panel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1808.4.</num>
    <text>Review panelists who are not employees of the District government may be compensated for time served on a panel provided that funds have been authorized and appropriated for such purposes, at a rate that obtains the best qualified panelists at one
      of the following rates:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The maximum rate allowable by the federal grantor Department for its own review panelists;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The amount available in the administrative budget of the grant or subgrant; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The maximum daily rate of a current DS-15 pay scale for the Department.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1808.5.</num>
    <text>The Department shall be responsible for the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Ensuring that the review panelists have the information needed to serve on a panel; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Convening a meeting of the panelists prior to the review activities and instructing the panelists on:</text>
    </level>
    <text>The goals and objectives of the grant and the RFA;</text>
    <text>The scoring criteria and instruments; and</text>
    <text>The timeframe for completion of the panel’s work.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1808.6.</num>
    <text>The review panel shall score the applications and make recommendations which applications should be funded based upon the applicant’s demonstrated ability to perform successfully under the terms and conditions of the proposed grant or subgrants. All
      materials received by the Department or a panel member from any applicant shall be protected, treated as confidential, and used only for purposes of evaluating the applicant’s proposal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1808.7</num>
    <text>1808.7 After the Grant Officer has received the evaluations and records of the review panel, the Director or his/her designee shall make final decisions on awards and the amounts of each grant or subgrant, subject to the advice of any advisory body
      required by law or regulation for the funding grant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1808.8.</num>
    <text>If the Director or his/her designee decides not to follow the review panel’s recommendations, the Director or his/her designee shall provide a written justification in the grant records that includes a strong rationale supported by documentation for
      the decision to not follow the review panel’s recommendation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1808.9.</num>
    <text>The Director has the discretion to review any claims against the grant review process but the Director’s decision is final and shall not be appealed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 15243 (November 1, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>