<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-4000</num>
  <heading>CONTRACTING OFFICER RESPONSIBILITIES (ยง 27-4000)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4000.1.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall ensure that the goods, services, or construction procured under each District contract conform to the quality and quantity requirements of the contract, including inspection, acceptance, warranty, and any other measures
      associated with quality assurance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4000.2.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall be responsible for the following;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Ensuring that each contract includes inspection and other quality requirements, including warranty clauses when appropriate, which are necessary to protect the District&amp;#8217;s interest;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Ensuring that contract quality assurance is conducted by the District before acceptance, except as otherwise provided in this chapter, by or under the direction of District personnel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Ensuring that no contract precludes the District from performing inspection;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Ensuring that nonconforming goods, services, or construction are rejected, except as otherwise provided in this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Ensuring that the quality assurance and acceptance services of the using agency are used when this will be effective, economical, or otherwise in the best interests of the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Obtaining any specifications for inspection, testing, and other contract quality requirements essential to ensure the integrity of the goods, services, or construction from the agency responsible for the technical requirements; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Including in solicitations and contracts the necessary requirements for the contractor&amp;#8217;s control of quality for the goods, services, or construction to be procured.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority of this chapter is the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, D.C. Law 6.85, as amended, D.C. Code ยง1-1181.1 et seq. (1981).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1714 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>