<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-4002</num>
  <heading>CONTRACTOR RESPONSIBILITIES (ยง 27-4002)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4002.1.</num>
    <text>The contractor shall be responsible for carrying out its obligations under the contract by doing the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Controlling the quality of goods, services, or construction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Ensuring that vendors or suppliers of raw materials, parts, components, and subassemblies have an acceptance quality control system;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Tendering to the District for acceptance only those goods, services, or construction that conform to contract requirements; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Maintaining substantiating evidence, when required by the contract, that the goods, services, or construction conform to contract quality requirements, and furnishing that information to the District, upon request.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4002.2.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer may require the contractor to provide and maintain an inspection system or program for the control of quality that is acceptable to the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4002.3.</num>
    <text>The control of quality by the contractor may relate to, but is not limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Manufacturing processes, to ensure that the product produced to and meets the contract&amp;#8217;s technical requirements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Drawings, specifications, and engineering changes, to ensure that manufacturing methods and operations meet the contract&amp;#8217;s technical requirements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Testing and examination, to ensure that practices and equipment provide the means for optimum evaluation of the characteristics subject to inspection;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Reliability and maintainability assessment, including life, endurance, and continued readiness;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Fabrication and delivery of products, to ensure that only conforming products are tendered to the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Technical documentation, including drawings, specifications, handbooks, manuals, and other technical publications;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Preservation, packaging, packing, and marking; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Procedures and processes for services and construction to ensure that services and construction meet contract performance requirements.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4002.4.</num>
    <text>The contractor shall be responsible for performing all inspections and tests required by the contract except those specifically reserved for performance by the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1715 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>