<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-4004</num>
  <heading>CONTRACT QUALITY REQUIREMENTS (ยง 27-4004)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4004.1.</num>
    <text>The type and extent of contract quality requirements needed in each solicitation or contract under ยง4000.2(a) shall depend on the particular procurement and may range from inspection at time of acceptance to a requirement for the contractor&amp;#8217;s
      implementation of a comprehensive program for controlling quality.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4004.2.</num>
    <text>A solicitation or contract may provide for alternative, but substantially equivalent, inspection methods to obtain broader competition and reduce costs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4004.3.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer may authorize alternative quality control or inspection methods recommended by the contractor when in the best interests of the District and approved by the agency responsible for the technical requirements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4004.4.</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise specified by the contract, required contractor testing may be performed in the contractor&amp;#8217;s, or a subcontractor&amp;#8217;s, testing facility or in any other testing facility acceptable to the contracting officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4004.5.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in ยง4004.6, when goods, services, or construction are procured by small purchase procedures pursuant to chapter 18 of this title, the District shall rely on the contractor to accomplish all inspection and testing needed to ensure
      compliance with contract quality requirements before the goods, services, or construction are tendered to the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4004.6.</num>
    <text>The District shall not rely on inspection by the contractor if the contracting officer determines that the District has a need to test the goods, services, or construction in advance of their tender for acceptance, or determines that there is a need
      to review the adequacy of the contractor&amp;#8217;s internal work processes. In making the determination, the contracting officer shall consider the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The nature of the goods, services, or construction being procured and their intended use;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The potential losses in the event of defects;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The likelihood of uncontested replacements or correction of defective work; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The cost of a detailed inspection by the District.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4004.7.</num>
    <text>With respect to goods, services or construction other than small purchase procurements, the contracting officer shall include in each solicitation and contract a standard clause, approved by the Director, setting forth inspection guidelines requiring
      the contractor to do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Provide and maintain an inspection system that is acceptable to the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Give the District the right to make inspections and tests while work is in progress; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Keep complete records of its inspection work which are available to the District upon request.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4004.8.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall determine the extent of contract quality requirements, including contractor inspection, required under each contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1717 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>