<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-4010</num>
  <heading>CONTRACT QUALITY ASSURANCE OF SUBCONTRACTS (ยง 27-4010)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4010.1.</num>
    <text>District contract quality assurance on subcontracted goods, services, or construction shall be performed only when required in the best interests of the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4010.2.</num>
    <text>District contract quality assurance on subcontracted goods, services, or construction shall not relieve the prime contractor of any responsibilities under the contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4010.3.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall perform quality assurance at the subcontract level in the following circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The item is to be shipped from the subcontractor&amp;#8217;s plant directly to the District, and inspection at source is required;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The conditions for quality assurance at the source under ยง4007 are applicable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The contract specifies that certain quality assurance functions, which can be performed only at the subcontractor&amp;#8217;s plant, are to be performed by the District; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>It is otherwise required by the contract or determined by the contracting officer to be in the best interests of the District.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4010.4.</num>
    <text>All written statements and contract terms and conditions relating to District quality assurance actions at the subcontract level shall be worded so as not to do any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Affect the contractual relationship between the prime contractor and the District, or between the prime contractor and the subcontractor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Establish a contractual relationship between the District and the subcontractor; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Constitute a waiver of the District&amp;#8217;s right to accept or reject the goods, services, or construction.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1720 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>