<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-4001</num>
  <heading>CONTRACT ADMINISTRATOR RESPONSIBILITIES (ยง 27-4001)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4001.1.</num>
    <text>The using agency, or the individual(s) responsible for contract administration in the case of a term contract, shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Develop and apply efficient procedures for performing District contract quality assurance actions under the contract in accordance with the written directions of the contracting officer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Perform all actions necessary to verify whether the goods, services, or construction conform to contract quality requirements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Implement any specific written instructions from the contracting officer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Report to the contracting officer any defects observed in design or technical requirements, including contract quality requirements; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Recommend any changes necessary to the contract, specifications, instructions, or other requirements that will provide more effective operations or eliminate unnecessary costs.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4001.2.</num>
    <text>The using agency shall maintain, as part of the performance records of the contract, suitable records reflecting the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Contract quality assurance actions, including, when appropriate, the number of observations made and the number and type of defects; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Decisions regarding the acceptability of the products as well as actions to correct defects.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1715 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>