<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-3203</num>
  <heading>USES OF PAID LEAVE (§ 7-3203)
    <text>An employee may use paid leave for the following reasons:</text>
    <text>An absence resulting from a physical or mental illness, injury, or medicalondition of the employee;</text>
    <text>An absence resulting from obtaining professional medical diagnosis or care orreventive medical care for the employee; or</text>
    <text>An absence for the purpose of caring for a family member who has any of theonditions or needs for diagnosis or care described in paragraphs (a) and (b) ofhis subsection.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <num>3203.2</num>
    <text>3203.2 An employee may also use paid leave for an absence if the employee orhe employee’s family member is a victim of stalking, domestic violence, orexual abuse and the absence is directly related to medical, social, or legalervices pertaining to
      the stalking, domestic violence, or sexual abuse for theurposes of:</text>
    <text>Seeking medical attention for the employee or the employee’s family member toreat or recover from physical or psychological injury or disability caused byhe stalking, domestic violence, or sexual abuse;</text>
    <text>Obtaining services for the employee or the employee’s family member from aictim services organization;</text>
    <text>Obtaining psychological or other counseling services for the employee or themployee’s family member;</text>
    <text>The temporary or permanent relocation of the employee or the employee’s familyember;</text>
    <text>Taking legal action, including preparing for or participating in any criminal orivil proceeding related to or resulting from the stalking, domestic violence,r sexual abuse; or</text>
    <text>Taking other actions that could be reasonably determined to enhance thehysical, psychological, or economic health or safety of the employee or themployee’s family member or the safety of those who work or associate with themployee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 5231, 5232 (June 18, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>