<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-3216</num>
  <heading>COMPLAINT RESOLUTION (§ 7-3216)
    <text>A person who believes that any of the rights created by the Act has beenmproperly denied him or her may file a complaint with the Department ofmployment Services in the form and manner prescribed by the Director of theepartment. Complaints shall be
      filed within sixty (60) days after the event onhich the complaint is based; provided that no sixty (60) day period shallommence until the employer has posted the notice required by section 10 of thect and § 3213 of this Chapter</text>
    <text>The Director shall review all complaints and shall investigate those complaintshich the Director determines require investigation.</text>
    <text>Complaints shall be investigated and resolved in an expeditious manneronsistent with the nature of the complaint. The Director shall make alleasonable efforts to resolve all complaints within forty-five (45) businessays of their filing and shall notify
      all parties if that time period cannot beet and shall make a good faith estimate of the expected resolution date.</text>
    <text>In the course of investigating, resolving and deciding complaints, the Directorhall have the authority to:</text>
    <text>Investigate and ascertain the length of service, hiring dates, paid leave usageequests, certifications provided by employees, and any other issue relating tohe rights created by the Act;</text>
    <text>Require sworn written statements from employers and employees concerning thessues raised by the complaint; and</text>
    <text>Conduct informal investigations, examinations, or meetings at which employersnd employees appear, give sworn statements, and answer questions from theirector or the adverse party.</text>
    <text>Following an investigation, the Director shall issue a decision concerning theomplaint. Copies of the decision shall be served on each party at their lastnown address.</text>
    <text>A party aggrieved by the Director’s decision may appeal the decision asrovided in the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approvedctober 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 et seq.).</text>
    <text>Complaints shall be investigated and resolved in an expeditious manneronsistent with the nature of the complaint.</text>
    <text>The employer shall maintain records of the accrual, granting and denial of leaveursuant to the Act for a period of three years as generally provided in 7 DCMR 911.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 5231, 5238 (June 18, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>