<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-405</num>
  <heading>MINUTES AND TRANSCRIPTS (§ 3-405)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>405.1.</num>
    <text>The minutes of Board meetings and hearings are a matter of public record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.2.</num>
    <text>The minutes of Board meetings shall include the vote of each member on each complaint, petition or procedural matter, and any ruling of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.3.</num>
    <text>The hearing shall be reported under the supervision of the Chairperson, stenographically or by other means, by an official reporter who may be designated from time-to-time by the Board or who may be a regular employee of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.4.</num>
    <text>The transcript, as prepared under § 405.3, shall be the sole official transcript of the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.5.</num>
    <text>The transcript shall be open for inspection at the Office of the General Counsel and the minutes available on the Board’s website.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.6.</num>
    <text>Copies of the official transcript shall be available to parties and to the public upon payment to the Board of the charges fixed for the copies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.7.</num>
    <text>Changes in the official transcript may be made only when they involve errors affecting substance and upon the filing of a motion to correct a transcript with the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.8.</num>
    <text>Copies of the motion to correct a transcript shall be served simultaneously on all opposing parties or legal representatives.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.9.</num>
    <text>Objections to the motion to correct a transcript shall be filed with the Board within five (5) days and served upon the parties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.10.</num>
    <text>The transcript may be changed by the Board at a public meeting to reflect any corrections.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 D.C. Reg. 432, 436-37 (January 23, 1998); and as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 D.C. Reg. 4738 (June 19, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>