<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6205</num>
  <heading>DISTRICT EXAMINATION (§ 17-6205)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6205.1.</num>
    <text>To qualify for licensure, an applicant shall receive a passing score of seventy-five percent (75%) on the written examination developed by the Board on laws and rules pertaining to the practice of nursing home administration (the District examination)
      and shall sit for an interview with the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6205.2.</num>
    <text>The Board shall administer the District examination and conduct interviews at least once every quarter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6205.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall not be eligible to take the District examination or sit for an interview until all other requirements for a license are met.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6205.4.</num>
    <text>The District examination may include, but is not limited, to, questions on the following subjects:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Grounds for disciplinary action set forth in § 514 of the Act, (D.C. Official Code § 3-1205.14) (2001);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Health-Care and Community Residence Facility, Hospice and Home Care Licensure Act of 1983 (D.C. Official Code § 44-501 et seq.) (2001); the District of Columbia Long Term Care Ombudsman Program Act of 1988 (D.C. Official Code § 7-701.01 et seq.)
        (2001); rules promulgated pursuant to the Act; rules governing nursing facilities care in the District of Columbia as set forth in 17 DCMR chapters 19, 23, 30, 31, and 62, and, 22 DCMR chapter 32; and the District of Columbia Health Occupations
        Revision Act of 1985 (D.C. Official Code § 3-1201.01 et seq.) (2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6205.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant who fails the District examination on three (3) consecutive attempts shall not be permitted to retake the examination for six (6) months following the third failure. Thereafter, the applicant shall not be permitted to retake the District
      examination for one (1) year after each failure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6205.6.</num>
    <text>The interview may include oral questions from Board members regarding the applicant&amp;#8217;s past and present experience relating to the practice of nursing home administration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6205.7.</num>
    <text>The Board shall not deny an applicant a license on the basis of an interview unless statements by the applicant at the interview indicate that the applicant has violated or does not qualify under the Act or this subtitle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3774, 3780 (May 20, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 10626 (November 19, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>