<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-908</num>
  <heading>DISPOSAL OF HUMAN EXCRETA (§ 21-908)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>908.1.</num>
    <text>All human excreta or body wastes removed from any privy or outhouses shall be handled, transported, stored, and disposed of by an authorized scavenger or by the District government.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>908.2.</num>
    <text>Authorization can be obtained by making application in writing to the Director and demonstrating an ability to perform the work in accordance with the requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>908.3.</num>
    <text>The handling, transportation, storage and disposal of all human excreta or body wastes removed from any privy or outhouse shall be carried out in a sanitary manner which does not endanger the public health or otherwise create a nuisance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>908.4.</num>
    <text>The contents of privies or outhouses must be quickly and skillfully transferred by means of portable fly-tight containers or suitable suction pumps and hose to a transportation container on the scavenger vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>908.5.</num>
    <text>The transportation container shall be tightly closed, and shall be made absolutely fly-tight immediately after the contents of the privy have been transferred. If portable containers are used, they shall be kept absolutely fly-tight during the process
      of transportation from the privy or outhouse to the scavenger vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>908.6.</num>
    <text>If suction pumps and hose are used, they shall be handled to prevent flies from coming in contact with any soiled portions or parts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>908.7.</num>
    <text>Transportation containers on scavenger vehicles shall be capable of being made fly-tight during the process of transportation to the disposal site.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>908.8.</num>
    <text>All vehicles used for the collection and transportation of human excreta or body wastes shall be so constructed as to carry the fly- tight transportation container as well as any portable containers, pumps, hose, tools, implements or apparatus used,
      entirely within a covered and fly-tight enclosure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>908.9.</num>
    <text>Any human excreta of body waste dropped or spilled in the process of collection or transportation shall be carefully taken up and the place or places where the material was dropped or spilled shall be well cleaned and disinfected.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>908.10.</num>
    <text>All human excreta or body wastes shall be transported and discharged into the sewerage system by the contractor at a point designated by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>908.11.</num>
    <text>All vehicles, tools and equipment used shall be kept in a clean and sanitary condition at all times.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>908.12.</num>
    <text>At the end of each day&amp;#8217;s work, all portable containers transportation containers, suction pumps and hose and other tools must be carefully washed and disinfected, and shall not again be used until in a clean and sanitary condition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order No. 300 417/2, dated August 3, 1944, 8 DCRR §§C-370, C-3310 through C-3313, Health Regulations Supplement.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>