<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-907</num>
  <heading>MAINTENANCE OF DISPOSAL SYSTEMS (§ 21-907)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>907.1.</num>
    <text>Each method for the reception, disposition, or storage, either temporarily or permanently, of human excreta or body wastes which is not connected with a sewerage system or with a properly installed and operated sewage disposal system shall be maintained
      in accordance with this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>907.2.</num>
    <text>When a person discontinues the use of an earth-pit privy according to §7(g) of the Wastewater System Regulation Amendment Act of 1985 and according to §902.1, the mound around the existing pit shall be leveled and the pit contents shall be buried
      with an earth covering of at least twelve inches (12 in.) in thickness.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>907.3.</num>
    <text>For the elimination of a privy which the Wastewater System Regulation Amendment Act of 1985 or §902.1 outlaws, the removal of the privy, the disposal of the excreta, and the filling of the pit shall be done without overflowing and without creating
      an unsanitary condition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>907.4.</num>
    <text>For other privies or outhouses, the receptacle containing the excreta shall be emptied at sufficiently frequent intervals to prevent overflowing or the creation of an unsanitary condition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>907.5.</num>
    <text>The receptacle shall be maintained in good repair to prevent leakage of the contents to the surrounding ground or onto floor or other portion of the privy structure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>907.6.</num>
    <text>When an earth-pit privy must be moved, in compliance with §907.2, the floor and building may be moved to the new location. The mound around the existing pit shall be leveled and the pit contents buried with an earth covering of at least twelve inches
      (12 in.) in thickness.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>907.7.</num>
    <text>In the case of other types of privies or outhouses, the receptacle shall be emptied at sufficiently frequent intervals to prevent overflowing or creation of an insanitary condition. The receptacle shall be maintained in good repair to prevent leakage
      of the contents to the surrounding ground or onto the floor or other portions of the privy structure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>907.8.</num>
    <text>The seat, floor, and ground immediately surrounding a privy or outhouse shall be kept clean at all times. A vent, if installed, shall be maintained in good repair and free from obstructions at all times.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>907.9.</num>
    <text>Seat covers shall be kept closed when the facility is not in use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>907.10.</num>
    <text>Bottles, broken glass, tin cans, brick bats, sticks, garbage, ashes, dirt, water, and other similar kinds of waste or liquids shall not be deposited in box or can privies or other outhouses where scavenger service is to be furnished by the District
      of Columbia. Bottles, broken glass, tin cans, brick bats, sticks, garbage, ashes, dirt, water and other similar kinds of waste or liquids should not be thrown into earth-pits or tanks.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>907.11.</num>
    <text>Chemical closets shall be maintained at sufficient caustic concentrations that septic action does not begin.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>907.12.</num>
    <text>Disinfectants, lime, deodorants, or other chemicals shall not be used in earth-pits, septic tank privies or septic toilets. Types of paper which do not readily disintegrate should be avoided.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>907.13.</num>
    <text>Enough water shall be added to the septic tank privy or septic toilet each day to keep the water up to the level of the overflow. The water added should also be used to keep the drop tube clean.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>907.14.</num>
    <text>Privies, outhouses, or other methods or systems for the storing or disposal of human excreta or body wastes shall be free from rodents and rodent harborages.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order No. 300,417/2, dated August 3, 1944, 8 DCRR §§C-360, C-3610 through C-3616, Health Regulations Supplement:</heading>
      <text>as amended by §17(f) of the Wastewater System Regulation Amendment Act of 1985. D.C Law 6-95, 33 DCR 577, 594 (January 31, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>