<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-1514</num>
  <heading>ORDER OF BUSINESS FOR REGULAR MEETINGS (§ 7-1514)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1514.1.</num>
    <text>The Board shall be called to order at the time and place designated pursuant to § 1509.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1514.2.</num>
    <text>The Chairman shall ascertain the presence of a quorum before any business is transacted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1514.3.</num>
    <text>The Board shall take up business, after a quorum is ascertained, in the following order:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Approval of the minutes of the previous meeting;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Approval of the Consent Agenda without objection by another member;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Chairman&amp;#8217;s Comments;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Report of the Executive Director;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Reports of Standing Committees;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Reports of Special Committees;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Final vote on rules that have been pending at least thirty (30) days since the publication of Notice of Proposed, Final, and/or Emergency Rulemaking in the District of Columbia Register pursuant to D.C. Code §2-205(a) (2001);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Official communications received from other governmental agencies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Other business previously placed on the agenda; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Other business not previously placed on the agenda.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1514.4.</num>
    <text>Items listed in §1514.3 which require Board action or approval cannot be acted upon in the absence of a quorum. The Board may, at the beginning of a meeting, set a different order for a particular meeting, in which case the order set by the Board
      shall be followed for that meeting, subject to the provisions of §1516.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 10803, 10804 (November 29, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>