<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-714</num>
  <heading>SPECIAL ADMISSION REQUIREMENTS FOR MENTALLY RETARDED PERSONS (ยง 29-714)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>714.1.</num>
    <text>Prior to the admission of a person who is at least moderately retarded to any day treatment program, the interdisciplinary team for the program shall review the individual&amp;#8217;s IHP to determine if the program can provide the services required.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>714.2.</num>
    <text>If a current IHP is not available for review, the program shall refer the individual to an outside vendor for development of an IHP and may accept the individual into the day program for a period of time not to exceed sixty (60) days without a current
      IHP.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>714.3.</num>
    <text>For persons not at least moderately mentally retarded, an interdisciplinary team shall carefully assess the physician&amp;#8217;s documentation and information obtained from other sources including the individual and the individual&amp;#8217;s family
      to determine if the individual can benefit from the day treatment program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>714.4.</num>
    <text>A pre-admission interview shall be held with the individual, his or her family, and members of the program staff&amp;#8217;s interdisciplinary team to review either the client&amp;#8217;s IHP or other information regarding the client&amp;#8217;s needs,
      and to discuss services available to meet those needs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>714.5.</num>
    <text>If the individual is being scheduled for development of an IHP, the placement in the day program shall again be reviewed at the IHP meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>714.6.</num>
    <text>Upon determination that the day program can meet the client&amp;#8217;s needs, the individual shall be admitted to the program for an eight (8) week trial period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>714.7.</num>
    <text>Placement shall again be reviewed with the participant, family, and other appropriate individuals and members of an interdisciplinary team six (6) weeks after the client begins the program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 326 (January 27, 1984).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>