<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-717</num>
  <heading>RECORD KEEPING AND REPORTING (ยง 29-717)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>717.1.</num>
    <text>Patient/client records shall contain the following identifying information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Name, address, telephone number, sex, age, and ethnic background;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name and telephone number of the person to be notified in case of emergency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Next of kin;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Travel directions between home and facility, when indicated; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Identifying numbers related to health care benefits;</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>717.2.</num>
    <text>Patient/client records shall contain functional assessments, including an original and revised version indicating the participant&amp;#8217;s progress.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>717.3.</num>
    <text>Patient/client records shall contain an assessment of the participant&amp;#8217;s home environment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>717.4.</num>
    <text>Patient/client records shall include the individual plan of care for each participant, which shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The physician&amp;#8217;s report, including medical (or psychiatric, when indicated) status evaluation and subsequent pertinent additional information;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Medications prescribed and any drug reactions; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Types of services participant is receiving, how often, who is providing them, and physician&amp;#8217;s approval, signature, and date.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>717.5.</num>
    <text>All records shall be maintained so that they are accessible only to the Director, staff, and to the funding and monitoring agencies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>717.6.</num>
    <text>The program staff shall not discuss or reveal the contents of any client&amp;#8217;s record without the client&amp;#8217;s written permission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>717.7.</num>
    <text>Individual personnel records shall be maintained on all program staff and consultants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>717.8.</num>
    <text>Individual personnel records shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Name, address, telephone number, age, and sex;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Educational background;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Employment history and notes on references;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Evaluation of performance and attendance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Certification that the staff member is free of tuberculosis in a communicable stage;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The names and means of contacting persons to be notified in case of emergency; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Copies of formalized agreements with consultants identifying services to be provided.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>717.9.</num>
    <text>Program administrative and fiscal records shall include at least the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Expenditures with supporting documentation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The fee schedule and fee charges;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Current and projected budgets, including specific cost allocations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The annual program evaluation report with supporting statistics;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>In-service programs offered;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Current health and fire safety inspection reports;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The daily menus of meals for a thirty (30) day period;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The daily schedule of activities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Attendance reports;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Audit reports;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>The number of individuals waiting for admission to the program; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>The source of gross monthly program income.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>717.10.</num>
    <text>The Program Director shall notify the Office of Health Care Financing immediately, in writing, in the following situations:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Fire, accident, injury, or evidence of serious communicable disease contracted by staff or participants;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Changes in professional staff;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The intention to relocate the program site before relocation takes place;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The death of a participant at, en route to, or en route from the program site; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>At least sixty (60) days in advance of planned action, notice of the provider&amp;#8217;s intention to withdraw from the Medicaid Program.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 326 (January 27, 1984).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>