<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-705</num>
  <heading>SOCIAL WORKERS, THERAPISTS, AND OTHER STAFF (§ 29-705)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>705.1.</num>
    <text>A social worker shall coordinate and provide individual, group, and family counseling.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.2.</num>
    <text>In specialized day treatment programs, the social worker shall have had at least one (1) year of experience in working with the speciality services being provided or specialized training.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.3.</num>
    <text>The Department of Human Services may waive the experience requirement set forth in §705.2 for exceptionally qualified individuals for the specialized day care programs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.4.</num>
    <text>The social worker shall also be responsible for the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Entering monthly notes in each participant&amp;#8217;s record;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Supporting participants and their families and informing them of available community services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Referring participants, as necessary, to agencies providing community services; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Assisting, as necessary, in the delivery of other required program services, including meeting the psycho-social needs of participants.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.5.</num>
    <text>A program aide shall have a minimum of one (1) or more years of experience working with adults or the elderly in a health or social service setting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.6.</num>
    <text>In specialized day treatment programs, the program aide shall have a minimum of one (1) or more years of experience in working with developmentally disabled persons or persons with mental disorders.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.7.</num>
    <text>The Department of Human Services may waive the experience requirements set forth in §§705.5 and 705.6 for exceptionally qualified individuals.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.8.</num>
    <text>If offered, physical therapy services shall be performed by or under the supervision of a licensed physical therapist.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.9.</num>
    <text>Physical therapy services shall be directly related to a physician&amp;#8217;s written plan of care that specifies the part or parts of the body to be treated, type of modalities or treatments to be rendered, expected results of physical therapy treatment,
      and the frequency and duration of treatment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.10.</num>
    <text>If offered, occupational therapy services shall be performed by or under the supervision of a licensed occupational therapist.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.11.</num>
    <text>Occupational therapy services shall be directly related to a physician&amp;#8217;s written plan of care that specifies frequency and duration of treatment, and expected results.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.12.</num>
    <text>If offered, speech therapy services shall be provided by a qualified speech therapist who is certified by the American Speech and Hearing Association or by an aide under the supervision of a speech therapist certified by that association.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.13.</num>
    <text>Speech therapy services shall be directly related to a physician&amp;#8217;s written plan of care that specifies frequency and duration of treatment and expected results.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.14.</num>
    <text>Each therapy consultant shall confer at least one (1) hour per month with program staff members to develop or improve therapeutic programming or to provide group therapy education classes for participants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.15.</num>
    <text>Therapy emphasis shall be placed on those activities that will enhance the habilitative process and supportive services that will assist participants to remain in or move toward a least restrictive environment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 326 (January 27, 1984).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>