<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1514</num>
  <heading>ENFORCEMENT PROCEDURES (ยง 21-1514)
    <text>Any notice, order, pleading, or other document produced by a party, includingASA, in response to an enforcement action brought pursuant to section 8 of theastewater System Regulation Act of 1985 (D.C. Law 6-95; D.C. Official Code ยง-105.07 (2008 Repl.
      &amp;#038; 2011 Supp.)), shall be served on all of the otherarty(s) to the action, by hand delivery or by first class mail to the addressf record of each party.</text>
    <text>The address of record for:</text>
    <text>Any party who has applied for, or been issued, a wastewater discharge permitursuant to the Wastewater System Regulation Act, shall be the address specifiedn the permit application, unless that party provides written notice to WASA ando the other party(s)
      to the action that a different address should be used;</text>
    <text>WASA shall be, Office of the General Manager &amp;#8211; Administrative Enforcementroceedings, D.C. Water and Sewer Authority, 5000 Overlook Ave, SW, Washington,.C. 20032; and</text>
    <text>Any other party shall be the last known address of that party, unless that partyrovides written notice to WASA and any other party to the action that aifferent address should be used.</text>
    <text>Service upon a party, or an attorney representing a party, shall occur at theime of hand delivery; or, if service is done by mail, by the date of theostmark on the envelope in which the document was sent, plus three (3) businessays.</text>
    <text>An answer to a Notice of Infraction and Proposed Order, shall be served on WASA,nd any other party to the action, within thirty (30) days after the date ofervice of the Notice of Infraction and Proposed Order.</text>
    <text>A response to any motion filed in an action shall be served on all the partiesithin thirty (30) days after the date of service of the motion or otherleading.</text>
    <text>The hearing examiner may extend the thirty (30) day deadline imposed by thisection upon a showing of good cause by the party seeking the extension.</text>
    <text>Unless otherwise directed by the hearing examiner, all requests to the hearingxaminer for an order or other relief, except for the Proposed Orderccompanying WASA&amp;#8217;s Notice of Infraction, shall be made by motion, inriting, except that motions
      made during a hearing may be made orally.</text>
    <text>The hearing examiner may decide a motion with or without a hearing.</text>
    <text>If a moving party fails to appear at a hearing on its motion, the hearingxaminer may treat the motion as withdrawn, and the motion may be refiled onlyith the permission of the hearing examiner, upon a showing of good cause by theoving party.</text>
    <text>If the opposing party fails to appear at the hearing, the hearing examiner mayreat the motion as conceded and grant the motion, except that the opposingarty may request that the hearing examiner vacate the order granting theotion, upon a showing of
      good cause by the opposing party.</text>
    <text>All parties are encouraged to engage in voluntary discovery. Discovery may bebtained by any of the following methods:</text>
    <text>Depositions upon oral examination or written questions;</text>
    <text>Written interrogatories;</text>
    <text>Requests for production of documents or other intangible things;</text>
    <text>Requests to conduct site visits; and</text>
    <text>Requests for admissions.</text>
    <text>Responses to requests for discovery shall be provided within thirty (30) daysnless the parties agree to a different deadline or the hearing examiner, uponotion by one of the parties and for good cause shown, establishes a differenteadline.</text>
    <text>If a party fails to permit or provide discovery, an aggrieved party may file aotion to compel discovery with the hearing examiner.</text>
    <text>When determining whether to admit any material or testimony into evidence, theearing examiner shall be guided by the rules of evidence applicable in civilroceedings in the D.C. Superior Court. If the hearing examiner concludes thathe admission of
      evidence that would not be permitted by the court would beelpful to the determination of the matter before him or her, the hearingxaminer may admit that testimony or material into evidence.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 6194, 6202 (October 10, 1986); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 2948 (April 28, 2000); asmended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 1021, 1074 (February0, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>