<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1502</num>
  <heading>PRETREATMENT REQUIREMENTS (§ 21-1502)
    <text>If any wastewater which is or may be discharged to the District&amp;#8217;sastewater system and which, in WASA&amp;#8217;s judgment has or may have aotential to upset the treatment plant, a deleterious effect on the wastewaterystem, receiving waters,
      the disposal of WASA’s biosolids, constitute auisance, or otherwise create a hazard to life or the environment, WASA may takeny of the following actions, including but not limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Reject the wastewater;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Require the pretreatment to an acceptable condition for discharge to theastewater system;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Require control over the quantities and rates of discharge; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Require payment of a high-strength waste fee.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Each Industrial User shall provide the wastewater pretreatment deemed necessaryo comply with the requirements of this chapter. Any pretreatment or controlacilities required to pretreat wastewater shall be installed, operated,onitored, and maintained
      at the Industrial User&amp;#8217;s expense.</text>
    <text>Increased use of process water or dilution of a discharge shall not constituteither a partial or complete substitute for adequate or necessary pretreatmento achieve compliance with any discharge limitation.</text>
    <text>Approval of existing or proposed pretreatment or control facilities or equipmenty WASA shall not, in any way, guarantee that these facilities or equipment willunction in the manner described by the owner, designer, constructor oranufacturer. WASA&amp;#8217;s
      approval shall not relieve any User of theesponsibility of enlarging or otherwise modifying such pretreatment or controlacilities to accomplish the intended purpose of pretreatment or control.</text>
    <text>Where pretreatment or control facilities are required, they shall be maintainedontinuously in satisfactory and effective condition by the Industrial User atis or her expense and shall be subject to periodic inspection by WASA.</text>
    <text>Each Industrial User shall provide pretreatment or control facilities to protecthe wastewater system from slug discharges, accidental discharges, prohibitedaterials, or other regulated wastes. The pretreatment or control facilitieshall be provided
      and maintained at the Industrial User&amp;#8217;s expense.</text>
    <text>Significant Industrial Users shall be evaluated to determine whether a plan orther action is needed to control slug discharges within one (1) year of beingesignated by WASA as a Significant Industrial User. Slug control plans shallddress at a minimum
      the following:</text>
    <text>Description of discharge practices, including non-routine batch discharges;</text>
    <text>Description of stored chemicals;</text>
    <text>Procedures to be used for notifying WASA immediately of any slug discharges,ncluding any discharge that would violate a prohibition under §1501.4 androcedures for follow-up written notification within five (5) days;</text>
    <text>Procedures to be used for notifying WASA immediately of any changes at itsacility affecting potential for a slug discharge; and</text>
    <text>If necessary, procedures to prevent adverse impact from accidental spills,ncluding:</text>
    <text>Inspection and maintenance of storage areas;</text>
    <text>Handling and transfer of materials;</text>
    <text>Loading and unloading operations;</text>
    <text>Control of plant site run-off;</text>
    <text>Worker training;</text>
    <text>Building of containment structures or equipment;</text>
    <text>Measures for containing toxic organic pollutants (including solvents); and</text>
    <text>Measures and equipment for emergency response.</text>
    <text>Industrial Users shall provide secondary containment measures where substancesre stored, transported, treated, disposed of, or otherwise handled in areasraining into a District sewer which, because of actual or potential discharger leakage from the
      storage or conveyance system, creates or may create anxplosion hazard in, or in any other way have a detrimental effect upon, theastewater system, or otherwise constitute or pose a hazard to human beings,nimals, property, or the receiving waters.</text>
    <text>Secondary containment plans are subject to review by WASA, and shall includeeasonable safeguards to eliminate or minimize the potential detrimental effect.</text>
    <text>Detailed plans delineating and describing the facilities and operatingrocedures required by § 1502.6 and 1502.7 shall be maintained by thendustrial User and made available for inspection by WASA or authorizedepresentatives at any reasonable time as
      provided for in § 1506.</text>
    <text>Whenever deemed necessary, WASA may require Industrial Users to restrict theirischarge during peak flow periods, designate specific sewers to dischargeastewater, relocate and/or consolidate points of discharge, separate sewageastestreams from industrial
      wastestreams, and such other conditions as may beecessary to protect the District’s wastewater system and determine thendustrial User’s compliance with the requirements of this chapter.</text>
    <text>WASA may require any User discharging to the District’s wastewater system tonstall and maintain, on their property and at their expense, a suitable storagend flow-control facility to ensure equalization of flow. A wastewaterischarge permit may be
      issued solely for flow equalization.</text>
    <text>WASA may issue any Industrial User a compliance schedule for installation ofechnology required to comply with this chapter in accordance with D.C. Officialode § 8-105.07(b)(3) (2008 Repl. &amp;#038; 2011 Supp.).</text>
    <text>Compliance schedules shall contain increments of progress in the form ofctivities to be performed and dates for the commencement and completion ofhese activities leading to the construction and operation of the pretreatmentechnology or completion
      of other activities required to bring the Industrialser into compliance.</text>
    <text>Failure to initiate or complete the required activities by the date specified inhe compliance schedule shall be a violation of this chapter and shall benforceable in accordance with § 1513.</text>
    <text>Industrial Users including, but not limited to, restaurants, cafeterias, hotelitchens, church kitchens, school kitchens, hospital cafeterias, bars, or otheracilities that have the potential to discharge oil or grease laden wastewaterhall provide and
      maintain a grease abatement system for the proper handling ofastewater containing excessive amounts of oil and grease in accordance with theistrict of Columbia Plumbing Code or as WASA requires.</text>
    <text>Industrial Users including, but not limited to, gas stations, maintenanceacilities, laundries, car washes, or other facilities that have the potentialo discharge oil, or sand laden wastewater shall provide oil or sandnterceptors for the proper handling
      of wastewater containing excessive amountsf oil or sand in accordance with the District of Columbia Plumbing Code or asASA requires.</text>
    <text>Industrial Users that have the potential of discharging grease, oil, or sandaden wastewater into the District’s wastewater system shall comply with theollowing requirements:</text>
    <text>Implement appropriate best management practices for minimizing the discharge ofrease, oil, or sand laden wastewater into the sewer system;</text>
    <text>All grease abatement systems and interceptors shall comply with the currentlypproved District of Columbia Plumbing Code requirements and shall be easilyccessible for cleaning and inspection;</text>
    <text>Grease abatement systems and interceptors shall be maintained and inspectedegularly and repaired as needed by the Industrial User at their expense;</text>
    <text>Grease, oil, and settled solids shall be removed from such grease abatementystems and interceptors at a frequency necessary to ensure proper operation ando prevent pass-through of these materials into the District’s wastewaterystem;</text>
    <text>Cleaning frequency shall not exceed thirty (30) days for an indoor greasebatement system and ninety (90) days for an outdoor grease abatement system,nless granted a written variance by WASA for those Industrial Users identifiedn §1502.16. A written
      variance may be issued if the Industrial User canatisfactorily demonstrate that the accumulation of grease, oils, and solidsoes not exceed twenty-five percent (25%) of the liquid retention capacity ofhe grease abatement system during the Industrial
      User’s proposed cleaningrequency. The entire contents of the grease abatement system shall be pumpedut and properly disposed of to allow for thorough cleaning of the greasebatement system. All costs for removal of material or cleaning of the greasebatement
      system shall be at the Industrial User’s expense; and</text>
    <text>Documentation of the most recent cleaning of the grease abatement system ornterceptor shall be retained on site and shall include, at a minimum, the dateleaned, the company or person performing the cleaning, the volume of materialemoved, and the method
      and location of disposal. Cleaning records shall beetained for a period of at least three (3) years.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 6194, 6195 (October 10, 1986); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 2948 (April 28, 2000); asmended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 1021, 1034 (February0, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>