<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1505</num>
  <heading>PERMIT CONDITIONS (§ 21-1505)
    <text>The following minimum conditions shall be incorporated into, and made a part ofvery Wastewater Discharge Permit, whether such conditions are recited thereinr not:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Industrial User shall report the actual wastewater constituents andharacteristics of its discharge;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Industrial User shall report significant changes in operation, and inastewater constituents and characteristics;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Industrial User shall allow reasonable access to its premises for theurpose of inspection or wastewater monitoring; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Industrial User shall comply with each and every term and condition ofhe permit.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Wastewater Discharge Permit holders shall comply with the requirements of thishapter. Individual or general permits may contain any or all of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Statement of duration (issuance date, effective date, and expiration date);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Statement of non-transferability without prior notification to WASA inccordance with § 1505.10-1505.13, and requirement to provide the new owner orperator with a copy of the existing Wastewater Discharge Permit;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Limits on rate and time of discharge and requirements for flow regulationnd equalization;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Effluent limits, including average and maximum wastewater constituents andoncentrations and Best Management Practices, based on applicable generalretreatment standards, Categorical Pretreatment Standards, local limits, andtate and local law;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Requirements for installation of inspection and sampling facilities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Pretreatment requirements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Self-monitoring, sampling, reporting, notification and recordkeepingequirements, Best Management Practices to be monitored, an identification ofhe pollutants to be monitored (including the process for seeking a waiver for aollutant neither present
        nor expected to be present in the discharge inccordance with 40 C.F.R. § 403.12(e)(2) and § 1507.11, or a specific waivedollutant in the case of an individual control mechanism), sampling location,ampling frequency, and sample type, based on the
        applicable generalretreatment standards in 40 C.F.R. § 403, Categorical Pretreatment Standards,ocal limits, and State and local law;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Requirement for immediate notification to WASA where self-monitoring resultsndicate non-compliance and to repeat sampling and analysis and submit resultso WASA within thirty (30) days after becoming aware of the violation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Requirement to immediately report a bypass or upset of a pretreatmentacility and all discharges, including slug loadings, that could adverselympact the District’s wastewater system;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Requirements for notification of, and acceptance by, WASA of any newntroduction of wastewater constituents or of any substantial change in theolume or character of the wastewater constituents being introduced into theastewater system;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Requirements for disposal of sludges, floats, and skimmings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Requirements for submission of technical reports or discharge reports,ncluding the submission of data obtained from monitoring which is conducted byhe Industrial User, but which is not required by law, and frequency ofubmission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Requirements for maintaining records relating to wastewater discharge,ncluding but not limited to, records of all information resulting from anyonitoring activities, including documentation associated with Best Managementractices;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>Requirements for payment of permit fees, sampling and analysis fees, hightrength waste fees, or other fees, as provided in chapter 1 of this title;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>Requirements to control slug discharges, if WASA determines that isecessary;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(p)</num>
      <text>Statement of applicable civil and criminal penalties for violation ofretreatment standards and requirements, and any applicable compliance schedule;nd</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(q)</num>
      <text>Additional requirements as that WASA may determine.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Wastewater Discharge Permit holders shall make available to their employeesopies of this chapter and any other wastewater information and notices whichASA may furnish from time to time to achieve more effective water pollutionontrol. A notice shall
      be furnished and permanently posted by the Industrialser in a conspicuous place advising employees whom to call in case of anyischarge or accident in violation of this chapter.</text>
    <text>Wastewater Discharge Permits issued by User Jurisdictions that are not requiredo implement a pretreatment program by applicable federal law shall contain theondition(s) enumerated in §§ 1505.2 and 1518.7, appropriate to the facts andircumstances of
      such User Jurisdiction.</text>
    <text>Permits for Industrial Users shall be issued for a specified period of time andn no event shall a permit extend beyond five (5) years from the effective datef the permit.</text>
    <text>Industrial Users shall apply to renew their permit at least thirty (30) daysrior to the expiration date of their permit. Upon request by an Industrialser, WASA may grant permission to submit an application to renew the permit at later date, but no
      later than the date of expiration of the permit. Failureo timely renew a permit shall constitute a violation of this chapter and shalle subject to the fines and penalties set forth in § 1516.</text>
    <text>If an Industrial User has timely applied to renew their permit and has submittedny additional information that WASA may request in connection with thepplication, and WASA does not issue a new permit before the expiration date ofhe previous permit,
      the previous permit shall be extended administratively andhall remain fully effective and enforceable.</text>
    <text>When WASA proposes changes in a permit before the expiration date of the permit,he permit holder shall be notified in writing at least sixty (60) days prior tohe effective date of the changes. The notice shall include a specific timechedule for compliance
      if new pretreatment or control facilities are required.he time schedule shall be based on practical delivery and construction timeequirements, and shall become a part of the permit.</text>
    <text>Wastewater Discharge Permits shall be issued to specific Industrial Users forpecific operations.</text>
    <text>A Wastewater Discharge Permit may be assignable or transferable to another ownerr operator only if:</text>
    <text>the Permittee gives advance written notice to WASA at least fourteen (14) daysrior to execution of the assignment or transfer;</text>
    <text>the Permittee gives the new owner or operator a copy of the existing Wastewaterischarge Permit; and</text>
    <text>WASA approves the Wastewater Discharge Permit transfer.</text>
    <text>The Wastewater Discharge Permit Transfer notice shall include a writtenertification by the new owner or operator, which:</text>
    <text>States that the new owner and/or operator has no immediate intent to change theacility’s operations and processes;</text>
    <text>Identifies the specific date on which the transfer is to occur; and</text>
    <text>Acknowledges full responsibility for complying with the existing Wastewaterischarge Permit.</text>
    <text>A Wastewater Discharge Permit shall not be transferable to a new orignificantly changed operation. The new Industrial User shall submit a newpplication for a Wastewater Discharge Permit and shall obtain a new permitrior to instituting a new or significantly
      changed operation.</text>
    <text>Any attempt to assign or transfer a Wastewater Discharge Permit without priorotice to WASA and WASA’s approval shall render the permit void from the datef the attempted assignment or transfer.</text>
    <text>Industrial Users may petition the General Manager to reconsider the issuance,evocation or denial of a Wastewater Discharge Permit or the terms or conditionsf a discharge permit within fifteen (15) calendar days of the effective date ofhe permit by
      submission of a Permit Appeal form. The submission of a Permitppeal for reconsideration shall not stay compliance with Wastewater Dischargeermit conditions.</text>
    <text>Failure to submit a timely Permit Appeal for review shall be deemed to be aaiver of administrative appeal unless a time extension is granted by theeneral Manager.</text>
    <text>In the Permit Appeal, the Industrial User shall indicate the discharge permitrovisions objected to, the reasons for the objection, and the alternativeondition, if any, it seeks to place in the discharge permit.</text>
    <text>The General Manager shall review and make a final decision on the Permit Appeal.The General Manager will send the Industrial User the final decision.</text>
    <text>If the Permit Appeal is denied by the General Manager or the Permittee is notatisfied with the General Manager’s final decision, the Industrial User mayppeal the Permit Appeal decision as set forth in § 1519 by filing a petitionor an administrative
      hearing within fifteen (15) calendar days of the date ofhe General Manager’s final decision. The petition for an administrativeearing shall be filed in accordance with the requirements set forth in 21 DCMR 412.</text>
    <text>Source: Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 6194, 6195 (October 10, 1986); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 2948 (April 28, 2000); asmended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 1021, 1034, 1044February 10, 2012).</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>