<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1506</num>
  <heading>RIGHT OF ENTRY (§ 21-1506)
    <text>For the purposes of inspection, observation, measurement, sampling and testing,ASA or WASA’s authorized representative shall have the right to enter upon orhrough any premises to determine compliance with this chapter. This right tonter and inspect
      shall be in accordance with section 9 of the Wastewater Systemegulation Amendment Act of 1985 (D.C. Law 6-95; D.C. Official Code § 8-105.082008 Repl. &amp;#038; 2011 Supp.)).</text>
    <text>Any temporary or permanent obstruction to safe and easy access to a facility toe inspected and/or sampled shall be promptly removed by the Industrial User athe request of WASA and shall not be replaced. The cost of clearing suchbstructions shall be
      the responsibility of the Industrial User.</text>
    <text>Where an Industrial User has security measures in place which would requireroper identification and clearance before entry, the Industrial User shall makehe necessary arrangements so that upon presentation of suitable identification,ASA, or WASA’s
      authorized representative, will be permitted entry withoutelay.</text>
    <text>Appropriate credentials for making an inspection shall include:</text>
    <text>A duly issued photo identification card showing the name of the inspector androof of employment with WASA; or</text>
    <text>A WASA authorized representative with a photo identification and a notice ofnspection issued by WASA, containing the following information:</text>
    <text>Name of the Industrial User;</text>
    <text>Address of the place or identification of the facility to be inspected;</text>
    <text>Date of the inspection;</text>
    <text>Name of the WASA authorized representative; and</text>
    <text>Signature of the WASA official.</text>
    <text>Entry by WASA or WASA’s authorized representative may be made with or withoutotice, as follows:</text>
    <text>At any time, in emergency situations, or where there is a potential immediatehreat to human health and safety, the environment or the District’sastewater system; or</text>
    <text>At any reasonable time in non-emergency situations. The following times shall beeemed reasonable for the purpose of entry:</text>
    <text>Between the hours of 7:30 a.m. and 6:00 p.m. on weekdays; and</text>
    <text>Any hour during which the facility is open for business or operation.</text>
    <text>Unreasonable delays in allowing WASA or WASA’s authorized representativeccess to the Industrial Users premises shall constitute a violation of the Actnd this chapter.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 6194, 6198 (October 10, 1986); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 2948 (April 28, 2000); asmended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 1021, 1048 (February0, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>