<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1500</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 21-1500)
    <text>The purpose of this chapter is to provide procedures for complying with theequirements of the Wastewater System Regulation Amendment Act of 1985 (D.C. Law-95; D.C. Official Code §§ 8-105.01, et seq. (2008 Repl. &amp;#038; 2011 Supp.)).</text>
    <text>These regulations shall apply to all Users that indirectly dischargeon-domestic wastewater to the District’s wastewater system or directlyischarge domestic or non-domestic wastewater into the District of Columbiaater and Sewer Authority’s Septage
      Receiving Facility.</text>
    <text>These regulations provide for the issuance of wastewater discharge permits;onitoring, compliance, and enforcement activities, reporting;, anddministrative review procedures.</text>
    <text>The objectives of these regulations are to:</text>
    <text>Prevent the introduction of pollutants into the District of Columbia Water andewer Authority (WASA) sewerage system that will or may interfere with theperation of the District’s wastewater system;</text>
    <text>Prevent the introduction of pollutants into the District’s wastewater systemhat will or may pass through the District’s wastewater system, inadequatelyreated, into the Potomac River and its tributaries or otherwise be incompatibleith the District’s
      wastewater system;</text>
    <text>Enable WASA to comply with its National Pollutant Discharge Elimination Systemermit conditions, and any other Federal, State or District law to which WASA isubject to;</text>
    <text>Ensure that the quality of the biosolids produced is maintained at a level thatllows for beneficial reuse in compliance with applicable statutes andegulations; and</text>
    <text>Protect the general public and WASA’s personnel.</text>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided herein, the WASA General Manager shall promulgate,dminister, implement, and enforce the provisions of these regulations. Anyowers granted to or duties imposed upon the General Manager may be delegated toASA personnel.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 6194 (October 10, 1986); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 2948 (April 28, 2000); asmended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 1021, 1022 (February0, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>