<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1503</num>
  <heading>NOTICES (§ 21-1503)
    <text>To collect information consistent with the purposes of the Act and this chapter,ASA may require any party who discharges, or whom WASA reasonably believesischarges, into the District&amp;#8217;s wastewater system, to provide reportsoncerning the nature,
      contents, quantity and frequency of such discharges andhe party&amp;#8217;s actions, if any, to monitor or alter such discharges. WASA mayequire such reports regardless of whether the party shall have a permit underhe Act.</text>
    <text>WASA may issue a discharge notification letter to such parties, identifying whatpecific information is sought, the frequency with which the information shalle provided, and a statement concerning the period of time during which thebligation to provide
      such information will continue.</text>
    <text>All Industrial Users shall promptly notify WASA prior to any new or increasedontribution of pollutants or change in the nature of pollutants or substantialhange in the volume or character of pollutants in their discharge, includinghe listed and characteristic
      hazardous waste for which the Industrial User hasubmitted initial notification under § 1503.6. WASA reserves the right torohibit or impose conditions on the discharge of any new, increased or changedontribution of pollutants.</text>
    <text>All Industrial Users that experience an unplanned discharge due to a spill, slugischarge, or other potential problem, shall notify WASA as follows:</text>
    <text>All Industrial Users shall notify WASA immediately of all discharges that couldause problems to the District’s wastewater system, including any slugoadings, which are defined as pollutant discharges which violate the specificrohibitions under § 1501.4;</text>
    <text>The notification shall include the date, time, and location of the discharge;ype, concentration and volume of waste; and corrective actions. The Industrialser shall be liable for any expense, loss, or damage to the District’sastewater system, in addition
      to any fines that WASA imposes;</text>
    <text>Within five (5) days following the unplanned discharge, the Industrial Userhall submit to WASA a detailed written report describing the cause of theischarge and the measures to be taken by the Industrial User to prevent similarccurrences in the future;
      and</text>
    <text>If the unplanned discharge contains a listed or characteristic hazardous waste,s defined in 40 C.F.R. Part 261 and District regulations, the Industrial Userhall also comply with the requirements of § 1503.6(a).</text>
    <text>Notice of Changed Discharge &amp;#8211; All Significant Industrial Users areequired to notify WASA immediately of any changes at their facility affectinghe potential for a slug discharge.</text>
    <text>All Industrial Users proposing to discharge hazardous waste into theistrict’s wastewater system shall comply with the following requirements:</text>
    <text>Industrial Users shall make a written notification to WASA, the Mayor, and theirector of EPA’s Region III Waste Management Division, prior to a dischargento the District’s wastewater system of a substance which, if otherwiseisposed of, would be a
      hazardous waste under 40 C.F.R. Part 261 and Districtegulations. Such notification shall include:</text>
    <text>The name of the hazardous waste as set forth in 40 C.F.R. Part 261;</text>
    <text>EPA hazardous waste number;</text>
    <text>The type of discharge (continuous, batch, or other); and</text>
    <text>A statement certifying that the Industrial User has a program in place to reducehe volume and toxicity of hazardous wastes generated to the degree it hasetermined to be economically practical;</text>
    <text>If the Industrial User intends to discharge more than one hundred kilograms (100g) of hazardous waste per calendar month to the District’s wastewater system,he notification shall also contain the following information to the extent thenformation is
      known and readily available to the Industrial User:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An identification of the hazardous constituents contained in the wastes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An estimation of the mass and concentration of such constituents in theastestream to be discharged during the calendar month; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An estimation of the mass of constituents in the wastestream expected to beischarged during the following twelve (12) months;</text>
    </level>
    <text>Industrial Users shall provide notification prior to the discharge of a listedr characteristic hazardous waste. This notification shall be submitted onlynce for each hazardous waste intended to be discharged. However, notificationsf changed discharges
      shall be submitted under 40 C.F.R. § 403.12(j) and §503.5. The notification requirement, however, does not apply to pollutantslready reported under the self-monitoring requirements of 40 C.F.R. §03.12(b), (d), and (e) and § 1508; and</text>
    <text>WASA shall review the hazardous waste discharge notification and may issue a newr revised pretreatment permit. Industrial Users shall not discharge a listedr characteristic hazardous waste prior to the issuance of a pretreatment permithat authorizes
      the discharge.</text>
    <text>In the case of any new regulations under § 3001 of the Resource Conservationnd Recovery Act (RCRA) identifying additional characteristics of hazardousaste or listing any additional substance as a hazardous waste, the Industrialser shall notify WASA,
      the EPA Regional Waste Management Waste Divisionirector, and the District of Columbia hazardous waste authorities of theischarge of such substance within ninety (90) days of the effective date ofuch regulations.</text>
    <text>Source: Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 6194, 6195 (October 10, 1986); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 2948 (April 28, 2000); asmended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 1021, 1034, 1038February 10, 2012).</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>