<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1517</num>
  <heading>JUDICIAL ENFORCEMENT REMEDIES (ยง 21-1517)
    <text>Notwithstanding any other remedial authority conferred by the Act or thishapter, WASA may seek declaratory, injunctive or other appropriate relief toestrain, minimize, halt, prevent, or eliminate a violation or imminentiolation of any provision of
      this chapter.</text>
    <text>Any User who violates any provision of the Act or this chapter shall be liableor a civil fine not exceeding ten thousand dollars ($10,000) for each dayuring which each violation continues, and shall be required to perform anyther action needed to
      correct any harm caused by any violation or to ensurehat future violations do not occur as set forth in D.C. Official Code ยง-105.14(a)(2008 Repl. &amp;#038; 2011 Supp.)).</text>
    <text>WASA may add any such civil fines and cost to the bill for the User&amp;#8217;ssual sanitary sewer service charges, high-strength waste fees, wastewaterreatment fees, administrative fines, and other fees, or may issue a separateill for civil fines
      and costs.</text>
    <text>Any User who violates any provision of the Act or this chapter shall be liableo the District and WASA for all expenses, losses, or damages incurred by theistrict and WASA by reason of the violation.</text>
    <text>Any person who intentionally, willfully or recklessly violates any provision ofhe Act or this chapter shall be punished by a criminal fine not to exceed tenhousand dollars ($10,000) for each day each violation continues, ormprisonment not to exceed
      one (1) year for each day each violation continues,r both, and to perform any other action needed to correct any harm caused byny violation or to ensure that future violations do not occur, as set forth in.C. Official Code ยง 8-105.14(b) (2008 Repl.
      &amp;#038; 2011 Supp.)).</text>
    <text>Any User who knowingly makes any false or misleading statement, representationr certification with respect to any information or data submitted to, orequired by, the District pursuant to the Act or this chapter, or who falsifies,ampers with, or knowingly
      renders inaccurate any monitoring device or method,amples or the results of same, upon conviction in a court of competenturisdiction shall be liable for a fine of up to ten thousand dollars ($10,000)or each count of such conviction.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 1021, 1087 (February0, 2012).</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>