<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1515</num>
  <heading>ANNUAL NOTICE OF SIGNIFICANT VIOLATIONS (§ 21-1515)
    <text>WASA shall publish annually a list of the Industrial Users in significantoncompliance with the pretreatment standards and requirements in the precedingalendar year in a newspaper(s) of general circulation that provides meaningfulublic notice within
      the jurisdiction(s) served by WASA.</text>
    <text>The notification shall summarize the nature of the significant noncompliance andny enforcement action taken against the Industrial User during the same twelve12) month period.</text>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, a Significant Industrial User (or anyndustrial User which violates § 1515.3(c), (d), or (h)) is in significantoncompliance with the pretreatment standards and requirements if its violationeets one (1) or more of the
      following criteria:</text>
    <text>Chronic violations of wastewater discharge limits, which are violations in whichixty-six percent (66%) or more of all the measurements taken for the sameollutant parameter during a six (6) month period exceed (by any magnitude) aumeric pretreatment
      standard or requirement, including instantaneous limits, asefined by 40 C.F.R. § 403.3(l);</text>
    <text>Technical Review Criteria (TRC) violations, which are violations in whichhirty-three percent (33%) or more of all of the measurements taken for the sameollutant parameter during a six (6) month period equal or exceed the product ofhe numeric pretreatment
      standard or requirement including instantaneous limits,s defined by 40 C.F.R. § 403.3(l) multiplied by the applicable TRC (TRC = 1.4or Biochemical Oxygen Demand, Total Suspended Solids, Fats, Oil, and Grease,nd 1.2 for all other pollutants except
      pH);</text>
    <text>Any other violation of a pretreatment standard or requirement as defined by 40.F.R. § 403.3(l) (daily maximum, long-term average, instantaneous limit, orarrative standard) that WASA determines has caused, alone or in combinationith other discharges,
      interference or pass through (including endangering theealth of WASA or District personnel or the general public);</text>
    <text>Any discharge of a pollutant that has caused imminent endangerment to humanealth, welfare or to the environment or has resulted in WASA’s exercise ofts emergency authority pursuant to 40 C.F.R. § 403.8(f)(1)(vi)(B) and D.C.fficial Code § 8-105.12
      (2008 Repl. &amp;#038; 2011 Supp.)) to halt or preventuch a discharge;</text>
    <text>Any violation of the terms of a wastewater discharge permit which remainsncorrected forty-five (45) days after notification of the violation is receivedy the Industrial User; or any failure to meet, within ninety (90) days afterhe schedule date, a
      compliance schedule milestone contained in a District orocal control mechanism or enforcement order for starting construction,ompleting construction, or attaining final compliance;</text>
    <text>Failure to provide required reports, such as baseline monitoring reports, ninety90) day compliance reports, periodic self-monitoring reports, and reports onrogress with compliance schedules or orders, within forty-five (45) days afterhe due date;</text>
    <text>Failure to timely and accurately report an instance of noncompliance with theretreatment standards and requirements; and</text>
    <text>Any other violation or group of violations, which may include a violation ofest Management Practices, which WASA determines will adversely affect theperation or implementation of the local pretreatment program or which WASAtherwise considers significant
      in light of the circumstances.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 1021, 1075 (February0, 2012).</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>