<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1510</num>
  <heading>HAULED WASTEWATER (§ 21-1510)
    <text>It shall be unlawful for any User to dispose of any hauled wastewater,omprising liquid or solid and liquid wastes, removed from septic tanks, greasebatement systems, portable toilets, or wastes from any other source, anywheren the District of Columbia
      except at the Septage Receiving Facility located athe wastewater treatment facility at 5000 Overlook Ave., S.W.</text>
    <text>Any User intending to discharge hauled wastewater in the District of Columbia,hall apply for and obtain a Waste Hauler Discharge Permit.</text>
    <text>The application for issuance of a Waste Hauler Discharge Permit shall beubmitted to WASA at least thirty (30) days prior to discharge for a new permitr the expiration of a current permit and shall include the followingnformation:</text>
    <text>Name, address, and contact information;</text>
    <text>Vehicle information for each vehicle used to discharge waste at the WASA Septageeceiving Facility, including:</text>
    <text>Make, model and year of the vehicle;</text>
    <text>Tag number;</text>
    <text>State of registration;</text>
    <text>Serial number;</text>
    <text>Tank capacity;</text>
    <text>Garage address; and</text>
    <text>Insurance coverage;</text>
    <text>Estimated number of loads per week;</text>
    <text>Services provided (type of waste and service area);</text>
    <text>List of commercial and industrial customers (if applicable);</text>
    <text>Waste characterization data, if requested by WASA;</text>
    <text>Operating permits (if applicable); and</text>
    <text>Certification statements (included on the application), signed by an authorizedepresentative in accordance with § 1508.11.</text>
    <text>After evaluation of the information submitted, WASA may:</text>
    <text>Deny any application for a Waste Hauler Discharge Permit; or</text>
    <text>Issue an invoice for the applicable Waste Hauler Discharge Permit fees asrovided in chapter 1 of this title, and upon payment, shall issue a Wasteauler Discharge Permit subject to terms and conditions provided in the Wasteauler Discharge Permit.</text>
    <text>Upon receiving a Waste Hauler Discharge Permit, the Waste Hauler shall complyith all permit conditions. Discharge of wastewater without a permit shall berohibited, unless authorized by WASA.</text>
    <text>Waste Hauler Discharge Permits shall be effective for a period of one (1) yearnd may contain any or all of the following conditions:</text>
    <text>Statement of duration;</text>
    <text>Statement of non-transferability;</text>
    <text>Load restrictions;</text>
    <text>Manifest requirements;</text>
    <text>Right of refusal;</text>
    <text>Hours of operation, and procedures for discharging outside of the normal hoursf operation; and</text>
    <text>Additional requirements as WASA may determine.</text>
    <text>Waste Hauler Discharge Permits are not transferable, unless WASA specificallyuthorizes in writing.</text>
    <text>The permittee shall notify WASA immediately if their license plate oregistration has changed on any of their permitted vehicles.</text>
    <text>Upon receiving notification from the permittee pursuant to § 1510.8, WASA shallssue a revised Waste Hauler Discharge Permit.</text>
    <text>Wastes that are not compatible with the District’s wastewater treatmentrocess, including, but not limited to, wastewater or additives containingetroleum products, solvents, formaldehyde, or 1,4-dichlorobenzene shall not beischarged at the Septage
      Receiving Facility.</text>
    <text>Wastes from water or wastewater treatment plants or other non-domestic sourceshall not be discharged at the Septage Receiving Facility unless WASApecifically authorizes in writing. WASA may require characterization of theischarge prior to authorization
      to discharge.</text>
    <text>Waste from water or wastewater treatment plants or other non-domestic sourceshall not be mixed with waste from domestic sources.</text>
    <text>The waste hauler shall submit a manifest form to WASA prior to entering the Bluelains facility which shall contain the following information on each load:</text>
    <text>Company name and Waste Hauler Discharge Permit number;</text>
    <text>Vehicle make, model, and license number;</text>
    <text>For each source, the customer’s name, address and volume of hauled waste;</text>
    <text>Type of waste(s) (for example grease trap, and septic tank);</text>
    <text>Total volume of the load; and</text>
    <text>Driver certification statement.</text>
    <text>Disposal into the Septage Receiving Facility shall be in accordance with theollowing provisions:</text>
    <text>All loads shall comply with WASA discharge standards as provided in § 1501;</text>
    <text>WASA shall reserve the right to refuse acceptance of any load;</text>
    <text>Dischargers may be required to cease unloading operations at any time;</text>
    <text>In the case of composite loads, any part of the load that is restricted orrohibited shall make the entire load unacceptable for discharge;</text>
    <text>Upon request, any Waste Hauler shall provide WASA personnel with access to theastewater contained in the vehicle for collecting samples or taking instrumenteadings;</text>
    <text>All haulers shall clean up all spills resulting from their discharge activity athe Septage Receiving Facility; and</text>
    <text>Additional expenses shall be charged to the hauler if WASA has to clean up anypills or deposits, unclog the septage discharge lines, or repair damageccurring as the result of the hauler’s discharge activity.</text>
    <text>Except as authorized by WASA, the discharge of truck-hauled wastewater without aermit or in violation of a permit shall be punishable as provided in § 15 ofhe Act and as provided in §§ 1513, 1516, and 1517.</text>
    <text>A Waste Hauler Discharge Permit may be suspended, terminated, or denied for goodause including, but not limited to, the following:</text>
    <text>Information indicating that the permitted discharge poses a threat to thereatment system or WASA personnel;</text>
    <text>Violation of any terms or conditions of the Waste Hauler Discharge Permit;</text>
    <text>Obtaining a Waste Hauler Discharge Permit by misrepresentation or failure toisclose fully, all relevant facts;</text>
    <text>The unauthorized discharge of wastewater from non-domestic sources;</text>
    <text>Denying WASA personnel access to a vehicle or its contents for purposes ofollecting a sample and/or obtaining instrument readings;</text>
    <text>Failure to obtain or maintain appropriate current hauling licenses or permitsrom Federal, State, or local agencies; and</text>
    <text>Failure to pay fees.</text>
    <text>Volume based disposal fees may be assessed in accordance with chapter 1 of thisitle for each load of hauled wastewater received at the Septage Receivingacility, based on the volume and type or strength of wastewater discharged.dditional fees may be
      assessed for hauled wastewater discharged outside oformal hours of operation.</text>
    <text>The actual volume of sewage discharged as determined by a method acceptable toASA; or</text>
    <text>The carrying capacity or a percentage of the carrying capacity of the wasteauler’s vehicle, if the actual volume of sewage discharged cannot beetermined by a method acceptable to WASA.</text>
    <text>Users may petition the General Manager to reconsider the issuance, suspension,ermination or denial of a Waste Hauler Discharge Permit or the terms oronditions of a Waste Hauler Discharge Permit within fifteen (15) calendar daysf the effective date
      of the Waste Hauler Discharge Permit by submission of aermit Appeal form. The submission of a Permit Appeal for reconsideration shallot stay compliance with Waste Hauler Discharge Permit conditions.</text>
    <text>Failure to submit a timely Permit Appeal for review shall be deemed to be aaiver of administrative appeal unless WASA grants a time extension.</text>
    <text>In the Permit Appeal, the User shall indicate the discharge permit provisionsbjected to, the reasons for the objection, and the alternative condition, ifny, it seeks to place in the Waste Hauler Discharge Permit.</text>
    <text>The General Manager will review and make a final decision on the Permit Appeal.</text>
    <text>The General Manager will send the User the final decision.</text>
    <text>If the Permit Appeal is denied by the General Manager or the User is notatisfied with the General Manager’s final decision, the User may appeal theermit Appeal decision as set forth in § 1519 by filing a petition for andministrative hearing within
      fifteen (15) calendar days of the date of theeneral Manager’s decision. The petition for an administrative hearing shalle filed in accordance with the requirements set forth in 21 DCMR § 412.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>WASA shall determine the volume of wastewater and shall base the determinationn either</heading>
      <text />
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 6194, 6202 (October 10, 1986); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 2948 (April 28, 2000); asmended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 1021, 1062 (February0, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>