<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-2703</num>
  <heading>FUNDING AMOUNTS AND LIMITATIONS (§ 1-2703)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2703.1.</num>
    <text>A grant or loan shall not exceed ten thousand dollars ($10,000) from any single project.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2703.2.</num>
    <text>The maximum total amount a nonprofit organization or public agency may be granted or loaned during any three (3) year period is ten thousand dollars ($10,000), except that a nonprofit District-based organization that requests funds on an emergency
      basis for a project to provide food, clothing, shelter or utilities to low-income District residents, or for other projects that address an urgent public need of low-income District residents, may receive one additional grant or loan during the
      three (3) year period not to exceed ten thousand dollars ($10,000) upon a unanimous recommendation by the Escheated Estates Fund Application Screening Committee and approval by the Mayor. In no event shall the aggregate amount of any grant or loan
      hereunder exceed twenty thousand dollars ($20,000) to any one nonprofit organization during any three (3) year period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2703.3.</num>
    <text>Applications for grants or loans to pay for staff or operating expenses of a recurring nature shall not be considered without the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Specific and satisfactory evidence of the applicant’s ability to pay for staff or operating costs associated with an eligible project with funds from other sources; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A notarized certification that the relevant staff services and/or operating expenses will be used exclusively to provide a direct benefit to low-income District residents.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 7114, 7115 (November 9, 1990); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 43 DCR 861 (February 23, 1996).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>