<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>9-442</num>
  <heading>FOOD OR DRINK PREPARED FOR IMMEDIATE CONSUMPTION (ยง 9-442)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>442.1.</num>
    <text>In addition to the definition set forth in the Act [which is codified at D.C. Code ยง 47-2001(n)(1)(a)], the term &amp;#8220;food or drink prepared for immediate consumption&amp;#8221; includes sales made by a street or sidewalk vendor who has no fixed
      place of business, even though the vendor does not sell from a vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>442.2.</num>
    <text>For the purposes this section, the term &amp;#8220;food or drink prepared for immediate consumption&amp;#8221; does not include food or drink sold or intended to be sold by grocery stores, supermarkets, delicatessens, or other grocery-type food stores
      for home preparation or consumption.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>442.3.</num>
    <text>If a business combines the sale of food or drink for home preparation or consumption with the sale of food or drink for immediate consumption, those sales of food or drink for home preparation or consumption shall be exempt only when sold in the same
      form, quantities, and packaging as is commonly sold in grocery type food stores.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>442.4.</num>
    <text>The owner or operator of any hotel, inn, tourist camp, tourist cabin, boardinghouse, or any other place furnishing meals or food together with rooms, lodgings, or accommodations to the public shall segregate and charge separately the sale price of
      such meals or food from any other charges to their customers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order 54-1415, 1 DCR 4 (July 19, 1954); as amended by Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order 62-481 effective March 20, 1962, 8 DCR 225 (April 2, 1962); by the Third Amendment to the Revenue Act of 1975 Act, D.C. Law 1-61, 22 DCR
        4383, 4384 (February 12, 1976); and by Final Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 4929 (November 7, 1980), incorporating text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 3347, 3354 (August 1, 1980).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>