<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2633</num>
  <heading>ARCHITECT-ENGINEER PERFORMANCE EVALUATION (ยง 27-2633)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2633.1.</num>
    <text>The contract administrator shall prepare a performance evaluation report for contracts of more than ten thousand dollars ($10,000) and may prepare a report for contracts of ten thousand dollars ($10,000) or less.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2633.2.</num>
    <text>The contract administrator shall prepare a performance report after final acceptance of the work or after contract termination, as appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2633.3.</num>
    <text>If the contract administrator concludes that a firm&amp;#8217;s overall performance is unsatisfactory, the contracting officer shall advise the firm in writing that a report of unsatisfactory performance is being prepared and shall state the basis
      for the report.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2633.4.</num>
    <text>If, after receiving the contract administrator&amp;#8217;s report, the firm responds with any written comments, the contract administrator shall include them in the report, and consider them in resolving any alleged factual discrepancies, and make
      any appropriate changes in the report.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2633.5.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall review each performance report for accuracy and reasonableness.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2633.6.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall include the performance evaluation report in the contract file, and shall send a copy to the office responsible for maintenance of the firm&amp;#8217;s qualifications data. The office shall retain the report for at least
      six (6) years after the date of the report.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1594 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>