<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2620</num>
  <heading>ARCHITECT-ENGINEER SERVICES (§ 27-2620)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2620.1.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall publicize all requirements for architect-engineer services in accordance with chapter 13 of this title, and negotiate contracts for these services based on the demonstrated competence and qualifications of prospective
      contractors to perform the services required at fair and reasonable prices.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2620.2.</num>
    <text>If the District accepts funding assistance for a project from a federal or other source, and a condition of assistance is that a nonprice competitive procedure for selection of architect-engineers which is in compliance with Public Law 6-85, §304(g),
      but that differs from the procedures specified in this section, a modified architect-engineer selection procedure, approved by the Director, may be used which is in compliance with both the Act and the assistance agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2620.3.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall select a contractor for architect-engineer services in accordance with the provisions of this section rather than the solicitation or source selection procedures specified elsewhere in this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2620.4.</num>
    <text>Compliance with the provisions of §§2620 through 2633 of this chapter shall constitute a competitive procedure for the procurement of architect-engineer services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2620.5.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall evaluate each potential contractor based on the following criteria:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Professional qualifications necessary for satisfactory performance of the required services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Specialized experience and technical competence in the type of work required;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Capacity to accomplish the work in the required time;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Past performance on contracts with the District, other governmental entities, and private industry in terms of cost control, quality of work, and compliance with performance schedules; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Acceptability under other appropriate evaluation criteria.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2620.6.</num>
    <text>When the use of design competition is approved by the head of the using agency, the contracting officer may evaluate firms on the basis of their conceptual design of the project.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2620.7.</num>
    <text>Design competition may be used in the following circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>When unique situations exist involving prestigious projects, such as the design of memorials or structures of unusual national or local significance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>When sufficient time is available for the production and evaluation of conceptual designs; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>When the design competition, with its costs, will substantially benefit the project.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1586 (February 26, 1988),</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>