<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2610</num>
  <heading>INVITATIONS FOR BIDS (ยง 27-2610)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2610.1.</num>
    <text>An invitation for bids (&amp;#8220;IFB&amp;#8221;) for construction shall allow a reasonable time for bidders to prepare and submit their bids, but in no event less than thirty (30) days. Each IFB shall be publicized in accordance with the provisions
      of the Act and chapter 13 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2610.2.</num>
    <text>In determining what is a reasonable time, the contracting officer shall consider the construction season and the time necessary for bidders to inspect the site, obtain subcontract bids, examine data concerning the work, and prepare estimates based
      on plans and specifications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2610.3.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall ensure that each IFB includes the following information, when applicable:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The appropriate wage determination as issued by the U.S. Department of Labor; or, if the IFB must be issued before the wage determination is received, a notice that the schedule for minimum wage rates to be paid under the contract will be issued
        as an amendment to the IFB;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The scope of the proposed construction project;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The period of performance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Arrangements for bidders to inspect the site and examine the data concerning performance of the work;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Information concerning any facilities, such as utilities, office space, and warehouse space, to be furnished during the construction period;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Any special qualifications or experience requirements that will be considered;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Any special instructions concerning bids, alternate bids, and award;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Any instructions concerning reporting requirements; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Any other clauses required by the Act or this title.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2610.4.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall provide notice of the IFB in accordance with chapter 13 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2610.5.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall send IFBs to prospective bidders who request them.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1583 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>