<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-977</num>
  <heading>AMOUNT OF WAGES OF EMPLOYEES WHICH MAY BE SUBJECTED TO GARNISHMENT PROCEEDINGSOR PAY PERIODS OTHER THAN WEEKLY (ยง 7-977)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>977.1.</num>
    <text>The maximum part of the disposable wages of any individual for pay periods other than weekly pay periods which may be subjected to garnishment are established as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Where the pay period is for less than one (1) workweek, the exemption from garnishment shall be the same as that for a weekly pay period. Thus, so long as the Federal minimum wage prescribed by ยง6(a)(1) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 is
        three dollars and thirty-five cents ($3.35) an hour, the following formula shall apply:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If an individual&amp;#8217;s disposable wages paid or payable for a pay period of less than one (1) workweek are one hundred dollars and fifty cents ($100.50), thirty times three dollars and thirty-five cents (30 x $3.35) or less, wages may not
        be garnished in any amount;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If an individual&amp;#8217;s disposable wages paid or payable for a pay period of less than one (1) workweek are more than one hundred dollars and fifty cents ($100.50), but less than one hundred thirty-four dollars ($134), only the amount above
        one hundred dollars and fifty cents ($100.50) of disposable wages shall be subject to garnishment; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If an individual&amp;#8217;s disposable wages paid or payable for a pay period of less than one (1) workweek are one hundred thirty-four dollars ($134) or more, not more than twenty-five percent (25%) of disposable wages shall be subject to garnishment.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Where the pay period is longer than one (1) workweek, the weekly statutory exemption formula shall be transformed to a formula, providing equivalent restrictions on wage garnishment as follows:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The twenty-five percent (25%) part of the formula shall apply to the aggregate disposable wages for all the work-weeks or fractions thereof compensated by the pay for the pay period;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The &amp;#8220;multiple&amp;#8221; of the Federal minimum hourly wage equivalent to that applicable to the disposable wages for one (1) week shall be represented by the following formula: the number of workweeks, or fractions thereof times (x) thirty
        (30) times three dollars and thirty-five cents ((x) x 30 x $3.35) (the applicable Federal minimum wage). For the purpose of this formula, a calendar month is considered to consist of four and one-third (4 1/3) workweeks. Thus, so long as the Federal
        minimum wage is three dollars and thirty five cents ($3.35) an hour, the &amp;#8220;multiple&amp;#8221; applicable to the disposable wages shall be computed as follows:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>For a two week period, two hundred and one dollars ($201, two times thirty times three dollars and thirty-five cents (2 x 30 x $3.35);</text>
    </level>
    <text>(ii) For a monthly period, four hundred thirty-five dollars and fifty cents ($435.50), four and one-third times thirty times three dollars and thirty-five cents (4 1/3 x 30 x $3.35); and</text>
    <text>(iii) For a semimonthly period, two hundred and seventeen dollars and seventy-five cents ($217.75), two and one-sixth times thirty times three dollars and thirty-five cents (2 1/6 x 30 x $3.35).</text>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The &amp;#8220;multiple&amp;#8221; for any other pay period longer than one (1) week shall be computed in a manner consistent with this paragraph.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>977.2.</num>
    <text>This section became effective January 1, 1981.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>