<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2308</num>
  <heading>MEDICAL DISQUALIFICATIONS FOR REGISTRATION (§ 24-2308)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2308.1.</num>
    <text>The records described in §2307.1 shall also be used to establish whether a person was acquitted of a criminal charge by reason of insanity or adjudged a chronic alcoholic.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2308.2.</num>
    <text>Any official court or medical record revealing a civil judgment of chronic alcoholism or involuntary commitment to a private or public facility for chronic alcoholism shall establish the existence of that condition or disease for the purpose of disqualification
      imposed by §203(a)(5) of the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2308.3.</num>
    <text>Any medical certification submitted to lift the disqualification imposed by §203(a)(5) of the Act shall meet the following criteria:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be written on the official letterhead of the institution or physician treating the person;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be signed by the treating physician, head of the treating physician&amp;#8217;s department, or medical director of the treating institution (signatures of non-medical administrative personnel shall not be acceptable);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Describe the condition from which the applicant has recovered, including physical manifestations of the disease, such as tremors or blackouts; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>State whether the person, in the certifying physician&amp;#8217;s opinion, is capable of the safe and responsible possession of the type of firearm for which an application has been filed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2308.4.</num>
    <text>With respect to medical certifications to lift the disqualifier imposed by §203(a)(6) of the Act upon persons voluntarily or involuntarily committed to a mental hospital or institution, the requirements imposed by §2308.3 shall be applicable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2308.5.</num>
    <text>Physical defects indicating that an applicant would not be able to safely and responsibly possess and use a firearm as required by §203(a)(7) of the Act include those conditions that, to the examining officer, visibly prevent or substantially interfere
      with the ability to hold, load, aim, fire, clean, or protect the weapon.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 23 DCR 8942 (May 6, 1977), incorporating text of the Proposed Rulemaking published at 23 DCR 7061, 7068 (March 4, 1977); 35 DCRR §306, November 1980, Special Edition.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>