<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2321</num>
  <heading>QUALIFICATIONS AND PROCEDURES TO OBTAIN A FIREARMS DEALER&amp;#8217;S LICENSE (§4-2321)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2321.1</num>
    <text>2321.1 A person is eligible to become a licensed dealer of firearms if thaterson:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Is eligible to register a firearm under this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Is eligible under federal law to engage in such business; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Has not previously violated any statutory duty of a licensed dealer if thaterson earlier was a licensed dealer.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2321.2</num>
    <text>2321.2 The license issued to a firearms dealer shall be valid for a period ofot more than one (1) year from the date of issuance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2321.3</num>
    <text>2321.3 To deal firearms lawfully, the holder of a firearms dealer’s licenseust also comply with any other license or zoning procedures required by law,ncluding having a certificate of occupancy and a basic business license issuedy the Department of
      Consumer and Regulatory Affairs in accordance withpplicable provisions in the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2321.4</num>
    <text>2321.4 Prior to applying to the Firearms Registration Section for a firearmealer’s license, an applicant must first obtain a Federal Firearms Dealer’sicense issued by the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, and Firearms.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2321.5</num>
    <text>2321.5 Each application for a dealer’s license and renewal shall be made on aorm prescribed by the Chief, shall be sworn to or affirmed by the applicant,nd shall contain:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>All information required by § 203 of the Act (D.C. Official Code §-2502.03 (2013 Supp.));</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The address where the applicant conducts or intends to conduct his/herusiness;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Whether the applicant, prior to September 24, 1976, held a license to dealn deadly weapons in the District; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Such other information as the Chief may require including, but not limitedo, fingerprints and photographs of the applicant.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 624 (January 16,009)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 4380, 4385June 5, 2009); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 17215December 27, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>