<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2326</num>
  <heading>RENEWAL OF FIREARM REGISTRATION (§ 24-2326)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2326.1</num>
    <text>2326.1 Pursuant to § 207a of the Act, a registration certificate shall expire three (3) years after the date of issuance, unless renewed in accordance with the Act and this section or otherwise stated in law or regulation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2326.2.</num>
    <text>Firearms registered before January 1, 2011 shall be renewed as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A registrant shall appear in person at the Firearms Registration Section and submit an attestation containing the following information:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Confirmation that the registrant continues to possess the firearm or firearms that were previously registered;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The registrant’s current residential address; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Confirmation that the registrant is compliant with each of the registration requirements under § 203(a) of the Act (D.C. Official Code § 7-2502.03(a) (2013 Supp.)).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A registrant shall also submit to being fingerprinted.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2326.3.</num>
    <text>Registrants subject to § 2326.2 shall be required to renew their registration pursuant to the following schedule based on the registrant’s date of birth:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If born between January 1 and February 15, the renewal period is between January 1, 2014 and March 31, 2014;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If born between February 16 and March 31, the renewal period is between April 1, 2014 and June 30, 2014;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If born between April 1 and May 15, the renewal period is between July 1, 2014 and September 30, 2014;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>If born between May 16 and June 30, the renewal period is between October 1, 2014 and December 31, 2014;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>If born between July 1 and August 15, the renewal period is between January 1, 2015 and March 31, 2015;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>If born between August 16 and September 30, the renewal period is between April 1, 2015 and June 30, 2015;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>If born between October 1 and November 15, the renewal period is between July 1, 2015 and September 30, 2015; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>If born between November 16 and December 31, the renewal period is between October 1, 2015 and December 31, 2015.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2326.4.</num>
    <text>If a registrant fails to renew his or her registration during the renewal period listed in § 2326.3, the registrant shall be subject to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If the registrant renews within thirty (30) days of the end of renewal period listed in § 2326.3, the renewal shall be processed as if submitted on time;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the registrant renews more than thirty (30) days but fewer than ninety (90) days after the end of the renewal period listed in § 2326.3, the registrant shall pay twice the amount of the firearm registration fee listed in § 2331.1; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If the registrant fails to renew ninety (90) days or more after the end of the renewal period listed in § 2326.3:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The registrant’s registration shall be cancelled;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The registrant shall be treated as a new registrant subject to §§ 2305 through 2313; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The firearm shall be subject to § 202 of the Act.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 17215 (December 27, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>