<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2309</num>
  <heading>OTHER DISQUALIFICATIONS FOR REGISTRATION (§ 24-2309)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2309.1</num>
    <text>2309.1 A firearm shall not be registered if the applicant meets any of theollowing conditions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The entry of a judgment or consent order or decree of negligence in anyivil suit concerning the discharge of a firearm resulting in death or seriousnjury to a human being without regard to the filing of criminal charges, or theinding by a coroner
        of negligent homicide, shall be considered an adjudicationf negligence to establish the disqualifier in § 203(a)(8) of the Act. For theurposes of this subsection, “serious injury” shall be deemed to haveccurred where the victim remains in a hospital
        in excess of forty-eight (48)ours;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>[RESERVED];</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The existence of a record described in § 2307.1 showing a conviction whichakes a person ineligible to possess a pistol under D.C. Official Code §2-4503 (2013 Supp.) shall establish that the person is disqualified fromossessing a rifle or shotgun
        under § 203(a)(9) of the Act;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A court record showing the applicant is a respondent in an intrafamilyroceeding in which a civil protection order was issued against the applicant,nless the applicant can demonstrate by a certified court record establishinghat the order has expired
        or has been rescinded for a period of five (5) years;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A court record showing the applicant is a respondent in which a foreignrotection order (as defined in D.C. Official Code § 16-1041(2) (2012 Repl.))as issued against the applicant, unless the applicant can demonstrate by aertified court record establishing
        that the order has expired or has beenescinded for a period of five (5) years;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Arrest records within the five (5) years immediately preceding thepplication, showing that the applicant has had a history of violent behavior.or purposes of this subsection, “history of violent behavior” includes, buts not limited to, arrests for
        violation of D.C. Official Code § 22-407 (2012epl.), regarding threats to do bodily harm, or D.C. Official Code § 22-4042012 Repl.), regarding assaults and threats, any crime of violence as definedn D.C. Official Code § 23-1331(4) (2013 Supp.),
        or any similar provision ofhe law of any other jurisdiction so as to indicate a likelihood to makenlawful use of a firearm;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Two (2) or more violations of D.C. Official Code 50-2201.05b (2012 Repl.) orny law in the District or another jurisdiction restricting driving under thenfluence of drugs or alcohol; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Any other provision enumerated in D.C. Official Code § 7-2502.03(a) (2013upp.).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 23 DCR 8942 (May 6, 1977), incorporatingext of the Proposed Rulemaking published at 23 DCR 7061, 7069 (March 4, 1977);5 DCRR §306, November 1980, Special Edition; as amended by Emergency androposed Rulemaking published
        at 56 DCR 624 (January 16, 2009)[EXPIRED]; asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 4380, 4381 (June 5, 2009); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 17215 (December 27, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>