<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-1300</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 3-1300)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1300.1.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this chapter, a vacancy is deemed to exist in the office of a member of an Advisory Neighborhood Commissioner when any of the following occurs and upon the publication of the notice of vacancy in the D.C. Register:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Resignation of the incumbent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Failure of the incumbent to actually reside in the Single-Member District from which the member is elected and the procedures outlined in § 1304 have been followed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The assumption by the incumbent of another elected public office as defined by D.C. Official Code § 1-309.05(a)(2) (2006 Repl.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Death of the incumbent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Declaration of vacancy by a court;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The successful recall of the incumbent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>When the office of an Advisory Neighborhood Commissioner from a Single-Member District remains vacant after a general or special election, in which case the effective date of the vacancy is the date on which the Commissioner’s new term would otherwise
        begin;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>When the Board determines, through its established procedure for the maintenance of the voter registration roll, that a Commissioner is no longer a registered qualified elector actually residing in the Single-Member District from which he or she
        was elected; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>When the incumbent submits a sworn, irrevocable letter of prospective resignation to the Board of Elections, pursuant to § 1303 of this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1300.2.</num>
    <text>Except when a vacancy occurs in the office of a member of an Advisory Neighborhood Commission pursuant to § 1300.1(h), the Executive Director or his or her designee shall be authorized to certify the seat vacant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1300.3.</num>
    <text>Within ninety (90) days of the date that the Board declares a vacancy, the members of the Advisory Neighborhood Commission area where the vacancy exists shall fill the vacancy pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 1-309.06(d)(6) (2006 Repl. &amp;#038;
      2012 Supp.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1300.4.</num>
    <text>Within five (5) days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays) after the date that the Board declares a vacancy, the Board shall make petitions available for obtaining signatures of registered electors within the affected Single-Member District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1300.5.</num>
    <text>In the event petitions are not obtained by any registered qualified elector within the affected Single-Member District within fourteen (14) working days after petitions have been made available, the Board shall republish the notice pursuant to § 1300.1
      of this chapter in the D.C. Register.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 43 DCR 1078, 1094-95 (March 1, 1996); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 5582 (April 12, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>