<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-1306</num>
  <heading>FORMAT OF PETITIONS TO FILL VACANCIES (§ 3-1306)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1306.1.</num>
    <text>The information required on the petition forms shall be provided in accordance with the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.2.</num>
    <text>The front of each petition page shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the candidate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The office to which the candidate seeks appointment or election; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Single-Member District from which the candidate seeks appointment or election.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.3.</num>
    <text>The front of each petition page shall state that any registered voter residing in the Single-Member District from which the candidate seeks appointment or election may sign the petition regardless of party affiliation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.4.</num>
    <text>No petition form shall be issued by the Board until the information pursuant to § 1306.2 of this chapter have been placed in all appropriate spaces on each page of the petition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.5.</num>
    <text>The back of each petition page shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name, address and telephone number of the person circulating the petition page; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The affidavit of the circulator required under § 1306.7 of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.6.</num>
    <text>The back of the petition page shall inform the circulator of the penalties of conviction for providing false information in the affidavit of the circulator pursuant to §1306.7 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.7.</num>
    <text>Each circulator shall swear or affirm under oath:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That he or she has personally circulated the petition sheet;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That he or she personally witnessed the signing of each signature on the petition sheet;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>That he or she has determined from each signer that he or she is a registered voter, in the same Single-Member District from which the candidate seeks appointment or election; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>That he or she meets the petition circulator requirements set forth in § 1307.1.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.8.</num>
    <text>Signatures appearing on the nominating petition sheets shall not be counted as valid unless all required information is provided by the circulator in his or her signed affidavit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1306.9.</num>
    <text>Each petition shall be accompanied by a Declaration of Candidacy pursuant to Chapter 6 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 43 D.C. Reg. 1078, 1099 (March 1, 1996); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 5582 (April 12, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>