<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2600</num>
  <heading>BOARD OF REAL ESTATE (ยง 17-2600)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2600.1.</num>
    <text>This chapter is adopted by the D.C. Board of Real Estate to protect the public against incompetence, fraud, and deception in real estate transactions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2600.2.</num>
    <text>The Board of Real Estate (hereinafter referred to as the &amp;#8220;Board&amp;#8221;), established by the Second Omnibus Regulatory Reform Act of 1998, effective April 20, 1999 (D.C. Law 12-261; D.C. Official Code ยง 47-2853.01 et seq.), shall be under
      the administrative control of the Mayor through the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs (hereinafter referred to as the &amp;#8220;Department&amp;#8221;).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2600.3.</num>
    <text>The Board shall adopt a seal with the design as the Board may prescribe engraved thereon, by which it shall authenticate its proceedings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2600.4.</num>
    <text>Copies of all records and papers pertaining to licensure, certification, registration, inspections, investigations, and other matters under the jurisdiction of the Board shall be maintained by the Department on behalf of the Board. Copies of all records
      and papers duly certified and authenticated by the seal of the Board shall be received in evidence in all courts equally and with like effect as the original.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2600.5.</num>
    <text>Records kept by the Department on behalf of the Board under the authority of this section shall be open to public inspection pursuant to the D.C. Freedom of Information Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2600.6.</num>
    <text>The Board may meet at least once a month in public session, but shall not meet less than four times per year. The Board shall publish public notice of the time and place of the meeting in the D.C. Register at least one week in advance of the meeting.
      The public has the right to appear before the Board and testify on subjects within the Board&amp;#8217;s jurisdiction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2600.7.</num>
    <text>The Chairperson shall be elected from among the members of the Board and shall have authority to sign all official documents issued on behalf of the Board, after approval by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2600.8.</num>
    <text>Five (5) members of the Board shall constitute a quorum.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2600.9.</num>
    <text>A majority vote of all Board members present and voting is necessary for any action taken by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2600.10.</num>
    <text>Board members may convene in committees of no less than three Board members to carry out specific functions of the Board if the full Board ratifies the actions of the small committees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7335 (September 17, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 6962 (July 29, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>