<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2603</num>
  <heading>LICENSURE OF PROPERTY MANAGERS (§ 17-2603)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2603.1.</num>
    <text>An applicant for licensure as a property manager shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Furnish evidence of having satisfactorily completed an examination approved by the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Submit a completed application on a prescribed form;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Include the applicant&amp;#8217;s business and home addresses, which cannot be a post office box, on the application;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Have the application sworn to or affirmed before a notary public;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Pay the required application fee; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Meet the requirements for licensure set forth in § 2610 of this chapter and D.C. Official Code §§ 47-2853.12(a) and 47-2853.142(a).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2603.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a property manager&amp;#8217;s license who has passed the required examination shall submit an application for a license to the Board with the required fees within six (6) months of passing the examination. An applicant who fails
      to comply with the requirements of this section shall be required to retake and pass the examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2603.3.</num>
    <text>A person licensed as a real estate broker pursuant to § 2601 of this chapter shall be deemed to have satisfied the educational and examination requirements for licensure as a property manager under this chapter, but is required to satisfy all other
      requirements for licensure as a property manager prior to acting as a property manager.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2603.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant may satisfy continuing education requirements by taking distance-learning courses approved by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2603.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant on inactive status who submits an application to reactivate a license shall submit proof pursuant to § 2605.8 of having completed all continuing education credits that the applicant would have been required to take per licensing cycle
      if the applicant&amp;#8217;s license had not been inactive.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 38 DCR 5010 (August 9, 1991); as amended by Emergency and Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 8501 (December 10, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 1108 (February 5, 1993); as amended by Final
        Rulemaking published at 42 DCR 3178 (June 23, 1995); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7335 (September 17, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking at 52 DCR 6962 (July 29, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>