<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2601</num>
  <heading>LICENSURE OF REAL ESTATE BROKERS (§ 17-2601)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2601.1.</num>
    <text>Every applicant for a real estate broker license shall apply for the license in writing upon an application prescribed and provided by the Commission. If the applicant is an individual, the applicant shall include a business and a home addresses,
      which cannot be a post office box number, on the application. If the applicant is not an individual the applicant shall provide a business address, which cannot be a post office box, on the application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.2.</num>
    <text>The proper fees and all required documents shall accompany the application at the time of filing. Each application shall be sworn to or affirmed before a notary public or, if applicable, by electronic signature or other authentication methods as authorized
      by the Council and the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.3.</num>
    <text>All applicants for licensure as a real estate broker shall furnish at the time of filing an application, evidence of having satisfactorily completed the approved course(s) pursuant to § 2606 of this chapter. The coursework shall consist of a minimum
      of 135 clock hours and shall include the following subject areas:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Real Estate Law;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Fair Housing Law;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Real Property Ownership/Transfer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Principles and Practices for Brokers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Agency Relationships/Principles and Practices for Brokers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Real Estate Appraisal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Real Estate Financing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>D.C. Real Estate Licensing Law and Regulations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Code of Ethics.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.4.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § 2611 of this chapter, applicants for licensure as real estate brokers shall furnish at the time of filing an application evidence of having satisfactorily completed an examination, the type and form to be determined by the
      Commission. The applicant must have a passing score of at least 75 on the examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.5.</num>
    <text>Within six (6) months of having successfully passed the required examination, the applicant shall pay the prescribed fee and comply with the filing requirements. Failure to comply with the requirements of this subsection shall require reexamination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.6.</num>
    <text>An applicant for licensure as a real estate broker shall establish to the satisfaction of the Commission that the applicant has met the requirements for licensure as a real estate salesperson.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.7.</num>
    <text>An applicant must have been actively engaged in business as a licensed real estate broker or licensed real estate salesperson in the District or elsewhere for the two (2) years immediately preceding the date on which the application for a real estate
      broker license is filed, or must have equivalent experience acceptable to the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.8.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall accept the following as proof of two (2) years equivalent experience:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Certification by a licensed real estate broker; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Certification by the Real Estate Commission in the jurisdiction where the applicant is licensed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.9.</num>
    <text>As an alternative to the experience requirement of § 2601.8 of this section, an applicant for a real estate broker&amp;#8217;s license shall be deemed to have equivalent experience if the applicant complies with the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Has been licensed and actively engaged in business as a licensed real estate broker or licensed real estate salesperson in the District or elsewhere for at least two (2) years immediately preceding the date on which the application for real estate
        broker&amp;#8217;s license is filed; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the applicant does not have the two (2) years of experience required by paragraph (a) of this subsection, the applicant must have been actively engaged in the real estate business for two continuous years or more prior to the date of receiving
        his or her real estate broker&amp;#8217;s or real estate salesperson&amp;#8217;s license and actively involved in six (6) verified real estate transactions per year in one or more of the following capacities:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Builder;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Investor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Land or Condominium Developer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Attorney; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Related Occupation where the applicant worked at least 1920 hours per year for two consecutive years in a field that is directly related to the acquisition, financing, or conveyance of real estate, or positions in which the applicant has been directly
        involved in real estate business, including serving as the decision-making authority in any of the following positions:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>A loan or trust officer of a federal or state-regulated depository institution;</text>
    </level>
    <text>(ii) A loan or trust officer of a mortgage company;</text>
    <text>(iii) A real estate officer of a corporation, which is not a licensed real estate broker;</text>
    <text>(iv) A title insurance company officer engaged in the closing of escrow accounts and real estate closings; or</text>
    <level>
      <num>(v)</num>
      <text>A real estate property appraiser.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Active engagement under paragraph (b) of this subsection means personal involvement with decision-making authority in negotiating the terms of a transaction, supervising the execution of agreements, managing the purchase or sale of properties, or
        direct involvement in the zoning, subdivision, or other related land use processes.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Where state law requires a person to be licensed to perform an activity listed in paragraph (b) of this subsection, credit shall not be granted for experience obtained without proper licensure.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.10.</num>
    <text>An applicant whom the Commission determines is eligible for licensure as a real estate broker by waiver or reciprocity under § 2611 of this chapter shall, prior to receiving the broker&amp;#8217;s license, pass the D.C. Real Estate Law Examination
      and complete a D.C. Fair Housing course approved by the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.11.</num>
    <text>An applicant for licensure as a real estate broker who is not an individual but instead is a firm, franchise, partnership, association, or corporation may be issued a real estate broker license by the Commission if the Commission finds that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The applicant is properly organized under applicable District and federal law;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Every person, member, partner, trustee, or officer who is engaged in any activity regulated under this chapter is licensed under this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Every employee who will render services regulated under this chapter holds a valid license issued by the Commission; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Every branch office within the District is managed by a real estate broker.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 38 DCR 5010 (August 9, 1991); as amended by Emergency and Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 8501 (December 10, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 42 DCR 3178 (June 23, 1995); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 52 DCR 6962 (July 29, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 5047 (June 11, 2010), as corrected by Errata Notice published at 57 DCR 7207 (August 13, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>