<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2622</num>
  <heading>REINSTATEMENT OF AN EXPIRED LICENSE (ยง 17-2622)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2622.1.</num>
    <text>This section shall apply to an applicant for reinstatement of an expired license issued under the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2622.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant for reinstatement under this section shall file an application with the Board on the prescribed form and shall pay the required reinstatement fee as well as any current assessment for the Fund.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2622.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant for reinstatement under this section shall demonstrate fitness to resume practice by submitting evidence satisfactory to the Board that the applicant has the competency and knowledge of District and federal laws necessary to resume practice
      and that the applicant&amp;#8217;s resumption of practice will not be detrimental to the public interest or the integrity of the real estate profession.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2622.4.</num>
    <text>In making a determination pursuant to ยง 2622.3, the Board shall consider the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The length of time that the applicant has practiced in the District or another jurisdiction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The length of time after expiration of the applicant&amp;#8217;s license that the applicant was not practicing in either the District or another jurisdiction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s violations of any laws;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s present character; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s present qualifications and competency to practice.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2622.5.</num>
    <text>The Board may require an applicant to complete certain educational or training requirements, in addition to any continuing education requirements, prior to or after reinstatement, to ensure that the applicant is competent to practice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2622.6.</num>
    <text>The Board shall not reinstate the license of a real estate broker, a real estate salesperson or property manager who fails to apply for reinstatement of a license within five (5) years after the license expires. Any person who is ineligible for reinstatement
      may become licensed by meeting the requirements for initial licensure under this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2622.7.</num>
    <text>An applicant for reinstatement of an expired license shall submit proof of having completed all continuing education credits required pursuant to ยง 2605.7 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2622.8.</num>
    <text>In an application for reinstatement of an expired license, if the applicant is an individual, the applicant shall provide the street address, not a post office box, for the applicant&amp;#8217;s residence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 38 DCR 5010 (August 9, 1991); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 1108 (February 5, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 42 DCR 3178 (June 23, 1995); as amended by Final Rulemaking published
        at 52 DCR 6962 (July 29, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 5867 (April 19, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>