<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-1101</num>
  <heading>ASSESSMENT OF PUBLIC VEHICLE FOR HIRE OPERATORS (§ 31-1101)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1101.1.</num>
    <text>As provided for in D.C. Official Code § 50-320(d) (2009 Repl.), each public vehicle for hire operator licensed by the Commission shall be assessed fifty dollars ($50) per year upon the issuance or renewal of each operator license identification (Face)
      card issued pursuant to D.C. Official Code §§ 47-2829(e) and (h) (2012 Supp.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1101.2.</num>
    <text>The assessment levied pursuant to § 1101.1 shall be paid by each public vehicle for hire operator licensed by the Commission in addition to the annual license fee authorized pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 47-2829(e) and (h) (2012 Supp.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1101.3.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall collect the assessment levied at the time of the issuance or renewal of the operator license identification (Face) card of each public vehicle for hire operator.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1101.4.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall have deposited into the Public Vehicle for Hire Consumer Service Fund all assessments collected from public vehicle for hire operators licensed by the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1101.5.</num>
    <text>On an annual basis, or at other times as determined by the Commission, the Office of the Chief Financial Officer provide a written report to the Commission of all monies collected and deposited in the Fund.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 8528 (December 28, 1990); as amended by Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Act of 2009, effective March 3, 2010 (D.C. Law 18-111), at 57 DCR 181, 294 (January 8, 2010); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published
        at 59 DCR 3173, 3174 (April 20, 2012); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 14015 (December 7, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>