<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3711</num>
  <heading>LICENSURE BY RECIPROCITY OR ENDORSEMENT (§ 17-3711)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3711.1.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a license by reciprocity or endorsement shall furnish proof satisfactory to the Board that the applicant has paid the applicable fee and:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If applying for licensure by reciprocity the applicant must provide a letter of good standing from a jurisdiction with requirements which, in the opinion of the Board, were substantially equivalent at the time of the applicant’s licensure to those
        of the District of Columbia, and which jurisdiction admits barbers and cosmetologists licensed by the District in a like manner; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If applying for licensure by endorsement the applicant must provide the Board with written certification that he or she:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Passed an examination acceptable to the Board that is applicable to the license sought in the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Has an active certification from a recognized national certifying organization that is listed in § 3711.5 of this chapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Has not been disciplined or otherwise disqualified by the national certifying organization relied upon for the application for licensure by endorsement.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3711.2.</num>
    <text>The Board may deny an application for a license by reciprocity or endorsement to a person against whom disciplinary action has been taken, or who has been convicted of a crime bearing on the applicant&amp;#8217;s fitness to practice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3711.3.</num>
    <text>The Board may interview an applicant under this section to determine whether the applicant&amp;#8217;s education, training, or character meets the requirements of the Act and this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3711.4.</num>
    <text>In addition to the requirements of §3711.1, an applicant for a license by reciprocity or endorsement shall prove to the satisfaction of the Board that the applicant was actively engaged in the profession in the other jurisdiction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3711.5.</num>
    <text>The following organizations shall be recognized by the Board as national certifying organizations acceptable to the Board whose standards for certification are at least as high as the education and experience standards set forth in this chapter for
      the same profession or occupation in the District:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Master Estheticians &amp;#8211; National Coalition of Estheticians, Manufacturers/Distributers &amp;#038; Associations (NCEA).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 7699 (September 12, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 512, 517 (January 8, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>