<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3712</num>
  <heading>APPLICANTS EDUCATED IN FOREIGN COUNTRIES (ยง 17-3712)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3712.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant a license to practice barbering, cosmetology, or specialty cosmetology to an applicant who completed an educational program in a foreign country if the applicant meets the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Submits proof to the Board of an official transcript or notarized copy of the degree, diploma, or certificate indicating that the applicant has completed a barbering or cosmetology program in a country other than the United States and its territories
        or comparable experience and training in other specialties;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Submits evidence satisfactory to the Board of the applicant&amp;#8217;s competency in the English language; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Satisfactorily completes the District of Columbia barbering, cosmetology and special cosmetology examination administered by the Board or its designee, in accordance with ยง3707 of this title.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3712.2.</num>
    <text>If a document required by this chapter is in a language other than English, an applicant shall arrange for its translation into English by a translation service acceptable to the Board, at the applicant&amp;#8217;s own expense, and shall submit a
      translation on the translator&amp;#8217;s official stationery that is also signed and dated by the translator attesting to its accuracy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3712.3.</num>
    <text>The Board may interview an applicant under this section to determine whether the applicant&amp;#8217;s education, training, or character meets the requirements of the Act and this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 7699 (September 12, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>