<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3710</num>
  <heading>WAIVER OF EXAMINATION[COLON] SPECIALTY COSMETOLOGY MANAGER (ยง 17-3710)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3710.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may waive the examination requirement for an applicant for a license as a specialty cosmetology manager who meets the training, qualifications, and experience requirements to practice braiding, manicuring, electrology, or esthetics and who
      proves to the satisfaction of the Board that the applicant has had experience managing a salon that offers braiding, manicuring, electrology, or esthetics on a substantially full-time basis in the District of Columbia for the four (4) years immediately
      preceding the effective date of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3710.2.</num>
    <text>The application for waiver for special examination will be waived within two (2) years of the effective date of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3710.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall demonstrate to the Board that the applicant has been managing a salon that offers braiding, manicuring, electrology, or esthetics, on a substantially full-time basis by submitting evidence satisfactory to the Board that includes
      the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Affidavits from the applicant and three (3) licensed cosmetologists attesting to the nature of the applicant&amp;#8217;s practice during the applicable time period;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An affidavit from a certified public accountant or bookkeeper of the applicant&amp;#8217;s income tax or business records covering the applicable time period; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any other information the Board considers relevant.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 7699 (September 12, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>