<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-3203</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION PROCEDURES (ยง 29-3203)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3203.1.</num>
    <text>Each institution applying for certificate of approval to provide nurse aide training shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>At least 90 days in advance of the scheduled starting date, submit to the Department of Human Services, LTCA, a statement of intent to establish a nurse aide training program; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An application for a certificate of approval which contains the following information:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A statement of purpose;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A statement of need for the training program in the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The proposed program&amp;#8217;s potential effect on existing nurse aide training programs in the area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The organizational structure of the institution showing the relationship of the proposed training program within the organization;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Evidence of financial resources adequate for planning, implementation, and continuation of the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Licensure status of the proposed training facility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The availability of qualified instructors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The number of budgeted instructor positions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The availability of adequate clinical facilities for the training program;</text>
    </level>
    <text>(10) The anticipated trainee population and tentative time schedule for planning and initiating the program; and</text>
    <text>(11) Fee schedules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3203.2.</num>
    <text>The LTCA shall review the application to determine if sufficient information has been submitted to determine whether the program complies with sections 3201-3212.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3203.3.</num>
    <text>The LTCA shall within thirty (30) days of the date of the receipt of a request for approval of certification or the receipt of additional information requested from an applicant:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Advise the applicant of the action taken on the request for approval of certification; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Request additional information from the applicant.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3203.4.</num>
    <text>After reviewing the application, the LTCA shall take one of the following actions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Grant provisional approval of the application if it is found that the proposed program meets the criteria in sections 3201-3212;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Deny provisional approval if the proposed program fails to meet the criteria as stated in sections 3201-3212; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Defer provisional approval, if additional information is needed to make a determination.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3203.5.</num>
    <text>The LTCA shall send a written notice of its decision by mail to the applicant within thirty (30) days of the receipt of all necessary information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3203.6.</num>
    <text>After a provisional approval of the application has been granted, the LTCA shall authorize a visit to the facility by a program evaluation team.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3203.7.</num>
    <text>The LTCA shall appoint the program evaluation team which shall include representatives from LTCA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3203.8.</num>
    <text>The team shall visit each facility to determine if the applicant&amp;#8217;s program complies with sections 3201-3212. The program&amp;#8217;s evaluation may include, but is not limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Interviews with the institution&amp;#8217;s faculty, staff, and trainees;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Inspection of facilities including patient care areas, classrooms, and laboratories;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A review of the records, record keeping procedures, and trainee support facilities; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any other information and assessments as may be relevant to the application.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3203.9.</num>
    <text>Each institution shall cooperate in the evaluation process with the evaluation team by ensuring that pertinent documents are available for review by the team.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3203.10.</num>
    <text>Following the on site evaluation of the facility by the evaluation team, LTCA shall take one of the following actions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Grant certificate of approval to provide nurse aide training if it is determined that the program meets all criteria in sections 3201-3212;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Defer approval if there are deficiencies in the program which may be corrected in a short period of time; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Deny approval if the program fails to meet the criteria in sections 3201-3212.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3203.11.</num>
    <text>Each training program shall have a certificate of approval to operate a nurse aide training program before nurse aide trainees may be admitted to the program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3203.12.</num>
    <text>Each certificate of approval shall remain in effect for a period not to exceed two (2) years from the date of issuance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3203.13.</num>
    <text>Each nurse aide training program shall be recertified with a new certificate of approval every two (2) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 38 DCR 2008 (April 5, 1991).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>