<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-3251</num>
  <heading>NURSE AIDE REGISTRY (ยง 29-3251)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3251.1.</num>
    <text>The Director shall establish and maintain a registry of all individuals who have satisfactorily completed a nurse aide training and competency evaluation program or a nurse aide competency evaluation program approved by the Department, and who have
      been issued a certification of credentials by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3251.2.</num>
    <text>The registry may be maintained by the Department, or the Director may contract the daily operation and maintenance of the registry to a non-state entity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3251.3.</num>
    <text>The registry shall contain the following information with respect to each nurse aide:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Full name, including any maiden name or other surnames used;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Last known address;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Certification number, including indication of type of certification;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Date of birth;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Last known employer, including date of hiring and date of termination of employment, if applicable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Prior employment data if qualifying pursuant to subsection 3200.2;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The date the nurse aide passed the competency evaluation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Current certification expiration date;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Name and address of entity which administered the competency evaluation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Information on any Department findings of abuse, neglect or misappropriation of property, as required pursuant to subsection 3252.11; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Any information required by federal law or regulation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking Published at 38 DCR 2023 (April 5, 1991); as amended by Final Rulemaking Published at 49 DCR 3696 (April 19, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>