<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-3254</num>
  <heading>OPERATION OF REGISTRY (ยง 29-3254)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3254.1.</num>
    <text>The Registry shall be accessible to the public and to health facilities for at least 6 hours per day, Monday through Friday, between the hours of 7 a.m. and 6 p.m. except for District of Columbia and federal holidays. Facilities shall be informed
      of the hours of operation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3254.2.</num>
    <text>The address and phone number of the Registry shall be made available to the public by the Director of the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3254.3.</num>
    <text>The Registry shall orally inform requesters who call for information whether an individual specified by the requester is certified, but shall not disclose further information about a nurse aide except in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3254.4.</num>
    <text>Upon request, the Registry will send written verification as to whether an individual is certified, the date of the individual&amp;#8217;s competency evaluation and the name of the entity which performed the evaluation within ten (10) working days
      of the request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3254.5.</num>
    <text>Names listed in the Nurse Aide Abuse Registry shall be accessible electronically through the Department&amp;#8217;s Internet website.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3254.6.</num>
    <text>The Registry shall disclose all information contained in the Registry within ten (10) working days to any Medicaid or Medicare participating nursing facility, home health agency, hospital, ombudsman, or any other representative of any official agency
      with a need to know, upon receipt of a written request for such information, which must include the reason for the request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3254.7.</num>
    <text>The Registry shall provide the nurse aide with a copy of all information contained in the Registry on him or her within thirty (30) days of the date the individual is placed on the Registry, and within thirty (30) days of the date that any changes
      or additions to the Registry are made. The nurse aide shall be permitted thirty (30) days to correct any misstatements or inaccuracies in the information pertaining to him or her in the Registry.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking Published at 38 DCR 2023 (April 5, 1991); as amended by Final Rulemaking Published at 49 DCR 3696 (April 19, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>