<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-3202</num>
  <heading>TYPES OF FACILITIES ELIGIBLE FOR CERTIFICATION (ยง 29-3202)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3202.1.</num>
    <text>The following types of institutions may apply for certificate of approval to provide nurse aide training:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Private, degree-granting educational institutions operating or incorporated in the District of Columbia which are licensed by the Education Licensure Commission in accordance with the Educational Institution Licensure Act of 1976; D.C. Law 1-104;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Private, non-degree post secondary schools operating in the District of Columbia which are licensed by the Education Licensure Commission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>District public vocational or trade schools;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>District public universities or colleges; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Nursing homes operating in the District of Columbia that are licensed as nursing facilities by the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs, licensed as training facilities by the Education Licensure Commission and have received no adverse
        actions during the preceding two (2) years.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3202.2.</num>
    <text>LTCA shall consider any one of the following as an adverse action which would preclude a nursing home from providing nurse aide training:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A facility&amp;#8217;s participation in the Medicaid or Medicare Program is terminated, restricted or revoked;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A facility, other than a new facility, has received a provisional or restricted license; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A facility is given a provider agreement of less than one (1) year.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 38 DCR 2008 (April 5, 1991).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>