<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-1005</num>
  <heading>ISSUANCE OF LICENSES (§ 31-1005)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1005.1.</num>
    <text>The Chairperson shall issue a license to any applicant who has complied with the requirement of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1005.2.</num>
    <text>The Chairperson shall collect the current license fee for each license issued.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1005.3.</num>
    <text>Each hacker&amp;#8217;s license shall have marked on its face a statement indicating it is valid only for the type of vehicle operation for which it is issued.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1005.4.</num>
    <text>Each license shall contain a number, photograph of the licensee, and any other information that the Chairperson considers desirable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1005.5.</num>
    <text>A person to whom a taxicab operator’s license has been issued shall continue to reside within the Metropolitan Area during the term of the license and shall, no later than five (5) days after the termination of the residence within the Metropolitan
      Area, surrender the license to the Office.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1005.6.</num>
    <text>When the Commission obtains knowledge that the licensee is no longer in compliance with any of the license requirements, the Chairperson may initiate an action against the licensee to revoke or suspend the operator’s license and retrieve the operator
      identification (Face) card.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1005.7.</num>
    <text>Upon successful completion of the initial application process, an applicant shall receive an initial one (l) year hacker license, which shall be a probationary period of licensure. If the licensee is convicted, during the probationary period, of any
      crime for which licensee would not qualify for licensure, the Chairperson may take disciplinary actions including the suspension, revocation, or non-renewal of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1005.8.</num>
    <text>During this probationary period, the Commission shall monitor complaints and violations relating to moral character, customer service, safety, discrimination, including destination discrimination, overcharging, and other consumer-based complaints.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1005.9.</num>
    <text>If the licensee is the subject of multiple consumer complaints, liability findings from Notices of Infractions, or penalties during the probationary period and beyond, the Chairperson may require remedial actions, such as re-taking the operator training
      course or attending an anger management course or cultural sensitivity training, and/or take disciplinary actions including the imposition of fines and the suspension, revocation, or non-renewal of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1005.10.</num>
    <text>Referral of a licensee for remedial action is not appealable and the cost for such remedial action shall be borne by the licensee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 72-13, approved June 30, 1972, 19 DCR 61 (July 24, 1972), 32 DCRR §§ 10.208, 10.209, and 10.210, Special Edition; as amended by Final Rulemaking published by 34 DCR 6704 (October 23, 1987); as amended by Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support
        Act of 2009, effective March 3, 2010 (D.C. Law 18-111), at 57 DCR 181, 294 (January 8, 2010); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 3158, 3163 (April 20, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>