<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-103</num>
  <heading>APPOINTMENT OF ATTORNEY-IN-FACT OR GENERAL AGENT (ยง 16-103)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>103.1.</num>
    <text>Each person covered under this chapter who is a nonresident of the District shall appoint or employ and maintain in the District an attorney-in-fact or general agent upon whom all judicial and other process or legal notice directed to the nonresident
      may be served relative to conduct subject to this chapter or other laws relating to retail installment transactions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.2.</num>
    <text>The attorney-in-fact or general agent appointed or employed under this section must be a resident of the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.3.</num>
    <text>The nonresident registrant shall notify the Department of the appointment or employment and the name and address of the appointee or employee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.4.</num>
    <text>Within five (5) business days after any change in the appointment or employment of the attorney-in-fact or general agent, the nonresident registrant shall notify the Department of the identity and the address of the substituted appointee or employee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.5.</num>
    <text>If a person fails to appoint or maintain a registered agent in the District, or whenever the registered agent cannot with reasonable diligence be found at the registered office of that person in the District, or whenever the registration of that person
      shall be revoked, the Department shall be an agent upon whom any process or other legal notice may be served and upon whom any notice or demand required or permitted by law to be served upon such person may be served.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.6.</num>
    <text>Service on the Department of any process, notice, or demand shall be made by delivering to and leaving with the Director of the Department or the Director&amp;#8217;s designated agent duplicate copies of the process, notice, or demand.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.7.</num>
    <text>If the Department is served under ยง 103.5, the Department shall cause one copy of the process, notice, or demand to be forwarded by registered or certified mail to the last known address of the registrant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.8.</num>
    <text>The Department shall keep a record of all processes, notices, and demands served upon it under this section, and shall record the time of the service and the action taken by the Department under ยง 103.7.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>