<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-116</num>
  <heading>RECEIPTS[COLON] STATEMENT OF ACCOUNT (ยง 16-116)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>116.1.</num>
    <text>When any payment is made on account of any retail installment contract, the seller receiving the payment shall, if the payment is made in cash, give the buyer a written receipt for the payment including the date and amount of payment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>116.2.</num>
    <text>If the buyer specifies that the payment is made on one of several obligations, the receipt shall state the obligation(s) to which the payment is to be applied.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>116.3.</num>
    <text>With respect to other than an open end credit plan, within six (6) months after the execution of a retail installment transaction, and within every six-month period thereafter until the buyer has discharged all obligations under the contract, the
      seller or a subsequent assignee, in addition to any other statements or notices required by this chapter, shall send to the buyer upon written request a statement of account which shall list the following items:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The annual percentage rate or rates;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The amounts, if any, which have become due but remain unpaid, setting forth any charge for delinquencies, expenses of repossession, and extensions; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The dollar amount not due but still to be paid and the remaining period the agreement is to run.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>116.4.</num>
    <text>The buyer shall be entitled to only one statement under ยง 116.3 in any six-month period free of charge. The sum of one dollar ($ 1.00) may be charged for each additional written statement requested by the buyer before supplying the additional written
      statement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>