<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-120</num>
  <heading>DE-REGISTRATION (ยง 16-120)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>120.1.</num>
    <text>If the Director of the Department or his or her designee believes there is evidence to indicate a persistent pattern of conduct by a registrant in violation of this chapter, the Department may give notice to the registrant of the Department&amp;#8217;s
      intent to hold a hearing to determine whether the registrant&amp;#8217;s registration under this chapter should be suspended.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>120.2.</num>
    <text>The hearing shall be scheduled not sooner than fifteen (15) days from the date of the notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>120.3.</num>
    <text>The notice to be given by the Department shall state the time and place for the hearing and the basis upon which the Department proposes to suspend the registrant&amp;#8217;s registration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>120.4.</num>
    <text>The notice shall be served upon the registrant personally or be served by one of the following means:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>By leaving the notice at the last business address (or home address, if there is no business address) of which the Department has been given notice by the registrant; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>By mailing the notice by certified mail to the last business address (or home address if there is no business address) of which the Department has been given notice by the registrant; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>In accordance with ยง 103, if the registrant is a non-resident.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>120.5.</num>
    <text>Notice of the hearing shall be published in the D.C. Register at least fifteen (15) days prior to the date of the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>120.6.</num>
    <text>The Department shall conduct the hearing in accordance with the provisions of ยง 10 of the D.C. Administrative Procedure Act (D.C. Code ยง 1-1509 (1981 Ed.)).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>120.7.</num>
    <text>If, on the basis of the evidence, the Director of the Department or his or her designee is satisfied that the registrant has engaged in a persistent pattern of conduct that is in violation of this chapter, he or she may issue an order suspending the
      registrant&amp;#8217;s registration for such time and under such circumstances as the Department deems proper, including, but not limited to a permanent suspension of the registration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>120.8.</num>
    <text>The Director of the Department is authorized to promulgate rules of procedure to govern such hearings, consistent with the D.C. Administrative Procedure Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>