<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-7607</num>
  <heading>APPROVED CONTINUING EDUCATION PROGRAMS AND ACTIVITIES (§ 17-7607)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7607.1.</num>
    <text>Beginning with the renewal period of 2007, the Board shall only grant CEUs for continuing education programs and activities administered or approved by organizations listed in § 7607.8 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7607.2.</num>
    <text>For the renewal period of 2007 only, the Board may accept CEUs for education programs and activities that were not administered or approved by an organization listed in § 7607.8 of this chapter if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Board determines that the CEUs were sufficiently related to the practice of respiratory therapy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The program or activity was approved by a recognized approving body; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The CEUs were obtained prior to the enactment of these regulations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7607.3.</num>
    <text>The Board may approve a seminar, workshop, or an educational program given at a conference for approved CEU credit, if the seminar, workshop, or program is administered or approved by one of the organizations listed in § 7607.8 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7607.4.</num>
    <text>The Board may approve CEU credit for an applicant who serves as an instructor or speaker at a seminar, workshop, or program that is approved by one of the organizations listed in § 7607.8 of this chapter for both preparation and presentation time,
      subject to the following restrictions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The maximum number of approved CEUs that may be granted for preparation time is twice the number of hours spent preparing for the presentation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The maximum number of approved CEUs that may be granted pursuant to this subsection is fifty percent (50%) of an applicant&amp;#8217;s CEU requirement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If an applicant has previously received a credit in connection with a particular presentation, the Board shall not grant credit for a subsequent presentation unless it involves either a different subject or substantial additional research concerning
        the same subject; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The presentation shall have been presented during the period for which credit is claimed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7607.5.</num>
    <text>The Board may approve the following independent home studies and distance learning continuing education activities:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Publication of an article in a professional journal, publication of a book or a chapter in a book, or publication of a book review in a professional journal or bulletin provided that the article, book or chapter was published during the period for
        which credit is claimed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Internet courses, video courses, telecourses, videoconferences, and teleconferences offered by accredited colleges or universities, or pre-approved by the AARC or MD/DC Society.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7607.6.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant continuing education credit under § 7607.5.(a) only if the applicant proves to the satisfaction of the Board that the work has been published or accepted for publication during the period for which credit is claimed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7607.7.</num>
    <text>No more than eight (8) CEUs may be accepted in any renewal period, or for reinstatement or reactivation of a license, for approved independent home studies and distance learning continuing education activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7607.8.</num>
    <text>To qualify for approval by the Board, a continuing respiratory care education seminar, workshop, or program shall be administered or approved by:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The American Association of Respiratory Care (AARC);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Maryland/District of Columbia Society for Respiratory Care (MD/DC Society);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A health care facility accredited by the Joint Commission on the Accreditation of Health Care Organizations (JCAHCO);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A college or university approved by an accrediting body recognized by the Council on Postsecondary Accreditation or the Secretary of the United States Department of Education; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any of the following organizations provided that the training is related to respiratory care services:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>American Medical Association under Physician Category I</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>American Thoracic Society</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>American Association of Cardiovascular and Pulmonary Rehabilitation</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>American Heart Association</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>American Nurses Association</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>American College of Chest Physicians</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>American Society of Anesthesiologists</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>American Academy of Sleep Medicine</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The Accreditation Council for Continuing Medical Education (ACCME)</text>
    </level>
    <text>(10) The American College of Cardiology</text>
    <text>(11) The American Lung Association</text>
    <text>(12) The National Society for Cardiopulmonary Technologists</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7607.9.</num>
    <text>The Board shall not grant CEU credit for basic life support courses or training, or for CPR courses or training.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7607.10.</num>
    <text>The applicant shall verify that a seminar, workshop, or program is approved by the Board pursuant to this section, prior to attending the seminar, workshop or program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7282 (September 17, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 2396 (March 31, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>