<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2304</num>
  <heading>VARIATION IN QUANTITY[COLON] SUPPLY CONTRACTS (ยง 27-2304)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2304.1.</num>
    <text>A fixed-price supply contract may authorize District acceptance of a variation in the quantity of items if the variation is caused by conditions of loading, shipping, packing, or by allowances in manufacturing processes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.2.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in ยง2304.3, any permissible variation shall be stated as a percentage. The variation may be an increase, a decrease, or a combination of both.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.3.</num>
    <text>Contracts for subsistence items may use other applicable terms of variations in quantity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.4.</num>
    <text>There shall be no standard or usual variation percentage.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.5.</num>
    <text>The overrun or underrun permitted in each contract shall be based upon the normal commercial practices of a particular industry for a particular item, and the permitted percentage shall be no larger than is necessary to afford a contractor reasonable
      protection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.6.</num>
    <text>The permissible variation shall not exceed plus or minus ten percent (10%), unless a different limitation is established by the contracting officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.7.</num>
    <text>In establishing the permissible variations, the contracting officer shall consider the quantity of items to which the percentage variation applies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.8.</num>
    <text>Contractors shall be responsible for delivery of the specified quantity of items in a fixed-price contract, within allowable variations, if any.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1550 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>