<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-600</num>
  <heading>ADMINISTRATION (§ 16-600)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>600.1.</num>
    <text>The primary responsibility for the administration of the licensing program established pursuant to this chapter shall rest with the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs (which is also referred to in this chapter as the &amp;#8220;Department&amp;#8221;).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.2.</num>
    <text>The Department shall perform the following functions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Conduct investigations and public hearings from time to time to determine the need for regulation of additional repair industry categories;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Establish license classifications for consumer goods repair dealers and supervisory inspectors licensed by this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Establish, in its discretion, advisory panels for each repair industry category required by this regulation to serve as technical consultants to the Department and to assist in the preparation of competency examinations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Develop, after appropriate study, a recommended fee system for repair dealer and supervisory inspector licensees for adoption by the Mayor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Devise and administer a competency examination system for the licensing of supervisory inspectors in each repair industry category or specialty covered by this regulation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Establish pursuant to the D.C. Administrative Procedure Act (D.C. Code § 1-1501 et seq. (1981 Ed.)), the necessary rules to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.3.</num>
    <text>License classifications established under § 600.2(b) shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The designation of repair industry specialties within their respective repair industry categories and specific consumer goods repair services within their appropriate specialties; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The type of repair industry license required by each consumer goods repair dealer and the type of supervisory inspector to be required by each such dealer.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.4.</num>
    <text>Each advisory panel established under § 600.2(c) shall consist of three (3) members, who shall be appointed by the Mayor from recommendations submitted to the Mayor by the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.5.</num>
    <text>Two (2) members of each advisory panel shall be representatives of the relevant repair industry category or specialty, and one (1) member shall not be affiliated with any repair industry category but shall have relevant technical expertise.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.6.</num>
    <text>Tenure for advisory panel members shall be determined by the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.7.</num>
    <text>The fee system developed by the Department shall be devised in accordance with D.C. Code § 47-2842 (1981 Ed.), so that the license fee is commensurate with the cost to the District of the inspection, competency testing, and other regulatory functions
      required by this chapter. The fee system shall be structured to fairly apportion these costs among the licensees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.8.</num>
    <text>A person who violates any provision of this chapter shall be subject to a fine or imprisonment pursuant to D.C. Code § 47-2846 (1981 Ed.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>