<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-601</num>
  <heading>COMPETENCY EXAMINATION SYSTEM (ยง 16-601)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>601.1.</num>
    <text>In carrying out the competency examination system function, the Department shall prepare and conduct, at least semi-annually, practical examinations which measure diagnostic and performance ability rather than written and communicative skills.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.2.</num>
    <text>Written components in the tests shall be kept to a minimum.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.3.</num>
    <text>The content of the examinations shall be determined by the Department with the assistance of the appropriate advisory panels.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.4.</num>
    <text>In place of an examination prepared by the Department, the Department may certify the use of privately developed examinations, or other appropriate examinations, for the licensing of supervisory inspectors in any given repair industry category or
      specialty.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.5.</num>
    <text>A competency examination not developed by the Department shall be certified only when it meets the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The exam is conducted at least semi-annually in the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The exam is approved by the Department as a reliable indicator of performance ability, and is reviewed regularly by the Department; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The exam is administered with the participation of the Department or according to standards approved by the Department.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.6.</num>
    <text>If an examination certified by the Department is wholly or primarily in written form, the Department shall make available a practical examination as specified in ยง 601.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.7.</num>
    <text>If more than one examination has been made available or certified by the Department, an applicant shall have the option to choose which examination to take.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>