<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-650</num>
  <heading>PROHIBITED PRACTICES AND CONDUCT (ยง 16-650)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>650.1.</num>
    <text>A licensee shall not make or authorize any written or oral statement which is untrue or misleading; or any oral or written statement which is known to be untrue or misleading, or which by the exercise of reasonable diligence should be known to be
      untrue or misleading.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>650.2.</num>
    <text>Advertising deemed to be misleading or untrue shall include, but not be limited to, advertising which fails to conform to the requirements of ยง 651.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>650.3.</num>
    <text>A licensee shall not fail or refuse to give the customer a copy of the final bill or any document requiring the customer&amp;#8217;s signature, as soon as the customer signs the document.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>650.4.</num>
    <text>A licensee shall not commit any act related to the operation of consumer repair services involving dishonesty, fraud, or deceit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>650.5.</num>
    <text>A licensee shall not follow any course of conduct which constitutes gross negligence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>650.6.</num>
    <text>A licensee shall not make false promises of a character likely to influence, persuade, or induce a customer to authorize the repair, service, or maintenance of consumer goods.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>650.7.</num>
    <text>A licensee shall not aid or abet an associate, employer, or partner in the commission of any of the acts prohibited under this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>650.8.</num>
    <text>A licensee shall not condone or affirm the commission by an employee of any act prohibited by this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>650.9.</num>
    <text>A licensee shall not exhibit a persistent pattern of conduct which departs from or disregards accepted trade standards.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>650.10.</num>
    <text>A licensee shall not fail in any material respect to comply with the applicable provisions of this chapter or the rules adopted pursuant to this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>