<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-607</num>
  <heading>APPOINTMENT OF RESIDENT AGENT (ยง 16-607)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>607.1.</num>
    <text>Each consumer goods repair dealer licensed pursuant to this chapter who is not a resident of the District shall, upon issuance of the license, immediately appoint a resident agent who resides or who has an office in the District, and shall promptly
      notify the Department of the name and address of the resident agent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>607.2.</num>
    <text>The Department shall be notified within five (5) days of any change in the appointment of the resident agent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>607.3.</num>
    <text>All judicial or other legal process intended for the non-resident licensee and related to the scope of this chapter or other laws or regulations relating to consumer goods repair transactions shall be served upon the resident agent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>607.4.</num>
    <text>If a non-resident consumer goods dealer fails to appoint or maintain a registered agent in the District, or whenever any registered agent cannot with reasonable diligence be found at the agent&amp;#8217;s office in the District, or whenever the appointment
      of the agent is revoked and no new agent is named, the Director of Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs or the Director&amp;#8217;s designee (also referred to in this chapter as the &amp;#8220;Director&amp;#8221;) shall be the agent upon
      whom any process or other legal notice may be served and upon whom any notice or demand required or permitted by law to be served upon that person may be served.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>607.5.</num>
    <text>Service on the Director of any process, notice, or demand shall be made by delivering to and leaving duplicate copies of the process notice, or demand with the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>607.6.</num>
    <text>If the Director is served, the Director shall cause one copy of the process, notice, or demand to be forwarded by certified mail to the last known address of the non-resident consumer goods repair dealer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>607.7.</num>
    <text>The Director shall keep a record of all processes, notices, and demands served upon the Director under this section and shall record the time of the service and the action taken.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>