<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-620</num>
  <heading>INVESTIGATIONS (ยง 16-620)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>620.1.</num>
    <text>For purposes of administering, or discovering violations of this chapter, the Department shall be authorized to conduct investigations and hearings that it deems necessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>620.2.</num>
    <text>The Department may at any time during normal business hours inspect records relating to matters within the scope of this chapter of any person subject to this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>620.3.</num>
    <text>If the records are located outside the District, a person subject to this chapter shall, at that person&amp;#8217;s option, either make the records available to the Department at a convenient location within the District or pay the reasonable and
      necessary expenses for the Department to examine them at the place where they are maintained.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>620.4.</num>
    <text>The Department may designate representatives, including comparable officials of the State in which the records are located, to inspect the records on its behalf.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>620.5.</num>
    <text>Each consumer goods repair dealer shall prepare and maintain, at the appropriate place of business, records on each repair job.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>620.7.</num>
    <text>Records of repair jobs shall be available for inspection by the Department under this section for a minimum period of four (4) years and shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A copy of each written estimate, as required by ยง 633;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A copy of each final bill, as required by ยง 637;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the customer ordering the repair work;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A description of the article repaired, including type, serial number, or license tag number in the case of motor vehicles, and other information that would reasonably identify the repaired item; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>All changes of significant identifying numbers.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>