<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-699</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 16-699)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>699.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Consumer goods &amp;#8211; chattels owned and normally used by an individual for personal, family, or household purposes; and those chattels, normally used for personal, family, or household purposes, which are acquired or used for commercial or business
      purposes other than for sale or resale.</text>
    <text>Consumer goods repair dealer &amp;#8211; any person who for compensation undertakes to perform or have performed repair services on consumer goods in the District, unless that person performs those services solely in the course of carrying out his
      or her duties as a salaried employee of an organization or public agency. Persons licensed pursuant to D.C. Code provisions or other federal laws or regulations relating to the rendering of repair services are exempt from this definition unless
      they perform other repair services not covered by the statute or regulation and are otherwise subject to this chapter.</text>
    <text>Customer &amp;#8211; the person who presents consumer goods for repair cost estimates or repairs, or the person in whose name the written estimate and final bill, as defined in ยง 633 and ยง 637, respectively, of this chapter.</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; the Director of the D.C. Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs or the Director&amp;#8217;s representative, agent, or designee.</text>
    <text>Organization &amp;#8211; a corporation, agency, trust, estate, partnership, cooperative association, or individually owned business.</text>
    <text>Person &amp;#8211; a natural person or an organization.</text>
    <text>Repair industry category &amp;#8211; consumer goods repair services which fall into a broad class or into a category of related consumer goods as established and defined by the Department.</text>
    <text>Repair services &amp;#8211; any kind of activity, including labor, performed or agreed to be performed for compensation involving inspection, pick-up, installation, adjustment, servicing, modification, replacement of parts, or improvement of consumer
      goods in the District unless that activity is performed in fulfillment of a long-term commercial service contract with a business or commercial organization.</text>
    <text>Repair specialty &amp;#8211; consumer goods repair services which fall into a subcategory of a repair industry category as specified and defined by the Department.</text>
    <text>Supervisory inspector &amp;#8211; a repair technician, service manager, or other employee, agent or independent contractor licensed under ยง 603 and authorized by a licensed consumer goods repair dealer to ascertain on behalf of that dealer that all
      work performed on consumer goods by that dealer within the supervisory inspector&amp;#8217;s repair industry category or specialty has been performed properly, in accordance with accepted standards of that repair industry category or specialty and
      in conformity with all regulations governing repair services in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>