<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-622</num>
  <heading>DEPARTMENTAL ACTION ON COMPLAINTS (ยง 16-622)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>622.1.</num>
    <text>In response to a complaint filed by a complainant or a class of complainants who failed to obtain relief under ยง 621, or upon its own initiative, the Department may do any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Deny, suspend, revoke or refuse to renew any license issued pursuant to this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Issue a cease and desist order against persons the Department determines to be in violation of this chapter, under ยง 623; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Refer the complaint, when the Department determines that immediate legal action may be necessary, to the Corporation Counsel, who shall seek restraining action, including temporary or permanent injunctions, or initiate other appropriate legal action.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>622.2.</num>
    <text>The Department shall provide notice to the applicant or licensee of its intended action and shall notify the applicant or licensee of the right to a hearing relating to Department action authorized by ยง 622.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>622.3.</num>
    <text>All hearings conducted by the Department shall be conducted pursuant to chapter 1 of Title 17 of the D.C. Municipal Regulations (DCMR) and shall be consistent with the provision of the D.C. Administrative Procedure Act (D.C. Code, Title 1, chapter
      15).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>622.4.</num>
    <text>For purposes of hearings held pursuant to this section, the Department shall have the power to issue subpoenas in the name of the Chief Judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia to compel witnesses to appear and testify or to produce
      all books, records, papers or documents before the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>