<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-943</num>
  <heading>HOT LOTTO PRIZE STRUCTURE (§ 30-943)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>943.1.</num>
    <text>The Hot Lotto® Grand Prize shall be determined on a pari-mutuel basis. Except as provided in these rules, all other prizes awarded shall be paid as set cash prizes with the following expected prize payout percentages.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>943.2.</num>
    <text>Provided the prize pools are fully funded, the fixed prize payments for Hot Lotto® based on a one dollar ($1) bet are as follows:</text>
    <text>Number of Matches Per Play</text>
    <text>Prize Payment</text>
    <text>Prize Pool % Allocated to Prize</text>
    <text>All five (5) of first set plus one (1) of the second set</text>
    <text>Gross Grand Prize Value*</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>52.1188</num>
    <text>52.1188%</text>
    <text>All five (5) of first set and none of the second set</text>
    <text>$30,000</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3.7056</num>
    <text>3.7056%</text>
    <text>Any four (4) of first set plus one (1) of the second set</text>
    <text>$3,000</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4.3232</num>
    <text>4.3232%</text>
    <text>Any four (4) of first set and none of the second set</text>
    <text>$100</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2.5940</num>
    <text>2.5940%</text>
    <text>Any three (3) of first set plus one (1) of the second set</text>
    <text>$50</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2.9542</num>
    <text>2.9542%</text>
    <text>Any three (3) of first set and none of the second set</text>
    <text>$6</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6.3811</num>
    <text>6.3811%</text>
    <text>Any two (2) of first set plus one (1) of the second set</text>
    <text>$6</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4.7268</num>
    <text>4.7268%</text>
    <text>Any one (1) of first set plus one (1) of the second set</text>
    <text>$3</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>11.5214</num>
    <text>11.5214%</text>
    <text>None of the first set plus one (1) of the second set</text>
    <text>$2</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>11.6750</num>
    <text>11.6750%</text>
    <text>* The above reflects the Gross Grand Prize Value; the “Advertised Grand Prize” is described elsewhere in these Rules. The Gross Grand Prize Value amount will be reduced by federal and jurisdictional withholding taxes (if any) that will be remitted
      by the Lottery on behalf of the prizewinner with the prizewinner receiving the residual amount as their Grand Prize payment (subject to offsets). The prize amount reported to the federal and jurisdictional revenue authorities by the Lottery as subject
      to income taxation shall reflect the amount paid to the prize winner (including any offsets) and also the amount remitted as withholding taxes to the federal and jurisdictional authorities (if any) on behalf of the prize winner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>943.3.</num>
    <text>The prize money allocated to the Gross Grand Prize Value category shall be divided equally by the number plays winning the Grand Prize.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>943.4.</num>
    <text>If the prize pools are not fully funded and there are not sufficient funds in the prize pool to pay fixed prizes, the prizes shall be paid pursuant to § 943.5, including payment on a pari-mutuel basis if required.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>943.5.</num>
    <text>The prize pool percentage allocated to the fixed prizes (the cash prize of $30,000.00 thousand dollars or less) shall be carried forward to subsequent draws if all or a portion of it is not needed to pay the fixed prizes awarded in the current draw.
      If the total of the fixed prizes awarded in a drawing exceeds the percentage of the prize pool allocated to the fixed prizes, then the amount needed to fund the fixed prizes awarded shall be drawn from the following sources in the following order:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The amount allocated to the fixed prizes and carried forward from previous draws, if any.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An amount from the Prize Reserve Account, if available, not to exceed the balance of that account.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An amount from the set-aside account, if available not to exceed the balance of the account.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>943.6.</num>
    <text>If, after these sources are depleted, there are not sufficient funds to pay the fixed prizes awarded, the highest fixed prize shall become a pari-mutuel prize. If the amount of the highest fixed prize when paid on a pari-mutuel basis, drops to or
      below the next highest fixed prize and there are still not sufficient funds to pay the remaining fixed prizes awarded, the next highest fixed prize shall become a pari-mutuel prize. This procedure shall continue down through all fixed prize levels,
      if necessary, until all fixed prize levels become pari-mutuel prize levels. In that instance, the money available from the funding sources listed in this chapter shall be divided among the winning plays in proportion to their respective prize percentages.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>943.7.</num>
    <text>Minimum guaranteed prizes or increases offered by the Executive Director pursuant to § 942.14 may be waived if the alternate funding mechanism set out in Subsections §§ 943.5 and 943.6 becomes necessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 2400 (March 5, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 6656 (May 10, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>