<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-932</num>
  <heading>CASH 4 LIFE GRAND PRIZE PAYMENT (§ 30-932)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>932.1.</num>
    <text>Subject to the limitations of §§ 931.3 through 931.5, the Lifetime Grand Prize of $ 1,000 per week, or the share of such prize as determined in §§ 931.3 through 931.5, shall be paid to the owner of a ticket which matches all four (4) winning numbers
      in the single set of four (4) numbers at the top of the ticket and identified as the &amp;#8220;$ 1,000 a week for life&amp;#8221; prize group. A Lifetime Grand Prize payment shall be made as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Term. The Lifetime Grand Prize shall commence on the first Wednesday following the date of the win and shall be paid every Wednesday thereafter for a minimum of 10 years and for no more than the lifetime of the natural person who claims the prize
        and is validated as the winner of the prize. If the Executive Director has permitted an organization or one individual, acting as a single legal entity on behalf of a group, to claim a Lifetime Grand Prize, then the individual or organization
        claiming the prize or a share of the prize shall identify, for the purpose of determining the term of the prize, a single natural person, who is a member of the group. If the winner, or if one or more in a group of winners, is not a natural person,
        then the entity claiming the prize or share of the prize shall identify, for the purpose of determining the term of the prize, a single natural person who is an owner, or shareholder, partner, or beneficiary of the entity claiming the prize.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Estate Claims. In the event of the death of a lottery winner during the minimum 10 year payment period, payment will continue to be made to the winner&amp;#8217;s estate or designated beneficiary until the minimum 10 year payment period is completed.
        Upon the petition of the estate of the lottery winner (the &amp;#8220;Estate&amp;#8221;) to the Executive Director, and subject to all applicable tax law, the Executive Director in his sole discretion, may accelerate the payment of the remaining
        lottery proceeds held to make the payments for the minimum 10 year payment period to the Estate. If the Executive Director makes such a determination, then the remaining securities and/or cash held to fund the minimum 10 year payment period for
        the deceased lottery winner&amp;#8217;s annuitized prize may be distributed to the Estate. The identification of the securities to fund the annuitized prize shall be at the sole discretion of the Executive Director.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Payment. If an individual winner&amp;#8217;s share of the Lifetime Grand Prize is less than $ 100 per week, the Executive Director, in his sole discretion, may elect to pay such winner, in lieu of weekly payments, the winner&amp;#8217;s share held
        in the prize pool held to fund the weekly payments. To continue receiving the weekly payment after the minimum ten (10) years, the winner of the prize must complete and execute an annual winner information form provided by the Executive Director
        which shall include a certification that the winner is alive. If the form is not received by the Executive Director within thirty (30) days after the anniversary date of the win, the Executive Director shall have the option to terminate payments
        or to suspend payments pending a determination of the winner&amp;#8217;s status.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>932.2.</num>
    <text>Except for the Lifetime Grand Prize, all prizes shall be paid in a single cash payment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>932.3.</num>
    <text>All prizes shall be rounded down so that prizes can be paid in multiples of whole dollars. Breakage resulting from rounding these prizes shall be carried forward to the prize pool for the next drawing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>932.4.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director may make changes in the allocation of prize money if he or she finds that it would be in the best interest of the game. Changes in the allocation of prize money shall be designed to retain approximately the same prize allocation
      percentages, over a year&amp;#8217;s time, set out in these rules. Minimum guaranteed prizes may be waived if the alternate funding mechanism set out in §§ 931:3 through 931.5 becomes necessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>932.6.</num>
    <text>The holder of a winning ticket may win only one prize per set of numbers in connection with the winning numbers drawn, and shall be entitled only to the prize won by those numbers in the highest matching prize category per set of numbers. There are
      fifteen (15) sets of numbers per ticket.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>932.7.</num>
    <text>All Cash 4 Life prizes must be claimed within one year after the drawing date. Prize claims submitted after that time shall not be valid and will not be paid.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 604 (January 22, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>