<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-951</num>
  <heading>DC JACKPOT FAST PLAY GAMES (§ 30-951)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>951.1.</num>
    <text>The Agency may conduct Fast Play games called DC JACKPOT to the public and for such time periods as determined by the Executive Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>951.2.</num>
    <text>DC JACKPOT is an instant ticket style game with a Fast Play Progressive Jackpot top prize. The tickets are printed and played through the Agency agent’s online terminal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>951.3.</num>
    <text>DC JACKPOT tickets may be purchased in three (3) different price points: two dollars ($2); five dollars ($5); or ten dollars ($10) per ticket.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>951.4.</num>
    <text>A player wins by matching three (3) like symbols out of the five (5) in a single SPIN across, winning the corresponding prize shown on the PRIZE LEGEND. Each SPIN is played separately.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>951.5.</num>
    <text>The DC JACKPOT price range determines the amount of spins / plays per ticket and the jackpot percentage of the Fast Play Progressive Jackpot received if that Jackpot prize is won.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>951.6.</num>
    <text>The table below summarizes the DC JACKPOT number of spins, chance of winning, and percentage of jackpot that may be won. Section 952 of this chapter states the prizes and the fixed payout levels for each of the three (3) price points: two dollars
      ($2); five dollars ($5); or ten dollars ($10) per ticket.</text>
    <text>DC JACKPOT Price Point</text>
    <text>Amount of Spins per ticket</text>
    <text>Max amount of Wins per ticket</text>
    <text>Percentage of Fast Play Progressive Jackpot Won</text>
    <text>Two Dollars ($2)</text>
    <text>Five (5)</text>
    <text>Five (5)</text>
    <text>20%</text>
    <text>Five Dollars ($5)</text>
    <text>Ten (10)</text>
    <text>Ten (10)</text>
    <text>50%</text>
    <text>Ten Dollars ($10)</text>
    <text>Fifteen (15)</text>
    <text>Fifteen (15)</text>
    <text>100%</text>
    <text>Additionally, the overall odds and PRIZE LEGEND are printed on the game ticket.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 2677, 2679 (March 25, 2011); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 3146, 3148 (April 20, 2012); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 9201 (August 3, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>