<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-920</num>
  <heading>DESCRIPTION OF THE ROLLING CASH 5™ GAME (§ 30-920)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>920.1.</num>
    <text>The Agency may offer a game known as Rolling Cash 5 TM.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>920.2.</num>
    <text>The Rolling Cash 5 TM game is a five (5) out of thirty-five (35) on-line lottery game that pays set prizes for matching two (2), three (3) or four (4) of the five (5) selected numbers. Rolling Cash 5 TM pays a pari-mutuel jackpot prize for matching
      five (5) out of five (5) of the Agency selected numbers. The Jackpot prize is a rolling jackpot with a guaranteed minimum.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>920.3.</num>
    <text>To play the Rolling Cash 5 TM game, a player shall select five (5) numbers from one (1) to thirty-five (35) for input into a terminal. The Agency shall select five (5) out of thirty-five (35) numbers in a Rolling Cash 5 TM drawing. The holder of a
      winning Rolling Cash 5 TM game ticket may win in only one prize category per game board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>920.4.</num>
    <text>The price of a Rolling Cash 5 TM game ticket shall be one (1) board for one dollar ($ 1) or any other price designated by the Executive Director from a price schedule adopted by the Agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>920.5.</num>
    <text>If a single ticket contains more than one (1) winning play on separate game boards, the prize amounts shall be added together and shall be paid in accordance with the prize payment limits set forth in §§ 920.6 and 921.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>920.6.</num>
    <text>The holder of a winning Rolling Cash 5 TM ticket may win in only one prize category per board in connection with the winning numbers drawn, and shall be entitled only to the prize for the highest prize category won by those numbers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>920.7.</num>
    <text>A ticket subject to the validations requirements of this title shall be the only proof of a wager.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 43 DCR 5110 (September 20 1996) and 53 DCR 299 (January 13, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>