<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-941</num>
  <heading>PRIZE POOL (§ 30-941)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>941.1.</num>
    <text>The prize pool for all prize categories shall consist of fifty percent (50%) of each drawing period’s sales, including tax, after the prize reserve accounts are funded consistent with all agreements in place governing the conduct of Hot Lotto®.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>941.2.</num>
    <text>The prize money allocated to the Grand Prize category shall be awarded equally to the number of game boards winning a Grand Prize.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>941.3.</num>
    <text>Any amount remaining in the prize pool at the end of each game shall be carried forward to a replacement game or expended in a manner consistent with all agreements in place governing the conduct of Hot Lotto® and in accordance with District law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>941.4.</num>
    <text>An amount equal to up to one percent (1%) of a Lottery’s sales, including tax, shall be deducted from a Lottery’s Grand Prize Pool and placed in trust in one or more prize reserve accounts when the Grand Prize exceeds $2,000,000.00. An additional
      two percent (2%) of a Lottery’s sales, including tax, shall be deducted from a Lottery’s Grand Prize Pool and placed in trust in one (1) or more prize reserve accounts when the Grand Prize exceeds $5,000,000.00 until the Lottery’s share of the prize
      reserve account(s) reach(es) the amounts designated by MUSL Product Group.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>941.5.</num>
    <text>The MUSL Product Group has established the following prize reserve accounts for the Hot Lotto® game: the Prize Reserve Account (“PRA”), which is used to guarantee the payment of valid, but unanticipated, Grand Prize claims that may result from a system
      error or other reason, and to fund deficiencies in low-tier prize payments (subject to the limitations of these rules); the Set-Aside Account, which is used to guarantee payment of the minimum or starting Grand Prize; the Hot Lotto® Sizzler Rollover
      Account, which is described in Part III of these rules; and the Lower Tier Prize Pool, which holds the temporary balances that may result from having fewer than expected winners in the low-tier set prize categories. The source of the Lower Tier
      Prize Pool funds is the Party Lottery’s weekly prize contributions less actual set prize liability.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 2400 (March 5, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 6656 (May 10, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>