<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-940</num>
  <heading>DESCRIPTION OF THE HOT LOTTO GAME (§ 30-940)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>940.1.</num>
    <text>The Agency may offer a game known as Hot Lotto® to the public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>940.2.</num>
    <text>The provisions of §§ 501.2, 503.4, 503.5, 607.2, 611.1, and 805.1 shall apply to ticket purchase, void and cancelled tickets, ticket validation, and prize payments in the Hot Lotto® game.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>940.3.</num>
    <text>Hot Lotto® is a five (5) out of forty-seven (47) plus one (1) out of nineteen (19) on-line lottery game that pays Grand Prize payments as a cash lump sum payment on a pari-mutuel basis. All prizes are paid on a cash basis. To play Hot Lotto®, a player
      shall select five (5) different numbers, between one (1) and forty-seven (47) and one (1) additional number between one (1) and nineteen (19), for input into a terminal. The additional number may be the same as one of the first five numbers selected
      by the player.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>940.4.</num>
    <text>Drawings shall be held at the times and places established by MUSL Product Group and the results shall be subsequently announced to the public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>940.5</num>
    <text>940.5 If a single ticket contains more than one (1) winning play on separate game boards, the prize amounts shall be added together and shall be paid in accordance with the prize payment limits set forth in §§ 940.6 and 943.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>940.6</num>
    <text>940.6 The holder of a winning Hot Lotto® ticket may win in only one prize category per board in connection with the winning numbers drawn, and shall be entitled only to the prize for the highest prize category won by those numbers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>940.7.</num>
    <text>The price of a Hot Lotto® game ticket shall be one play for one dollar ($1) or any other price designated by the Executive Director from a price schedule adopted by the Agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>940.8.</num>
    <text>A ticket subject to the validations requirements of this title shall be the only proof of a wager.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 2400 (March 5, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 6656 (May 10, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>