<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-5016</num>
  <heading>AUDITS AND REVIEWS (ยง 29-5016)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5016.1.</num>
    <text>DHCF shall perform audits to ensure that Medicaid payments are consistent with efficiency, economy and quality of care and made in accordance with federal and District rules governing Medicaid.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5016.2.</num>
    <text>The audit process shall be routinely conducted by DHCF to determine, by statistically valid scientific sampling, the appropriateness of services rendered and billed to Medicaid. These audits shall be conducted on-site or through an off-site, desk
      review.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5016.3.</num>
    <text>Each Provider shall allow access to relevant records and program documentation upon request and during an on-site audit or review by DHCF, other District of Columbia government officials and representatives of the United States Department of Health
      and Human Services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5016.4.</num>
    <text>If DHCF denies a claim, DHCF shall recoup, by the most expeditious means available, those monies erroneously paid to the Provider for denied claims, following the period of Administrative Review as set forth in ยง 5017 of these rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5016.5.</num>
    <text>The recoupment amounts for denied claims shall be determined by the following formula:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A fraction shall be calculated with the numerator consisting of the number of denied paid claims resulting from the audited sample. The denominator shall be the total number of paid claims from the audit sample; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This fraction shall be multiplied by the total dollars paid by DHCF to the Provider during the audit period, to determine the amount recouped. For example, if a Provider received Medicaid reimbursement of ten thousand dollars ($10,000) during the
        audit period, and during a review of the claims from the audited sample, it was determined that ten (10) claims out of one hundred (100) claims are denied, then ten percent (10%) of the amount reimbursed by Medicaid during the audit period, or
        one thousand dollars ($1000), would be recouped.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5016.6.</num>
    <text>DHCF shall issue a Notice of Proposed Medicaid Overpayment Recovery (NR), which sets forth the reasons for the recoupment, including the specific reference to the particular sections of the statute, rules, or provider agreement, the amount to be recouped,
      and the procedures for requesting an administrative review.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 15537 (November 8, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>