<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-5009</num>
  <heading>PERSONAL CARE AIDE QUALIFICATIONS (§ 29-5009)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5009.1.</num>
    <text>Each PCA, whether an employee of the Provider or secured through a staffing agency, shall meet the following qualifications:</text>
    <text>Be at least eighteen (18) years of age;</text>
    <text>Be a citizen of the United States or an alien who is lawfully authorized to work in the United States;</text>
    <text>Be mentally, physically and emotionally competent to provide services as certified by a physician;</text>
    <text>Be able to accept instruction from an R.N.;</text>
    <text>Be certified and meet all of the qualifications, including training requirements, in accordance with the Practice of Nursing Amendment Act of 2009, effective July 7, 2009 (D.C. Law 18-18; 56 DCR 3624).</text>
    <text>Be certified in cardiopulmonary resuscitation (CPR) and maintain current CPR certification;</text>
    <text>Complete three (3) hours of continuing education at quarterly intervals, in addition to annual CPR recertification and be trained on the beneficiary’s plan of care;</text>
    <text>Be able to read and write the English language at least at the fifth (5th)</text>
    <text>grade level and carry out instructions and directions in English;</text>
    <text>Be able to recognize an emergency and be knowledgeable about emergency procedures;</text>
    <text>Be knowledgeable about infection control procedures;</text>
    <text>Confirm on an annual basis that he or she is free from tuberculosis by undergoing an annual purified protein derivative (PPD) skin test;</text>
    <text>Confirm, on an annual basis, that he or she is free from communicable disease by undergoing an annual physical examination by a physician, and obtaining written and signed documentation from the examining physician confirming freedom from communicable
      disease;</text>
    <text>Pass a criminal background check pursuant to the Health-Care Facility Unlicensed Personnel Criminal Background Check Act of 1998, effective April 20, 1999 (D.C. Law 12-238; D.C. Official Code, §§ 44-551 et seq. (2005 Repl. &amp;#038; 2012 Supp.));</text>
    <text>Pass a reference check and a verification of prior employment;</text>
    <text>Provide documentation of acceptance or declination of the hepatitis vaccine; and</text>
    <text>Have an individual NPI number obtained from NPPES.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 3957 (May 23, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 6643 (July 2, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 1696 (March 10, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published
        at 59 DCR 1760, 1774 (March 2, 2012); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 15537 (November 8, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>