<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-5099</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 29-5099)
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms and conditions shall have theollowing meanings:</text>
    <text>Activities of Daily Living &amp;#8211; The ability to bathe, transfer, dress, eatnd feed self, engage in toileting, and maintain bowel and bladder controlcontinence).</text>
    <text>Advanced Practice Registered Nurse &amp;#8211; A person who is licensed oruthorized to practice as an advanced practice registered nurse pursuant to theistrict of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, effective March5, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99;
      D.C. Official Code §§ 3-1201 et seq. (2007 Repl.#038; 2012 Supp.)).</text>
    <text>Authorized representative – Any person other than a provider:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Who is knowledgeable about a resident&amp;#8217;s circumstances and has beenesignated by that resident to represent him or her; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Who is legally authorized either to administer a resident&amp;#8217;s financialr personal affairs or to protect and advocate for a resident&amp;#8217;s rights.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Department of Health Care Finance – The executive agency of the governmentesponsible for administering the Medicaid program within the District ofolumbia, effective October 1, 2008.</text>
    <text>Family &amp;#8211; Any person related to the client or beneficiary by blood,arriage, or adoption.</text>
    <text>Order – A formal, written instruction signed by a physician or advancedractice R.N. regarding a specific patient’s medical care, treatment oranagement. An order for PCA services may only be written by a physician inccordance with § 5006.1.</text>
    <text>PCA Service Authorization Form – A form that has been developed or approved byHCF that identifies the amount, duration and scope of PCA services and theumber of hours authorized based upon a face-to-face assessment in accordanceith § 5003.</text>
    <text>Primary care physician &amp;#8211; A person who is licensed or authorized toractice medicine pursuant to the District of Columbia Health Occupationsevision Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Officialode §§ 3-1201 et seq. (2007
      Repl. &amp;#038; 2012 Supp.)).</text>
    <text>Registered Nurse &amp;#8211; A person who is licensed or authorized to practiceegistered nursing pursuant to the District of Columbia Health Occupationsevision Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Officialode §§ 3-1201 et seq.
      (2007 Repl. &amp;#038; 2012 Supp.)).</text>
    <text>Staffing Agency – Shall have the same meaning as set forth in the Nursetaffing Agency Act of 2003, effective March 10, 2004 (D.C. Law 15-74, D.C.fficial Code § 44-1051.01 et seq.).</text>
    <text>Start of Care – The first date upon which a beneficiary receives or ischeduled to receive PCA services.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 3957 (May 23, 2003); as amended byinal Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 1760, 1779 (March 2, 2012).Final Rulemakingublished at 60 DCR 15537 (November 8, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>