<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-8303</num>
  <heading>WAIVER OF EDUCATIONAL REQUIREMENTS (§ 17-8303)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8303.1.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § 8303.2, the Board shall waive the educational requirements set forth under § 8302.1 of this chapter for an applicant for licensure who can demonstrate to the satisfaction of the Board that he or she has been performing the
      functions of a pharmaceutical detailer as defined in § 8399 of this chapter on a full-time, or substantially full-time, basis for at least 12 months immediately preceding March 26, 2008.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8303.2.</num>
    <text>The Board may extend the waiver set forth in § 8303.1 up to an additional 12 months for an applicant who was on approved leave under the Family and Medical Leave Act or the District of Columbia Family Medical Leave Act for any portion of the 12 months
      immediately preceding March 26, 2008. The waiver may only be extended by the actual amount of leave taken by the applicant under the Acts up to an additional 12 months.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8303.3.</num>
    <text>To apply for a waiver of the educational requirements set forth under § 8302.1 of this chapter, an applicant shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Submit a sworn statement attesting to the fact that the applicant has been performing the functions of a pharmaceutical detailer as defined in § 8399 of this chapter, for at least thirty-two (32) hours per week for at least twelve (12) months immediately
        preceding March 26, 2008, which shall include:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s employers and contact information;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The time period of practice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The name(s) and contact information of supervisor(s) or professional colleagues, as applicable; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A description of the applicant&amp;#8217;s duties; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Submit two (2) letters of attestation from current or previous supervisors who supervised the applicant&amp;#8217;s work in pharmaceutical detailing and who can attest to the fact that the applicant has been practicing as a pharmaceutical detailer
        for at least twelve (12) months. If the applicant does not have at least two (2) supervisors who can provide letters, applicant may submit one letter from a professional colleague who has first-hand knowledge that the applicant has been practicing
        as a pharmaceutical detailer for at least twelve (12) months.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 9317 (August 29, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>