<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-8308</num>
  <heading>CONTINUING EDUCATION CREDITS (ยง 17-8308)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8308.1.</num>
    <text>A minimum of fifty (50) minutes shall constitute one (1) contact hour.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8308.2.</num>
    <text>For approved undergraduate courses, each semester hour of credit shall constitute fifteen (15) contact hours of continuing education credit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8308.3.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant credit to an applicant who serves as an instructor or speaker at an acceptable program for both preparation and presentation time, subject to the following restrictions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The maximum amount of credit which may be granted for preparation time shall be twice the amount of the associated presentation time; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The maximum amount of credit which may be granted pursuant to this subsection shall be fifty percent (50%) of an applicant&amp;#8217;s continuing education requirement; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The presentation shall have been completed during the period for which credit is claimed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8308.4.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant an applicant who is an author or editor of a published book fifteen (15) continuing education credits, if the book has been published or accepted for publication during the period for which credit is claimed, and the applicant
      submits proof of this fact in the application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8308.5.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant an applicant who is an author of a published original paper five (5) continuing education credits, subject to the same restrictions set forth for books in ยง 8308.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8308.6.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant an applicant who is the sole author of a published book review, review paper, or abstract, two (2) continuing education credits, subject to the same restrictions set forth for books in ยง 8308.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 9317 (August 29, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 2951 (April 17, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>