<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-8300</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (ยง 17-8300)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8300.1.</num>
    <text>Effective, October 1, 2008, this chapter shall apply to applicants for and holders of a license to practice pharmaceutical detailing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8300.2.</num>
    <text>Effective April 1, 2009, a person shall be licensed under the Act before the individual may practice pharmaceutical detailing in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8300.3.</num>
    <text>A person who practices pharmaceutical detailing in the District of Columbia without a license shall be subject to a fine of up to ten thousand dollars ($10,000.00) in addition to the other penalties and sanctions set forth in the Act and the HORA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8300.4.</num>
    <text>Chapters 40 (Health Occupations: General Rules), and 41 (Health Occupations: Administrative Procedures) of this title shall supplement this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8300.5</num>
    <text>8300.5 For purposes of this chapter, an individual shall be deemed as engaging</text>
    <text>in the practice of pharmaceutical detailing if:</text>
    <text>He or she is acting as a representative of a pharmaceutical manufacturer or</text>
    <text>labeler; and</text>
    <text>Communicating in person with a licensed health professional or an employee</text>
    <text>or representative of a licensed health professional located in the District of</text>
    <text>Columbia;</text>
    <text>In a non-conference setting, as defined in this chapter;</text>
    <text>For the purpose of selling, marketing, or promoting a prescription or over-the-counter pharmaceutical product for use in humans, or providing information about a pharmaceutical product for the purpose of selling, marketing, or promoting such product.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8300.6.</num>
    <text>The scope of this chapter shall not apply to representatives who only sell, market, or promote veterinary drugs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8300.7.</num>
    <text>The scope of this chapter shall not apply to the act of providing information about a pharmaceutical product solely for the purpose of conducting or pertaining to clinical trials, investigational drugs, or a Risk Evaluation and Mitigation Strategy
      pursuant to the Federal Food, Drug and Cosmetic Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8300.8.</num>
    <text>The scope of this chapter shall not apply to activities taking place at a conference, as defined in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8300.9.</num>
    <text>The scope of this chapter shall not apply to health professionals</text>
    <text>participating in a conference, as defined in this chapter, including conferences targeting a local audience, solely as a speaker or presenter with respect to his or her area of expertise.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 9317 (August 29, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 2951 (April 17, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>