<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-305</num>
  <heading>LOSS OF ALL OPERATING PRIVILEGES AND SURRENDER OF LICENSE (§ 18-305)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>305.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall drive a motor vehicle on any public highway in the District at any time when his or her privilege to do so is suspended or revoked.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.2.</num>
    <text>Any resident or non-resident whose driver’s license or privilege to operate a motor vehicle in the District has been revoked or suspended shall not operate a motor vehicle in the District under a license or permit issued by any other jurisdiction
      or otherwise during the suspension or after the revocation until a new license is obtained or the non-resident privilege is restored according to the provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.3.</num>
    <text>The Director upon canceling, suspending or revoking a license shall require that the license shall be surrendered to and retained by the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.4.</num>
    <text>Any person whose license has been canceled, suspended, or revoked shall immediately return the license to the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.5.</num>
    <text>The Director, upon receiving record of the conviction of any person of a violation of § 305.1, may extend the period of suspension or revocation for an additional period of the same length.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.6.</num>
    <text>Whenever the license or privilege of a nonresident is suspended or revoked, notice of the suspension or revocation shall be forwarded to the licensing authority of the jurisdiction of the non-resident. For purposes of this subsection, a non-resident
      shall include any person holding a license from another jurisdiction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 72-13 effective June 30, 1972, 32 DCRR § 2.311, 2.312, 2.403, 2.706, Special Edition.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>