<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-302</num>
  <heading>SUSPENSION AND REVOCATION FOR TRAFFIC OFFENSES (§ 18-302)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>302.1.</num>
    <text>Negligent involvement as a driver in any accident which resulted in the death of another person is grounds for suspension or revocation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>302.2.</num>
    <text>Not being physically or mentally qualified to operate a motor vehicle in a manner which will not jeopardize the safety of persons or property, in the opinion of the Director, is grounds for suspension or revocation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>302.3.</num>
    <text>Operating a motor vehicle at a speed in excess of thirty (30) miles per hour above the authorized speed limit is grounds for suspension or revocation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>302.4.</num>
    <text>Commitment by a driver of a traffic violation resulting in an accident for which by order of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, collateral of fifty dollars (＄50.00) or more, or a bond in any amount, is required is grounds for suspension
      or revocation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>302.5.</num>
    <text>Operating a motor vehicle while physically or mentally unqualified to operate a motor vehicle by reason of diabetic coma, or epileptic or other seizure, is grounds for suspension or revocation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>302.6.</num>
    <text>Having been convicted or found civilly liable pursuant to the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act with such frequency of offenses against traffic regulations of the District of Columbia and elsewhere as to indicate a disrespect for traffic
      laws and a disregard for the safety of other persons or property, such fact being established by the point system described in § 303 of this chapter, is grounds for suspension or revocation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>302.7.</num>
    <text>Having committed an offense for which mandatory revocation is required under § 301.1 is grounds for suspension or revocation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>302.8.</num>
    <text>Having been convicted or found civilly liable for a pattern of traffic offenses or infractions over a one (1) year period which indicates a disregard for the safety of other persons or property is grounds for suspension or revocation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>302.9.</num>
    <text>Failure to appear at a hearing for the administrative adjudication of a traffic infraction pursuant to the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act is grounds for suspension or revocation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>302.10.</num>
    <text>Operating a motor vehicle or permitting the operation of a motor vehicle which is not insured pursuant to the No-Fault Insurance Act is grounds for suspension or revocation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>302.11.</num>
    <text>Providing the Director with false or inaccurate information as requested by the Director pursuant to § 411.10 or § 413.12 is grounds for suspensions or revocation</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>302.12.</num>
    <text>Falsely certifying to the Director that a motor vehicle is insured pursuant to the No-Fault Insurance Act is grounds for suspension or revocation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>302.13.</num>
    <text>Being convicted of a violation of the No-Fault Insurance Act is grounds for suspension or revocation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>302.14.</num>
    <text>Reckless driving, as that term is defined in § 9 of the District of Columbia Traffic Act of 1925, effective March 3, 1925 (43 Stat. 1125; D.C. Official Code §§ 50-2201.04), is grounds for suspension or revocation</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>302.15.</num>
    <text>Offenses and circumstances listed in § 13(a) of the District of Columbia Traffic Act of 1925, effective March 3, 1925 (43 Stat. 1125; D.C. Official Code § 50-1403.01 (a)) are grounds for license suspension or revocation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 72-13 effective June 30, 1972, 32 DCRR § 305(a) Special Edition; as amended by § 105 of the District of Columbia Motor Vehicle Act, D.C. Law 1-133, 23 DCR 6770, 6721 (February 25, 1977); by § 604 of the District of Columbia Traffic
        Adjudication Act of 1978, D.C. Law 2-104, 25 DCR 1275, 1321 (August 11, 1978); and as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 30 DCR 4757 (September 16, 1983); and as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 4023 (April 22, 2005); as amended
        by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 846 (Feb 10, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>