<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-306</num>
  <heading>PERIOD OF SUSPENSION OR REVOCATION (§ 18-306)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>306.1.</num>
    <text>The suspension period of any resident’s or non-resident’s driver’s license or privilege to operate a motor vehicle in the District shall be from two (2) to ninety (90) days, at the discretion of the Director, based upon the seriousness of the case;
      except that the period of a license suspension due to point accumulation pursuant to § 303.3 shall be ninety (90) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>306.2.</num>
    <text>The period of suspension for a person whose license or privilege has been suspended and fines and penalties imposed for failure to appear at a hearing for the administrative adjudication of a traffic infraction or for failure to pay a civil fine and
      any penalties or attend traffic school pursuant to the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act of 1978, DC Official Code § 50-2301.01 et seq.), (the “Act”) shall terminate only upon the payment of such fines and penalties, or the successful
      completion of traffic school, or both.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>306.3.</num>
    <text>At the end of a period of suspension a license surrendered to the Director shall be returned to the licensee, subject to the payment of a reinstatement fee of ninety-eight dollars ($ 98).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>306.4.</num>
    <text>The minimum revocation period following a first offense of any resident’s or non-resident’s driver’s license or privilege to operate a motor vehicle in the District for which revocation is made mandatory by law or under the discretionary authority
      of the Department shall be for six (6) months.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>306.5.</num>
    <text>The period of revocation shall be one (1) year following a second offense, and two (2) years following a third or subsequent offense(s), except as provided in §§ 306.6 &amp;#038; 306.7.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>306.6.</num>
    <text>A person convicted of a second offense pursuant to sections 10(b)(1) and (b)(2) of the Act (D.C. Official Code §§ 50-2201.05(b)(1) and (b)(2)) within a 15-year period shall have their license revoked for two (2) years, unless the person is enrolled
      in the ignition interlock program established in § 311 of this Title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>306.7.</num>
    <text>A person convicted of a third or subsequent offense pursuant to sections 10(b)(1) and (b)(2) of the Act (D.C. Official Code §§ 50-2201.05(b)(1) and (b)(2)) within a 15-year period shall have their license revoked for three (3) years, unless the person
      is enrolled in the ignition interlock program established in § 311 of this Title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>306.8.</num>
    <text>Each person whose license has been revoked shall be eligible to apply for restoration of privileges at the expiration of the period for which the privileges have been revoked.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>306.9.</num>
    <text>The Director shall not issue a new license to a resident or restore the operating privilege of any nonresident whose license has been revoked unless and until he or she is satisfied, after investigation of the driving ability of that person, that
      it will be safe to grant the privilege of driving a motor vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>306.10.</num>
    <text>An applicant for reinstatement or a new driver’s license after a suspension or revocation pursuant to §§ 301 or 302 for an alcohol-related offense may be required to pass a breathalyzer test, at the discretion of the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>306.11.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a new driver’s license after a revocation pursuant to §§ 301 or 302 for an alcohol or drug related violation must present written proof from a state certified drug and/or alcohol counseling program certifying:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The applicant has successfully completed a state-certified drug and/or alcohol-counseling program after the date of revocation; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The applicant applied to participate in a state certified drug and/or alcohol-counseling program after the date of revocation, but that the application was denied because the program determined that such counseling was unnecessary.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>306.12.</num>
    <text>Any person whose driving privileges were revoked or suspended pursuant to § 13 of the District of Columbia Traffic Act of 1925, effective March 3, 1925 (43 Stat. 1125; D.C. Official Code § 50-1403.01), and who was approved for a diversion program
      by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, may apply to the Director for rescission of the revocation or suspension action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>306.13.</num>
    <text>If a revocation or suspension was rescinded pursuant to § 306.12, and the driver does not successfully complete the diversion program, he or she will be subject to a mandatory revocation upon a court conviction for the same underlying offense, pursuant
      to § 301 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>306.14.</num>
    <text>If a driver’s license is suspended or revoked pursuant to § 302 of this title and is subsequently revoked again based upon a court conviction for the same underlying offense, the Director may allow the suspension and revocation periods to run concurrently
      or may credit time already spent in suspension or revocation status towards the duration of the revocation based on a court conviction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 72-13 effective June 30, 1972, 32 DCRR § 2.309, 2.310, Special Edition; as amended by Regulation No. 74-17 effective June 29, 1974; by §105 of the D.C. Motor Vehicle Act, D.C. Law 1-133,23 DCR 6720, 6721 (February 25, 1977); and by
        §10 of the Anti-Drunk Driving Act of 1982, D.C. Law 4-145,29 DCR 3138, 3148 (July 23, 1982); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 4399 (June 6, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 5984 (July 25, 2003); as amended
        by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 5029 (May 14, 2004); as amended by D.C. Act 15-704 published at 52 DCR 1700 (February 25, 2005);as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 2065 (March 4, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published
        at 52 DCR 5754 (June 17, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 845 (February 10, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 7218 (September 1, 2006);as amended by D.C. Act 16-488 published at 53 DCR 8675 (October
        27, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 1572 (February 16, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>