<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-510</num>
  <heading>POWER SYSTEM GENERATING PERFORMANCE REPORTING REQUIREMENTS (ยง 15-510)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>510.1.</num>
    <text>The company shall, on the prescribed form, file semiannually with the Commission a report which contains the most current semiannually values of the following power plant performance indices for each generating unit and for the PEPCO system on a system-wide
      average basis. (See Appendix 5-1 for definitions):</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Operating availability factor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Equivalent availability factor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Capacity factor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Heat rate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Forced outage rate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Equivalent forced outage rate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Planned outage rate; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Maintenance outage rate;</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>510.2.</num>
    <text>PEPCO shall also provide additional information to the Commission on scheduled, maintenance and forced outages. For each full outage of twelve (12) hours or longer involving units of one hundred (100) MW or greater capacity, and each partial outage
      in units of one hundred (100) MW or greater which exceed five percent (5%) of net summer unit capacity, the date, type, cause, duration, MW on outage, and corrective action(s) shall be reported semiannually on forms prescribed by the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>510.3.</num>
    <text>The total man-hours spent and total cost of outages (including the estimated cost of replacement power) shall also be reported for each month, on forms prescribed by the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>510.4.</num>
    <text>In the event of a full, unplanned outage of five (5) or more days in duration of any stream electric generating station, PEPCO shall inform the Director of the Commission&amp;#8217;s Office of Engineering by telephone of the outage before the sixth
      (6th) day of such an outage.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>510.5.</num>
    <text>PEPCO shall submit before the tenth (10th) day after the occurrence of any outage described in ยง510.4 a written report to the Director of the Commission&amp;#8217;s Office of Engineering consisting of a statement of the probable cause of the outage
      and either the date the station returned to service or the anticipated date the station will return to service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 29 DCR 5130, 5135 (November 19,1982); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 1568 (March 6, 1987); and by Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 1089 (June 26, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>