<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-522</num>
  <heading>MANAGEMENT AUDITS (ยง 15-522)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>522.1.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall periodically (but not less often than every six (6) years) have a full-scale management and operations audit of the company to determine the quality of the performance of management and identify areas for productivity to improvement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>522.2.</num>
    <text>A major purpose of the audit shall be to ensure that PEPCO&amp;#8217;s efforts to optimize fuel costs and improve its fuel-related operations are not resulting in unjustifiably higher capital equipment or other non fuel expenditures (e.g., maintenance)
      which offset fuel economies or improvements in generating system productivity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>522.3.</num>
    <text>The audit shall include a thorough evaluation of the company&amp;#8217;s management of the fuel procurement process. In particular, the audit shall address the following PEPCO requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Planning for fuel requirements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Internal structure and organization of personnel and how their assignment facilitates the continuing assessment of fuel prices and conditions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Fuel source selection procedures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Negotiation and contracting procedures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Incentives for efficient and economical fuel procurement and utilization;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Impacts of changing environmental policies and standards on fuel procurement planning and fuel utilization;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Research efforts to ensure an effective future fuel procurement strategy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Review of interchange arrangements; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Strategies for identifying and developing cost-effective productivity improvement objectives.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>522.4.</num>
    <text>The Commission may, in its discretion, conduct an evidentiary proceeding to consider the results and recommendations of the audit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>522.5.</num>
    <text>The company shall also submit a copy of any statutorily required annual management audit of PEPCO&amp;#8217;s fuel procurement policies and procedures. The company shall also file with the Commission copies of any other audits of its operations conducted
      by any regulatory body.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 29 DCR 5130, 5140 (November 19, 1982); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 42 DCR 5540 (October 6, 1995).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>