<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-4399</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 20-4399)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4399.1.</num>
    <text>Terms not defined in this chapter shall have the meanings ascribed in § 3 of the District of Columbia Hazardous Waste Management Act, D.C. Official Code § 81302; § 2 of the Illegal Dumping Enforcement Act, D.C. Official Code § 8901; § 2 of the District
      of Columbia Solid Waste Facility Permit Act, D.C. Official Code § 81051; and 20 DCMR Chapter 42.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4399.2.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter and 20 DCMR Chapter 42, the following terms have the meanings ascribed in the subsections below:</text>
    <text>CFR – the Code of Federal Regulations, including the most recently updated volumes and any amendments thereto.</text>
    <text>Department – the District Department of the Environment, or its successor agency.</text>
    <text>Director – the Director of the District Department of the Environment, or its successor agency.</text>
    <text>Regulated Medical Waste – shall mean:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Cultures and stock of microorganisms and biologicals including:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Discarded cultures, stocks, specimens, vaccines, and associated items likely to have been contaminated by them, if they are likely to contain organisms likely to be pathogenic to healthy humans;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Discarded etiologic agents;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Wastes from the production of biologicals and antibiotics likely to have been contaminated by organisms likely to be pathogenic to healthy humans;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Liquid or semi-liquid blood or other potentially infectious materials including:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Contaminated items that would release blood or other potentially infectious materials in a liquid or semi-liquid state if compressed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Items that are caked with dried blood or other potentially infectious materials and are capable of releasing these materials during handling;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Contaminated sharps, pathological and microbiological wastes containing blood or other potentially infectious materials;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Tissues and all human anatomical wastes and all wastes that are human tissue including:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Pathological and microbiological wastes containing blood or other potentially infectious materials;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Organs; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Body parts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Potentially infectious materials including the following human body fluids:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Semen, vaginal secretions, cerebrospinal fluid, synovial fluid, pleural fluid, pericardial fluid, peritoneal fluid, amniotic fluid, saliva in dental procedures, any body fluid that is visibly contaminated with blood, and all body fluids in situations
        where it is difficult or impossible to differentiate between body fluids;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any unfixed tissue or organ (other than intact skin) from a human (living or dead); and HIV-containing cell, tissue, or organ cultures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>HIV, HBV, or Hepatitis C-containing culture medium or other solutions; and blood, organs, or other tissues from experimental animals infected with HIV or HBV;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Sharps likely to be contaminated with organisms that are pathogenic to healthy humans, including:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>All needles, syringes with attached needles, suture needles, and scalpels; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Sharps generated through veterinary practice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Animal carcasses, body parts, bedding, and related wastes:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>When animals are intentionally infected with organisms likely to be pathogenic to healthy humans for the purposes of research, in vivo testing, production of biological materials, or any other reason;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The animal carcasses, body parts, bedding material, and all other wastes likely to have been contaminated, when discarded, disposed of, or placed in accumulated storage;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Any residue or contaminated soil, water, or other debris resulting from the cleanup of a spill of any regulated medical waste; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Any solid waste contaminated by or mixed with regulated medical waste.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Responsible Person – a person who is or has been the generator of hazardous waste, used oil, or regulated medical waste; the owner or operator of a site that contains, or a vehicle that transports, hazardous waste, used oil, or regulated medical waste;
      or a person who by contract, agreement, or otherwise arranges for the storage, treatment, or disposal of hazardous waste, used oil, or regulated medical waste.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 9653 (October 28, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 5586 (June 8, 2007); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 379 (January 18, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>