<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-3180</num>
  <heading>SCHEDULE OF FEES (§ 11-3180)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3180.1.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in §§ 3180.1(e) and 3180.3, at the time of filing an appeal or application with the Board, the appellant or applicant shall pay a filing fee in accordance with the following schedule:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>For an application for a variance, one thousand forty dollars ($1,040) for each provision of the Zoning Regulations from which a variance is requested;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For an application for a special exception:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For a parking lot, parking garage, or accessory parking, one hundred four dollars ($104) for each parking space;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For a child development center or private school, thirty-three dollars ($33) for each full-time or part-time student based on the maximum capacity requested, with a maximum of three thousand two hundred fifty dollars ($3,250);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>For a college or university use, six thousand five hundred dollars ($6,500) for the processing of a new or revised campus plan, and three thousand two hundred fifty dollars ($3,250) for review of a specific building or use within an approved plan;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>For a residential use in the R-5-A District under § 353, five hundred twenty dollars ($520) for each dwelling unit;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>For a community-based residential facility, one hundred four dollars ($104) for each person housed based on the maximum capacity requested (not including resident supervisors and their families), with a maximum of five thousand two hundred dollars
        ($5,200);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>For an office use in the SP District, fifty-two dollars ($52) for each one hundred square feet (100 ft.2) or part thereof of gross floor area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>For roof structures under § 411, two thousand six hundred dollars ($2,600);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>For a hotel or inn in the SP District, one hundred four dollars ($104) for each sleeping room or suite;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>For a gasoline service station, five thousand two hundred dollars ($5,200);</text>
    </level>
    <text>(10) For a repair garage, one thousand five hundred sixty dollars ($1,560);</text>
    <text>(11) For a home occupation under § 203, one thousand five hundred sixty dollars ($1,560);</text>
    <text>(12) For an accessory apartment under § 202, three hundred twenty-five dollars ($325);</text>
    <text>(13) For a theoretical lot under § 2516, one thousand five hundred sixty dollars ($1,560) for the first lot and five hundred twenty dollars ($520) for each lot thereafter;</text>
    <text>(14) For an intermediate materials recycling facility under § 802, five thousand two hundred dollars ($5,200);</text>
    <text>(15) For an antenna under § 211, two thousand six hundred dollars ($2,600); and</text>
    <text>(16) For any other special exception not listed in this section, one thousand five hundred sixty dollars ($1,560);</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>For an application for permission to locate, replace, or expand a chancery in an R-5-D, R-5-E, or SP District or in the Diplomatic (D) Overlay District, or to reconstruct an existing chancery that is destroyed in an R-1, R-2, R-3, R-4, R-5-A, R-5-B,
        or R-5-C District, sixty-five dollars ($65) for each one hundred square feet (100 ft.2) or part thereof of gross floor area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>For an application involving one owner-occupied, one-family dwelling or flat, regardless of the number of variances, special exceptions, or alternatives requested, three hundred twenty-five dollars ($325);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>For an appeal of any decision of the Zoning Administrator or other administrative officer, one thousand forty dollars ($1,040), except that the following appellants shall not be required to pay a filing fee:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A department, office, or agency of the Government of the District of Columbia, including an Advisory Neighborhood Commission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The National Capital Planning Commission; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A citizens’ association or association created for civic purposes that is not for profit; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>For a time extension, a minor modification of plans or a modification of conditions of an order of the Board for an owner-occupied one-family dwelling or flat, one hundred thirty dollars ($130); for all other applicants, twenty-six percent (26%)
        of the original filing fee.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3180.2.</num>
    <text>In the case of an application combining two (2) or more actions described in §§ 3180.1(a) and 3180.1(b), or for an application requesting consideration of more than one alternative, the fee shall be the total of the amounts for each action or alternative
      computed separately.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3180.3.</num>
    <text>A department, office, or agency of the Government of the District of Columbia shall not be required to pay a filing fee for a special exception or variance where the property is owned by the District of Columbia or that agency or is under one or both
      of their jurisdictions and the property is to be occupied for a government building or use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7853, 7920-22 (October 1, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of. Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8572 (October
        20, 2000). Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 3072 (April 6, 2007); as amended by Final Rulemaking and Order No. 09-01 published at 56 DCR 4388 (June 5, 2009); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 9480, 9485 (October 8, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>