<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-1002</num>
  <heading>ADDITIONAL PROTECTIONS FOR VICTIMS OF AN INTRAFAMILY OFFENSE (§ 4-1002)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1002.1.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this chapter shall not apply to rental or leasing of real property used for a dwelling, if the following conditions exists:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The owner or a member of the owner’s family resides on the property in question; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>No more than one family resides independently on the property with the owner but in a separate living unit; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The owner or a member of the owner’s family resides on the property with five (5) or fewer families and the owner or the owner’s family member shares a kitchen or bathroom with a residing family.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.2.</num>
    <text>The provision regarding familial status in this chapter shall not apply to housing intended for and solely occupied by persons 62 years of age or older. Further, the prohibition regarding housing for older persons does not apply to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Housing intended and operated for occupancy by at least one person 55 years of age or older per unit.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>In order to qualify as housing for older persons under this subsection, at least 80% of the units in the housing facility must be occupies by at least one person 55 years of age or older.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.3.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to prohibit any private or government supported educational institution, hospital, nursing home, homeless shelter, youth correctional institution, or other organization, with a bona fide business necessity
      to so do, from limiting occupancy or use of a dwelling on the basis of sex or age.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.4.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this chapter shall be considered to repeal any regulations previously enacted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.5.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this chapter shall prohibit a religious, or any organization operated for charitable or educational purposes, which is operated, supervised, or controlled by or in connection with a religious organization, from limiting the sale or rental
      of housing accommodations to persons of the same religion, or from giving preference to persons of the same religion.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.6.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this chapter shall prohibit a person engaged in the business of furnishing appraisals or residential real property from taking into consideration factors other than race, color, religion, sex, age, marital status, national origin, disability,
      family responsibilities, familial status, personal appearance, sexual orientation, matriculation, source of income, and place of residence or business.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.7.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this chapter shall prohibit discrimination against a person because the person has been convicted under federal law or the law of any other state of the illegal manufacture or distribution of a controlled substance as defined in § 102 of
      the Control Substance Act (21 U.S.C. § 802).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 5464, 5468 (July 15, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 4339 (May 14, 1999), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 2817, 2823-24 (March 19, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>