<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-2904</num>
  <heading>MEASUREMENT LOCATIONS (ยง 20-2904)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2904.1.</num>
    <text>Measurements shall be taken at the following locations:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>At the property line of the property on which the noise source is located, or as close as practicable if there is an obstruction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>At a distance of one (1) meter from any musical instrument or device, or loud speaker, sound amplifier, or other similar machine or device for the production or reproduction of sound, with exceptions as designated in the Act;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>At a distance of twenty five feet (25 ft.) from the outermost limits of a construction site; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>At a distance of fifty feet (50 ft.) from the center line of traffic for motor vehicles.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2904.2.</num>
    <text>The microphone shall be at least three feet (3 ft.) above the surface while measurements are being taken, except for motor vehicle stationary tests which shall be determined.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2904.3.</num>
    <text>The microphone orientation shall be as specified by the manufacturer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2904.4.</num>
    <text>Measurements conducted on private property shall be taken with the permission of the owner or the owner&amp;#8217;s representative, or under the authority of a search warrant or a court order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2904.5.</num>
    <text>Outdoor measurements shall not be conducted in the presence of wind speeds greater than twelve miles per hour (12 mph), nor in the presence of precipitation or fog.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 26 DCR 1499, 1502 (September 28, 1979).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>