<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3214</num>
  <heading>SEAL OF AN INTERIOR DESIGNER (ยง 17-3214)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3214.1.</num>
    <text>Each licensed interior designer shall procure a seal, which shall contain the name of the licensed interior designer, his or her license number, and the words LICENSED INTERIOR DESIGNER-DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA. This seal shall comply in all respects,
      including size and format, with the specimen shown below:</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3214.2.</num>
    <text>Any interior design construction documents, including drawings, plans, specifications, or reports prepared or issued by the licensed interior designer and being filed for public record with any jurisdiction or local building department for the purposes
      of obtaining a building permit, shall bear the signature and seal of the licensed interior designer who prepared or approved the document and the date on which they were sealed. The seal shall be evidence of the authenticity of the document. Interior
      design construction documents bearing the seal of a licensed interior designer shall be accepted for filing by the appropriate jurisdiction or local building department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3214.3.</num>
    <text>No licensed interior designer shall affix or permit to be affixed his or her seal or signature to any plan, specification, drawing, or other document which depicts work which he or she is not competent to perform.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3214.4.</num>
    <text>No licensed interior designer shall affix his or her signature or seal to any plan, specifications or other document that was not prepared by him or her or under his or her responsible supervisory control or by another interior designer and reviewed,
      approved, or modified and adopted under his or her responsible supervisory control according to the rules adopted by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3214.5.</num>
    <text>When the license of a licensed interior designer has been revoked or suspended by the Board, the licensed interior designer shall surrender his or her seal to the secretary of the Board within a period of thirty (30) days after the revocation or suspension
      has become effective. If the license of the interior designer has been suspended for a period of time, his or her seal shall be returned upon expiration of the suspension period. The seal shall not be used for any purpose after the effective date
      of any suspension or revocation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3214.6</num>
    <text>3214.6 The licensed interior designer, when affixing his or her seal to plans, drawings, specifications, or other instruments of services, shall affix his or her name, by manual signature or electronic signature, across the printed image of the seal.
      An electronic signature must be:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Unique to the person using it;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Capable of verification;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Under the sole control of the person using it; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Linked to a document in such a manner that the electronic signature is invalidated if any data in the document is changed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3214.7.</num>
    <text>All plans, drawings, specifications, or other instruments of services shall be identified as interior design documents.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 5441 (May 9, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 9963, 9965 (August 17, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>