<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3299</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 17-3299)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3299.1.</num>
    <text>As used in this chapter, the following words and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Act &amp;#8211; The Second Omnibus Regulatory Reform Act of 1998, effective April 20, 1999 (D.C. Law 12-261; D.C. Official Code § 47-2853.01 et seq.) (2001).</text>
    <text>Aesthetic planning &amp;#8211; The selection of colors, materials, and finishes to appropriately convey the design concept, and to meet socio-psychological, functional, maintenance, life-cycle performance, environmental, and safety requirements.</text>
    <text>Applicant &amp;#8211; A person who has submitted an application for licensure to the Board. Board &amp;#8211; The Board of Architecture and Interior Designers, as established by the Act.</text>
    <text>Building shell &amp;#8211; The architecture of an existing building, including the framework, the perimeter/exterior walls, the building core and columns, and other structural, load-bearing elements of the building.</text>
    <text>Contact hour &amp;#8211; A period of sixty (60) minutes of instruction in a continuing education program. One (1) contact hour equals one tenth (0.1) of a continuing education unit.</text>
    <text>Construction documents &amp;#8211; The detailed drawings that define the work to be constructed. This may include partition plans, power and communications plans, reflected ceiling plans, material and finishes plans, and furniture layout plans, as
      well as elevations, sections and details, along with the drawings of associated consultants.</text>
    <text>Consultations &amp;#8211; Research and analysis of the client&amp;#8217;s goals and requirements, and the development of documents, drawings, and diagrams that outline those needs.</text>
    <text>Design analysis &amp;#8211; Building design based on systematic, behavioral, or user criteria, rather than intuitively developed notions of what is required.</text>
    <text>Electronic signature – A digital authentication process which is attached to, or logically associated with, an electronic document.</text>
    <text>Environmental &amp;#8211; The aggregate of the physical conditions of the interior environment that affects the health and safety of the occupants, including air quality and circulation, temperature control, ergonomic layout, physical circulation
      plan, and related matters.</text>
    <text>IDCEC &amp;#8211; The Interior Design Continuing Education Council.</text>
    <text>Interior design &amp;#8211; A multi-faceted profession in which creative and technical solutions are applied within a structure to achieve a built interior environment. These solutions are functional, enhance the quality of life and culture of the
      occupants, and are aesthetically attractive. Designs are created in response to and coordinated with the building shell, and acknowledge the physical location and social context of the project. Designs must adhere to code and regulatory requirements,
      and encourage the principles of environmental sustainability. The interior design process follows a systematic and coordinated methodology, including research, analysis, and integration of knowledge into the creative process, whereby the needs and
      resources of the client are satisfied to produce an interior space that fulfills the project goals.</text>
    <text>Licensed interior designer &amp;#8211; A person licensed to practice interior design under this chapter who is qualified by education, experience, and examination to affect the function, safety and quality of interior spaces and who renders or offers
      to render interior design services.</text>
    <text>Maintenance &amp;#8211; The ability of a product or material to be kept to its proper condition, and the work required to sustain that condition over the life of that material.</text>
    <text>Manual signature – The handwritten name of a person applied to a document that identifies the person, serves as a means of authentication of the contents of the document, and provides responsibility for the creation of the document and accountability
      for the contents of the document.</text>
    <text>National examination &amp;#8211; The examination administered by the National Council for Interior Design Qualification.</text>
    <text>NCIDQ &amp;#8211; The National Council for Interior Design Qualification.</text>
    <text>Partition &amp;#8211; A wall that does not support a vertical load of a structure other than its own weight, but that may support loads attached to it such as cabinetry, shelving, or grab bars; and that does not extend further than from the floor
      of an interior area of a structure designed for human habitation or occupancy to the underside of the deck of that structure.</text>
    <text>Programming &amp;#8211; The scope of work which includes conducting research; identifying and analyzing the needs and goals of the client or occupant of the space; evaluating existing documentation and conditions; assessing project resources and limitations;
      identifying life, safety, and code requirements; and developing project schedules and budgets.</text>
    <text>Reflected ceiling plan &amp;#8211; A ceiling design that illustrates a ceiling as if it was projected downward and may include lighting and other elements.</text>
    <text>Responsible supervisory control &amp;#8211; The direct responsibility for supervision by a licensed interior designer of the work and the decision making process, i.e., to review, enforce, and control compliance with all design criteria and life safety
      requirements. Each location designated for the practice of interior design must have a licensed interior designer who shall bear the regulatory responsibility for any interior design work at that location. This licensed interior designer must provide
      responsible supervisory control over any non-licensed persons working in the practice of interior design at that location.</text>
    <text>Signature – Includes manual signature or electronic signature.</text>
    <text>Space planning &amp;#8211; The analysis and design of spatial and occupancy requirements, including space layouts and final planning.</text>
    <text>Specifications &amp;#8211; The detailed written description of construction, workmanship, and materials of the work to be undertaken.</text>
    <text>Sustainability &amp;#8211; The use of resources in such a way that they are not depleted; a method of practice or use of materials that is capable of being continued with minimal long-term effect on the environment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3299.2.</num>
    <text>The definitions in § 3399 of Chapter 33 of this Title are incorporated by reference and are applicable to this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 5441 (May 9, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 9963, 9965 (August 17, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>