<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-6006</num>
  <heading>MANUAL TANK GAUGING (ยง 20-6006)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6006.1.</num>
    <text>Manual tank gauging, conducted weekly, may be used as the sole method of release detection only for tanks with a nominal capacity of five hundred fifty (550) gallons or less. Owners or operators of tanks with a nominal capacity of greater than five-hundred-fifty-one
      (551) gallons shall not use this method to meet the requirements of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6006.2.</num>
    <text>Manual tank gauging shall be conducted in accordance with the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6006.3.</num>
    <text>Each tank liquid level measurement shall be taken at the beginning and end of a period of at least thirty-six (36) hours during which no liquid is added to or removed from the tank. The level measurements shall be based on an average of two (2) consecutive
      stick readings taken at both the beginning and the end of the period. The measurements shall be recorded on a form approved by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6006.4.</num>
    <text>The equipment used for manual tank gauging shall be capable of measuring the level of product over the full range of the height of the tank to the nearest one-eighth inch (1/8&amp;#8243;).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6006.5.</num>
    <text>The owner or operator shall suspect a release and follow the applicable requirements of Chapter 62 if the variation between beginning and ending measurements taken in accordance with this section exceeds ten (10) gallons or more between weekly test
      measurements, or an average variation of five (5) gallons or more over four (4) consecutive weekly tests.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 7835, 7871 (November 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7699 (October 1, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>