<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6607</num>
  <heading>REPAYMENT OF BENEFITS (ยง 29-6607)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6607.1.</num>
    <text>For any month or period of months in which an IDA recipient receives both IDA and SSI, he or she shall repay to the District of Columbia:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The entire amount of the IDA payments received if the SSI benefits received for the same period equaled or exceeded the IDA payment; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That portion of the IDA payments equal in amount to the SSI benefits received for the period if the SSI benefits received were less than the IDA payment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6607.2.</num>
    <text>To make repayment, an IDA applicant shall sign an Interim Assistance Reimbursement Authorization form, which:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Permits SSA to send the individual&amp;#8217;s past due SSI benefit payment to the Department; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Permits the Department to deduct from these payments an amount equal to the IDA benefits provided.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6607.3.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of an IDA recipient&amp;#8217;s past-due SSI benefit, DHS shall calculate the amount of the benefit due to DHS as repayment and the amount, if any, due to the IDA recipient.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6607.4.</num>
    <text>The Department shall provide the IDA recipient with a written explanation of the calculation set forth in subsection 6607.3 and shall pay any amount due to the IDA recipient, in accordance with section 1631 of the Social Security Act, approved October
      30, 1972 (86 Stat. 1475; 42 U.S.C. ยง 1382 (g)) and the SSA Interim Assistance regulations, 20 C.F.R. 416.1901-1922.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6607.5.</num>
    <text>If an IDA recipient is determined by SSA to meet the disability requirements for purposes of SSI eligibility but withdraws the SSI application prior to payment of the past-due benefits, the IDA benefits received by that individual shall be considered
      an overpayment and that individual shall be liable to the District for repayment of all IDA benefits received.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 4948 (June 20, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>