<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-3508</num>
  <heading>BOARD (§ 19-3508)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3508.1.</num>
    <text>Each Council shall establish a twenty (20) member Board consisting of the following:</text>
    <text>a. The Elected Officers;</text>
    <text>b. Six Elected Adult Members-at-large; and</text>
    <text>c. Seven Elected Youth Members-at-large.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3508.2.</num>
    <text>The youth members-at-large shall be 17 years and under. At least three (3) of these members shall be male and three (3) shall be female.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3508.3.</num>
    <text>The officers of the Council shall serve as the officers of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3508.4.</num>
    <text>The members-at-large of the Board shall be elected from among the Council’s members immediately following the election of officers in October.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3508.5.</num>
    <text>Each Board Member shall serve for two (2) years or until a successor is elected and qualified.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3508.6.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in section 3508.7, any vacancy among the elected officials created by death, resignation, or other causes shall be subsequently filled by the NPC Chairperson through temporary appointment until an election can be held as provided
      in section 3507.5.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3508.7.</num>
    <text>If the NPC Chairmanship becomes vacant, the outgoing chairperson shall not appoint his successor. If the chairmanship of the NPC becomes vacant for any reason, the Vice-Chairperson shall automatically assume the position of NPC Chairperson, until
      a new election is held in accordance with section 3507.5.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3508.8.</num>
    <text>If a vacancy shall occur on the Council’s Board, the NPC Chairperson shall have the authority to appoint new members to unexpired terms of vacant Board Member seats, except in the case of its Youth Representatives, who shall have the same appointing
      authority and ascending process related to youth activities as their adult counterparts. Any appointment of officers, however, shall be temporary until new elections can be held pursuant to section 3507.5.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3508.9.</num>
    <text>Any Board Member who misses three (3) consecutive meetings of the Board without cause shall automatically cease to be a Board Member and his office shall become vacant. A Board Member shall be removed from office for any conduct deemed detrimental
      and damaging to the Neighborhood Planning Council by a four-fifths (4/5) vote of members present after proper notification of such a meeting to do so as set forth in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3508.10.</num>
    <text>The Board may also act to suspend any Board Member during an investigation, by the same four-fifths vote process, which may lead to his or her removal. Any Board Member removed shall have the opportunity to be heard.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3508.11.</num>
    <text>It shall be the duty of the Council’s Board to conduct its affairs and manage its property. It shall promptly report to the Council’s members all reports and recommendations of its committees and all its actions and deliberations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3508.12.</num>
    <text>Special Meetings of the Board may be called by the Chairperson on his or her own initiative and shall be called by the Chairperson at the request of one-third of the Board or at the request of twenty (20) members of the Council.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 2521, 2526-27 (April 10, 1992).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>