<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-3520</num>
  <heading>COUNCIL OF CHAIRPERSONS (§ 19-3520)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3520.1.</num>
    <text>The Council of Chairpersons shall be the official policymaking body for the Neighborhood Planning Councils. The policymaking responsibilities of the Council of Chairpersons shall include, but not be limited to, prior review of all policies and regulations
      developed for the Neighborhood Planning Councils by the Administrator, CBPA. Approval of policies and regulations will be done in consultation between the Administrator, CBPA, and the Council of Chairpersons.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.2.</num>
    <text>The Council of Chairpersons shall serve as liaison between the Neighborhood Planning Councils and the D.C. Department of Parks and Recreation, Community-Based Programs Administration, the United Planning Organization, and Federal, District and private
      agencies and institutions, with regard to the operation of area programs. The Council of Chairpersons shall coordinate NPC activities on a city-wide basis and serve in any capacity necessary to insure the effective and efficient operation of NPC
      programs and activities. This provision is not intended to abrogate the role and responsibility of the Administrator, CBPA, as liaison to the Neighborhood Planning Councils and the Council of Chairpersons, and to other agencies as appropriate, but
      to define the role of the Council of Chairpersons in relationship to the Neighborhood Planning Councils.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.3.</num>
    <text>The Council of Chairpersons, by majority vote of its members, may take positions and pass resolutions on any issue, legislation, or pending developments that impact on youth in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.4.</num>
    <text>Positions adopted by the Council of Chairpersons may be presented before the Council of the District of Columbia, Board of Education, Congress, or other body deemed appropriate by the Council of Chairpersons.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.5.</num>
    <text>Each NPC shall be represented in the Council by its Adult Chairperson and its Youth Chairperson. In their absence, the ranking elected adult and youth officers present shall represent the NPC.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.6.</num>
    <text>In the event that no elected officer can attend, the NPC Adult Chairperson may designate another adult member to represent the NPC. A youth representative shall be designated by the Youth Chairperson.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.7.</num>
    <text>If by the time of a regularly scheduled meeting of the Council there has been no designated representative from one of the 20 NPCs, then the Council can recognize a member of that NPC who is present and in good standing as the official representative
      for that day.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.8.</num>
    <text>The Officers of the Council shall be an Adult and a Youth Chairperson; an Adult and Youth Vice Chairperson; and Adult and Youth Recording Secretary; and an Adult Corresponding Secretary and Adult Treasurer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.9.</num>
    <text>The Officers of the Council shall be elected from the membership for a term of two (2) years. No more than one officer shall come from any one NPC. Election shall be by majority vote, and voting shall be by ballot. Each officer shall serve until his
      successor is elected and installed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.10.</num>
    <text>Any vacancy occurring among the officers during their term for any reason shall be filled through the election process as outlined in the Council’s Bylaws, at the next regular meeting following the one at which the vacancy is announced.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.11.</num>
    <text>Absences from three consecutive regular meetings shall constitute grounds for removal from office. Notice of such removal shall be given to the officer in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.12.</num>
    <text>The Adult Chairperson shall preside at all regular and special meetings of the Council and the Executive Committee, except as otherwise provided in the Council’s Bylaws; shall keep the membership advised of developments relative to NPC operations;
      shall maintain continuous contact with UPO and government agencies with regard to NPC funding and activities; and shall represent the membership whenever and wherever necessary to promote the best interest of the NPCs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.13.</num>
    <text>The Youth Chairperson shall be under the general supervision of the Adult Chairperson and shall preside over not less than one-third (1/3) of all regular meetings held. The Youth Chairperson shall represent the interests of the Youth membership whenever
      and wherever necessary to promote the best interest of the NPCs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.14.</num>
    <text>The Vice Chairpersons shall serve in the absence of their respective Chairpersons at meetings of the Council, and/or the Executive Committee, and shall assist the Chairpersons in the performance of their duties as representatives of all the NPCs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.15.</num>
    <text>The Recording Secretaries shall be responsible for recording and maintaining the minutes of the regular and special meetings of the Council and Executive Committee, and shall send a copy of the minutes to each NPC Chairperson (Adult and Youth) prior
      to the date of the next meeting and shall perform such duties as may be requested by the Chairpersons. The Youth Secretary shall record at least one-third (1/3) of the meetings during the year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.16.</num>
    <text>The Corresponding Secretary shall notify the Council members of regular and special meetings; notify the Council officers of Executive Committee meetings, and perform such other duties as may be requested by the Chair. In the absence of the Recording
      Secretary, the Corresponding Secretary shall record and distribute the minutes of regular and special meetings and Executive Committee meetings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.17.</num>
    <text>The Treasurer shall keep the financial records of the Council and make reports at regular intervals to the Council membership.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.18.</num>
    <text>In the absence of the Chairpersons and Vice Chairpersons of the Council, the position of Chair shall be filled by the Council officers in the order named in the Council’s Bylaws.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.19.</num>
    <text>The Council shall establish an Executive Committee, which shall conduct the necessary business of the Council between regular meetings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.20.</num>
    <text>The Council shall establish a Publicity Committee, which shall be responsible for all publicity and promotional activities of the NPCs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.21.</num>
    <text>The Council shall establish a Grievance Committee, which shall handle any matter referred to it by the Council and shall report its actions and recommendations to the Council.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.22.</num>
    <text>The Council shall establish a Legislative Committee, which shall be responsible for reviewing the legal and operational documents of the Council and NPCs annually; shall act as an oversight committee for NPC elections; and shall recommend such actions
      as may be necessary pertaining thereto.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.23.</num>
    <text>The Council shall establish a Budget Committee, which shall insure the participation of the NPCs in the development of the annual Fiscal Year budget for NPC support, as per D.C. Law 1-93; and which shall develop and oversee the budget of the Council.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.24.</num>
    <text>Special Committees may be created by the Chair to serve a special need. Such Committees shall be dissolved at the completion of the assignment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.25.</num>
    <text>The Chair of each Standing and Special Committee shall be appointed by the</text>
    <text>Chairs of the Council and shall serve at their discretion.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3520.26.</num>
    <text>Each Standing Committee shall consist of not less than three (3) members. Each Committee shall have youth representation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 2521, 2531-34 (April 10, 1992).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>