<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-3500</num>
  <heading>PURPOSE (§ 19-3500)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3500.1.</num>
    <text>The purpose of this chapter is to provide the Neighborhood Planning Councils’ (NPCs) structure for adult and youth participation in the development, implementation, and evaluation of programs for children and youth in the various geographic locations
      shown on the official Neighborhood Planning Councils Map incorporated herein by reference.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3500.2.</num>
    <text>The Neighborhood Planning Councils shall insure the broadest possible adult and youth participants in its programs and activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3500.3.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this chapter shall be deemed to supersede the powers of the Neighborhood Planning Councils or of their Council of Chairpersons as provided in the District of Columbia Youth Services Act of 1976, codified at D.C. Code §§ 1-2601 et seq. (1999
      Repl.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3500.4.</num>
    <text>Rules in this chapter governing the organization of the Neighborhood Planning Councils are subject to amendment in accordance with the provisions of the uniform constitution and bylaws of the Neighborhood Planning Councils.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3500.5.</num>
    <text>Rules in this chapter governing the organization of the Council of Chairpersons of the Neighborhood Planning Councils are subject to amendment in accordance with the provisions of the bylaws of the Council of Chairpersons.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is section 10 of the District of Columbia Youth Services Act of 1976, D.C. Law 1-93, D.C. Code § 1- 2609 (1999 Repl.).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 2521-22 (April 10, 1992).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>