<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-4609</num>
  <heading>PREPARING SOLICITATIONS (§ 27-4609)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4609.1.</num>
    <text>After conducting market research, when required, the Contracting Officer shall make a determination as to which procurement method identified in section 4614 of these regulations is most beneficial to the Hospital. The Contracting Officer will ordinarily
      prepare a solicitation requesting responses; however, the Contracting Officer may determine to purchase the required goods or services through its small purchase procedures or from a federal or District supply schedule contract, or any other method
      set forth in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4609.2.</num>
    <text>When the Contracting Officer issues a solicitation, its length and contents will depend on factors such as the size of the procurement, the nature and complexity of the goods or services, the contracting procedure to be used, and the contract type.
      In general, however, a solicitation should clearly describe the Hospital’s needs (for example, by providing a statement of work outlining the type of services required or information specifying product characteristics or capabilities) and method
      of award.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4609.3.</num>
    <text>In preparing a solicitation, the Contracting Officer should seek to enhance competition by carefully scrutinizing and eliminating, to the extent possible, any unnecessary requirements that may restrict the number of prospective sources or the range
      of goods or services they can offer. Such provisions may include, for example, technical specifications that unnecessarily limit the competitive field, unnecessarily aggressive delivery schedules, or burdensome terms and conditions that might deter
      smaller companies from competing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4609.4.</num>
    <text>The Contracting Officer may issue solicitations in paper form or electronically. The Contracting Officer may also use oral solicitations where efficient and practical (for example, where the procurement does not involve extensive specifications, detailed
      evaluation criteria, or numerous line items). Oral solicitations shall not be used for contracts that have an estimated value in excess of twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4609.5.</num>
    <text>The Contracting Officer with the approval of the CCO may cancel a solicitation or reject all bids or proposals received at any time before the contract award when the Contracting Officer determines in writing that the cancellation is in the Hospital’s
      best interests.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 8507 (October 8, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 3086 (April 18, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking
      published at 58 DCR 4565, 4573 (May 27, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>