<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-3003</num>
  <heading>SERVICE OF PAPERS; METHODS OF SERVICE; PROOF OF SERVICE (ยง 11-3003)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3003.1.</num>
    <text>Any paper required to be served upon a party shall be served upon that party or upon the representative designated by that party or by law to receive service of papers. When a party has appeared through a representative, service may be made upon the
      representative of record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3003.2.</num>
    <text>Where there are numerous parties to a proceeding, the Commission may designate representative parties or make other special provisions regarding the service of papers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3003.3.</num>
    <text>Service may be made and shall be considered complete as indicated in paragraphs (a) through (f) of this subsection, or as otherwise authorized by law:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>By personal delivery, on handing the paper to the person to be served, or leaving it at that person&amp;#8217;s office with that person&amp;#8217;s clerk or other person in charge or, if there is no one in charge, by leaving it in a conspicuous
        place in the office; or, if the office is closed or the person to be served has no office, by leaving it at that person&amp;#8217;s usual place of residence with some person of suitable age and discretion then residing in that place;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>By telegram or mailgram, when deposited with a telegram or mailgram company, properly addressed and with charges prepaid;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>By first-class mail, when deposited in the United States mail, properly stamped and addressed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>By telecopy or FAX, when telecopied with the proper telephone number of the intended recipient&amp;#8217;s telecopier;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>By e-mail, when transmitted electronically, properly addressed to the attention of the intended recipient, with the proper e-mail address; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>In any specific manner prescribed by the Commission in a proceeding.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3003.4.</num>
    <text>Proof of service, stating the name and address of the person on whom the document was served and the manner and date of service, shall be shown for each document filed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3003.5.</num>
    <text>Proof of service may be made by any of the following means:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Written acknowledgement of the party served or that party&amp;#8217;s attorney of record;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The certificate of the attorney of record if the attorney made the service; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The certificate of the person making the service.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7855, 7857-58 (October 1, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8538-39 (October
        20, 2000); and Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 2742, 2748 (March 22, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>