<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6408</num>
  <heading>PROVIDER QUALIFICATIONS (ยง 29-6408)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6408.1.</num>
    <text>Each provider shall enter into a provider agreement with the DOH, Medical Assistance Administration, which shall specify the services to be provided, methods of operation, and financial and legal requirements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6408.2.</num>
    <text>Each provider shall furnish the necessary personnel, facilities, equipment, material, and supplies to provide comprehensive Medicaid benefit package services as required pursuant to these rules. Each provider shall have a demonstrated ability to comply
      with all District and federal laws and rules governing participation of providers in the District of Columbia Medicaid Program, including the ability to meet all District and federal requirements for documentation, billing, and audits.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6408.3.</num>
    <text>Each provider shall comply with the requirements set forth in the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revisions Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code ยง3-1201 et. seq.) or comply with the licensure requirements
      to provide health or medical services in the jurisdiction where the services are rendered.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6408.4.</num>
    <text>All providers participating in the Demonstration Project shall be licensed to do business in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6408.5.</num>
    <text>Each provider participating in the Demonstration Project shall ensure that all staff providing services to waiver participants are qualified and properly supervised.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6408.6.</num>
    <text>Each provider shall establish and adhere to policies and procedures for selection and hiring of staff, including but not limited to requiring:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Evidence of licensure, certification, or registration required by the job being performed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For unlicensed staff, evidence of completion of an appropriate degree, training program, or credentials;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Appropriate references and criminal background checks; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Evidence of completion of communicable disease testing as required by District laws and rules.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6408.7.</num>
    <text>Each provider shall comply with all applicable provisions of District and Federal law and rules pertaining to Title XIX of the Social Security Act, and all District and federal law and rules applicable to the services or activity provided.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Emergency Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 5605 (May 28, 2004) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 7435 (July 30, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>