<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-1903</num>
  <heading>STREET FRONTAGE DESIGN REQUIREMENTS (ARTS) (§ 11-1903)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1903.1.</num>
    <text>The design requirements of §§ 1903.2 through 1903.4 shall apply to any lot that fronts on one or more of the following streets, hereafter referred to in this section as &amp;#8220;pedestrian streets&amp;#8221;:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Fourteenth Street;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>U Street;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Seventh Street; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Florida Avenue between 7th and 9th Streets.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1903.2.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of § 2117.8(c)(1), no driveway that provides access from a pedestrian street to required parking spaces or loading berths shall be permitted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1903.3.</num>
    <text>Each new building on a lot that fronts on a pedestrian street shall be designed and built so that not less than seventy-five percent (75%) of the streetwall(s) to a height of not less than fifteen feet (15 ft.) shall be constructed to the property
      line between the subject lot and the abutting street right-of-way.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1903.4.</num>
    <text>Not less than fifty percent (50%) of the surface area of the streetwall(s) at the ground level of each building on a lot that fronts on a pedestrian street shall be devoted to display windows and to entrances to commercial uses or to the building;
      provided:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The windows shall use clear or low-emissivity glass, except for decorative or architectural accent; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Entrances to the building, including entrances to shops and the main lobby, shall be separated by not more than forty feet (40 ft.) on average for the linear frontage of the building.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 1392, 1397 (February 23, 1990); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 8323, 8325 (November 13, 1992); and Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference
        the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8492 (October 20, 2000); as corrected by Errata Notice published at 58 DCR 4314, 4316 (May 20, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>