<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-2799</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 15-2799)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2799.1</num>
    <text>2799.1 When used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall havehe meaning ascribed:</text>
    <text>Abandonment of Certification Application &amp;#8211; an application to abandon theertification to operate as a CLEC in the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Abandonment of Service Application &amp;#8211; an application to abandonrovisioning of telecommunications services in the District, either in whole orn part (including, but not limited to, for a class of customers {such asesidential customers or business
      customers} or customers located in specifiedeographic areas).</text>
    <text>Access line &amp;#8211; a telecommunications channel of varying size that isssociated with a particular telephone number.</text>
    <text>Applicant _ a CLEC filing an abandonment of certification or an abandonment ofervice application.</text>
    <text>Business customer &amp;#8211; a customer who subscribes to a telecommunicationservice provider’s business services.</text>
    <text>Clearing &amp;#8211; that the telecommunications service provider has restored theervice to the customer, so the out-of-service problem no longer exists.</text>
    <text>Commission &amp;#8211; the Public Service Commission of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Competitive Local Exchange Carrier (CLEC) &amp;#8211; any provider ofelecommunications service that was not an incumbent local exchange carrier onanuary 31, 1996, and has been granted certification to provideelecommunications services in the District
      of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Customer trouble report &amp;#8211; a report of trouble on a customer’s accessine received by the telecommunications service provider. The customer troubleeport can be filed by the customer, a third party, or an employee of theelecommunications service
      provider.</text>
    <text>Days &amp;#8211; calendar days, unless otherwise provided.</text>
    <text>FCC &amp;#8211; Federal Communications Commission.</text>
    <text>Incumbent local exchange carrier &amp;#8211; with respect to an area, the localxchange carrier or its successor(s) that provided local exchange service inuch an area on the date of enactment of the federal Telecommunications Act of996 (P.L. 104-104).</text>
    <text>Installation date &amp;#8211; the date set by the telecommunications servicerovider by which an installation of an access line is to be completed.</text>
    <text>Local Exchange Service &amp;#8211; a telecommunications service provided within anxchange area.</text>
    <text>Local Exchange Carrier &amp;#8211; a provider of local exchange service within anxchange area.</text>
    <text>NENA standards &amp;#8211; the standards adopted by the National Emergency Numberssociation to provide guidance with 911 and E911 technical and operationalssues.</text>
    <text>Out-of-service &amp;#8211; a condition in which the customer either cannot completeutgoing calls or receive incoming calls or where interference makes connectedalls incomprehensible.</text>
    <text>Outage report &amp;#8211; a report to the telecommunications service provider of anut-of-service condition.</text>
    <text>Residential customer _ a customer who subscribes to a telecommunications servicerovider’s residential services.</text>
    <text>Retail Quality of Service Measures &amp;#8211; the measures used to evaluateelecommunications service providers’ quality of service to retail customers.</text>
    <text>Service outage &amp;#8211; an outage that lasts for at least thirty (30) minutes andffects one hundred (100) or more retail customers or one hundred (100) or moreetail access lines. This definition includes an outage affecting the Districtf Columbia’s
      PSAP in one of the following ways:</text>
    <text>A loss of communications to the District of Columbia’s PSAP that is neither onhe premises of the PSAP nor caused by the PSAP and no rerouting of calls isvailable;</text>
    <text>A loss of E911 call processing capabilities in at least one (1) of the E911elective routers/tandems;</text>
    <text>Isolation of end-office switches or host/remote clusters from E911 service; or</text>
    <text>loss of associated number and associated location information and/or a failuref location determination equipment that is neither on the premises of the PSAP</text>
    <text>nor caused by the PSAP.</text>
    <text>Tariff &amp;#8211; a written schedule that describes the service being offered,ists all terms and conditions, and specifies the rate or rates charged for theervice.</text>
    <text>Telecommunications &amp;#8211; the transmission, between or among points specifiedy the user, of information of the user&amp;#8217;s choosing, without change in theorm or content of the information as sent and received.</text>
    <text>Telecommunications industry &amp;#8211; communications businesses using regulated ornregulated facilities or services and includes broadcasting,elecommunications, cable, computer data transmission, software, programming,dvanced messaging and electronics.</text>
    <text>Telecommunications service _ the offering of telecommunications for a feeirectly to the public or to such classes of users as to be effectivelyvailable to the public, regardless of the facilities used.</text>
    <text>Telecommunications service provider &amp;#8211; an entity that provideselecommunications services. An entity that provides only telecommunicationservices that are not regulated by the Commission is not included in thisefinition.</text>
    <text>Trouble &amp;#8211; an impairment of the telephone network, or a deviation from itsesign specifications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 4664, 4670 (May 25, 2001); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR10016 (October 29, 2004); asmended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 9020, 9041 (October1, 2011); as amended by Notice
        of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 781, 785February 3, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>