<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-1000</num>
  <heading>SWEEPSTAKES, BONUS AND PROMOTIONAL GAMES (§ 30-1000)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1000.1.</num>
    <text>The Agency may conduct sweepstakes, contests, bonus games, second chance drawings, or other promotional games and campaigns.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.2.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of Chapters 5 through 10, the term &amp;#8220;sweepstakes&amp;#8221; shall include all promotional games and devices in which chance is the dominant factor in determining the allocation of a prizes and in which there is no element
      of consideration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.3.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of Chapters 5 through 10, the term &amp;#8220;bonus games&amp;#8221; shall mean any game or drawing which is based in whole or in part on any other lottery game(s) without additional cash consideration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.4.</num>
    <text>For purposes of Chapters 5 through 10, promotional campaigns shall include, but not limited to, all promotional schemes based on lottery games, cross-promotions, coupons, redemptions, free tickets, free merchandise, or merchandise prizes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.5.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director shall issue instructions governing the terms and conditions of bonus games, contests, sweepstakes, and other promotional games or campaigns authorized by this section. The instructions shall be issued and made available to agents
      and the public in the same manner as the instructions required by Chapters 7 and 8.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.6.</num>
    <text>The promotional games, contests, sweepstakes, campaigns, or devices authorized by this section shall be subject to the provisions of §§613 and 614 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.7.</num>
    <text>The final determination of the winner or award of prizes or merchandise or other thing of value, in any promotional game, contest, sweepstakes or other promotional devices authorized by this section rests solely with the Executive Director. The provisions
      of Chapter 4 of this title shall not be applicable to this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.8.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director may, without amending the applicable game rules, conduct promotional campaigns in which prize payouts in any on-line game are increased for a period of ninety (90) days or less. Payment of the prize shall be governed by instructions
      issued pursuant to § 1000.5.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 7439, 7464 (October 2, 1992); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 6959, 6962 (October 1, 1993).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL NOTE</heading>
      <text>Prior to October 2, 1992, the D.C. Lottery and Charitable Games Control Board published Final Rulemakings at 29 DCR 4885 (November 5, 1982); and at 36 DCR 6681 (September 22, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>