<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-1503</num>
  <heading>PROHIBITED ACTIVITIES (§ 19-1503)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1503.1.</num>
    <text>It shall be unlawful to do any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Introduce any species of fish or other aquatic organism not indigenous to the District of Columbia into the waters of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Possess a fish with a total length less than the minimum set in § 1504;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Possess a number of fish of a particular species greater than the possession limit set in § 1504;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Possess aboard any boat, while fishing or while in possession of fishing equipment, any fish for which a size or weight limit is prescribed in § 1504 from which the head or tail has been removed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Capture, harass, harm, or fail to return to the water immediately any organism which is listed by U.S. Department of Interior as endangered or threatened except for direct application under § 1501.4;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Take, kill or injure fish or other aquatic organisms by the use of explosives, chemicals, firearms, or electricity, except for direct application under §1501.4;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Take, catch, or possess any species of Sturgeon, Striped Bass (Morone saxatilis), American Shad (Alosa sapidissima), Hickory Shad (Alosa mediocris), Chain Pickerel (Esox niger), and Northern Pike (Esox lucius), unless a special season is posted
        by the Department;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Take fish except as specified in this chapter; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Take, catch or possess striped bass or hybrid striped bass.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1503.2.</num>
    <text>Nets of any kind shall be prohibited in Rock Creek Park for catching fish.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1503.3.</num>
    <text>Digging for bait in Rock Creek Park shall be prohibited.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 2028, 2030 (March 27, 1987); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 5650 (August 4, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 D.C. Reg. 3361 (May 12, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>