<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-401</num>
  <heading>MARKET SPACE FEES (§ 24-401)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>401.1.</num>
    <text>The Director of the D.C. Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs, the Director&amp;#8217;s designee, or some other person designated by the owners of the farmers&amp;#8217; market houses for that purpose, may collect forty cents (40¢) from each
      farmer for each of the spaces the farmer occupies each day.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.2.</num>
    <text>At the time of making each collection of forty cents (40¢), each farmer from whom the collection is made shall receive a printed and numbered ticket receipt for the amount collected.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.3.</num>
    <text>The printed and numbered ticket receipts shall be furnished by the District of Columbia, in space lots of one hundred (100) or multiples of one hundred (100), through the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs, upon payment of fifteen cents
      (15¢) for each ticket receipt.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.4.</num>
    <text>The Director shall issue receipts in writing for all moneys received from the sale of ticket receipts, and shall deposit all moneys on the day received with the D.C. Treasurer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.5.</num>
    <text>The twenty-five cent (25¢), difference between the price of fifteen cents (15¢), paid to the District and the amount of forty cents (40¢), collected from each farmer may be retained by the respective owners of the market houses as full compensation
      for cleaning all sidewalks, parking space, and other public space adjacent to their respective market houses, and for the use of electric lights when required, where farmers occupy space for the sale of products.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.6.</num>
    <text>No owner of any market house named in §400, or any other person, shall collect from any farmer, or other person, any money whatsoever in addition to the sum of forty cents (40¢) for the occupancy of the spaces named, except as provided in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.7.</num>
    <text>The owners of any market house, or any person designated by them, may furnish trays, trestles, and other equipment to the occupants of any of the spaces provided for the sale of farm products, and may provide storage for those materials when not in
      use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.8.</num>
    <text>For all service or equipment furnished, the owners may collect from each occupant, separate and above the occupancy fee of forty cents (40¢) per space, one of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A sum not exceeding twenty-five cents (25¢) for each weekday; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A sum not exceeding forty cents (40¢) for each Saturday, or day preceding a holiday, when the time is extended to 8:30 p.m.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 5, §§2(c) &amp;#038; (d) of the Police Regulations (May 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>