<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-508</num>
  <heading>PREVENTION OF POLLUTION BY WATERCRAFT (§ 21-508)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>508.1</num>
    <text>508.1 The discharge into the Potomac River or its tributaries of any waste, whether liquid or solid, treated or untreated, from any vessel berthed at a marina, dock, or basin, is prohibited.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>508.2.</num>
    <text>Each marina, dock, or basin where a vessel or other watercraft is berthed, except for facilities that are owned by the United States Department of Defense and not generally open to the public, shall be provided with water closets, urinals, and lavatories
      which are separate for each sex, readily available, and in sufficient numbers to meet the needs of persons using the marina facilities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>508.3.</num>
    <text>Each marina, dock, or basin where vessels or other watercraft suitable for overnight accommodations are berthed shall be equipped with suitable bathing facilities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>508.4</num>
    <text>508.4 The Department shall approve the facilities required under this section to be acceptable for the purposes set forth.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>508.5.</num>
    <text>New or existing marinas within the Anacostia Waterfront Development Zone shall comply with the program elements outlined in the current version of the Clean Marina Guidebook issued by the National Park Service, and the owner of the marina shall submit
      a copy of its Clean Marina Checklist and any supporting documentation to the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE Section 2 of the Water Quality Standard Approval Act of 1977 (D.C. Law 2-68; 24 DCR 6809 (February 17, 1978)), 8 DCRR §§8.2:808 and 8-2:</heading>
      <text>810, Health Regulations (1965 Edition); as amended by § 22 of the Water Pollution Control Act of 1984 (D.C. Law 5-188, 32 DCR 919 (February 15, 1985)); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10640 (July 19, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>