<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-547</num>
  <heading>SOIL EROSION AND SEDIMENT CONTROL[COLON] RESPONSIBLE PERSONNEL (ยง 21-547)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>547.1.</num>
    <text>If a site involves a land disturbance of five thousand square feet (5,000 ft2) or more, the owner of the site and the site manager shall ensure that a responsible person is present or available as this section requires.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>547.2.</num>
    <text>A responsible person shall, while the site is in a phase involving land-disturbing activity, ensure that the activity complies with this chapter by:</text>
    <text>Inspecting the site and its erosion and sediment control measures at least once biweekly and after a rainfall event to identify and remedy each potential or actual erosion problem;</text>
    <text>Being available to respond to each potential or actual erosion problem identified by construction personnel; and</text>
    <text>Being available to speak on site with the Department to remedy each potential or actual erosion problem.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>547.3.</num>
    <text>A responsible person shall be:</text>
    <text>Licensed in the District of Columbia as a civil or geotechnical engineer, a land surveyor, or architect; or</text>
    <text>Certified through a training program that the Department approves, including a course on erosion control provided by another jurisdiction or professional association.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>547.4.</num>
    <text>During construction, the responsible person shall have available on site proof of professional licensing or of successful completion of a Department-approved training program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>547.5.</num>
    <text>A Department-approved training program shall cover the following topics, as demonstrated in the training syllabus:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The detrimental effects of sediment pollution to waterbodies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The benefits of proper and effective erosion and sediment control implementation and maintenance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The purpose and provisions of the District of Columbia erosion and sediment control laws, rules, and regulations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A description of sediment as a pollutant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The process of:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Erosion;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Sediment transport; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Sediment deposition;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Proper implementation of erosion and sediment control;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Recognition and correction of improperly implemented erosion and sediment controls;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Proper maintenance of erosion and sediment controls; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Responsibilities of supervisory and enforcement personnel.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10640 (July 19, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>