<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-561</num>
  <heading>STORMWATER FEE DISCOUNT PROGRAM[COLON] APPROVAL PERIOD; REAPPROVAL (ยง 21-561)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>561.1.</num>
    <text>A stormwater fee discount shall be approved for a discount period of three (3) years, running ordinarily from the date of approval.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>561.2.</num>
    <text>In order to receive approval for an additional stormwater fee discount period, a customer must submit an application to the District Department of the Environment (Department).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>561.3.</num>
    <text>In order to avoid a lapse in a discount while the Department reviews an application for approval of an additional discount period, a customer must submit the application by sixty (60) days before the expiration of the current stormwater fee discount
      period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>561.4.</num>
    <text>The application shall be submitted on such forms, and in hard copy or electronically, as the Department may designate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>561.5.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of an application for approval of an additional discount period, the Department may perform an inspection to verify that the Best Management Practice (BMP) remains eligible for the discount.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>561.6.</num>
    <text>The Department may deny or approve an application for approval of an additional discount period, in whole or in part.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>561.7.</num>
    <text>If the Department approves the application, the stormwater fee discount shall be approved for an additional discount period running from the earlier of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The date of the approval; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The expiration of the preceding approval period.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>561.8.</num>
    <text>An eligible BMP may be approved for more than one (1) period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10732 (July 19, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>