<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-501</num>
  <heading>FEES (§ 21-501)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>501.1.</num>
    <text>The District Department of the Environment (Department) shall adjust the fees in this section for inflation annually, using the Urban Consumer Price Index published by the United States Bureau of Labor Statistics.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall pay a supplemental review fee for each Department review after the review for the first resubmission of a plan, and the fee shall be paid before a building permit may be issued, except that a project or portion of a project entirely
      in the existing public right of way shall not be required to pay a supplemental review fee for a review specified for a design phase under the Maximum Extent Practicable (MEP) process described in the Department’s Stormwater Management Guidebook.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant for Department approval of a soil erosion and sediment control plan shall pay the fees in Table 1 for Department services at the indicated time, as applicable:</text>
    <text>Table 1. Fees for Soil Erosion and Sediment Control Plan Review</text>
    <text>Payment Type</text>
    <text>Payment Requirement</text>
    <text>Fees by Land Disturbance Type</text>
    <text>Residential</text>
    <text>All Other</text>
    <text>≥ 50 ft2 and</text>
    <text>&lt; 500 ft2</text>
    <text>≥ 50ft2 and</text>
    <text>&lt; 5,000 ft2</text>
    <text>≥ 5,000 ft2</text>
    <text>Initial</text>
    <text>Due upon filing for building permit</text>
    <text>$50.00</text>
    <text>$435.00</text>
    <text>$1,070.00</text>
    <text>Final</text>
    <text>Due before building permit is issued</text>
    <text>n/a</text>
    <text>$0.15 per 100 ft2</text>
    <text>• Clearing and grading &gt; 5,000 ft2</text>
    <text>• Excavation base fee</text>
    <text>n/a</text>
    <text>$435.00</text>
    <text>• Excavation &gt; 66 yd3</text>
    <text>$0.10 per yd3</text>
    <text>• Filling &gt; 66 yd3</text>
    <text>$0.10 per yd3</text>
    <text>Supplemental</text>
    <text>Due before building permit is issued</text>
    <text>$100.00</text>
    <text>$100.00</text>
    <text>$1,000.00</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant for Department approval of a Stormwater Management Plan (SWMP) shall pay the fees in Table 2 for Department services at the indicated time, as applicable:</text>
    <text>Table 2. Fees for Stormwater Management Plan Review</text>
    <text>Payment Type</text>
    <text>Payment Requirement</text>
    <text>Fees by Land Disturbance Type</text>
    <text>≥ 5,000 ft2 and ≤ 10,000 ft2</text>
    <text>&gt; 10,000 ft2</text>
    <text>Initial</text>
    <text>Due upon filing for building permit</text>
    <text>$3,300.00</text>
    <text>$6,100.00</text>
    <text>Final</text>
    <text>Due before building permit is issued</text>
    <text>$1,500.00</text>
    <text>$2,400.00</text>
    <text>Supplemental</text>
    <text>Due before building permit is issued</text>
    <text>$1,000.00</text>
    <text>$2,000.00</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant for Department approval of a plan and any other person requesting the services in Table 3 shall pay the additional fees in Table 3 for Department services before issuance of a building permit, except:</text>
    <text>If a person is applying for relief from extraordinarily difficult site conditions, the person shall pay the fee upon applying for relief; and</text>
    <text>If a person is not applying for a building permit, the person shall pay before receipt of a service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.6.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall be required to pay the fee for review of a Stormwater Pollution Prevention Plan only if the site is regulated under the Construction General Permit issued by Region III of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
    <text>Table 3. Additional Fees</text>
    <text>Review or Inspection Type</text>
    <text>Fees by Land Disturbance Type</text>
    <text>≤ 10,000 ft2</text>
    <text>&gt; 10,000 ft2</text>
    <text>Soil characteristics inquiry</text>
    <text>$150.00</text>
    <text>Geotechnical report review</text>
    <text>$70.00 per hour</text>
    <text>Pre-development review meeting</text>
    <text>No charge for first hour</text>
    <text>$70.00 per additional hour</text>
    <text>After-hours inspection fee</text>
    <text>$50 per hour</text>
    <text>Stormwater pollution plan review</text>
    <text>$1,100.00</text>
    <text>Dewatering pollution reduction plan review</text>
    <text>$1,100.00</text>
    <text>$2,100.00</text>
    <text>Application for relief from extraordinarily difficult site conditions</text>
    <text>$500.00</text>
    <text>$1,000.00</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.7.</num>
    <text>An applicant for Department approval of a SWMP for a project being conducted solely to install a Best Management Practice (BMP) or land cover</text>
    <text>for Department certification of a Stormwater Retention Credit (SRC) shall pay the fees in Table 4 for Department services at the indicated time, as applicable, except that:</text>
    <text>A person who is paying a review fee in Table 2 for a major regulated project shall not be required to pay a review fee in Table 4 for the same project; and</text>
    <text>A person who has paid each applicable fee to the Department for its review of a SWMP shall not be required to pay a review fee in Table 4 for the same project:</text>
    <text>Table 4. Fees for Review of Stormwater Management Plan to Certify Stormwater Retention Credits</text>
    <text>Payment Type</text>
    <text>Payment Requirement</text>
    <text>Fees by Land Disturbance Type</text>
    <text>≤ 10,000 ft2</text>
    <text>&gt; 10,000 ft2</text>
    <text>Initial</text>
    <text>Due upon filing for building permit</text>
    <text>$575.00</text>
    <text>$850.00</text>
    <text>Final</text>
    <text>Due before building permit is issued</text>
    <text>$125.00</text>
    <text>$200.00</text>
    <text>Supplemental</text>
    <text>Due before building permit is issued</text>
    <text>$500.00</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.8.</num>
    <text>A person who requires Departmental approval of an as-built SWMP for SRC certification for a BMP or land cover for which a plan review fee has not been paid to the Department shall pay each applicable fee for initial and final SWMP review in Table
      4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.9.</num>
    <text>A person who requires the Department’s review of a proposed or as-built SWMP solely for the purpose of applying for a stormwater fee discount under this Chapter shall not be required to pay a plan review fee to the Department for that project, except
      that a person who subsequently applies for SRC certification for the same project shall pay each applicable fee for initial and final plan review before the Department will consider the application for SRC certification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.10.</num>
    <text>An applicant for Department approval of a Green Area Ratio plan shall pay the fees in Table 5 for Department services at the indicated time:</text>
    <text>Table 5. Fees for Review of Green Area Ratio Plan</text>
    <text>Payment Type</text>
    <text>Payment Requirement</text>
    <text>Fees by Land Disturbance Type</text>
    <text>≤ 10,000 ft2</text>
    <text>&gt; 10,000 ft2</text>
    <text>Initial</text>
    <text>Due upon filing for building permit</text>
    <text>$575.00</text>
    <text>$850.00</text>
    <text>Final</text>
    <text>Due before building permit is issued</text>
    <text>$125.00</text>
    <text>$200.00</text>
    <text>Supplemental</text>
    <text>For reviews after first resubmission</text>
    <text>$500.00</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.11.</num>
    <text>The in lieu fee shall be three dollars and fifty cents ($3.50) per year for each gallon of Off-Site Retention Volume (Offv).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.12.</num>
    <text>The administrative late fee for an in-lieu fee payment shall be ten percent (10%) of the late payment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.13.</num>
    <text>A person shall pay the fees in Table 6 for the indicated resource before receipt of the resource:</text>
    <text>Table 6. Fees for Resources</text>
    <text>Paper Copies of Documents</text>
    <text>Cost</text>
    <text>District Standards and Specifications for Soil Erosion and Sediment Control</text>
    <text>$50.00</text>
    <text>District Stormwater Management Guidebook</text>
    <text>$50.00</text>
    <text>District Erosion and Sediment Control Standard Notes and Details (24 in x 36 in)</text>
    <text>$25.00</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE Section 2 of the Soil Erosion and Sedimentation Control Act of 1977( D.C. Law 2-23; 24 DCR 792 (July 22, 1977)); as amended by 8 DCRR § 8-2:803 and 8-2:</heading>
      <text>804, Health Regulations (1965 Edition); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 3858 (June 2, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10640 (July 19, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>