<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-554</num>
  <heading>PUBLIC HEARING (ยง 21-554)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>554.1.</num>
    <text>The hearing shall be conducted not earlier than thirty (30) days after publication of the notice specified in ยง 553.1 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>554.2.</num>
    <text>The Director, or his or her designee, shall conduct the public hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>554.3.</num>
    <text>Any member of the public who wants to testify at the public hearing shall submit his or her name, and the name of any organization(s), if any, which he or she represents, to the Department at least three (3) days before the date of the hearing, except
      that this requirement may be waived by the Director at the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>554.4.</num>
    <text>Statements of members of the public who are testifying on their own behalf shall be limited to five (5) minutes, and statements of those who are appearing on behalf of organizations shall be limited to ten (10) minutes, except that this requirement
      may be waived by the Director at the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>554.5.</num>
    <text>Others present at the hearing who wish to be heard may testify after those on the witness list have been called and heard.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>554.6.</num>
    <text>If, in the opinion of the Director, or his or her designee conducting the hearing, a witness is abusive or unruly, such that his or her behavior is disrupting the conduct of the hearing, the Director, or his or her designee conducting the public hearing
      may call for a recess, order the witness to cease the behavior, or order the witness to leave the hearing. A person who is ordered to leave a hearing may submit written comments, pursuant to the requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>554.7.</num>
    <text>In addition to, or in place of, oral testimony, members of the public may submit written testimony or comments during the period specified in the notice of proposed ratemaking. Either form of comment shall be given equal weight.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 10004 (September 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>