<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-529</num>
  <heading>STORMWATER MANAGEMENT[COLON] COVENANTS AND EASEMENTS (§ 21-529)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>529.1.</num>
    <text>The owner of each lot and parcel that is part of a site that undertook a major regulated project shall record with the Recorder of Deeds:</text>
    <text>A declaration of covenants that includes the on-site and off-site responsibilities in the Department-approved Stormwater Management Plan (SWMP); and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An easement that the Department requires to ensure access for inspection and maintenance of a Best Management Practice (BMP) or land cover employed to comply with this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>529.2.</num>
    <text>An agency of the federal government or District government shall not be required to make or record a declaration of covenants, except that, if a District-owned property is sold to a private owner or leased for more than three (3) years, the property’s
      SWMP must be incorporated in a declaration of covenants and recorded as a burden on the property or the leasehold.</text>
    <text>The declaration of covenants and easement shall:</text>
    <text>Be determined legally sufficient by the Attorney General or the Department’s designee;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be binding on each subsequent owner;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Include an agreement to indemnify the District of Columbia, its officers, agents, and employees from and against all claims or liability that may arise out of or in connection with, either directly or indirectly, any of the owner’s actions or omissions
        with regard to the construction, operation, maintenance or restoration of the BMP or land cover; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Provide for inspection of and access to the BMP or land cover at reasonable times by the Department or its authorized representative.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>529.4.</num>
    <text>If the Department determines that a change to an approved SWMP for a site affects the terms of a declaration of covenants or an easement required by this chapter, the owner of each affected lot or parcel of that site shall revise as the Department
      approves and record the declaration of covenants or easement accordingly.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 21 (January 1, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10640 (July 19, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>