<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-504</num>
  <heading>STOP WORK ORDERS (§ 21-504)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>504.1.</num>
    <text>Upon notice from the Department that it has determined that one (1) or more of the following conditions exists, a person shall stop identified work immediately until the situation is corrected:</text>
    <text>Noncompliance with a notice that requires corrective action;</text>
    <text>Material false statement or misrepresentation of fact in an application that the Department approved for the project;</text>
    <text>During the project, the license of a contractor or subcontractor is void, has expired, or has been suspended or revoked;</text>
    <text>Work involving an activity regulated under this chapter is being conducted:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In violation of a provision of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In an unsafe manner; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>In a manner that poses a threat to the public health or the environment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>504.2.</num>
    <text>A stop work order shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Have immediate effect;</text>
    </level>
    <text>Be issued in writing; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Be provided to:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The person who has received an approval under this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The person doing the work; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The person on site who is responsible for the work.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>504.3.</num>
    <text>The stop work order shall identify the:</text>
    <text>Address and location of the work;</text>
    <text>Corrective action or cessation required;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Time period required to complete corrective action;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Reason for the order;</text>
    </level>
    <text>Person issuing the order, including telephone contact, and, if available, email or other electronic means of address; and</text>
    <text>Steps to be taken to challenge or appeal the order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>504.4.</num>
    <text>The Department shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Post the stop work order at the property; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Send the stop work order in a manner likely to insure receipt, including first class mail, fax with return receipt, email with return read receipt, or hand-delivery with certification of service.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>504.5.</num>
    <text>No person shall remove a stop work order posted at a site without the Department’s written approval.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>504.6.</num>
    <text>A person who continues work stopped by an order shall be in violation of this chapter for each day on which work is conducted, except for work:</text>
    <text>Required immediately to stabilize the activity and place the property in a safe and secure condition;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That the Department orders; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Required immediately to eliminate an unsafe condition or threat to the public health or the environment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE Section 2 of the Soil Erosion and Sedimentation Control Act of 1977 (D.C. Law 2-23; 24 DCR 792 (July 22, 1977)), 8 DCRR §8-2:</heading>
      <text>804, Health Regulations (1965 Edition); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10640 (July 19, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>