<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-502</num>
  <heading>DUTY TO COMPLY (ยง 21-502)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>502.1.</num>
    <text>A person who engages in an activity that this chapter regulates shall comply with the provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>502.2.</num>
    <text>A person shall conduct all work in accordance with each submittal approved by the Department, including each plan and approved change.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>502.3.</num>
    <text>Each provision of an approved plan shall be complied with as a distinct provision of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>502.4.</num>
    <text>A person shall promptly notify the Department of an actual or likely material change in the performance provided for in an approved SWMP, including a material change in the volume of stormwater flowing into a Best Management Practice (BMP), a shared
      BMP, or a land cover.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>502.5.</num>
    <text>A person shall undertake a reasonable inquiry to confirm that the facts stated and calculations made are true and correct for each communication with the Department under this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>502.6.</num>
    <text>No person shall negligently, recklessly, or knowingly make a false statement in a communication with the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE Section 2 of the Soil Erosion and Sedimentation Control Act of 1977 (D.C. Law 2-23; 24 DCR 792 (July 22, 1977)), 8 DCRR ยง8-2:</heading>
      <text>804, Health Regulations (1965 Edition); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 7692 (October 21, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 8552 (December 9, 1988); as amended by ยง4(b) of the Soil Erosion and Sedimentation
        Control Amendment Act of 1994 (D.C. Law 10-166, 41 DCR 4892, 4893 (July 22, 1994)); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10640 (July 19, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>