<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-2210</num>
  <heading>GENERAL REQUIREMENTS FOR PESTICIDES (ยง 20-2210)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2210.1.</num>
    <text>Registered pesticides shall be used in strict accordance with the manufacturer&amp;#8217;s labeling directions, and in compliance with District and federal laws and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2210.2.</num>
    <text>Pesticide equipment or application apparatus shall be in sound mechanical condition and capable of satisfactory operation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2210.3.</num>
    <text>Pesticide containers shall not be used for any purposes other than containing the original labeled product.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2210.4.</num>
    <text>The water supply for any equipment being filled shall be protected from contamination by means of an effective anti-siphon device.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2210.5.</num>
    <text>Pesticide applications shall be made in a manner to prevent harmful effects to the environment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2210.6.</num>
    <text>No pesticide application shall be made by air or ground equipment whenever the wind velocity will cause the pesticide to drift beyond the target area.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2210.7.</num>
    <text>Pesticides in leaking, broken, corroded, or otherwise damaged containers, or with damaged or obscure labels, shall not be displayed or offered for sale.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2210.8.</num>
    <text>The inspection of premises to determine the presence of termites or other wood destroying organisms for the purpose of issuing wood infestation certificates shall only be performed by pesticide operators licensed in the subcategory of &amp;#8220;Wood
      Destroying Organisms,&amp;#8221; as described in ยง 2301.1(d)(2) of Chapter 23 of this subtitle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 3044, (October 6, 1978), incorporating Proposed Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 2118 (August 25, 1978)</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>