<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-999</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 15-999)
    <text>When used in this chapter; the following terms and phrases shall have theollowing meaning:</text>
    <text>“Capacity” means the maximum output, expressed in kilowatts, of an electricenerator under specific conditions designated by the manufacturer, as indicatedn a nameplate physically attached to the generator.</text>
    <text>“Commission” means the Public Service Commission of the District ofolumbia.</text>
    <text>“Competitive Electricity Supplier” means a person, including an aggregator,roker, or marketer, who generates electricity; sells electricity; or purchases,rokers, arranges or markets electricity for sale or retail customers: The termxcludes the following:
      (A) Building owners, lessees, or managers who manage thenternal distribution. system serving such building and who supply electricityolely to occupants of the building for use by the occupants; (B)(1) Any personho purchases electricity for its own
      use or for the use of its subsidiaries orffiliates; or (2) Any apartment building or office building manager whoggregates electric service requirements for his or her building or buildings,r who does not: (a) Take title to the electricity; (b) Market
      electric serviceso the individually-metered tenants of his or her building; or (c) Engage in theesale of electric service to others; (C) Property owners who supply smallmounts of power, at cost, as accommodation to lessors or licensees of theroperty;
      and (D) A consolidator.</text>
    <text>“Customer-generator” means a residential or commercial customer that ownsor leases or contracts) and operates an electric generating facility that: (a)as a capacity of not more than 1000 kilowatts; (b) uses renewable resources,ogeneration, fuel cells,
      or microturbines; (c) is located on theustomer&amp;#8217;s premises; (d) is interconnected with the Electricompany&amp;#8217;s transmission and distribution facilities; and (e) is intendedrimarily to offset all or part of the customer&amp;#8217;s
      own electricityequirements.</text>
    <text>“Electric Company” means the company that provides distribution service.</text>
    <text>“Eligible customer-generator” means a customer-generator whose net energyetering system for renewable resources, cogeneration, fuel cells, andicroturbines meets all applicable safety and performance standards.</text>
    <text>“Full Retail Distribution Rate” means the per kilowatt-hour distributionharges applicable to the net energy billing customer during the billing period.</text>
    <text>“Full Retail Transmission Rate” means the per kilowatt-hour transmissionharges applicable to the net energy billing customer during the billing period.</text>
    <text>“Generation value” means the product of the applicable SOS kilowatt-hourate times the number of kilowatt-hours consumed and/or supplied, during theime period(s) associated with such usage and/or supply.</text>
    <text>“Net energy metering” means the difference between the kilowatt-hoursonsumed by a customer-generator and the kilowatt-hours generated by theustomer-generator’s facility over any time period determined as if measuredy a single meter capable of registering
      the flow of electricity in twoirections.</text>
    <text>“Net energy billing” means a billing and metering practice under which austomer-generator is billed on the basis of net energy over the billing period.</text>
    <text>“Standard Offer Service Provider” means a provider of standard offer servicehosen pursuant to Chapter 29 of the Commission&amp;#8217;s rules.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 1588 (February 18, 2005); asmended by 55 DCR 7302 (July 4, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking publishedt 57 DCR 5249, 5253 (June 18, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>