<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6599</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 29-6599)
    <text>When used in this Chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have theeanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Accrual Method of Accounting means a method of accounting pursuant to whichevenue is recorded in the period earned, regardless of when collected andxpenses are recorded in the period, regardless of when paid.</text>
    <text>Base Year means the standardized year on which rates for all facilities arealculated to derive a prospective reimbursement rate.</text>
    <text>BO1 means the case mix index scores developed by the Centers for Medicare andedicaid Services for the Medicaid 34-group Resource Utilization GroupsRUG-III) classification system.</text>
    <text>Case Mix Index means a number value score that describes the relative resourcese for the average resident in each of the groups under the RUGS IIIlassification system based on the assessed needs of the resident.</text>
    <text>Case Mix Neutralization means the process of removing cost variations betweenursing facilities nursing and resident care costs resulting from differentevels of case mix.</text>
    <text>Ceiling means a pre-determined rate that sets the upper limit of reimbursement.</text>
    <text>Change of Ownership shall have the same meaning as &amp;#8220;acquiring of effectiveontrol&amp;#8221; as set forth in D.C. Official Code ยง 44-401(1).</text>
    <text>Day-Weighted Median means the point in an array from high to low of the per diemosts for all facilities at which half of the days have equal or higher per diemosts and half have equal or lower per diem costs.</text>
    <text>District-wide Average Case Mix Index means the arithmetic mean of the individualesidents case mix indices for all residents, regardless of payer, admitted andresent in all nursing facilities located in the District of Columbia on theicture date. The
      arithmetic mean shall be carried to four decimal places.</text>
    <text>District-wide Medicaid Average Case Mix Index means the arithmetic mean of thendividual residents case mix indices for all residents admitted and present inll nursing facilities on the picture date for whom the Medical Assistancedministration is the
      payer source. The arithmetic mean shall be carried to fourecimal places.</text>
    <text>F102 (fraction of inspired oxygen) means the ratio of the concentration ofxygen to the total pressure of other gases in inspired air.</text>
    <text>Facility Medicaid Case Mix Index means the arithmetic mean of the individualesident case mix index for all residents, for whom the Medical Assistancedministration (MAA) is the payer source, admitted and present in the nursingacility on the picture
      date. The arithmetic mean shall be carried to fourecimal places.</text>
    <text>Fair Market Value means the value at which an asset could be sold in the openarket in a transaction between unrelated parties.</text>
    <text>Leasehold Improvements means the improvements made by the owners of a facilityo leased land, buildings or equipment.</text>
    <text>Mechanical Ventilation means a method for using machines to help an individualo breathe when that individual is unable to breathe sufficiently on his or herwn to sustain life.</text>
    <text>Median means the point in an ordered array from lowest to highest of nursingacility per diem costs at which the facilities are divided into equal halves.</text>
    <text>Medical Assistance Administration (MAA) means an administration within theepartment of Health that is responsible for the day-to-day administration andversight of the District&amp;#8217;s Medicaid Program.</text>
    <text>Minimum Data Set (MDS), Version 2.0 means the resident assessment instrument andata used to determine the RUGS classification of each resident.</text>
    <text>New Provider means a nursing facility that entered the Medicaid Program aftereptember 30, 2000.</text>
    <text>Normalized means the process by which the average case mix for the District iset to 1.0. This process shall only be performed at implementation and rebasing.</text>
    <text>Nursing Facility means a facility that is licensed as a nursing home pursuant tohe requirements set forth in the &amp;#8220;Health Care and Community Residenceicense Act of 1983, effective February 24, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-48; D.C. Officialode ยง 44-501
      et seq.) and meets the federal conditions of participation forursing facilities in the Medicaid program as set forth in 42 CFR 483.1 et seq.</text>
    <text>Out of State Facility means a nursing facility located outside the District ofolumbia which meets the licensure standards in the jurisdiction where servicesre provided and meets the federal conditions of participation for nursingacilities in the Medicaid
      program as set forth in 42 CFR 483.1 et seq.</text>
    <text>Peer Group means a group of nursing facilities sharing the same characteristics.</text>
    <text>Per Diem Rate means a rate of payment to the nursing facility for coveredervices in a resident day.</text>
    <text>Picture Date means one day per quarter in each fiscal year, as selected by theedical Assistance Administration.</text>
    <text>Prudent Buyer means the price paid by a prudent buyer in the open market underompetitive conditions.</text>
    <text>Reserved Bed Day means a day for hospitalization or therapeutic leave ofbsence, when provided for in the resident&amp;#8217;s plan of care and when theres a reasonable expectation that the resident will return to the nursingacility.</text>
    <text>Reserved bed days may not exceed a total of 18 days during any 12-month periodhat begins on October 1st and ends on September 30th. A therapeutic leave ofbsence includes visits with relatives and friends and leave to participate in atate-approved
      therapeutic and rehabilitative program.</text>
    <text>Resident means an individual who, because of physical, mental, familial orocial circumstances, or mental retardation, resides in a nursing facility.</text>
    <text>Resident Day means one continuous 24-hour period of care furnished by a nursingacility that concludes at midnight each calendar day, including reserved bedays that are paid for by MAA. The day of the resident&amp;#8217;s admission isounted as a resident
      day. The day of discharge is not counted as a residentay.</text>
    <text>Resource Utilization Groups, Version III (RUGS III) means a category-basedesident classification system developed by the U.S. Department of Health anduman Services, Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS) used tolassify nursing facility residents
      into groups based on each resident&amp;#8217;seeds and functional, mental and psychosocial characteristics.</text>
    <text>Tidal volume means the volume of air inspired and expired during a normalespiratory cycle.</text>
    <text>Total Facility Average Case Mix Index means the arithmetic mean of thendividual resident case mix indices for all residents, regardless of payer,dmitted and present in the nursing facility on the picture date. The arithmeticean shall be carried to
      four decimal places.</text>
    <text>Tracheostomy means a surgical opening in the trachea or windpipe through which aube is channeled to assist breathing.</text>
    <text>Ventilator dependent means a resident who requires at least sixteen (16) hourser day of mechanically assisted respiration to maintain a stable respiratorytatus.</text>
    <text>Weaning means the process of gradually removing an individual from theentilator and restoring spontaneous breathing after a period of mechanicalentilation.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 1370 (February 24, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>