<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-1329</num>
  <heading>TAXIMETER BUSINESS &amp;#8211; SALE OF TAXIMETERS (ยง 31-1329)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1329.1.</num>
    <text>A taximeter business owner shall only sell and install taximeters for use in a District of Columbia licensed taxicab that have been approved by the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1329.2.</num>
    <text>A taximeter business owner shall not sell a taximeter for use in a taxicab licensed by the Commission unless a valid vehicle license from the Commission is presented.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1329.3.</num>
    <text>A taximeter business owner shall not sell a taximeter for use in a Commission licensed vehicle unless the installation, testing and certification of the taximeter/vehicle assembly is performed by the taximeter business licensee or an employee thereof.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1329.4.</num>
    <text>A taximeter business owner shall report to the Commission, within seven (7) days, all sales, trades or exchanges of taximeters by the licensed taximeter business on a form prescribed by the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1329.5.</num>
    <text>A taximeter business owner shall inform all purchasers in writing, before the sale takes place, of any and all restrictions imposed by the taximeter manufacturer and/or taximeter business licensee regarding the testing, repairs, calibration and installation
      of the taximeter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1329.6.</num>
    <text>A taximeter business owner shall remove, deface, or otherwise void the validity of the certification sticker upon receipt of a taximeter purchased, exchanged, or accepted in trade by the taximeter business licensee, and report such decertification
      to the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1329.7.</num>
    <text>The certification sticker must conform to all specifications established by the Commission and bear the name of the Chairperson of the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1329.8.</num>
    <text>All installations of taximeters in taxicabs license to operate in the District of Columbia must be in accordance with specifications which have been filed with and approved by the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1329.9.</num>
    <text>No change in the method of installation shall be made unless the installation method has been filed with and approved by the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 3831 (April 11, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>