<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-1399</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 31-1399)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1399.1.</num>
    <text>The words and phrases in this chapter shall have the meaning as set forth below:</text>
    <text>Applicant &amp;#8211; An individual, partnership or corporation seeking a taximeter business license from the Commission.</text>
    <text>Commission &amp;#8211; The DC Taxicab Commission.</text>
    <text>Driver &amp;#8211; A person licensed by the Commission to drive a licensed DC taxicab in the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Hack-up &amp;#8211; To outfit a vehicle as a taxicab and obtain approval from the Commission for that vehicle to serve as a taxicab for the first time.</text>
    <text>Mailing address &amp;#8211; The address designated by an applicant or licensee for the receipt of all notices and correspondence from the Commission. Unless otherwise approved in advance, the mailing address of a taximeter business licensee shall
      be the street address of the business.</text>
    <text>Owner &amp;#8211; An individual, partnership, limited liability company or corporation licensed by the Commission to own and operate a taxicab or taxicabs.</text>
    <text>Rate of fare &amp;#8211; The established fare which may be charged by a licensed taxicab, which fare has been promulgated by the Commission, and which fare may include, but is not limited to surcharges and waiting times.</text>
    <text>Seal &amp;#8211; A device, approved by the Commission, which may be installed on a taximeter, wire, wiring mechanism, gear or other device, so that no adjustment, repair, alteration or replacement can be made without removing or mutilating the seal
      or seals.</text>
    <text>Taximeter &amp;#8211; An instrument or device approved by the Commission by which the charge to a passenger for hire of a licensed taxicab is automatically calculated and on which such charge is plainly indicated.</text>
    <text>Taximeter business &amp;#8211; Any business which engages, in whole or in part, in the manufacture, sale (whether of new or used equipment), installation, repair, adjustment, testing, sealing or calibrating of taximeters, for use upon any licensed
      vehicle in the District of Columbia including any business which engages in whole or in part in the installation of taxicab cruiser lights.</text>
    <text>Taximeter business owner &amp;#8211; An individual, partnership or corporation licensed by the Commission to own and operate a taximeter business.</text>
    <text>Taximeter test (sometimes alternatively referred to as &amp;#8220;test&amp;#8221;) &amp;#8211; Shall mean a method to determine compliance with distance and time tolerances, utilizing either a road test over a precisely measured road course or a simulated
      road test determining the distance traveled by use of a roller device, or by computation from rolling circumference and wheel-turn data, said test having been conducted in accordance with the National Institute of Standards and Technology Handbook
      No. 44.</text>
    <text>Wiring harness &amp;#8211; Any wire or collection of wires, including all connections thereto, which is connected in any manner whatsoever to a taximeter or in any way affects the operation of a taximeter.</text>
    <text>Repeal Subject Index reference as follows:</text>
    <text>Zone charts&amp;#8230;&amp;#8230;&amp;#8230;&amp;#8230;&amp;#8230;&amp;#8230;&amp;#8230;..§§ 801.1, 801.2</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 3831 (April 11, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>