<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-1326</num>
  <heading>TAXIMETER BUSINESS &amp;#8211; RECORD OF TAXIMETER TESTS (ยง 31-1326)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1326.1.</num>
    <text>The taximeter business owner shall record the results of any inspections or tests, and the taximeter make, model, and serial number on a form, prescribed by the Office of Taxicabs, which the taximeter business licensee shall submit to the Commission
      within seven (7) days of such inspection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1326.2.</num>
    <text>Upon a determination that a taximeter has passed an inspection, the taximeter business owner, in addition to complying with ยง 1326.1, shall affix a certification sticker, prescribed and approved by the Office of Taxicabs, to the taximeter. Any certification
      sticker shall not be re-affixed to the taximeter if removed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1326.3.</num>
    <text>A taximeter business owner shall provide for the safekeeping of certification stickers, shall control their sequence of issuance, and shall ensure that such stickers are placed only on taximeters in accordance with these regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1326.4.</num>
    <text>When a taximeter is installed in preparation for &amp;#8220;hack-up,&amp;#8221; the taximeter business owner, in addition to complying with ยง 1326.1 and ยง1326.2 shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Prepare a vehicle &amp;#8220;hack up&amp;#8221; certification form approved by the Office of Taxicabs at the completion of the preparatory work for vehicle &amp;#8220;hack-up&amp;#8221;;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Submit to the Commission, within 24 hours, all documents relating to the installation and inspection of such taximeter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Provide the vehicle owner with an itemized list of all work performed in preparation for &amp;#8220;hack-up.&amp;#8221;</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 3831 (April 11, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>