<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-1599</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 27-1599)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1599.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Apparent clerical mistake &amp;#8211; clerical or typographical mistake apparent on the face of a bid.</text>
    <text>Bid samples &amp;#8211; a sample to be furnished by a bidder to show the characteristics of the product offered in a bid.</text>
    <text>Descriptive literature &amp;#8211; information (such as cuts, illustrations, drawings, and brochures) which shows the characteristics or construction of a product or explains its operation.</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; the agency head of the Office of Contracting and Procurement (OCP) or the Chief Procurement Officer (CPO).</text>
    <text>Lowest evaluated bid price &amp;#8211; the lowest bid price after considering all price related factors.</text>
    <text>Minor informality or irregularity – an immaterial defect in a bid or variation of a bid from the exact requirements of the IFB that can be corrected or waived without being prejudicial to other bidders. The defect or variation is immaterial when the
      effect on price, quantity, quality, or delivery is negligible when contrasted with the total cost or scope of the requirement.</text>
    <text>Responsive bid &amp;#8211; a bid that conforms in all material respects to the invitation for bids.</text>
    <text>Reverse auction – an on-line procurement method wherein bidders bid on specified goods or non-professional services through electronic competitive bidding. During the bidding process, bidders’ prices are public and are revealed electronically, and
      bidders have the opportunity to modify their bid prices for the duration of the time period established for the auction.</text>
    <text>Two-step sealed bidding &amp;#8211; a method of contracting designed to obtain the benefits of competitive sealed bidding when adequate specifications are not initially available.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1445 (February 26, 1988); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 3714 (March 6, 2012)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 6290, 6314 (June
        1, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>