<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-1507</num>
  <heading>DESCRIPTIVE LITERATURE (ยง 27-1507)
    <text>Each IFB shall state whether the bidder is required to furnish descriptiveiterature.</text>
    <text>The contracting officer shall not require bidders to furnish descriptiveiterature unless the contracting officer needs it to determine, before award,hether the product offered meets the specifications or to establish exactlyhat the bidder proposes
      to furnish.</text>
    <text>The contracting officer shall document, in writing, the reasons why productcceptability cannot be determined without submission of descriptive literaturend shall include the document in the contract file.</text>
    <text>The IFB shall clearly identify the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The descriptive literature required to be furnished;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The purpose for which the literature is required;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The extent to which the literature shall be considered in the evaluationf bids; and</text>
    </level>
    <text>The rules that shall apply if a bidder fails to furnish the literature beforeid opening or the literature furnished does not comply with the requirements ofhe IFB.</text>
    <text>After receipt of bids, the contracting officer may waive the requirement forurnishing descriptive literature if either of the following occurs:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The bidder states in its bid that the product being offered is the same as product previously or currently being furnished to the District; or</text>
    </level>
    <text>The contracting officer determines that the product offered by the bidderomplies in all material respects with the specification requirements of theFB.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1424 (February 26, 1988); asmended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 3714March 6, 2012)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at9 DCR 6290, 6291 (June 1,
        2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>