<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-1521</num>
  <heading>FOGGY BOTTOM OVERLAY DISTRICT (FB) (§ 11-1521)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1521.1.</num>
    <text>The Foggy Bottom Historic District is a unique resource to the District of Columbia that must be preserved and enhanced. The historic district was designated and included in the National Register of Historic Places in 1986 and 1987, respectively.
      It is characterized by low scale residential structures forming a cohesive neighborhood of modest dwellings. Given the high density development pressures caused by the proximity of the Central Employment Area, George Washington University, medical
      clinics, and hotels, strong protection is needed to retain the historic district’s low-scale residential character, human scale streetscape, and historic character.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1521.2.</num>
    <text>The Foggy Bottom (FB) Overlay District has the identical boundaries of the Foggy Bottom Historic District and is applied to the area, the boundaries of which begin at the intersection of K and 25th Streets, N.W., and proceed as follows: east along
      the center line of K Street, turning south along the eastern edge of Lot 19 in Square 28 to the northern edge of the alley; then eastward and southward along the alley to the northern boundary of Lot 92 in Square 28; then eastward to the center
      line of 24th Street; then south along the center line of 24th Street to New Hampshire Avenue; then southwest along the center line of New Hampshire to H Street; west along the center line of H Street to 25th Street; north along the center line of
      25th Street to the southern edge of Lot 42 in Square 17; then west along the lot line to the alley in Square 17; then through the alley and then north along the western line of Lot 848 (encompassing Lots 812 through 820, 28 through 35, and 834,
      848, and 849) in Square 17 to the center line of I Street; then west along the center line of I Street to the center line of 26th Street; then north on 26th Street to the northern edge of Lot 73 in Square 16; then east along the northern edge of
      Lot 73 to the easternmost corner of Hughes Mews and then south along the eastern edge of Hughes Mews to the northern edge of Lots 883, 858, and 856; then east along the lots to the center line of 25th Street; then north along the center line of
      25th Street to the origination point at the center line of K Street. The FB Overlay District includes the following: Square 16, excluding Lots 884, 863, 93, 17, 71, and 2009 through 2161 (The Griffin Condominium Apartment Building); Square 17, excluding
      Lots 2001 through 2051 (The Plaza Condominium Apartment Building); Square 28, excluding Lots 884 and 168; and Square 29 in its entirety.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1521.3.</num>
    <text>The purposes of the FB Overlay District is to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Require a scale of development consistent with:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Comprehensive Plan, which provides that the land use map for the Foggy Bottom Historic District be amended from the present &amp;#8220;medium &amp;#8221; category to the &amp;#8220;moderate&amp;#8221; category; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The characteristics of the low scale harmony of rhythmic townhouses of a purely residential neighborhood that formed the basis on which the area was designated a historic district;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Protect the integrity of the historic district, its small scale, and open spaces; require compatibility of any development with the purposes of the Historic Landmark and Historic District Protection Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law
        2-144, as amended; D.C. Official Code §§ 6-1101 to 6-1115 (2001)(formerly codified at D.C Code §§ 5-1001 to 5-1015 (1994 Repl. &amp;#038; 1999 Supp.))), and preclude demolitions or partial demolitions that would lead to an increase in height and
        floor area ratio inappropriate to the area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Enhance the residential character of the area by maintaining existing residential uses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Preserve areas planned as open backyards and alleyways that provide the only access to historic alley dwellings, and protect the light, air, and privacy that they provide;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Enhance the special human scale streetscape by maintaining the public space in front of the buildings as landscaped green spaces and limiting future curb cuts; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Encourage greater use of public transportation through use of the nearby Foggy Bottom Metrorail Station, so as to protect the narrow residential streets and alleys from the deleterious effects of disruptive excessive traffic.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 2741 (April 17, 1992); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8457-59 (October 20,
        2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>