<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-7009</num>
  <heading>REQUIREMENTS FOR INSTITUTIONAL PARTICIPATION &amp;#8211; GRANT PAYMENT WHEN STUDENTTTENDS MORE THAN ONE INSTITUTION (§ 29-7009)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7009.1.</num>
    <text>During any award year, a student who is enrolled at least half-time in a program leading to a recognized educational credential at an eligible institution (“first institution”) may receive the grant for courses taken at a second institution (eligible
      or non-eligible institution) if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The student remains enrolled as a regular student at the first eligible institution during his or her study at the second institution;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The courses taken at the second institution apply toward the recognized educational credential at the first eligible institution; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The first eligible institution and the second institution have a written agreement that provides for the first eligible institution to determine the grant amount for the tuition and fees at both institutions and request payment on behalf of the
        student.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7009.2.</num>
    <text>The eligible institution that requests the grant payment on behalf of the student in accordance with the agreement entered into under §7009.1(c) shall take into account all courses taken by the student at each institution participating in the agreement
      and which apply to the recognized educational credential when determining the student’s enrollment status and amount of grant, and maintain all records regarding the student’s eligibility for and receipt of the grant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7009.3.</num>
    <text>If a student who receives a grant at one eligible institution subsequently transfers to a second eligible institution in the award year, the student may receive tuition assistance at the second institution only if the second institution complies with
      the requirements contained in §7007.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7009.4.</num>
    <text>The second institution may receive a grant on behalf of the student under §7009.3 only for that portion of the award year in which the student is enrolled at that institution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7009.5.</num>
    <text>The second institution shall request payment for the student in accordance with §7010 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7009.6.</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall be responsible for calculating and/or tracking a student’s maximum annual and lifetime award amounts and adjusting them, as appropriate, to address transfers between types of schools (public to private or private to public).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7009.7.</num>
    <text>Each time a student transfers from one type of eligible institution to another type of eligible institution (public to private nonprofit or private nonprofit to public) the Mayor’s office will adjust the amount of the total lifetime award received
      to date to reflect the amount the student would have received if all awards had been received at the second type of institution. The new total lifetime award to date will be calculated by:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Dividing the total grant amount the student has received at the eligible institution from which the student is transferring by the maximum lifetime amount of grant award the student could receive while attending that type of institution (public
        &amp;#8211; $50,000 or private non-profit &amp;#8211; $12,500); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Multiplying the percentage obtained under (a) above by the lifetime maximum at the type of institution to which the student is transferring to determine the student’s new total award received to date.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 5013, 5025 (June 1, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>