<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2799</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 29-2799)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2799.1.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this Chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Brand &amp;#8211; any registered trade name commonly used to identify a drug.</text>
    <text>Compound medication &amp;#8211; any prescription drug, excluding cough preparations, in which two (2) or more ingredients are extemporaneously mixed by a registered pharmacist.</text>
    <text>Container &amp;#8211; a light resistant receptacle designed to hold a specific dosage form which is or maybe in direct contact with the item and does not interact physically or chemically with the item or adversely affect the strength, quality or
      purity of the item.</text>
    <text>Department of Health Care Finance (DHCF)- the executive department responsible for administering the Medicaid program within the District of Columbia effective October 1, 2008.</text>
    <text>Generic drug- a drug that is produced and distributed without patent protection.</text>
    <text>Legend drug- a drug that can only be dispensed to the public with a prescription.</text>
    <text>Medicaid Drug Rebate Program- This program was created pursuant to the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990ย(OBRA&amp;#8217;90). The Drug Rebate program requires a drug manufacturer to enter into and have in effect a national rebate agreement
      with the Secretary of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) for states to receive Federal funding for outpatient drugs dispensed to Medicaid patients.</text>
    <text>Maintenance narcotic medication- A narcotic medication that has been dispensed in quantities sufficient for thirty (30) days or more for pain management therapy.</text>
    <text>Multiple source drug &amp;#8211; a drug marketed or sold by two (2) or more manufacturers or labelers.</text>
    <text>Pharmacy benefit manager &amp;#8211; a company under contract with managed care organizations, self-insured companies and government programs to manage pharmacy networks, provide drug utilization reviews, outcome management and disease management.</text>
    <text>Prescribed drugs- legend drugs approved as safe and effective by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration and those over-the-counter medications which fall into the following categories:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Oral analgesics with a single active ingredient (such as, aspirin, acetaminophen, andibuprofen);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Ferrous salts (such as, sulfate and gluconate);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Antacids with up to three active ingredients, (such as, aluminum, magnesium, and bismuth);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Diabetic preparations (such as, insulin and syringes);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Pediatric, prenatal, and geriatric vitamin formulations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Family planning drugs and supplies; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Senna extract, single dose preparations when required for diagnostic radiological procedures performed under the supervision of a physician.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 2298, 2311 (March 23, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>