<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-614</num>
  <heading>BURDEN OF PROOF (ยง 15-614)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>614.1.</num>
    <text>The burden of proof shall be by a preponderance of the evidence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>614.2.</num>
    <text>A preponderance of the evidence is that degree of relevant evidence which a reasonable mind, considering the record as a whole, would accept as sufficient to find a contested fact more probably true than untrue.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>614.3.</num>
    <text>The PSP shall bear the burden of proof with regard to issues of whether the pay telephone is in compliance with these Rules, except as provided in ยง 614.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>614.4.</num>
    <text>The complainant shall bear the burden of proof with regard to issues of whether the pay telephone is associated with illegal purposes or constitutes a public nuisance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>614.5.</num>
    <text>In weighing evidence regarding whether an existing or proposed pay telephone is, or is likely to be, associated with illegal activity, the Hearing Officer shall give great weight to any written statement or testimony from an MPD officer that, based
      on his or her knowledge and experience, the installation or continued operation of the pay telephone significantly contributes, or is likely to significantly contribute, to criminal activity in the neighborhood and, thereby, adversely affect the
      health, safety, and welfare of the residents.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>614.6.</num>
    <text>In weighing evidence regarding whether a pay telephone constitutes a public nuisance, the Hearing Officer shall give great weight to the written recommendation of the ANC for the neighborhood in which the pay telephone is located or proposed to be
      located.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>614.7.</num>
    <text>For the purpose of this section, &amp;#8220;great weight&amp;#8221; means that, unless there is a compelling reason to do other-wise, the Hearing Officer shall defer to the opinion of the MPD or ANC.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>614.8.</num>
    <text>A pay telephone shall constitute a public nuisance if it adversely affects the common rights of the surrounding community, including, for example, injury to community members&amp;#8217; health, safety, peace, comfort, or convenience.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 1151 (February 9, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>