<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-609</num>
  <heading>PAY TELEPHONE SERVICES (§ 15-609)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>609.1.</num>
    <text>All pay telephones shall provide the following operational characteristics:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Free access to dial tone, 911 emergency service, and toll-free numbers without having to deposit a coin(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Free access to all locally available long distance carriers at no charge and without having to deposit a coin(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Free access to telecommunications relay service for hearing-impaired and speech-impaired callers and without having to deposit a coin(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Access to 411 or “Directory Assistance”, and the caller must be advised of any charge either through a statement posted on the pay telephone instrument or through the use of voice prompts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The ability to return any deposited coin(s) if the call is not completed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Compatibility with telecommunications switching technology that enables the pay telephone to be located in connection with 911 emergency and 311 non-emergency public safety calls.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>609.2.</num>
    <text>Pay telephones shall display prominently the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Registration Number issued to the PSP, pursuant to § 604.9;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The telephone number of the pay telephone unless, for public safety reasons, the Commission determines that the telephone number should not be displayed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The address of the pay telephone (as shown on the approved Registration Application);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The cost of a local call;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Notice of any limitations on service such as the instrument&amp;#8217;s inability to receive incoming calls or its inoperability during certain hours;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Notice of the instrument&amp;#8217;s inability to provide change, if applicable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The name, address (as shown on the approved Registration Application) and telephone number of the PSP;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Procedures for obtaining customer refunds;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Procedures for reporting service difficulties; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Notice that complaints concerning the pay telephone may be directed to the Commission&amp;#8217;s 24-hour hotline, (202) 737-4PSC, and the Office of the People&amp;#8217;s Counsel at (202) 727-3071.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>609.3.</num>
    <text>Pay telephones shall display notice of a time limit, if any, for a local call and may also provide such information through a voice prompt.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>609.4.</num>
    <text>Existing pay telephones shall have sixty (60) days from the date these rules are adopted to display registration number(s) and all other information required by these Rules, unless the time period is extended by the Commission for good cause.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>609.5.</num>
    <text>Pay telephone shall be connected to one local exchange carrier and only one pay telephone per line shall be permitted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>609.6.</num>
    <text>Pay telephones shall comply with generally accepted telecommunications industry technical standards, the current National Electric Code and National Electrical Safety Code.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>609.7.</num>
    <text>PSPs shall adequately maintain their pay telephones at all times.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The PSPs&amp;#8217; duty to provide adequate maintenance to their pay telephones shall apply not only to the performance and operational characteristics of pay telephone(s) as outlined in Sections 609.1 to 609.6, and 609.8, but shall also include
        the PSPs&amp;#8217; duty to take all reasonable measures necessary to keep their pay telephone instruments and housing clean and presentable for public use, absent of any debris, unsanitary substances or defacement, including graffiti, unlawful
        writings, markings, gougings, and scratchings; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>PSPs shall remediate any noncompliance respecting this section according to the requirements outlined in Section 609.9, infra.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>609.8.</num>
    <text>deleted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>609.9.</num>
    <text>deleted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>609.10.</num>
    <text>The PSP shall notify the Commission in writing as to what actions have been taken to bring the pay telephone into compliance with the pay telephone service requirements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>609.11.</num>
    <text>deleted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 1151 (February 9, 2001); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 544 (January 21, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 1316 (February 8, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>