<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-604</num>
  <heading>PAY TELEPHONE REGISTRATION (ยง 15-604)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>604.1.</num>
    <text>A PSP shall not install and/or operate a pay telephone in the District until the instrument is registered with the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>604.2.</num>
    <text>Registration Applications shall be submitted for each proposed pay telephone.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>604.3.</num>
    <text>Each Registration Application shall identify the proposed site of the pay telephone and state whether the pay telephone is to be located on public or private space.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>604.4.</num>
    <text>If the proposed pay telephone location is located outdoors on public space, the Registration Application shall contain a copy of the public space permit for that location issued by the Department of Public Works.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>604.5.</num>
    <text>If the proposed pay telephone application is located outdoors on private space, the Registration Application shall be accompanied by a photograph of the proposed site.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>604.6.</num>
    <text>The Registration Application shall be executed by an officer of the corporation, a partner in the case of a partnership, a designated agent of an owner, or a sole proprietor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>604.7.</num>
    <text>Each completed Registration Application shall be accompanied by a check or money order in the amount of $ 50.00, which is a fee covering expenses associated with pay telephone regulation. The check or money order shall be made payable to the D.C.
      Treasurer. A PSP may apply for and receive a refund in the amount of $ 50.00, provided that (a) the refund request is made before the 121st day after the Commission approves the PSP&amp;#8217;s Registration Application, and (b) the PSP certifies
      that it has not and will not install a pay telephone at the location specified in its Registration Application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>604.8.</num>
    <text>Upon the filing of a completed Registration Application for an outdoor pay telephone, the Commission shall notify, in writing, the Office of the People&amp;#8217;s Counsel (&amp;#8220;OPC&amp;#8221;), the Advisory Neighborhood Commission (&amp;#8220;ANC&amp;#8221;)
      Chairperson, the Single Member District ANC Commissioner, and the Metropolitan Police Department (&amp;#8220;MPD&amp;#8221;) district for the area in which the pay telephone is to be located, as well as any local civic association that asks to be
      on the Commission&amp;#8217;s service list, that the Commission intends to take action on the pending application. The notice shall contain the name of the PSP, the proposed location of the pay telephone, and state whether the pay telephone is to
      be located on private or public property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>604.9.</num>
    <text>If a Registration Application is approved, the Commission shall issue a Registration Number for each pay telephone to the PSP. A Registration Number may not be altered, reused, or transferred to another PSP or pay telephone.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>604.10.</num>
    <text>The Registration Application shall be available for public inspection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>604.11.</num>
    <text>If a Registration Application or Renewal Application contains incorrect information, a PSP shall submit an amendment to the Application within 30 days of the date of notification from the Commission of the error(s). All amendments must be signed by
      the PSP and notarized. If a PSP fails to submit the requested information within thirty (30) days of notification, the Commission shall deny the Application, and the Registration Application or Renewal Application fees shall not be refunded.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 1151 (February 9, 2001); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 1316 (February 8, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>