<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-4500</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (ยง 27-4500)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4500.1.</num>
    <text>The Director shall establish and conduct classes, workshops, and other training programs based on District procurement law, rules, and procedures in accordance with ยง1101 of the D.C. Procurement Practices Act of 1985 (the &amp;#8220;Act&amp;#8221;).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4500.2.</num>
    <text>The Director may designate the size and enrollment of procurement training courses, and may target specific programs to particular groups of employees or non- employees, including the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Programs open to District procurement personnel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Programs open to all District employees;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Programs for non-employees; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Programs open to all employees and non-employees.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4500.3.</num>
    <text>The Director may establish a tuition or program fee for non-employee participants in programs open to the public. Any fee shall be based on the costs of providing materials and instruction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4500.4.</num>
    <text>The Director shall provide the head of each agency with notice of scheduled training programs for employees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4500.5.</num>
    <text>The Director shall provide notice to the public of all programs open to non-employees by publication of a notice of program offerings in the D.C. Procurement Digest, posting of program notices on public bulletin boards, and in any other manner the
      Director may deem appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4500.6.</num>
    <text>District training programs and training requirements shall be designed to ensure that persons who have authority to contractually bind the District have the necessary experience, training, and technical knowledge to make sound decisions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, D.C. Law 6-85, as amended, D.C. Code ยง1-1181.1 et seq. (1981).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1750 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>