<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-713</num>
  <heading>FACT-FINDING CONFERENCE (§ 4-713)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>713.1.</num>
    <text>Within fifteen (15) calendar days of the filing of a complaint, the Office shall serve a notice of the complaint and a copy of the complaint on the respondent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>713.2.</num>
    <text>If considered appropriate, the Director or the Director’s designee shall schedule a fact-finding conference within twenty (20) calendar days of the date that a complaint is filed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>713.3.</num>
    <text>The Director or the Director’s designee shall, at least seven (7) calendar days prior to the fact-finding conference, do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Inform the parties of the date of the fact-finding conference; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Inform the parties of their responsibility to provide the Director or the Director’s designee with names of witnesses who will provide information at the fact-finding conference.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>713.4.</num>
    <text>If a witness for a party is unable to attend the fact-finding conference, that party may request the witness to submit a notarized statement. The party shall deliver the statement to the Office no later than two (2) calendar days before the scheduled
      date of the fact-finding conference.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>713.5.</num>
    <text>The purpose of the fact-finding conference shall be to provide for the rapid processing of charges that are narrowly defined and limited to allegations of direct harm to the charging party.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>713.6.</num>
    <text>A record of the fact-finding conference shall be made by a recording device. If a settlement negotiation is initiated during the conference, the settlement discussions shall be confidential and off the record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>713.7.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, a “fact-finding conference” is an informal, investigative technique, not an adversary proceeding.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>713.8.</num>
    <text>Each allegation of the charge shall be closely examined and fully discussed. Each party shall be allowed ample time to present and defend his or her position.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>713.9.</num>
    <text>If counsel for the respondent or the complainant is present, counsel shall be limited to an advisory role and will not be permitted to speak for their clients. For cross-examination purposes, counsel may ask questions through the conference leader.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>713.10.</num>
    <text>The fact-finding conference may be waived or suspended when it becomes apparent to the Director or the Director’s designee that the remedy sought by the complainant may be achieved through a negotiated settlement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>713.11.</num>
    <text>A request for rescheduling a fact-finding conference shall be granted at the discretion of the Director or the Director’s designee. A scheduled court appearance of counsel for either party, illness of either party, or other extenuating circumstances
      are factors that shall be considered in rescheduling a fact-finding conference.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 007324 (September 4, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>