<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-710</num>
  <heading>MEDIATION (§ 4-710)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>710.1.</num>
    <text>The complainant and respondent must attenda mandatory mediation session to be held on a mutually agreed upondate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>710.2.</num>
    <text>A Mediator shall be appointed by theDirector, or his designee, from a list of individuals qualified inalternative dispute resolution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>710.3.</num>
    <text>Prior to beginning the mediation session,the Mediator shall require both parties and their representativesto sign an agreement that all aspects of the mediation are to bekept confidential.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>710.4.</num>
    <text>No aspect of the mediation shall become apart of the investigative record, and the Mediator shall not becalled as a witness in any later proceeding between theparties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>710.5.</num>
    <text>During the mediation, the parties shalldiscuss the issues in the complaint in an effort to reach anagreement that satisfies the interest of all concernedparties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>710.6.</num>
    <text>The parties shall have forty-five (45) daysfrom the date of the initial mediation session within which tomediate a settlement.Â  If an agreement is reached duringthe mediation process, the terms of the agreement shall controlresolution of the complaint.Â Â</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>710.7.</num>
    <text>The Office may initiate a preliminaryinvestigation before the conclusion of the mediation proceedings.If the parties are finalizing a settlement agreement, therespondent may request an extension of time in which to file ananswer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>710.8.</num>
    <text>If an agreement is not reached, the Officeshall proceed with an investigation of the complaint. SOURCE: FinalRulemaking published at 56 DCR 007324 (September 4,2009).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>