<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-721</num>
  <heading>SUBPOENAS (ยง 4-721)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>721.1.</num>
    <text>Subpoenas issued by the Director may require the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The attendance and testimony of witnesses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The production of evidence, including, but not limited to, books, records, correspondence, or documents in the possession or under the control of the person subpoenaed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Access to evidence for the purpose of examination and copying.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>721.2.</num>
    <text>The form, issuance, and manner of service of subpoenas shall be as prescribed by the Rules of Civil Procedure of the D.C. Superior Court.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>721.3.</num>
    <text>A subpoena shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>State the name and address of its issuer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Identify the evidence or person to be subpoenaed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Identify the person to whom and the place, date, and time at which the subpoena is returnable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Identify the nature of the evidence which is to be examined or copied; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>State the date and time when access is requested.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>721.4.</num>
    <text>A subpoena shall be returnable to a duly authorized investigator or other representative of the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>721.5.</num>
    <text>Upon failure of any person to comply with a subpoena issued under this section, the Office shall request that the OAG undertake appropriate action to compel compliance with the subpoena.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>721.6.</num>
    <text>Witnesses who are subpoenaed shall be entitled to the same fees and mileage that are paid to witnesses under the schedule used by the D.C. Superior Court.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 007324 (September 4, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>