<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2026</num>
  <heading>PERMITS FOR EVENTS (§ 19-2026)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2026.1.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § 2026.2, no person shall hold an event or telecast an event without a permit issued pursuant to this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2026.2.</num>
    <text>A permit is not required for an event for which no prize or purse is offered or for which no admission fee is charged.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2026.3.</num>
    <text>Only a promoter licensed pursuant to this chapter and in good standing may apply for a permit under this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2026.4.</num>
    <text>Subject to § 2026.5, an applicant for a permit under this section shall at least thirty (30) days prior to the event do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Submit a completed application to the Commission on the prescribed form including the following information:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The applicant’s name, street address, and license number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The date and location of the event;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The name of each contestant in each event;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The number of rounds in each event;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The designation of the main event and “semi-main” event or events; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A list of all sources from which the applicant reasonably expects to derive income in connection with the event for which the permit is sought and the amount of income projected from each source.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Pay the required fee; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Submit with the application the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A financial statement demonstrating that the applicant has sufficient funds to meet all financial obligations of promoting the event for which the permit is sought;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Certificates of insurance evidencing that the applicant has obtained:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Insurance covering property damage and personal injury to spectators in an amount as required by the facility at which the event will be held and as approved by the Commission; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Insurance providing medical coverage for each contestant in an amount to be approved by the Commission based on prevailing costs of medical treatment and the circumstances of each event, but in no case less than ten thousand dollars ($10,000); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A deposit, in the form of cash, certified check, cashier’s check, or money order in the amount of the total purse of all contestants in the event.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2026.5.</num>
    <text>The Commission, in its discretion, may shorten the period required by § 2026.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2026.6.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall not issue a permit for a boxing event unless the program of which the event is a part has been scheduled for a total of thirty-two (32) rounds of boxing, in the case of a professional program, or twenty-six (26) rounds, in the
      case of a professional-amateur event. The Commission, in its discretion, may reduce the number of rounds required.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2026.7.</num>
    <text>The Commission, in its discretion, may make the permit contingent upon approval by the Fire Department, prior to the event, of plans showing the seating arrangements, aisle spacing, exit facilities, and location of fire fighting appliances.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2026.8.</num>
    <text>The chief inspector shall report to the Commission any violation that cannot be corrected by the starting time of the event and, upon such a report, the Commission may cancel the permit for the event issued under this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3710, 3717-19 (May 20, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>