<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-599</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 1-599)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>599.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have the meaning ascribed:</text>
    <text>Board &amp;#8211; the Board of Appeals and Review as established by Mayor’s Order 96-27, dated March 5, 1996.</text>
    <text>Chairperson &amp;#8211; the Chairperson of the Board, Hearing Committee, or, in the chairperson’s absence, the Vice Chairperson.</text>
    <text>Hearing Committee or Committee &amp;#8211; a three-member or single-member committee of the Board assigned by the Executive Officer to hear an appeal.</text>
    <text>Executive Officer &amp;#8211; the Executive Officer to the Board.</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; the Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs, or the Director of a department or agency of the government of District of Columbia, or his or her authorized designee, or an administrative law judge, or a hearing
      examiner, or attorney examiner, or any board, commission, council, or other governmental entity with respect to whose action, decision, or order an appeal is taken to the Board, or a hearing, is held, or is to be held, by the Board.</text>
    <text>District &amp;#8211; the government of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Legal holidays &amp;#8211; those public holidays listed in D.C. Code § 1-613.2(a) and (c) (1999 Repl.).</text>
    <text>Party &amp;#8211; an appellant, cross appellant, an appellee, a petitioner, or a respondent, or the director of a department or agency of the government of the District of Columbia, or his or her authorized designee, or any board, commission, council,
      or other governmental entity with respect to whose action, decision, or order an appeal is taken to the Board, or a hearing is held, or is to be held, by the board.</text>
    <text>Person &amp;#8211; an individual, firm, partnership, corporation, association, public agency, or governmental agency or department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 3665 (June 27, 1997), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 2934, 2955-56 (May 16, 1997).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>