<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4120</num>
  <heading>PETITIONS FOR RECONSIDERATION (ยง 17-4120)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4120.1.</num>
    <text>A respondent or the Corporation Counsel may file a petition for reconsideration, rehearing, or reargument within ten (10) days after the date of the service of the decision on that party. The party filing a petition shall serve a copy of the petition
      on each party separately represented.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4120.2.</num>
    <text>Neither the filing nor the granting of a petition shall operate as a stay of a decision unless specifically ordered by a board. A stay shall be granted only upon good cause, which shall involve a consideration of the likelihood of board error, irreparable
      harm to the petitioning party, the harm to other parties, and the public interest.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4120.3.</num>
    <text>A petition shall state briefly and specifically the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The matters of record or points of law alleged to have been erroneously decided or overlooked;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The grounds relied upon; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The relief sought.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4120.4.</num>
    <text>If a petition is based in whole or in part on new matter, the matter shall be set forth in an affidavit, containing a statement that the petitioner could not with due diligence have known or have discovered the new matter prior to the hearing before
      the board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4120.5.</num>
    <text>A board, in its discretion, may permit or require oral argument upon a petition before the board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4120.6.</num>
    <text>A board shall grant or deny a petition within forty-five (45) days after the filing of the petition, but the failure by the board to act within that period shall be deemed a denial of the petition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4120.7.</num>
    <text>A decision shall be in writing, and shall be signed by the chairperson. The chairperson shall serve copies of the decision on all parties or their counsels of record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 5872, 5893 (September 11, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>