<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4199</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 17-4199)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4199.1.</num>
    <text>As used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Act &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revisions Act of 1985, D.C. Law 6-99, D.C. Code §§2-3301.1 to 2-3312.1 (1987 Supp.).</text>
    <text>Administrative Law Judge (ALJ) &amp;#8211; a hearing examiner authorized to hear cases pursuant to the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985, D.C. Code §§6-2701 to 6-2723 (1987 Supp.).</text>
    <text>Board &amp;#8211; the Board of Dentistry, Board of Dietetics and Nutrition, Board of Medicine, Board of Nursing, Board of Nursing Home Administration, Board of Occupational Therapy, Board of Optometry, Board of Pharmacy, Board of Physical Therapy,
      Board of Psychology, Board of Podiatry, or Board of Social Work established by the Act, as the context requires.</text>
    <text>Certificate &amp;#8211; a certificate to practice a specialty of a health occupation issued by a board pursuant to this subtitle or the Act.</text>
    <text>Chairperson &amp;#8211; the chairperson of a health occupation board designated by the Mayor pursuant of §405(c) of the Act, D.C. Code §2-3304.5(c) (1987 Supp.), or a person designated by the board to preside at a hearing or act in place of the chairperson.</text>
    <text>Day &amp;#8211; a calendar day.</text>
    <text>Department &amp;#8211; the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; the Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs, or the Director&amp;#8217;s designee.</text>
    <text>Health professional &amp;#8211; a person who holds a license, certificate, or registration issued under the authority of this subtitle or the Act.</text>
    <text>Legal holiday &amp;#8211; one of the following holidays:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>New Years&amp;#8217;s Day:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Martin Luther King, Jr.&amp;#8217;s Birthday;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Washington&amp;#8217;s Birthday;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Memorial Day;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Independence Day;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Labor Day;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Columbus Day;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Veterans Day;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Thanksgiving Day;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Christmas Day; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Any other day designated as a legal holiday by the President, the Congress, the Mayor or the Council of the District of Columbia, on the actual day the legal holiday is celebrated by the government of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
    <text>License &amp;#8211; a license to practice a health occupation issued pursuant to this subtitle or the Act.</text>
    <text>Registration &amp;#8211; a registration required to practice a health occupation issued pursuant to this subtitle or the Act.</text>
    <text>Respondent &amp;#8211; a person againt whom an adverse action is contemplated, proposed, or taken.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 5872, 5897 (September 11, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>