<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-4802</num>
  <heading>REVIEW OF PETITION (ยง 14-4802)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4802.1.</num>
    <text>The Attorney General shall complete the review of the petition and complaint within 7 days of their receipt. The period of review may be extended with the consent of the petitioner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4802.2.</num>
    <text>If the Attorney General determines that a petition and complaint are complete, the affected tenant, resident, or resident association may file the complaint with the Court to commence an action pursuant to section 1303 of the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4802.3.</num>
    <text>If the Attorney General determines that either a petition or complaint is incomplete, a notice of the deficiencies shall be mailed to the affected tenant, resident, or resident association at the address contained in the complaint. The petitioner
      may not file the proposed complaint until the deficiencies have been corrected and resubmitted to the Attorney General and the Attorney General has made a determination that all deficiencies have been cured. The Attorney General shall complete the
      review of any resubmitted petition and complaint within 7 days of their receipt. The period of review may be extended with the consent of the petitioner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4802.4.</num>
    <text>A determination that a petition and complaint are complete and that they may be filed with the Court shall not prohibit the Attorney General from moving the Court to join the District of Columbia or any other party so authorized by the Act as a co-plaintiff
      to the complaint, or from moving the Court to intervene in the case commenced by the complaint at a later time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 5044-5048 (June 23, 2006), incorporating by reference the text of Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 933-937 (February 10, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>