<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-4899</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 14-4899)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4899.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>“Act” means the Residential Drug-Related Evictions Re-enactment Act of 2000 (the “Act”), effective October 19, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-172; D.C. Official Code § 42-3601 et seq.) (2001)</text>
    <text>“Attorney General” means the Attorney General of the District of Columbia or his or her designee.</text>
    <text>“Controlled dangerous substance” means any of the controlled dangerous substances as defined in D.C. Official Code § 48-901.02(4).</text>
    <text>“Controlled Substances Act” means the Controlled Substances Act of 1970, approved October 27, 1970 (84 Stat. 1243; 21 U.S.C.S. § 801 et seq.).</text>
    <text>“Court” means the Landlord and Tenant Branch of the Civil Division of the Superior Court.</text>
    <text>“Drug haven” means a housing accommodation, or land appurtenant to or common areas of a housing accommodation where drugs are illegally stored, manufactured, used, or distributed.</text>
    <text>“Drug” means a controlled substance as defined in D.C. Official Code § 33-504(4) or the Controlled Substances Act.</text>
    <text>“Housing accommodation” means a building that is or contains at least one rental unit and the land appurtenant to the building.</text>
    <text>“Manufacture” shall have the same meaning as that term has in D.C. Official Code § 48-901.02(13) or the Controlled Substances Act.</text>
    <text>“Nuisance” means a property that is used:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>By persons who assemble for the specific purpose of illegally using a controlled dangerous substance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For the illegal manufacture or distribution of:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A controlled dangerous substance; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Drug paraphernalia, as defined in D.C. Official Code § 48-1101(3); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>For the illegal storage or concealment of a controlled dangerous substance in sufficient quantity to reasonably indicate under all the circumstances an intent to manufacture, distribute, or dispense:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A controlled dangerous substance; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Drug paraphernalia, as defined in D.C. Official Code § 48-1101(3).</text>
    </level>
    <text>“Occupant” means a person authorized by the tenant or housing provider to be on the premises of the rental unit.</text>
    <text>“Rental unit” means an apartment, room, or part of a publicly or privately owned housing accommodation that is rented or offered for rent for residential occupancy, and the land appurtenant to the apartment, room, or part of the housing accommodation.</text>
    <text>“Resident” means:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>any individual who is domiciled or maintains a place of abode within a housing accommodation, multifamily building, or a single complex of jointly managed multifamily buildings that is alleged to be a drug haven or nuisance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>a member of a tenant’s family who is identified on the tenant’s lease or sublease for a housing accommodation that is alleged to be a drug haven or nuisance; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>a nontenant who resides, with the permission of the tenant, within a tenant’s housing accommodation that is alleged to be a drug haven or nuisance.</text>
    </level>
    <text>“Resident association” means an organization of residents of a multifamily building or a single complex of jointly managed multifamily buildings.</text>
    <text>“Tenant” means a lessee, sublessee, or other person entitled to the possession or occupancy of a rental unit.</text>
    <text>“Uniform” Controlled Substances Act means Chapter 9 of Title 48 of the D.C. Official Code.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 5044-5048 (June 23, 2006), incorporating by reference the text of Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 933-937 (February 10, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>