<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-505</num>
  <heading>AGREEMENTS WITH PARTICIPATING EMPLOYERS (ยง 7-505)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>505.1.</num>
    <text>Participating employers shall enter into a formal agreement with the Director in order to participate in the program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>505.2.</num>
    <text>The agreement shall contain the employer&amp;#8217;s assurance that only eligible individuals referred by the D.C. Government&amp;#8217;s Public Job Service shall be employed in jobs approved by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>505.3.</num>
    <text>The agreement shall certify the employer&amp;#8217;s intention to do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Provide a brief outline of the training that the participants will acquire through work and classroom training away from the work place;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>State the method of computing and maximum amount of reimbursement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>State the number of participants to be employed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Provide a job description and specification of participants&amp;#8217; wage rates and the amount of wages subsidized and matched, if applicable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Comply with a requirement that employers are to maintain payroll records, time and attendance records, and job duties statements related to each participant; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Provide assurance that the employer shall comply with the Act, and rules or regulations issued under the Act, and other terms and conditions normally associated with employment and training agreements.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>505.4.</num>
    <text>The Director shall exercise his or her authority with respect to contracts and grant agreements in accordance with the delegation contained in Commissioner&amp;#8217;s Order No. 74-144.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>