<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-506</num>
  <heading>TRANSFER, TRANSITION AND PLACEMENT AND PARTICIPANTS (ยง 7-506)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>506.1.</num>
    <text>The Director may approve the transfer or re-employment of a participant; Provided, that the participant has demonstrated a good faith effort to perform all the normally required duties of an employee and that the total time of the participant&amp;#8217;s
      employment does not exceed fifty-two (52) weeks.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>506.2.</num>
    <text>The Director shall encourage participating employers to transfer participants to full unsubsidized employment at any time during the wage subsidized period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>506.3.</num>
    <text>Employers may terminate or suspend participants for good cause, but shall consult with the Director prior to formal and final termination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>506.4.</num>
    <text>In the event of a transition or termination, any unused wage subsidy funds shall automatically revert to the Director if not claimed on a certified invoice within forty-five (45) days of transition or termination so that the Director may reallocate
      the unused funds for additional youth employment opportunities or other use under the Out-of-School Year Round Program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>506.5.</num>
    <text>The Director shall give first priority in funding new fifty-two (52) week employment opportunities to those employers who have transferred participants to regular unsubsidized employment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>506.6.</num>
    <text>Participating employers shall provide job placement assistance to participants whom they are unable to employ in fully unsubsidized jobs. This assistance may take the form of personal referrals within the network of the employer&amp;#8217;s associates
      and friends, letters of recommendation, job search suggestions, and other means.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>