<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2706</num>
  <heading>EMPLOYEES (ยง 19-2706)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2706.1.</num>
    <text>The Board shall appoint an Executive Director who shall be an employee of the Commission and shall serve as the chief executive officer of the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2706.2.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director shall not be a member of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2706.3.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director shall serve at the pleasure of the Board and shall receive such compensation as shall be fixed by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2706.4.</num>
    <text>In addition to any other duties prescribed by law, these By-Laws, or the Board, the Executive Director shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Direct and supervise the administration and management of the Commission, and direct the affairs and activities of the Commission, in accordance with the policies, rules, and regulations of the Commission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Serve as Secretary to the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Attend meetings of the Board, prepare, and keep, at the principal office of the Commission, minutes of all proceedings of the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Maintain and keep, at the principal office of the Commission, the corporate seal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Authenticate records of the Commission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Approve all accounts for salaries, per diem payments, and allowable expenses of the Commission and its employees and consultants, and approve all expenses incidental to the operation of the Commission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Report and make recommendations to the Board on the merits and status of efforts of any proposed facility or sports events and present financial reports at each meeting of the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Hire such personnel as the Executive Director deems necessary to carry out the functions of the Commission, subject to Board approval;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Prepare the annual budget;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Prepare annual financial statements required by the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Ensure adequate internal accounting and funds management controls;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Advise the Board relative to the fiscal activities of the Commission; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Procure goods and services, except that contracts for goods and services in excess of $50,000 shall require approval by the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 487 (January 24, 1997), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 43 DCR 3100, 3107-3108 (June 14, 1996).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>