<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-2811</num>
  <heading>HOW TO SERVE A PAPER (§ 1-2811)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2811.1.</num>
    <text>“Service” of a paper or to “serve” a paper means to send or deliver it as set forth in this Section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2811.2.</num>
    <text>Every paper filed at OAH shall be served on the other parties or their attorneys or representatives no later than the day it is filed with OAH.</text>
    <text>Exceptions may be identified in these Rules, by statute, or by OAH order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2811.3.</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise ordered by an Administrative Law Judge or agreed by the parties, service shall be by delivering a copy, mailing a copy, faxing a copy, or sending a copy by commercial carrier.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2811.4.</num>
    <text>Service by delivery means:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Handing a copy to the party or a representative;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Leaving it at the party’s or representative’s place of business with an employee; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Leaving it at the party’s residence with an adult who lives there.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2811.5.</num>
    <text>Service by mail means mailing a properly addressed copy with first-class postage by depositing it with the United States Postal Service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2811.6.</num>
    <text>Service by fax means faxing a legible copy to the correct fax number and receiving confirmation of transmission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2811.7.</num>
    <text>Service by commercial carrier means giving a copy properly addressed to the commercial carrier with the cost of delivery pre-paid for delivery within three (3) calendar days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2811.8.</num>
    <text>Parties may agree, in writing, to other means of service and may withdraw their agreement in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2811.9.</num>
    <text>Any paper filed must include a signed statement that the paper was served on the parties. Such a statement is known as a “certificate of service.” The certificate of service shall identify the individual serving the paper, the parties served and their
      addresses, the way it was served, and the date served.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2811.10.</num>
    <text>The Clerk may reject, or an Administrative Law Judge may strike, a paper if a party fails to file a certificate of service with the paper.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2811.11.</num>
    <text>Actual receipt of a paper shall bar any claim of defective service except for a claim of late service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 6399 (June 25, 2004); as amended by Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 9322 (October 1, 2004) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 720 (January 28, 2005); as amended
        by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 5 7 DCR 12541, 12550 (December 31, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>