<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-2805</num>
  <heading>DEFAULTS IN CIVIL FINE CASES (§ 1-2805)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2805.1.</num>
    <text>This Section contains rules for deciding civil fine cases in which the Respondent does not file an answer. There are separate procedures for Civil Infractions Act cases, Litter Control Administration Act cases, and other cases, because the law establishes
      different requirements for each of those cases.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2805.2.</num>
    <text>In a Civil Infractions Act case filed on or before September 30, 2010, if a Respondent fails to answer a Notice of Infraction within the time allowed by law, the Government must issue a second Notice of Infraction, as required by the Civil Infractions
      Act. OAH also may issue a notice of default. The notice of default shall inform the Respondent of any penalty provided by law, and shall direct the Government to issue a second Notice of Infraction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2805.3</num>
    <text>2805.3 In a Civil Infractions Act case filed on or before September 30, 2010, if the Government fails to file a second Notice of Infraction within thirty (30) calendar days after a notice of default is served, an Administrative Law Judge may dismiss
      the charge against the Respondent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2805.4.</num>
    <text>In a Civil Infractions Act case filed on or before September 30, 2010, if a Respondent fails to answer a second Notice of Infraction within the time allowed by law, an Administrative Law Judge shall determine whether:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Government has submitted evidence of proper service; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Each Notice of Infraction meets all legal requirements on its face.</text>
    </level>
    <text>If so, the Administrative Law Judge shall find the Respondent in default and shall impose the legally authorized fine and penalty. If not, the Administrative Law Judge shall dismiss both Notices of Infraction without prejudice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2805.5</num>
    <text>2805.5 In a Civil Infractions Act case filed on or after October 1, 2010, and in a Litter Control Administration Act case, if a Respondent fails to answer within the time allowed by law, an Administrative Law Judge shall determine whether:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Government has submitted evidence of proper service; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Notice of Infraction or Notice of Violation meets all legal requirements on its face.</text>
    </level>
    <text>If so, the Administrative Law Judge shall find the Respondent in default and shall impose the legally authorized fine and penalty. If not, the Administrative Law Judge shall dismiss the Notice of Infraction or Notice of Violation without prejudice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2805.6.</num>
    <text>In a Civil Infractions Act case filed on or after October 1, 2010, if the USPS returns an order finding the Respondent in default to the Clerk’s Office, for reasons that call into question the accuracy of any affidavit filed under Subsection 2803.5
      (for example, “no such address,” “addressee unknown”), an Administrative Law Judge shall issue an order requiring the Government to show why the default order should not be vacated.</text>
    <text>If the Government does not respond with sufficient evidence showing that it mailed the Notice of Infraction to a valid address for the Respondent, the default order shall be vacated and the Notice of Infraction shall be dismissed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2805.7</num>
    <text>2805.7 In default cases not brought under the Civil Infractions Act or the Litter Control Administration Act, the procedure shall be consistent with the applicable law and shall ensure that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>There is sufficient evidence of proper service on the Respondent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The charging document meets all legal requirements on its face; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A Respondent who fails to answer shall be held in default and must pay the legally authorized fine and penalty.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 6399 (June 25, 2004); as amended by Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 9322 (October 1, 2004) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 3838 (April 15,
        2005) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 720 (January 28, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 5675 (June 17, 2005); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 12541, 12545 (December
        31, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>