<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-1899</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 7-1899)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1899.1.</num>
    <text>Terms and phrases used in this chapter shall have the meaning set forth in the Reform Act, the Legal Service Act, and as set forth below unless the text or context of the particular section, subsection, or paragraph provides otherwise.</text>
    <text>Classification &amp;#8211; shall mean the system by which job value is determined and a job hierarchy is developed.</text>
    <text>Employee or staff &amp;#8211; shall mean staff appointed by the Retirement Board pursuant to the Reform Act (D.C. Code ยง 1-711(g)(2)).</text>
    <text>Executive Director &amp;#8211; shall mean the chief operations officer appointed by the Retirement Board.</text>
    <text>Midpoint-to-midpoint differential &amp;#8211; shall mean the percentage distance between the midpoint of one grade and the midpoint of the adjacent grades.</text>
    <text>Operations Committee &amp;#8211; shall mean a standing committee of the Retirement Board described at 7 DCMR, Chapter 15.</text>
    <text>Range spread &amp;#8211; shall mean the distance from the minimum to the maximum of the salary range calculated as a percentage of the minimum.</text>
    <text>Relevant markets &amp;#8211; shall mean jobs or job families within comparable labor markets and geographic locations for purposes of comparison.</text>
    <text>Retirement Funds &amp;#8211; shall mean assets which comprise the &amp;#8220;Retirement Fund for police officers and fire fighters&amp;#8221; (D.C. Code ยง 1-782.1) and assets which comprise the &amp;#8220;Retirement fund for teachers&amp;#8221; (D.C.
      Code ยง 1-782.2).</text>
    <text>Total compensation &amp;#8211; shall mean the total value of base pay, incentive or bonus pay, and benefits.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9902-03 (December 15, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>