<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2701</num>
  <heading>BID BONDS AND OTHER SECURITY (ยง 27-2701)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2701.1.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer may require bid security in connection with any solicitation, regardless whether any payment or performance security will be required under the contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2701.2.</num>
    <text>When the District independent price estimate for a construction contract exceeds one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000), the contracting officer shall require a bid security for the invitation for bids or request for proposals.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2701.3.</num>
    <text>When the District&amp;#8217;s independent price estimate for a construction project is less than one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000), the contracting officer may require a bid security.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2701.4.</num>
    <text>The bid security for a construction contract shall be in an amount equal to at least five percent (5%) of the amount of the bid or price proposal. The bid security for non-construction contracts shall be in an amount set by the contracting officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2701.5.</num>
    <text>When a bid security is requiring the solicitation shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A statement that bid security is required;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Notice that the bid security will remain in effect for as long as the bid or proposal is required to remain effective; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Sufficient information to allow bidders or offerors to determine the amount of the required bid security.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2701.6.</num>
    <text>No action shall be taken against the bid security of a bidder or offeror that is permitted to withdraw a bid or proposal prior to award due to a mistake in the bid or proposal, in accordance with the applicable provisions of chapters 15 or 16.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1597 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>