<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-3510</num>
  <heading>FINES (ยง 24-3510)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3510.1.</num>
    <text>An intercity bus service operator shall be subject to the following fines:</text>
    <text>Failure to obtain a permit for an intercity bus passenger loading zone: five hundred dollars ($500) for the first offense, one thousand dollars ($1,000) for the second offense, and one thousand five hundred dollars ($1,500) for the third and all subsequent
      offenses. Each bus loading or unloading passengers without a permit shall constitute a separate offense.</text>
    <text>Failure to display a permit for the use of an intercity bus passenger loading zone: one hundred dollars ($100) for the first offense, two hundred dollars ($200) for the second offense, and three hundred dollars ($300) for the third and each subsequent
      offense. Each bus failing to display a permit while loading or unloading passengers shall constitute a separate offense.</text>
    <text>Providing intercity bus passenger loading or unloading service outside of the hour(s) and day(s) of the week permitted: one hundred dollars ($100) for the first offense, two hundred dollars ($200) for the second offense, and three hundred dollars
      ($300) for the third and each subsequent offense. Each bus loading or unloading passengers outside of the approved hour(s) or day(s) of the week permitted shall constitute a separate offense.</text>
    <text>Failure to abide by a condition of the permit: two hundred dollars ($200) for the first offense and three hundred dollars ($300) for the second and each subsequent offense.</text>
    <text>Knowingly falsifying material information provided on the permit application:</text>
    <text>one thousand dollars ($1,000).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3510.2.</num>
    <text>The District Department of Transportation and the Metropolitan Police Department may issue the fines specified in this section.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 5323, 5334 (June 24, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>