<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-3501</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION FOR PUBLIC SPACE PERMIT BY INTERCITY BUS SERVICE OPERATORS (§4-3501)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3501.1.</num>
    <text>An intercity bus service operator seeking to occupy the public right-of-way shall submit to the Department a public space permit application and application fee, as specified in section 225 of this Title. The application shall be submitted on a form
      provided by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3501.2</num>
    <text>3501.2 An intercity bus operator already operating at the time these regulations become effective shall have sixty (60) days from the effective date of the final rulemaking to submit an application for use of public space for intercity bus loading
      and unloading.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3501.3.</num>
    <text>If an intercity bus service operator seeks to use more than one (1) location for loading and unloading passengers from the public right-of-way, a separate application shall be filed for each location requested by the operator. A separate application
      fee shall also be required for each location. If approved, a separate permit shall be issued for each location.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3501.4.</num>
    <text>Each completed public space permit application shall include the following information:</text>
    <text>The corporate name, mailing address, email address, web site, and telephone number of the intercity bus service operator;</text>
    <text>The name, mailing address, email address, web site, and telephone number of the intercity bus service operator’s contact person, who shall be located within thirty (30) miles from the U.S. Capitol Building;</text>
    <text>The name, mailing address, email address, web site, and telephone number of the operator’s agent for service of process, who shall be located in the District of Columbia;</text>
    <text>A valid U.S. Department of Transportation number and interstate operating authority;</text>
    <text>A copy of the intercity bus service operator’s liability insurance certificate that meets the requirements listed in § 3509.2;</text>
    <text>Six (6) photographic-quality color copies each of three (3) eight inch by ten inch (8″ x 10″) color photographs of the public space, including the sidewalk, curb space, and the roadway, of and adjacent to the proposed passenger loading zone. The three
      (3) photographs shall show the following views:</text>
    <text>Frontal view from roadway;</text>
    <text>Sharp angle right side view along sidewalk or curb; and</text>
    <text>Sharp angle left side view along sidewalk or curb;</text>
    <text>Six (6) photographic-quality color copies of eight inch by ten inch (8″ x 10″) color photographs of any signs designating parking, standing, or stopping prohibitions in or within ten feet (10 ft.) of the proposed passenger loading zone;</text>
    <text>Six (6) copies of a schematic drawing of the proposed passenger loading zone, to scale and with dimensions. The schematic drawing shall show the proposed intercity bus passenger loading zone, the roadway and sidewalk between the nearest intersections
      on either side of the proposed intercity bus passenger loading zone, and the proposed public space required for passenger assembly, including any fixtures and signage proposed to be installed by the intercity bus service operator. In addition, the
      schematic drawing shall show all existing fixtures in the public space between the nearest intersections on either side of the proposed intercity bus passenger loading zone including Metro bus and Circulator bus stops and bus stop zones, Metrorail
      station entrances and Metrorail elevators, vault covers and manholes, fire hydrants, trees and tree boxes, signs (including their content) and sign posts, street lights and traffic signals, sidewalk and roadway vendors, driveways, alleys, and other
      curb cuts, marked loading zones and building entrances, bike racks, parking meters, designated bike lanes in the roadway, and existing curb ramps, roadway, and crosswalk markings or any other similar public safety or accessibility designation;</text>
    <text>A proposal for orderly queuing of waiting passengers so that pedestrian movement along the sidewalk will not be obstructed and so that pedestrian movement from the sidewalk into adjacent buildings will not be impeded;</text>
    <text>A proposed trash management plan for the removal of trash created by waiting or arriving passengers;</text>
    <text>The proposed intercity bus service schedule, including all regularly scheduled departure and arrival times;</text>
    <text>The hours of the day and the days of the week for which the applicant seeks to occupy the intercity bus passenger loading zone (fractions of an hour are not permitted); and</text>
    <text>Any other information that the Director requires to evaluate the application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3501.5</num>
    <text>3501.5 The Department will provide the intercity bus service operator with contact information of a Department representative who will accept comments on the application. The contact information shall be included by the applicant in all notices to
      the public.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 5323, 5325 (June 24, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>