<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-3505</num>
  <heading>USE OF LOADING ZONE; DISPLAY OF PERMIT (ยง 24-3505)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3505.1.</num>
    <text>An intercity bus service operator shall use a permitted passenger loading zone for the drop-off and pick-up of passengers for intercity bus service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3505.2.</num>
    <text>No intercity bus service operator shall occupy a passenger loading zone except during the approved hours as posted on the sign.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3505.3.</num>
    <text>No intercity bus service operator shall occupy an intercity bus service passenger loading zone other than a loading zone it has been permitted to use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3505.4.</num>
    <text>In occupying and making use of a passenger loading zone, the intercity bus service operator shall:</text>
    <text>Conduct intercity bus service passenger loading and unloading operations in public space only within its authorized passenger loading zone;</text>
    <text>Conduct active loading and unloading in a safe and expedient manner;</text>
    <text>Refrain from ticket vending or any other direct commercial activity on public space other than the loading and unloading of passengers; and</text>
    <text>Queue assembled passengers awaiting intercity bus service in an orderly manner that maintains a ten foot (10 ft.) clear and unobstructed pedestrian pathway on the sidewalk in the Central Business District and a six foot (6 ft.) clear and unobstructed
      pedestrian pathway on the sidewalk in all other parts of the city, and that does not interfere with ingress or egress to adjacent buildings or businesses.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3505.5.</num>
    <text>The intercity bus operator shall display a copy of the loading zone permit in a conspicuous location visible from the public space on the curb side of each authorized intercity motor carrier operating in the approved passenger loading zone.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 5323, 5331 (June 24, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>