<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-5902</num>
  <heading>REPAIR OR REPLACEMENT OF UST SYSTEMS (§ 20-5902)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5902.1.</num>
    <text>Each owner or operator of an UST system shall ensure that repairs are made using the proper materials and techniques, and that repairs will prevent releases due to structural failure or corrosion as long as the UST or UST system is used to store regulated
      substances.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5902.2.</num>
    <text>In complying with the requirements of this section, owners or operators shall follow a code of practice developed by a nationally recognized association or independent testing laboratory, as specified by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5902.3.</num>
    <text>Repairs to fiberglass-reinforced plastic tanks may be made by the manufacturer&amp;#8217;s authorized representatives or in accordance with a code of practice developed by a nationally recognized association or an independent testing laboratory, as
      specified by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5902.4.</num>
    <text>Repairs to or replacement of internal tank linings may be made by the manufacturer&amp;#8217;s authorized representatives or in accordance with a code of practice developed by a nationally recognized association or an independent testing laboratory,
      as specified by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5902.5.</num>
    <text>Metal pipe sections and fittings that have released a regulated substance as a result of corrosion or other damage, or appear to have incurred sufficient corrosion or other damage to constitute a threat of release, shall be replaced in accordance
      with § 5704.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5902.6.</num>
    <text>Fiberglass pipes and fittings that have released a regulated substance as a result of damage, or appear to have incurred sufficient damage to constitute a threat of a release shall be replaced in accordance with §5704 and the manufacturer’s specifications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5902.7.</num>
    <text>Flexible pipes that have released a regulated substance as a result of damage, or that appear to have incurred sufficient damage to constitute a threat of a release shall be replaced in accordance with § 5704 and the manufacturer&amp;#8217;s specifications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5902.8.</num>
    <text>Each repaired tank and piping shall be tested for tightness with a precision test method in accordance with §§ 6007 and 6013.3 of this Subtitle upon completion of the repair prior to being placed back in service, unless one (1) or more of the following
      actions have been taken:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The repaired tank has been internally inspected in accordance with a code of practice developed by a nationally or locally recognized association or an independent testing laboratory, as specified by the Director; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The repaired portion of the UST system is monitored monthly for releases in accordance with a method specified in §§ 6008 through 6012 of this chapter; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Another test method is used that is determined by the Director to be no less protective of human health and the environment than the other provisions of this subsection.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5902.9.</num>
    <text>Within six (6) months following the repair of any cathodically protected UST system, the cathodic protection system shall be tested in accordance with the applicable provisions of §§ 5901.4 through 5901.6 of this Subtitle to ensure that it is operating
      properly.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5902.10.</num>
    <text>Each UST system owner or operator shall maintain records of each repair for the remaining operating life of the repaired UST.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5902.11.</num>
    <text>Each owner or operator shall ensure that each UST system is repaired by a certified UST System Technician.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5902.12.</num>
    <text>The owner or operator shall ensure that the certified UST System Technician completes the certification of compliance provided on the UST Notification form approved by the Director in accordance with § 5600 of this Subtitle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5902.13.</num>
    <text>A repair that involves removing and putting back in 100 % of the piping, excluding connectors, connected to a single underground tank is considered to be a replacement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 7835, 7864 (November 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7699 (October 1, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 6678 (August 21, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>