<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-5901</num>
  <heading>TANK CORROSION PROTECTION (§ 20-5901)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5901.1.</num>
    <text>Each owner or operator of a steel tank UST system or a steel-fiberglass-reinforced plastic composite UST system with corrosion protection shall comply with the requirements of this section for as long as the UST system is used to store regulated substances.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5901.2.</num>
    <text>In complying with the requirements of this section, owners or operators shall follow a code of practice developed by a nationally recognized association or independent testing laboratory, as specified by the Director pursuant to §§ 5506.1 and 5506.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5901.3.</num>
    <text>Each corrosion protection system shall be operated and maintained to continuously provide corrosion protection to the metal components of those portions of the tank and piping system that routinely contain regulated substances and are in contact with
      the ground.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5901.4.</num>
    <text>Each UST system equipped with a cathodic protection system shall be inspected for proper operation by a qualified cathodic protection tester within six (6) months of installation and at least once every three (3) years thereafter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5901.5.</num>
    <text>Cathodic protection testing shall be done in accordance with criteria set forth in a code of practice developed by a nationally recognized association, as specified by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5901.6.</num>
    <text>Each UST system with an impressed current cathodic protection system shall also be inspected every sixty (60) days to ensure the equipment is running properly.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5901.7.</num>
    <text>For each UST system using cathodic protection, the owner or operator shall maintain records of the operation of the cathodic protection in accordance with § 5602, to demonstrate compliance with the performance standards set forth in this section.
      Cathodic protection records shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The results of testing from the last two (2) inspections required in § 5901.4 of this section; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The results of the last three (3) inspections required in § 5901.6 of this section.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 7835, 7863 (November 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7699 (October 1, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>