<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-309</num>
  <heading>REPAYMENT OF SECURITY DEPOSITS TO TENANTS (§ 14-309)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>309.1.</num>
    <text>Within forty-five (45) days after the termination of the tenancy, the owner shall do one of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Tender payment to the tenant, without demand, any security deposit and any similar payment paid by the tenant as a condition of tenancy in addition to the stipulated rent, and any interest due the tenant on that deposit or payment as provided in
        paragraph (4)(a) and (a-1) (14 DCMR § 311); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Notify the tenant in writing, to be delivered to the tenant personally or by certified mail at the tenant&amp;#8217;s last known address, of the owner&amp;#8217;s intention to withhold and apply the monies toward defraying the cost of expenses properly
        incurred under the terms and conditions of the security deposit agreement.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>309.2.</num>
    <text>The owner, within 30 days after notification to the tenant pursuant to the requirement of paragraph (2)(a)(2) (14 DCMR § 309.1(b)), shall tender a refund of the balance of the deposit or payment, including interest not used to defray such expenses,
      and at the same time give the tenant an itemized statement of the repairs and other uses to which the monies were applied and the cost of each repair or other use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>309.3.</num>
    <text>Failure by the owner to comply with § 309.1 and § 309.2 of this section shall constitute prima facie evidence that the tenant is entitled to full return, including interest as provided in § 311, of any deposit or other payment made by the tenant as
      security for performance of his or her obligations or as a condition of tenancy, in addition to the stipulated rent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>309.4.</num>
    <text>Failure by the owner to serve the tenant personally or by certified mail, after good faith effort to do so, shall not constitute a failure by the owner to comply with § 309.1 and § 309.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE The Housing Regulations of the District of Columbia, 5G DCRR § 2908, Commissioners’ Order 55-1503 (August 11, 1955); as amended by:</heading>
      <text>section 3 of the Security Deposit Act, D.C. Law 1-48, 22 DCR 2823 (November 28, 1975); and section 2 of the Unitary Rent Ceiling Adjustment Amendment Act of 1992, D.C. Law 9-191, §§ 2908.6 and 2908.7, 40 DCR 2184 (April 2, 1993); as amended by D.C.
        Act 16-633 at 54 DCR 889 (February 2, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>