<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-9499</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 14-9499)
    <text>When used in this Chapter, the following words or phrases shall have theeanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>AHAP Contract &amp;#8211; Agreement to Enter into Project-Based Housing Choiceoucher Program Housing Assistance Payments Contract entered into by DCHA andwner with respect to the property in accordance with the Partnership Program.</text>
    <text>Announcement &amp;#8211; one or more announcements that may periodically be made byCHA of the availability of financial assistance under this Chapter.</text>
    <text>Applicable laws -federal and District of Columbia laws and regulations of theistrict of Columbia, DCHA or HUD in effect and applicable to DCHA, the owner orhe property, as such laws and regulations may periodically be amended,odified, supplemented
      or replaced.</text>
    <text>Dwelling unit &amp;#8211; residential space in existing rental housing thatualifies under the laws of the District of Columbia as a place of habitation orbode for a family, including an apartment or house that contains a living room,itchen area, sleeping
      area consisting of 2 or more bedrooms, and bathroom(s).welling units shall not include any units occupied or to be occupied by thewner or any family member of the owner.</text>
    <text>Energy conservation improvement &amp;#8211; equipment or improvements which, asetermined by DCHA, enhance the energy efficiency of the property, reduce energyonsumption at the property or are otherwise consistent with the energyonservation policy
      of HUD or DCHA.</text>
    <text>Financial assistance &amp;#8211; loans or grants offered periodically by DCHAursuant to this Chapter.</text>
    <text>HAP Contract &amp;#8211; Project-Based Housing Choice Voucher Program Housingssistance Payments Contract entered into by DCHA and owner with respect to theroperty in accordance with the Partnership Program.</text>
    <text>Housing Choice Voucher &amp;#8211; a voucher for tenant-based assistance madevailable by or on behalf of HUD pursuant the Section 8 of the United Statesousing Act of 1937, as amended.</text>
    <text>Housing Quality Standards or HQS &amp;#8211; the housing quality standardsromulgated by HUD and set forth in Section 982.401 of Title 24 of the Code ofederal Regulations, as such standards may periodically be amended, modified,upplemented or replaced
      by HUD.</text>
    <text>HUD &amp;#8211; the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text>
    <text>Owner &amp;#8211; one or more individuals, corporations, partnerships, limitediability companies or other privately-controlled legal entities that hold validegal title to the property.</text>
    <text>Partnership Program &amp;#8211; Partnership Program for Affordable Housing of DCHAstablished pursuant to Chapter 93 of this Title 14 of the Code of District ofolumbia Municipal Regulations, as the same may periodically be amended,odified, supplemented
      or replaced by DCHA</text>
    <text>Project &amp;#8211; (a) rehabilitation or renovation necessary, as determined byCHA, to make dwelling units in the property comply with UFAS; (b)ehabilitation or renovation to construct or install energy conservationmprovements in the property to
      enhance the energy conservation or efficiency ofhe dwelling units as determined by DCHA; or (c) repairs to the propertyecessary, as determined by DCHA, to correct or remove any violations of HQSncluding repair of specific conditions which could
      result in future violationsf HQS occurring within five (5) years of the date of approval of thepplication for financial assistance.</text>
    <text>Property &amp;#8211; the improvements receiving financial assistance.</text>
    <text>Rehabilitation work &amp;#8211; renovation, rehabilitation, installation or repairf and to the property.</text>
    <text>Uniform Federal Accessibility Standards or UFAS &amp;#8211; the accessibilitytandards made applicable to public housing by HUD for purposes of complyingith Section 504 of Rehabilitation Act of 1977, as amended, currently set forthn Sections 8.3, 8.32
      and Appendix A to Section 40 of Title 24 of the Code ofederal Regulations, as the same may periodically be amended, modified,upplemented or replaced.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 10637 (November 2, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>