<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-9400</num>
  <heading>INTRODUCTION (ยง 14-9400)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>9400.1.</num>
    <text>DCHA recognizes that sufficient funding and financing sources may not be available to owners of eligible affordable housing dwelling units to finance or pay for costs of rehabilitation, renovation or repair necessary to modify such dwelling units
      to satisfy the Uniform Federal Accessibility Standards, or to make energy conservation improvements, or to satisfy the Housing Quality Standards. DCHA may periodically make financial assistance in the form of no or low interest loans and grants
      available to owners of existing dwelling units that are eligible to participate in DCHA&amp;#8217;s Partnership Program for Affordable Housing and enter into a Project-Based Housing Choice Voucher Housing Assistance Payments Contract with DCHA under
      the Partnership Program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9400.2.</num>
    <text>This Chapter will set forth rules governing the administration of a DCHA program to provide financial assistance to owners of affordable housing dwelling units.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9400.3.</num>
    <text>The purpose of the program will be to provide financial assistance in the form of no or low interest loans or grants to owners of affordable housing dwelling units in need of rehabilitation, renovation or repair to comply with the Uniform Federal
      Accessibility Standards, or to make energy conservation improvements, or to satisfy the Housing Quality Standards. DCHA may, from to time and subject to availability of funding, announce the availability of financial assistance under this program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9400.4.</num>
    <text>The program is established under the authority of D.C. Official Code ยง 6-203(10) (2001 Ed.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9400.5.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director, for good cause shown in writing, may waive any provision of this Chapter consistent with applicable law. All waivers shall be justified by a determination that undue hardship will result from applying the requirements and where
      application of the requirement would adversely affect the purpose and objectives of the program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 10637 (November 2, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>