<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-1502</num>
  <heading>NOTICE OF AN APPLICATION FOR A NEW LICENSE, RENEWAL OF A LICENSE, OR TRANSFER OF LICENSE TO A NEW LOCATION (§ 23-1502)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1502.1.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section shall govern notice to the public of all applications for new licenses, renewals, or a transfer to a new location, including Manufacturer, Wholesaler, and Retailer licenses, but shall not apply to Solicitor&amp;#8217;s
      licenses, Manager&amp;#8217;s licenses, Caterer&amp;#8217;s licenses, or to Temporary licenses.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.2.</num>
    <text>Upon acceptance of an application, the Board shall establish the date for a roll call hearing on the application, which shall be at least forty-five (45) days after the application is accepted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.3</num>
    <text>1502.3 At least forty-five (45) days prior to the roll call hearing, the Board shall give notice of an application to the entities set forth in D.C. Official Code § 25-421(a). This notice requirement shall not apply to renewal applications in those
      instances where the Applicant’s new license or transfer to a new location application has a 45 day public comment period ending within thirty (30) days of the renewal deadline for that license class.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.4.</num>
    <text>All fees associated with the newspaper advertisement required by D.C. Official Code § 25-422 shall be paid for by the applicant. Proof of payment must be submitted to the Board before placards will be provided to the applicant for posting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.5.</num>
    <text>At least forty-five (45) days before the roll call hearing, the applicant shall post at least two (2) notice placards, provided by the Board, on the main entrance doors to the premises so as to be visible from the street, or on such other place on
      the premises as designated by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.6.</num>
    <text>The Board shall inspect the premises at least once before the date of the roll call hearing specified on the notice in order to ensure that the placards continue to be prominently and visibly displayed to the public. If the placards have been removed
      or are posted in a manner not visible from the street, the establishment shall be re-advertised and replacarded for a further forty-five (45) calendar day period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.7.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the minimum forty-five (45) calendar day protest period, the applicant shall leave the placards posted until the roll call hearing date set out on the placards.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11580 (August 9, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>