<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2005</num>
  <heading>FUEL OIL TANKS IN PUBLIC SPACE[COLON] GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 24-2005)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2005.1.</num>
    <text>Storage tanks for fuel oil may be located in public space when, in the opinion of the Mayor, the installation is justified.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2005.2.</num>
    <text>The placement of fuel oil tanks in public space shall be subject in all cases to conditions of agreement relating to vaults which requires the removal of tank equipment when, in the opinion of the Mayor, the space that is occupied by the tank and
      equipment is needed for the introduction of water pipes, gas pipes, sewers, conduits, or other pipes or underground construction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2005.3.</num>
    <text>Unless specifically authorized to the contrary by the Mayor, in sections zoned other than residential, fuel oil tanks of an approved size and location shall be placed in existing or newly constructed vaults in public alleys, sidewalks, or parking
      space adjoining the property to be served.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2005.4.</num>
    <text>In sections zoned as residential, a fuel oil storage tank may, if necessary, be buried in the ground in a public alley, sidewalk, or parking abutting on the property to be served.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2005.5.</num>
    <text>The top of the fuel oil tank shall be at least four feet (4 ft.) below the surface of the alley, sidewalk, or parking; and the tank shall be placed so that its major axis is horizontal and parallel to the building line of the property to be served.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2005.6.</num>
    <text>The tank shall be placed as close to the building line as practical; but no part of the tank shall lie below a plane passing through the outside, lower edge of the footing of the bearing wall of any building, or projection of the building, and sloping
      downward and outward from the building at an angle of forty-five degrees (45○) below the horizontal plane passing through the same edge of the footing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2005.7.</num>
    <text>No part of the tank shall be closer than two and one-half feet (2 1/2 ft.) to the center line of a public alley, nor shall any part of the tank be closer than one foot (1 ft.) to a bearing wall or to any party line extended through the alley, sidewalk,
      or parking.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2005.8.</num>
    <text>The installation of each tank shall comply in other respects with the terms of any permit issued for the installation, and with applicable regulations covering underground storage tanks.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2005.9.</num>
    <text>The installation of each tank shall be subject to the execution of an agreement relating to fuel oil tanks in public space.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 12, §12 of the Police Regulations (May 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>