<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2203</num>
  <heading>ADMINISTRATION AND ENFORCEMENT (§ 24-2203)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2203.1.</num>
    <text>Any proclamation declaring the existence of an emergency issued pursuant to §2200, any proclamation terminating a state of emergency pursuant to §2202, and any emergency order or regulation issued under authority of §2201 shall be effective without
      prior publication.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2203.2.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of §2203.1, each proclamation and order issued under this chapter shall be, as promptly as practicable, filed in the Office of Documents and published in the D.C. Register.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2203.3.</num>
    <text>Each proclamation issues under this chapter shall be delivered to general news media for publication and for radio and television broadcast.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2203.4.</num>
    <text>Any person who violates any provision of an emergency order or regulation issued by the Mayor under the authority of §2201 shall, upon conviction, be punished by a fine of not more than three hundred dollars ($300), or by imprisonment for not more
      than ten (10) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2203.5.</num>
    <text>If there is a conflict between any regulation issued under authority of §2201 and any other regulation or municipal action of the District, the regulation issued under §2201 shall prevail for so long as it continues in effect.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2203.6.</num>
    <text>Except to the extent that a conflict appears, the provisions of regulations issued under authority of §2201 shall not supersede, but shall be in addition to, the provisions of all other regulations, municipal actions, and statutes applicable to the
      District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2203.7.</num>
    <text>If any provision of this chapter or the application of this chapter to any person or circumstance is held invalid, the validity of the remainder of this chapter and of its application to other persons and circumstances shall not be affected.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order No. 68-432, effective June 19, 1968, Article 48, §§3, 4, 7, 8 of the Police Regulations (May 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>