<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2601</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION PROCESS (ยง 29-2601)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2601.1.</num>
    <text>Each applicant for burial assistance shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Submit a written application on a Department &amp;#8220;Burial Assistance Application&amp;#8221; form and be signed by a relative, preferably the next of kin; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Establish that the deceased person is the person for whom assistance is being sought.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.2.</num>
    <text>The body of a deceased person shall not have been released to a funeral home that is not under contract with the District to receive funds from the Program at the time of the request for assistance. If the body of the deceased person is released to
      a contracted funeral home, the request for assistance must be made prior to receipt of burial or cremation services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.3.</num>
    <text>An authorized representative may apply on behalf of the applicant, if the applicant provides a written statement stating why he or she cannot attend an interview in person and provides the name and address of the person authorized to act on the applicant&amp;#8217;s
      behalf.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.4.</num>
    <text>An authorized representative shall be at least eighteen (18) years of age and have sufficient knowledge of the circumstances of the death to provide the requisite information, or be a person with legal authorization to act on behalf of the applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.5.</num>
    <text>Each applicant shall be interviewed on the date burial assistance is requested or, if that is not possible, on the following business day.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.6.</num>
    <text>Each applicant shall cooperate fully in establishing the deceased&amp;#8217;s eligibility. This shall include, but not be limited to, providing documentation or collateral proof of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Household composition;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Income and assets; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The cost of the funeral.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.7.</num>
    <text>The Department shall provide the applicant with a written request specifying the information needed to complete the application and discuss with the applicant how to obtain the information. The application shall be considered complete when all requested
      information is furnished to the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.8.</num>
    <text>The Department shall not request that documentation be provided when it can obtain the information more easily than the person applying for burial assistance, if that determination can be made. The Department may use documents, telephone conversations,
      personal, collateral sources, reports, correspondence, and conferences to verify the information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.9.</num>
    <text>If the burial is expected to occur within two (2) business days of the date of submission of the completed application, the Department shall take all reasonable steps to process the application timely.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.10.</num>
    <text>An application shall be considered abandoned if the applicant has not submitted the required information or contacted the assigned Department worker or supervisor within fourteen (14) days of the initial application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.11.</num>
    <text>An application shall not be denied if the applicant is attempting to obtain and furnish the required information, and has informed the Department accordingly.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2601.12.</num>
    <text>The Department shall give each applicant, whose application has been denied, a clear concise written statement of the reasons for the denial within three (3) business days of the denial. Each written notice shall also inform the applicant of the right
      to an administrative review and fair hearing to contest the denial, and the steps the applicant shall take to seek review.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 657 (January 19, 1990); as amended by Emergency Rulemaking at 51 DCR 3327 (March 26, 2004)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 5211 (May 21, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>