<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5703</num>
  <heading>RENEWAL OF CERTIFICATE (ยง 17-5703)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5703.1.</num>
    <text>A holder of a certificate to practice as a certified registered nurse-anesthetist shall renew his or her certificate by submitting a completed application on the forms required by the Board and paying the required fees prior to the expiration of the
      certificate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5703.2.</num>
    <text>The Board&amp;#8217;s staff shall mail out applications for renewal at least sixty (60) days prior to the date the certificate expires.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5703.3.</num>
    <text>A certificate holder shall have the burden of notifying the Board if a renewal notice is not received.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5703.4.</num>
    <text>A certificate holder shall notify the Board in writing of a change of home or business address within thirty (30) days after the change.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5703.5.</num>
    <text>A certificate holder applying for renewal of a certificate to practice nurse-anesthesia shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Maintain current licensure as a registered nurse in the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Submit evidence of current national certification or recertification, as applicable, by the Council on Certification of Nurse Anesthetists (CCNA) or Council on Recertification of Nurse Anesthetists (CRNA) or other national certifying body approved
        by the Board; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Beginning with the 2006 renewal period, submit proof of completion of fifteen (15) contact hours of continuing education, which shall include a pharmacology component. A continuing education program, course, seminar, or workshop shall be approved
        by the American Association of Nurse Anesthetists (AANA) or other nationally certifying organization recognized by the Board and shall be related to the certificate holder&amp;#8217;s specialty. Only continuing education hours obtained in the
        two (2) years immediately preceding the application date will be accepted.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5703.6.</num>
    <text>A certificate holder shall submit a verification form of completion, for each program, course, seminar, or workshop for which continuing education is claimed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5703.7.</num>
    <text>A certificate holder applying for renewal of a certificate who fails to submit proof of having completed the requirements as set forth in ยง 5703.5 by the date the certificate expires may renew the certificate within sixty (60) days after the expiration
      by submitting the required documents and paying the required late fees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5703.8.</num>
    <text>Upon submitting the required documents and paying the required late fees, the certificate holder shall be deemed to have possessed a valid certificate during the period between the expiration of the certificate and the submission of the required documents
      and fees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5703.9.</num>
    <text>If a certificate holder applying for renewal of a certificate fails to submit proof of completion of the requirements as set forth in ยง 5703.5 or pay the late fee within sixty (60) days after the expiration of the certificate holder&amp;#8217;s certificate,
      the certificate shall be considered to have lapsed on the date of expiration and the certificate holder shall thereafter be required to apply for reinstatement of an expired certificate and meet all requirements and fees for reinstatement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5703.10.</num>
    <text>The Board may, in its discretion, grant an extension of the sixty (60) day period to renew the certificate after expiration, if the certificate holder&amp;#8217;s failure to submit proof of the requirements or pay the late fee was for good cause.
      As used in this section &amp;#8220;good cause&amp;#8221; includes the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Serious and protracted illness of the certificate holder; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The death or serious and protracted illness of a member of the certificate holder&amp;#8217;s immediate family.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 3491 (May 12, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 11751 (December 27, 2002); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 7228 (July 23, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>