<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5715</num>
  <heading>SUPERVISED PRACTICE OF GRADUATES (ยง 17-5715)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5715.1.</num>
    <text>A graduate may practice nurse-anesthesia only in accordance with the Act and this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5715.2.</num>
    <text>An individual may be authorized to engage in the supervised practice of nurse-anesthesia, as a graduate registered nurse-anesthetist, without a District of Columbia certificate if the individual:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Graduated from a post-basic nursing education program in nurse anesthesia approved by the Council on Accreditation of Nurse Anesthesia Education Programs (COA) or other certifying body approved by the board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Is awaiting the results of the certification examination given by the CCNA or other certifying body approved by the board; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Has an initial application pending for certification to practice nurse-anesthesia in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5715.3.</num>
    <text>A person who has been denied a certificate, denied a license, disciplined, convicted of an offense that bears directly upon his or her fitness to be licensed, or who has such an action pending in the District of Columbia or another jurisdiction shall
      not practice pursuant to this section unless first authorized by the Board in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5715.4.</num>
    <text>Within five (5) business days after the application for certification has been received by the Board&amp;#8217;s staff, the Board&amp;#8217;s staff shall, at the request of the applicant, issue a supervised practice letter to the applicant to document
      that his or her application is pending and that he or she is authorized to practice under the Act and this chapter. The practice letter is not renewable and shall expire:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Six (6) months from the date of issuance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Upon receipt of written notice to the applicant of denial of certification by CCNA;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Upon receipt of notice to the applicant that the applicant has failed the certification examination; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Upon receipt of written notice to the applicant from the Board that the application for certification has been denied, whichever date is the earliest.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5715.5.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of the practice letter, the graduate shall inform employers of the date of expiration of the letter and shall immediately cease the practice of nurse anesthesia on that date or upon receipt of written notice as set forth in ยง 5715.4,
      whichever date is the earliest. The graduate thereafter may practice in any other area for which the graduate is qualified and licensed in the District, until receipt of a certificate to practice nurse anesthesia in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5715.6.</num>
    <text>The graduate shall immediately notify the Board and the graduate&amp;#8217;s supervisor of the results of the certification examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5715.7.</num>
    <text>Only a registered nurse anesthetist certified under the Act, who is a supervisor, shall be authorized to supervise the practice of nurse-anesthesia by a graduate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5715.8.</num>
    <text>A supervisor shall not supervise more than two (2) graduates at one time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5715.9.</num>
    <text>All supervised practice of a graduate shall take place under general or immediate supervision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5715.10.</num>
    <text>A graduate who practices pursuant to this section shall only practice at a hospital, long-term care facility, a health facility operated by the District or federal government, or other health care facility considered appropriate and approved by the
      Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5715.11.</num>
    <text>A graduate practicing under this section shall not assume administrative or technical responsibility for the operation of a nurse-anesthesiology program, unit, service, or institution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5715.12.</num>
    <text>A graduate shall identify himself or herself as such before practicing as a registered nurse anesthetist. A graduate shall wear a picture identification badge with lettering clearly visible to the client bearing the name of the graduate and the position
      title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5715.13.</num>
    <text>A graduate shall not receive compensation of any nature, directly or indirectly, from a client or client&amp;#8217;s family member, except for a salary based on hours worked under supervision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5715.14.</num>
    <text>The supervisor shall be fully responsible for the practice by a graduate during the period of supervision and may be subject to disciplinary action for violations of the Act or this chapter by the graduate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5715.15.</num>
    <text>The Board may deny an application for certification by, or take other disciplinary action against, a graduate who is found to have violated the Act or this chapter. The Board may, in addition to any other disciplinary actions permitted by the Act,
      revoke, suspend, or restrict the privilege of the graduate to practice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 7228 (July 23, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>