<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-105</num>
  <heading>PENALTY (§ 20-105)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>105.1.</num>
    <text>Each person who fails to comply with any of the provisions of this subtitle, or who refuses, interferes with, or prevents any inspection authorized by this subtitle, or who keeps false records or makes false reports or certificates required under
      this subtitle, shall be punished by a fine not to exceed ten thousand dollars ($10,000) or imprisonment not to exceed ninety (90) days, or both.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.2.</num>
    <text>Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this chapter pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication
      of any infraction of this chapter shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.3.</num>
    <text>Each person, other than a District employee, who shall furnish material and substantial evidence leading to the payment of a fine or the forfeiture of collateral imposed under this subtitle shall be paid subject to appropriation one-half (½) of each
      fine or forfeiture unless the Mayor or a court of competent jurisdiction shall otherwise direct. This section shall not be construed as to create any right to the proceeds of any fine or forfeiture.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.4.</num>
    <text>No person shall receive more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) total in any given twelve (12) months under §105.3.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.5.</num>
    <text>In the event of any violation of, or failure to comply with, the air quality provisions of this title, each and every day of the violation or failure shall constitute a separate offense, and the penalties described in § 105.1 shall be applicable to
      each separate offense.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 3 of the District of Columbia Air Pollution Control Act of 1984, D.C. Law 5-165, §105, 32 DCR 562, 568 (February 1, 1985), as amended by §485(a) of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Technical
        and Clarifying Amendments Act of 1980, D.C. Law 8-237, 38 DCR 314, 318 (January 11, 1991); and by Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 8105 (November 19, 1993); Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8638 (October 27, 2000); Final Rulemaking published
        at 47 DCR 9686 (December 8, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>