<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-107</num>
  <heading>CONTROL DEVICES OR PRACTICES (ยง 20-107)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>107.1.</num>
    <text>The devices or practices provided for the control of air pollutants discharged from stationary sources, or otherwise complying with the law, shall remain operative or effective, and shall not be removed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.2.</num>
    <text>Whenever it is necessary to shutdown air pollution control equipment for periodic maintenance, the owner or operator of the equipment shall report the planned shutdown to the Mayor at least forty-eight (48) hours prior to the shutdown. The prior notice
      shall include, but is not limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Identification of the specific facility to be taken out of service, as well as its location and permit number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The expected length of time that the air pollution control equipment will be out of service;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The nature and quantity of emissions of air pollutants likely to occur during the shutdown period;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Measures that will be taken to minimize the length of shutdown period; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The reasons that it would be impossible or impractical to shutdown the source operation during the maintenance period.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.3.</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall by notice to the owner or operator permit the continued operation of the stationary source for the time period proposed, or for the lesser time as the Mayor finds reasonable, or the Mayor may order the owner or operator to discontinue
      operation of the stationary source until the maintenance is completed, or the malfunctioning equipment is repaired.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.4.</num>
    <text>Any article, machine, equipment, device, or other contrivance which conceals an emission from any source shall not be installed or used.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 3 of the District of Columbia Air Pollution Control Act of 1984, D.C. Law 5-165, ยง107, 32 DCR 562, 571 (February 1, 1985).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>