<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-409</num>
  <heading>PROHIBITIONS (§ 31-409)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>409.1.</num>
    <text>No PSP shall participate in a transaction involving taxicab service in the District where the fare, rates, charges, or payment does not comply with the applicable provisions of this title, including this chapter, and §§ 603 and 801.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.2.</num>
    <text>No PSP shall allow its associated operators to limit service or refuse to provide service based on a person’s choice of payment method.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.3.</num>
    <text>No PSP shall allow its associated operators to access a passenger’s payment card information after the payment has been processed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.4.</num>
    <text>No PSP shall allow its MTS to be used by an operator or vehicle not on its inventory at the time the trip is booked by dispatch or by street hail.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.5.</num>
    <text>No PSP shall allow its MTS to be used by any person for a taxicab trip unless the taxicab passenger surcharge is collected from the passenger and paid to the District for such trip.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.6.</num>
    <text>No person shall operate as a PSP, process an in-vehicle payment for a taxicab trip, or sell, lease, lend, or otherwise provide an MTS unit to any person in the District, unless such person is a PSP with current approval of its MTS under this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.7.</num>
    <text>No PSP may alter or attempt to alter its legal obligations under this title or to impose an obligation on any person that is contrary to public policy or that threatens passenger or operator safety, or consumer protection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.8.</num>
    <text>A PSP shall not associate with a taxicab operator who provides service with a vehicle that displays on its exterior the name, logo, insignia, or other unique branding of a taxicab fleet or association, if such fleet or association does not agree to
      the operator’s association with the PSP, and:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>For thirty (30) days following the effective date of this rulemaking, such fleet or association is providing credit card processing services to its associated operators; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>After thirty (30) days following the effective date of this rulemaking, such fleet or association has filed an application for approval as a PSP under this chapter or has been approved as a PSP under this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.9.</num>
    <text>A PSP shall not allow its associated taxicab companies, independent owners, or taxicab operators to associate with a dispatch service that is not in full compliance with this title or other applicable law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.10.</num>
    <text>No PSP or DDS shall participate in processing a payment or otherwise providing service to a passenger who chooses to pay by digital payment, except in the manner required by all applicable provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.11.</num>
    <text>No PSP or DDS shall fail or refuse to participate in processing a digital payment in the manner required by all applicable provisions of this chapter, including, without limitation, a failure to maintain integration as required by § 408.16.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.12.</num>
    <text>No PSP or DDS shall associate with or integrate with a PSP or DDS that does not have the operating authority required by a provision of this title, or that is operated in violation of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 6993 (May 17, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10975 (July 26, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 15560 (November 8, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>