<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-405</num>
  <heading>DECISION TO GRANT OR DENY (§ 31-405)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>405.1.</num>
    <text>The Office shall complete the review process and issue its decision to grant or deny approval of a proposed MTS within thirty (30) days after the application is filed, provided however, that such period may be extended by the Office for no more than
      ten (10) days with notice to the PSP whenever the Office has five (5) proposed MTSs under review.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.2.</num>
    <text>If the Office denies approval on any ground, it shall state the reasons for its decision in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.3.</num>
    <text>A decision to deny approval may be appealed to the Chief of the Office within fifteen (15) business days, and, otherwise, shall constitute a final decision of the Office. The Chief shall issue a decision on such appeal within thirty (30) days. A timely
      appeal of a denial shall extend an existing MTS approval pending the Chief’s decision. A decision of the Chief to affirm or reverse a denial shall constitute a final decision of the Office. A decision of the Chief to remand to the Office for further
      review of the MTS shall extend an existing MTS approval pending the final decision of the Office.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.4.</num>
    <text>An approval shall continue in effect for twelve (12) months, during which time no substantial change shall be made to an approved MTS without written approval from the Office. A PSP shall promptly inform the Office of a proposed substantial change
      that would require written approval. A PSP’s integration with a DDS, including the submission of a proposed integration agreement, shall not constitute a substantial change.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>405.5.</num>
    <text>Each approved MTS shall be listed on the Commission’s website.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 6993 (May 17, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10975 (July 26, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>