<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-403</num>
  <heading>PROPOSED MODERN TAXIMETER SYSTEMS &amp;#8211; APPLICATIONS BY PSPS (§ 31-403)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>403.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall operate as a PSP, process an in-vehicle payment for a taxicab trip, market MTS units, or allow another person to use its MTS units, unless such person is a PSP with current approval of its MTS under this chapter. The approval of a
      PSP’s modern taximeter system under this chapter shall constitute the PSP’s operating authority under this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>403.2.</num>
    <text>Each person seeking approval of a proposed MTS shall file with the Office an application that includes the following information (including such documentation as required by the Office):</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The PSP’s name, business address, and business telephone number, and the name(s) of its owner and operator;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name, business address, and business telephone number of each affiliated business;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A brief narrative describing the proposed MTS and demonstrating that it would meet:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The MTS equipment requirements of § 603.8, including the requirement of § 603.8(n) that a passenger console be incorporated not later than December 1, 2013, and the requirement of § 603.8(n)(3) that a safety feature be incorporated not later than
        June 1, 2014; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The MTS service and support requirements of § 603.9;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A certification that the PSP owns the rights to, or holds licenses to use, all the intellectual property used by the proposed MTS;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The forms of in-vehicle payment that the PSP proposes to offer, in addition to cash (such as near-field communications);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Information showing the PSP is in compliance with federal and District licensing, permitting, registration, anti-discrimination, and taxation requirements applicable to a business operating in the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The address and telephone number for the PSP’s bona fide administrative office or for its registered agent authorized to accept service of process, information showing that the PSP’s bona fide administrative office, if any, is in compliance with
        all laws, rules, and regulations concerning the operation of a place of business in the District, and an indication of whether a place of business would be shared with an affiliated business;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The customer service telephone number that the PSP will provide for passengers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The technical support telephone number that the PSP will provide for taxicab owners and operators;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>The URL for the PSP’s website, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>The trade name for the MTS and for each service offered by an affiliated business;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>A certification that the PSP is in compliance with the Clean Hands Before Receiving a License or Permit Act of 1996 (“Clean Hands Act”), effective May 11, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-118, D.C. Official Code § 47-2862);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>An initial inventory of the vehicles and operators associated with the PSP, as required by § 408.12;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>Information showing the PSP will collect from the passenger and pay to the District the passenger surcharge for each taxicab trip, as required by</text>
    </level>
    <text>§ 408.15;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>A sample agreement used by the PSP to associate with taxicab companies, independent owners, and operators;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(p)</num>
      <text>The name of each dispatch service with which the PSP is associated, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(q)</num>
      <text>Information showing the PSP will be in compliance with the integration requirements of § 408.16; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(r)</num>
      <text>Such other information related to establishing compliance with this chapter as the Office may require at the time of application or during the review process.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>403.3.</num>
    <text>Each application shall be made under penalty of perjury, and shall be accompanied by an application fee of one-thousand dollars ($1,000) and by a surcharge bond.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>403.4.</num>
    <text>A request for approval may be denied if an application contains or was submitted with materially false information provided orally or in writing for the purpose of inducing approval.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 6993 (May 17, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10975 (July 26, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>