<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-321</num>
  <heading>FORMAT OF INVOICES AND CONTRACTS (§ 16-321)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>321.1.</num>
    <text>Spaces shall be provided on the first page of the retail installment contract for the signatures of the purchaser and the seller.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>321.2.</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, all printed portions of the invoice and the retail installment contract shall be at least eight point (8 pt.) type.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>321.3.</num>
    <text>There shall be printed or typed on the first page of each retail installment contract, in BOLD FACE TYPE no smaller than fourteen point (14 pt.), immediately above the line reserved for the signature of the purchaser, the following notice:</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>321.4.</num>
    <text>There shall be printed or typed on the first page of each retail installment contract in BOLD FACE TYPE no smaller than ten point (10 pt.) type, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Each of the captions designated and required by § 320;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A specific statement immediately under &amp;#8220;SUMMARY OF INSURANCE COVERAGE&amp;#8221; [See: § 320.1(g) and § 320.2(g)] that the insurance to be purchased by the seller, if any, does not include liability insurance coverage for personal injury
        and property damage caused to others, unless otherwise stated; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A statement immediately after the statement required by § 321.3(b) that insurance against physical damage to the motor vehicle protects the interests of the seller only, if that is the case.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>321.5.</num>
    <text>There shall be printed or typed on each invoice, in bold face type no smaller than ten (10) point, immediately under &amp;#8220;SUMMARY OF INSURANCE COVERAGE,&amp;#8221; [See: § 320.1(g) and § 320.2(g)] a specific statement that the insurance to be
      purchased by the seller, if any, does not include liability insurance coverage for personal injury and property damage caused others, unless otherwise stated.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>NOTICE TO PURCHASER</heading>
      <text>IT IS AGAINST THE LAW FOR THE SELLER TO PERMIT OR REQUEST YOU TO SIGN THIS DOCUMENT BEFORE ALL BLANKS ABOVE HAVE BEEN FILLED IN BY THE SELLER AND HE HAS SIGNED THIS PAPER CERTIFYING THAT THE ABOVE INFORMATION IS CORRECT.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>