<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-2002</num>
  <heading>PURCHASE OF ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES (§ 23-2002)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2002.1.</num>
    <text>A Caterer licensed under § 2000.1 shall not purchase alcoholic beverages from a Wholesaler other than for scheduled events to be attended by one hundred (100) persons or less. Upon purchasing alcoholic beverages for an event of one hundred (100) persons
      or less from a Wholesaler, a Caterer shall immediately provide the following information to the Wholesaler on a form prescribe by ABRA:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A description of the alcoholic beverages being purchased; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A description, including the location, of the scheduled event for which the alcoholic beverages are being purchased.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2002.2.</num>
    <text>Caterers shall maintain distinct records identifying the alcoholic beverages purchased from Wholesalers for each scheduled event of one hundred (100) persons or less and shall make such records available for inspection, upon request, by the Board
      and by the Wholesaler from which the alcoholic beverages were purchased. A Caterer licensed under § 2000.1 shall, concurrent with the information required in § 2006, provide to the Board a sworn affidavit on a form prepared by ABRA attesting that,
      in the preceding reporting period, it has used alcoholic beverages purchased from Wholesalers only for events of one hundred (100) persons or less. Upon request of the Board, the Caterer shall identify the Wholesaler(s) from whom alcoholic beverages
      have been purchased. The submission of a knowingly false or misleading affidavit shall be grounds for the Board to order the licensee to show cause why the license should not be suspended or revoked, or a civil fine imposed based upon the primary
      tier schedule set forth in D.C. Official Code § 25-830(c) and Chapter 8.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by D.C. ACT 15-442 published at 51 DCR 6525 (July 2, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>