<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-2006</num>
  <heading>CATERERS&amp;#8217; REPORTS (ยง 23-2006)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2006.1.</num>
    <text>Licensees subject to this section shall, semiannually, furnish to the Board, on a form to be prescribed by the Board, a report under oath that includes the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The quantity of alcoholic beverages sold by the licensee in gallons during the preceding six (6) months for beverage purposes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The total dollar amount of receipts for the sale of alcoholic beverages and food;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Of the total in paragraph (b) above, the amount received for the sale of alcoholic beverages and the amount received for the sale of food, and the percentages of the total receipts represented by the respective amounts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The amount expended for alcoholic beverages and the amount expended for food, and the percentages of the total expenditures represented by the respective amounts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The method used to compute the amounts and percentages; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>An affidavit executed by an individual licensee, partner of an applicant partnership, or the appropriate officer of an applicant corporation, attesting to the truth of the statement.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2006.2.</num>
    <text>The submission of a knowingly false or misleading affidavit shall be grounds for the Board to order the licensee to show cause why the license should not be suspended or revoked, or a civil penalty imposed based upon the primary tier schedule set
      forth in D.C. Official Code ยง 25-830(c).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2006.3.</num>
    <text>Licensees subject to this section shall semiannually furnish to the Board, on a form prescribed by the Board, a summary report of the alcoholic beverage purchases it has made from Wholesalers for events for one hundred (100) persons or less.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2006.4.</num>
    <text>In computing the amounts received for alcoholic beverages and for food, a licensee shall exclude all amounts received for taxes and gratuities in conjunction with these transactions, and all amounts, including surcharges, related to the obtaining
      and providing of entertainment or other goods and services at the licensed establishment.</text>
    <text>2006. 5 Failure to timely submit the reports listed ยง 2006.1 to the Board shall constitute grounds for the Board to fine the licensee or suspend the license. Violation of this subsection shall be deemed a secondary tier violation subject to the penalties
      set forth in D.C. Official Code ยง 25-830(d) and Chapter 8.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by D.C. ACT 15-442 published at 51 DCR 6525 (July 2, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>