<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-1406</num>
  <heading>RECORDATION OF THE CLOSING OF A STREET OR ALLEY (§ 24-1406)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1406.1.</num>
    <text>The Director shall record a copy of the law that closes the street or alley and shall record the plat prepared pursuant to this chapter when the following conditions are satisfied:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The law ordering the closing of the street or alley has become effective;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Where applicable, the applicant has complied with the conditions or contingencies required by the law ordering the closing of the street or alley;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Where applicable, the conditions and procedures of §405 of this title and §§ 210 and 211 the Act (D.C. Code §§7-430 and 7-431 (1981)) have been completed and satisfied; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The applicable fees and deposits have been paid by the applicant.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1406.2.</num>
    <text>The provisions of §1406.1 shall not be effective for closings by the District of Columbia Department of Housing and Community Development or by the Pennsylvania Avenue Development Corporation until the Department of Public Works has reviewed and approved
      the final development plans which shall include the information required by §§1400.7 and 1400.8.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1406.3.</num>
    <text>Upon recordation of the plat, the alley or street, or part thereof, as shown on the plat, shall be considered closed and title to the land shall revert to or be vested in fee simple to the owners as shown on the plat.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1406.4.</num>
    <text>Upon recordation of the plat, the right by the public to use the street or alley, or part thereof, which has been closed shall cease unless a temporary continued use is required by the Director, as agreed to by the applicant and the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1406.5.</num>
    <text>Upon the recordation of the plat, the real property encompassing any easement or dedication established or accepted by the law ordering the closing shall thereafter be available for the intended use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1406.6.</num>
    <text>Upon recordation of the plat, the Director shall send a copy of the plat to the applicant and to the Director of the Department of Finance and Revenue.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 560, 567 (February 10, 1984); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 5122, 5124 (July 21, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>