<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-1106</num>
  <heading>EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE (ยง 28-1106)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1106.1.</num>
    <text>The Executive Committee shall be composed of seven (7) members of the Juvenile Justice Advisory Group who shall serve (with the exception of the Vice Chairperson) at the pleasure of the Chairperson.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1106.2.</num>
    <text>Selection of the Executive Committee shall be as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Chairperson of the JJAG shall serve as the chairperson of the Executive Committee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Vice Chairperson shall be a member and shall chair meetings in the absence of the Chairperson;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The chairpersons of the three (3) task groups (subcommittees) shall serve as members of the Executive Committee; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The two (2) remaining membership positions of the Executive Committee shall be filled by appointment by the Chairperson of the JJAG consistent with the composition of the JJAG to ensure equitable representation from government, citizens, and persons
        under twenty-six (26) years of age, contingent upon the other five (5) positions.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1106.3.</num>
    <text>Any member of the JJAG may attend and participate in Executive Committee meetings, but only members of the committee shall have voting privileges.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1106.4.</num>
    <text>Special meetings of the Executive Committee may be held as often as necessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1106.5.</num>
    <text>Special meetings shall be governed by the provisions for regular meetings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1106.6.</num>
    <text>The Executive Committee of the JJAG shall adopt any special rules or procedures necessary consistent with the provisions of this chapter, the provisions of chapter 10 of this title (the rules and procedures of the Criminal Justice Supervisory Board),
      and any other administrative or legislative mandates that may govern this body.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1106.7.</num>
    <text>The primary duties of the Executive Committee shall be as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>To review and integrate components of the proposed Juvenile Justice Plan into a single document. The Executive Committee may, in its discretion, further develop problems and strategies recommended by the subcommittee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>To develop the annual Juvenile Justice travel and training plan;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>To advise the JJAG and its subcommittees about the completeness and comprehensiveness of juvenile justice needs and problems included in the annual plan; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>To review at the request of the Chairperson, recommendations from the subcommittees for grant funding if the subcommittee recommendations are at variance with the state plan, and to perform any other duties consistent with the provisions of this
        chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1106.8.</num>
    <text>Regular meetings of the Executive Committee shall be called as follows by the order of the Chairperson of the Executive Committee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1106.9.</num>
    <text>All meetings of the Executive Committee shall be conducted in accordance with this chapter, chapter 10 of this title, the parliamentary authority, and any other administrative or legislative mandates which may govern the JJAG.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1106.10.</num>
    <text>Official minutes shall be recorded and distributed to each member of the JJAG at least one (1) week in advance of the next Executive Committee meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1106.11.</num>
    <text>Each member or alternate of the Executive Committee shall be entitled to one (1) vote on each issue coming before the Committee in his or her presence. Proxy voting shall not be permitted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1106.12.</num>
    <text>All members of the Executive Committee shall be expected to attend meetings. If a member cannot attend a meeting, he or she shall notify the staff of the Office of Criminal Justice Plans and Analysis.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 1121, 1127-28 (March 14, 1980).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR&amp;#8217;S NOTE</heading>
      <text>Subsections 1106.11 and 1106.12 of the June 1984 edition of this title have been deleted because they were redundant to subsections 1106.4 through 1106.6 of this section.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>