<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-1107</num>
  <heading>SUBCOMMITTEES[COLON] GENERAL (ยง 28-1107)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1107.1.</num>
    <text>The Juvenile Justice Advisory Group shall have three (3) standing subcommittees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1107.2.</num>
    <text>The members shall be appointed by the Chair of the JJAG, consistent with the composition of the JJAG, ensuring equitable representation from government members, citizen members, and members under twenty-six (26) years of age.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1107.3.</num>
    <text>The chairperson of each subcommittee shall be appointed by the Chairperson of the JJAG. Each subcommittee chairperson shall be a member of the Executive Committee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1107.4.</num>
    <text>The subcommittees shall meet as necessary, in the judgment of their respective chairpersons, but not less than once each calendar quarter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1107.5.</num>
    <text>Subcommittee meetings shall be called by the respective Chairperson, in accordance with the notice requirements for regular meetings of the JJAG.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1107.6.</num>
    <text>Minutes shall be kept of all subcommittee meetings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1107.7.</num>
    <text>Upon report to and acceptance of the JJAG, minutes shall be filed with the JJAG.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1107.8.</num>
    <text>The three (3) subcommittees shall be the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>PRE-ADJUDICATION &amp;#8211; Encompasses programs and services which relate to juvenile delinquency prevention; diagnostic and treatment initiatives (such as those involving developmental disabilities); screening and treatment for substance abuse,
        mental health problems, and special education needs. Youth employment, the public school system, recreation, and outreach services shall be included in this area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>ADJUDICATION &amp;#8211; Includes all court related programs and services at both the initial court hearing and adjudication stages of court processing. Programmatically responsible for diversion and alternatives to secure detention services, including
        court processing of both Persons in Need of Supervision (PINS) and delinquents; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>POST-ADJUDICATION &amp;#8211; Includes all programs and services which affect a youth after conclusion of the fact finding hearing or trial and upon either commitment to an institution, placement on court probation, or in after care services. Responsibilities
        shall extend to the Children&amp;#8217;s Center and group homes for adjudicated youth.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1107.9.</num>
    <text>The subcommittees shall adopt any special rules or procedures necessary and consistent with the provisions of this chapter, the provisions of chapter 10 of this title, and any other administrative or legislative mandates that may govern the JJAG.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1107.10.</num>
    <text>Ad hoc committees may be appointed from time to time by the Chairperson of the Juvenile Justice Advisory Group.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 1121, 1128-29, 1131-32 (March 14, 1980).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>