<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-1100</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 28-1100)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1100.1.</num>
    <text>The Juvenile Justice Advisory Group (also referred to in this chapter as the &amp;#8220;JJAG&amp;#8221;) shall provide advice and consultation to the Mayor, the Office of Criminal Justice Plans and Analysis (also referred to in this chapter as the
      &amp;#8220;OCJPA&amp;#8221;), and the Criminal Justice Supervisory Board (also referred to as the &amp;#8220;CJSB&amp;#8221;) on problems and policy-related issues pertaining to, but not limited to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The identification and analysis of special service needs of District youth; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The identification of corrective measures within operating agencies and grant funded programs designed to address the special service needs of District youth.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.2.</num>
    <text>The JJAG shall participate in the development and review of the annual Law Enforcement Assistance Administration (&amp;#8220;LEAA&amp;#8221;) Juvenile Justice Comprehensive Plan for the District, prior to submission to the Criminal Justice Supervisory
      Board for final action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.3.</num>
    <text>The JJAG shall assist in the development of operating standards for all juvenile detention and correction facilities, group homes, and foster care homes and programs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.4.</num>
    <text>The JJAG shall assume a role in the monitoring of all juvenile detention and correction facilities and community-based programs to ensure compliance with the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974, as amended.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.5.</num>
    <text>The JJAG shall have an opportunity to review and comment on the progress and accomplishments of public and private sector juvenile justice and delinquency prevention programs funded under the comprehensive state plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.6.</num>
    <text>The JJAG shall have an opportunity to review and comment on &amp;#8220;special&amp;#8221; public and private juvenile justice research studies that impact upon District youth or juvenile services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.7.</num>
    <text>The JJAG shall have an opportunity to review and comment on all juvenile justice and delinquency prevention grant applications that are submitted to OCJPA, other than those subject to review by the State&amp;#8217;s judicial planning committee established
      pursuant to § 203(c) of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968, as amended.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.8.</num>
    <text>The review and comment permitted under § 1100.7 shall be made no later than thirty (30) days after the submission of an application to the advisory group.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.9.</num>
    <text>The JJAG shall assume an advisory role relative to the District&amp;#8217;s maintenance of effort under § 261(b) and § 520(b) of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act, of 1968, as amended.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.10.</num>
    <text>The JJAG shall assume an advisory role in the composition of the Criminal Justice Supervisory Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.11.</num>
    <text>The Office of Criminal Justice Plans and Analysis (also referred to in this chapter as the &amp;#8220;OCJPA&amp;#8221;) shall assist the JJAG in matters of administration and shall provide it with necessary staff, including secretarial service in
      matters of JJAG related business. Services shall include, but not be limited to, administrative support.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.12.</num>
    <text>The rules contained in the current edition of Robert&amp;#8217;s Rules of Order, Newly Revised, shall govern the JJAG in all cases to which they are applicable and in which they are not inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter or any special
      rules of order the JJAG may adopt.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.13.</num>
    <text>Proposed alterations, amendments, or repeal of the provisions of this chapter may be made by a recorded majority vote of the JJAG membership (not counting vacancies) at any regular meeting if notice of the meeting contains a statement of the proposed
      alteration, amendment, or repeal; and if the notice of alteration, amendment, or repeal has been given to each JJAG membership in writing at least two (2) weeks prior to the meeting.</text>
    <text>By Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 2000-149, dated October 3, 2000, the Office of Justice Grants Administration was designated as the sole agency responsible for implementing the provisions of the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974, as
      amended.</text>
    <text>By Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 2001-185, dated December 19, 2001, the Office of Policy Research and Development was established in the Executive Office of the Mayor and Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 93-34, dated April 1, 1992, which established the Office of
      Policy and Evaluation, was rescinded. Pursuant to paragraph 4 of Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 2001-185, &amp;#8220;all positions, personnel, property, records and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds of the Office of Policy
      and Evaluation [were] transferred to the Office of Policy Research and Development.&amp;#8221;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974, as amended, Pub. L. No. 93-415, 88 Stat. 1109; and Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 79-40, dated February 22, 1979.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 1121-1122, 1132-33 (March 14, 1980).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR&amp;#8217;S NOTE</heading>
      <text>Pursuant to section 301 of D.C. Law 9-145, the &amp;#8220;Omnibus Budget Support Act of 1992,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;the functions of the Office of Criminal Justice Plans and Analysis, established pursuant to section 4(a) of the Criminal Justice
        Supervisory Board Act of 1978 . . . and all positions, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available to or to made available relating the functions of the Office of Criminal Justice Plans
        and Analysis [were] transferred to the Mayor&amp;#8217;s Office of Policy and Program Evaluation. . . .&amp;#8221;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>MISCELLANEOUS NOTES</heading>
      <text>ESTABLISHMENT OF THE JUVENILE JUSTICE ADVISORY GROUP, See Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 84-167, dated September 18, 1984 (rescinding Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 79-40, dated February 22, 1979; Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 93-91, dated July 8, 1993 (rescinding
        Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 84-167); Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 95-60, dated April 17, 1995 (rescinding Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 93-91); Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 98-29, dated March 17, 1998 (rescinding Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 95-60); Mayor&amp;#8217;s
        Order 98-93, dated June 11, 1998 (rescinding Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 98-29); Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 2000-128, dated August 15, 2000 (rescinding, in part, Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 98-93); and Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 2000-149, dated October 3, 2000
        (rescinding Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 98-93).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>