<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-8299</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 17-8299)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8299.1.</num>
    <text>As used in this chapter, the following terms shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Applicant &amp;#8211; a person applying for a license to practice as a physical therapist assistant under this chapter.</text>
    <text>Board &amp;#8211; the Board of Physical Therapy, established by section 209 of the Act (D.C. Official Code ยง 2-1202.09).</text>
    <text>Continuing education unit &amp;#8211; a unit of measurement representing ten (10) hours of continuing education credit.</text>
    <text>Direct supervision &amp;#8211; the supervision in which a physical therapist is personally present and immediately available within the treatment area to give aid, direction, and instruction when physical therapy procedures or activities are performed.</text>
    <text>Physical therapist &amp;#8211; a person licensed to practice physical therapy under the Act.</text>
    <text>Physical therapist assistant &amp;#8211; a physical therapy assistant who is a person licensed to practice under the Act.</text>
    <text>Practice of physical therapy &amp;#8211; the independent evaluation of human disability, injury, or disease by means of noninvasive tests of neuromuscular functions and other standard procedures of physical therapy, and the treatment of human disability,
      injury, or disease by therapeutic procedures, rendered on the prescription of or referral by a licensed physician, osteopath, dentist, or podiatrist, or by a licensed registered nurse certified to practice as an advanced registered nurse as authorized
      pursuant to section 601 of the Act (D.C. Official Code ยง 3-1206.01), embracing the specific scientific application of physical measures to secure the functional rehabilitation of the human body. These measures include the use of therapeutic exercise,
      therapeutic massage, heat or cold, air, light, water, electricity, or sound for the purpose of correcting or alleviating any physical or mental disability, or preventing the development of any physical or mental disability, or the performance of
      noninvasive tests of neuromuscular functions as an aid to the detection or treatment of any human condition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8299.2.</num>
    <text>The definitions in ยง 4099 of chapter 40 of this title are incorporated by reference into and are applicable to this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 8802 (August 15, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>