<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-8206</num>
  <heading>CONTINUING EDUCATION REQUIREMENTS (§ 17-8206)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8206.1.</num>
    <text>Subject to § 8206.2, this section shall apply to applicants for the renewal, reactivation, or reinstatement of a license expiring January 31, 2011, and for subsequent terms.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8206.2.</num>
    <text>This section shall not apply to applicants for an initial license by examination or endorsement, nor shall it apply to applicants for the first renewal of a license granted by examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8206.3.</num>
    <text>A continuing education credit shall be valid only if it is part of a program or activity approved by the Board in accordance with § 8207.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8206.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant for renewal of a license shall submit proof pursuant to § 8206.7 of having completed three (3) continuing education units or thirty (30) hours of approved continuing education credit during the two (2) year period preceding the date the
      license expires.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8206.5</num>
    <text>8206.5 Beginning with the licensure period ending January 31, 2015, not more than one-half (1/2) of the total required number of Continuing Education Units (CEUs) may be accepted in any renewal period, or for reinstatement or reactivation of a license,
      for approved online courses, home study courses, video courses, telecourses, videoconferences, and teleconference activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8206.6.</num>
    <text>To qualify for a license, a person in inactive status within the meaning of Section 511 of the Act (D.C. Official Code § 3-1205.11) who submits an application to reactivate a license shall submit proof of having completed fifteen (15) hours of approved
      continuing education credit within one (1) year prior to application for each license year after January 31, 2011, that the applicant was in inactive status.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8206.7.</num>
    <text>To qualify for a license, an applicant for reinstatement of a license shall submit proof of having completed fifteen (15) hours of approved continuing education credit for each year after January 31, 2011, that the applicant was not licensed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8206.8.</num>
    <text>An applicant under this section shall prove completion of required continuing education credits by submitting with the application the following information with respect to each program:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the sponsor of the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name of the program, its location, a description of the subject matter covered, and the names of the instructors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The dates on which the applicant attended the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The hours of credit claimed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Verification by the sponsor of completion, by signature or stamp.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8206.9.</num>
    <text>If an applicant for renewal of a license fails to submit proof of having completed continuing education requirements by the date the license expires, the applicant shall not practice until his or her license has been renewed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8206.10.</num>
    <text>An applicant for renewal of a license who fails to submit proof of having completed continuing education requirements by the date the license expires may renew the license up to sixty (60) days after the expiration by submitting proof pursuant to
      § 8206.7 and paying the late fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8206.11.</num>
    <text>If an applicant for renewal of a license fails to submit proof of completion of continuing education requirements or pay the late fee within sixty (60) days after the expiration of the applicant&amp;#8217;s license, the license shall be considered
      to have lapsed and the applicant shall be required to apply for reinstatement pursuant to Section 512 of the Act (D.C. Official Code § 3-1205.12).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8206.12.</num>
    <text>The Board may, in its discretion, grant an extension of the sixty (60) day period to renew after expiration if the applicant&amp;#8217;s failure to submit proof of completion was for good cause. As used in this section, &amp;#8220;good cause&amp;#8221;
      includes the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Serious and protracted illness of the applicant; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The death or serious and protracted illness of a member of the applicant&amp;#8217;s immediate family.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8206.13.</num>
    <text>The Board may conduct an audit of licensees to determine compliance with the continuing education requirements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 8802 (August 15, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 6477 (May 3, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>