<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-8204</num>
  <heading>LICENSURE BY EXAMINATION (ยง 17-8204)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8204.1.</num>
    <text>An applicant for licensure as a physical therapist assistant by examination shall initiate the application process by submitting a completed application together with the appropriate application fee and the documentation required by ยง 8202.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8204.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant for licensure as a physical therapist assistant shall have pre-approval from the Board before taking any licensure examination. Only an applicant who has graduated from an accredited physical therapist assistant program may be approved
      by the Board to take the physical therapist assistant licensure examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8204.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant for licensure by examination shall take and pass the National Physical Therapist Examination (&amp;#8220;NPTE&amp;#8221;) and the District of Columbia jurisprudence examination for physical therapist assistants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8204.4.</num>
    <text>Following approval from the Board to take the applicable examinations, the applicant may take the national examination and the District jurisprudence examination in any order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8204.5.</num>
    <text>The passing score on the national examination shall be determined by the body administering the examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8204.6.</num>
    <text>The District jurisprudence examination shall be developed and administered by the Board or, a body approved by the Board, on laws and rules pertaining to the practice of physical therapy in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8204.7.</num>
    <text>The District jurisprudence examination may consist of questions on District of Columbia laws pertaining to the practice of physical therapy including the Act, this chapter, and chapters 40 and 41 of this title. The passing score of the District examination
      shall be determined by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8204.8.</num>
    <text>An applicant for licensure who does not pass either examination on the first attempt shall seek and obtain Board approval for any subsequent attempts to retake the examination. Before the Board may approve an applicant for subsequent testing beyond
      three (3) attempts, an applicant shall submit proof satisfactory to the Board of having completed any remediation as determined by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8204.9.</num>
    <text>If the Board determines that an applicant has engaged in or has attempted to engage in conduct that subverts or undermines the integrity of either the national examination or the District jurisprudence examination, the Board may disqualify the applicant
      from taking the examinations. Examples of such conduct may include, but are not limited to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Utilizing in any manner recalled or memorized examination questions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Failing to comply with all test center security procedures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Attempting to communicate with other examinees during the test; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Copying or sharing examination questions or answers or portions of questions or answers.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8204.10.</num>
    <text>All occurrences of any violation set forth in ยง 8204.9 shall be recorded in the official records of the Board. Board action may include, but is not limited to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Disqualifying test results of the applicant&amp;#8217;s examinations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Disqualifying the applicant, permanently or for a specified period of time, from eligibility for the examinations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Disqualifying the applicant, permanently or for a specified period of time, from eligibility for licensure; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Revocation, suspension, or imposition of probationary conditions on a license issued to the applicant.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 8802 (August 15, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>