<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-5306</num>
  <heading>CONFLICT OF INTEREST (§ 21-5306)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5306.1.</num>
    <text>No Authority employee, officer, board member or agent shall participate in or attempt to influence any procurement when the employee, officer, board member or agent knows or has reason to know:</text>
    <text>The employee, officer, board member or agent, or any relative of an employee, officer, board member or agent has a financial interest pertaining to the procurement;</text>
    <text>A business or organization in which the employee, officer, board member or agent, or any relative of an employee, officer, board member or agent has a financial interest pertaining to the procurement; or</text>
    <text>The employee, officer, board member or agent or any relative of an employee, officer, board member or agent has an agreement or arrangement for prospective employment with a business or organization involved with the procurement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5306.2.</num>
    <text>It is a breach of ethical standards for any employee to receive or attempt to realize personal gain or advantage, either directly or indirectly, as a result of their participation in any action related to any procurement. No employee, officer, board
      member or agent may solicit or accept, directly or indirectly, on his/her own behalf or on behalf of a relative, any benefit, such as a gift, gratuity, favor, compensation, offer of employment, or anything having more than a nominal monetary value
      from any person, or entity having or seeking to have a contractual, business, or financial relationship with the Authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5306.3.</num>
    <text>In the event an Authority employee, officer or agent, other than the General Manager, is offered or receives any benefit in violation of any provision of §§ 5304-5308 from any person or entity, the employee shall report the matter to the General Manager
      or designee who shall determine the disposition of the benefit. The failure to report such offer or benefit to the General Manager or designee is a breach of these ethical standards.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5306.4.</num>
    <text>In the event the General Manager, a Board member other than the Board Chair, or an alternate member receives any offer or benefit in violation of any provision of §§ 5304-5308 from any person or entity, the Board member, alternate member or General
      Manager shall report the benefit to the Board Chair who shall determine the disposition of the matter or benefit. In the event that the Board Chair receives any offer or benefit in violation of any provision of §§ 5304-5308 from any person or entity,
      the Board Chair shall report the benefit to the Vice Chair who shall determine the disposition of the matter or benefit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Emergency Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 613 (January 22, 1999) [EXPIRED]; as Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7349 (September 17, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 4484 (June 12, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>