<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-609</num>
  <heading>FEES FOR PERMITS (§ 21-609)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>609.1.</num>
    <text>Fees for permits to fill or dredge, construct, reconstruct, or repair any structure issued under this chapter shall be as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Work costing up to five hundred dollars ($500)………………………………………………$ 9.00;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Work costing from five hundred and one dollars ($501) to one thousand dollars ($1,000)…..$14.00; And</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>For each additional one thousand dollars ($1,000) of increased cost (over $1,000)…………..$14.00.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>609.2.</num>
    <text>Refunds of permit fees shall be made as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If no work has been done under authority of permit, the fee in excess of the following shall be refunded:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The cost of inspection to verify no work having been done, based on ten dollars ($10) per inspector hour; plus</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The cost of any engineering examination time previously devoted to approval of plans, based on fifteen dollars ($15) per hour; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Fourteen dollars ($14) administrative costs for issuance and refund.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If work authorized by permit has been only partially one, and if the District is satisfied that no more work will be done under the permit, the fee in excess of the following shall be refunded:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The cost of any engineering plans examination, based on fifteen dollars ($15) per hour;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Cost of inspections, based on ten dollars ($10) per inspector hour; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Fourteen dollars ($14) administrative costs of issuance and refund.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>609.3.</num>
    <text>In order to receive a refund under this section, the request for refund shall be made within six (6) months from date of issuance, and the permit and receipt shall be returned to the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>609.4.</num>
    <text>No permit fee shall be charged when supported by evidence indicating that the applicant is under contract or subcontract to perform the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Work done exclusively for the District of Columbia; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Work done under contract for the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 201 of the License Fees and Charges Act of 1976, D.C. Law 1-82, 23 DCR 111, 126 (July 2, 1976), 5T DCRR §4.1 (September 21, 1970).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>