<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-608</num>
  <heading>CONDUCT OF HEARINGS (§ 21-608)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>608.1.</num>
    <text>The hearing provided for in this chapter shall be a public hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>608.2.</num>
    <text>Any party may be represented by counsel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>608.3.</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall preside over the hearing, and shall make decisions and orders in the proceedings as deemed needful and just for the government, regulation, location, or control of any property, right, or privilege placed under the Mayor&amp;#8217;s
      jurisdiction by law. The Mayor shall determine the order of proof and may hear oral or receive written arguments.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>608.4.</num>
    <text>The hearing may be adjourned from time to time, and, if the time and place of the adjourned hearing is publicly announced when the adjournment is ordered, no further notice of the adjourned hearing needs to be published or given.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>608.5.</num>
    <text>Formal rules of evidence need not be applied by the Mayor in any hearing under this chapter, and the Mayor shall have authority, in his or her discretion, to receive evidence which, in the opinion of the Mayor shall be relevant and have probative
      value.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>608.6.</num>
    <text>After the hearing is closed and all evidence that the petitioners, representatives of the District, intervenors, and other interested parties desire to submit has been received, the Mayor shall make such findings and such order or orders as shall
      be just.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>608.7.</num>
    <text>Copies of the findings and order(s) shall be mailed to all interested parties after the entry of the findings and order(s).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>608.8.</num>
    <text>Any interested party may make application in writing for rehearing. The application must be made within ten (10) days after the mailing date of the copies of the findings and order(s) of the Mayor. The Mayor shall not be required in ruling upon an
      application for rehearing to have further hearings or to hear arguments, but may act upon the application for rehearing without a hearing or argument of the application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>608.9.</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall cause a record to be made of all proceedings conducted, findings entered, and orders issued under this chapter. The record may include a stenographic transcript of the proceedings, if ordered by the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>608.10.</num>
    <text>Following the Mayor&amp;#8217;s final decision, the record shall be filed promptly in the Department and shall be open to public inspection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order No. 54-576, dated March 16, 1954, 5T DCRR §§3.4, 3.5, and 3.7 (September 21, 1970).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>