<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-409</num>
  <heading>ITEMIZED STATEMENTS AND RECEIPTS (ยง 16-409)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>409.1.</num>
    <text>Before commencing a private tow, the tow truck operator shall furnish to the owner or operator of the vehicle to be towed a signed and itemized estimate of charges for the tow and other services to be rendered, on a form approved by the Director.
      The owner or operator of the vehicle shall sign the form before commencement of the tow.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.2.</num>
    <text>Each itemized estimate of charges, as prescribed in ยง 409.1, shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The location from which and to which the vehicle is to be towed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the towing business and the name of the tow truck operator;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If available, the name and address of the owner or operator of the vehicle to be towed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A brief description of the vehicle to be towed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The license plate number and state of registration of the vehicle to be towed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>An itemized estimate of fees to be charged for towing services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The maximum rate charged per 24 hour period or part thereof, for the storage of the towed vehicle, and a statement that the 24 hour period shall start when the vehicle enters the towing service storage lot; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The location of the towing service storage lot or repair facility to which the vehicle will be towed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.3.</num>
    <text>After rendering the towing and related services, the tow truck operator shall enter upon the itemized statement the actual amount paid for services rendered, and shall sign the statement to acknowledge receipt of payment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.4.</num>
    <text>A copy of each statement and receipt submitted by a tow truck operator in accordance with the requirements of this section shall be retained by the towing business for three (3) years from the date of issuance, and shall be exhibited upon demand to
      the Chief of Police or the Director or their agents.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.5.</num>
    <text>The direction to tow by an authorized official, in accordance with any section of these regulations, shall not constitute an agreement on his/her behalf, or on behalf of the agency for which he/she works, to pay any charges in connection with the
      tow, but shall constitute only an authorization to remove the motor vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.6.</num>
    <text>The owner of a towed vehicle shall be responsible for paying all charges for a public tow, and all related towing services charges, in an amount not to exceed the charges authorized by the Director pursuant to ยง 408.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.7.</num>
    <text>Payment of all lawful towing and storage charges shall be made by the owner of the vehicle, an agent of the owner, or the insurer of the vehicle before the vehicle is released by the towing business, the tow truck operator, or towing service storage
      lot operator.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 522 (January 21, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>