<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-799</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 28-799)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>799.1</num>
    <text>799.1 When used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have theeanings prescribed:</text>
    <text>Absconder &amp;#8211; A pretrial CCC defendant conditionally released pursuant to.C. Official Code ยง 23-1321(c)(1)(B)(xi) (2001) who fails to return to his/herssigned CCC after an authorized release into the community or who leaves theCC without authorization.
      The failure to return after an authorized release orn unauthorized absence is a violation of the conditions of release and mayesult in a prosecution for contempt of court pursuant to the provisions of D.C.fficial Code ยง 23-1329, or escape under
      D.C. Official Code ยง 22-2601.</text>
    <text>Administrative hold &amp;#8211; Confinement of a CCC defendant to the center, for aeriod not to exceed twenty-four (24) hours (excluding weekends and holidays),ending the investigation of a complaint/allegation of a program or centeriolation.</text>
    <text>Altered item &amp;#8211; An item that has been modified or remanufactured forurposes other than the original use.</text>
    <text>Chain of custody &amp;#8211; The practice of preserving evidence and documenting theecord of who handled and controlled the evidence.</text>
    <text>Contraband &amp;#8211; Any unauthorized item found in the possession or control of aCC defendant.</text>
    <text>Curfew &amp;#8211; The designated time that a CCC defendant is required by courtrder or program requirement to return to the CCC following an authorizedelease to the community.</text>
    <text>Curfew violator &amp;#8211; A CCC defendant who fails to return to the CCC at theuthorized time, returns after curfew, but before a warrant for escape isssued.</text>
    <text>Detention &amp;#8211; The placement of a CCC defendant in the Central Detentionacility (CDF) following a formal complaint/allegation of a Class I Infractionending judicial intervention and/or review, or following a formalomplaint/allegation of a Class
      II Infraction by a defendant who is reasonablyelieved to present a high risk of danger to self or others, or presents a riskf flight, and who has been remanded to the CDF for more than twenty-four (24)ours.</text>
    <text>Disciplinary team &amp;#8211; The CCC staff designated by the CCCdministrator/Director to conduct disciplinary hearings for violations of ClassI or Class III infractions.</text>
    <text>Evidence &amp;#8211; Any item or information that tends to establish or disprove aact.</text>
    <text>Room Confinement/Restriction &amp;#8211; The confinement of a CCC defendant, wheneemed appropriate by the CCC Administrator/Director or designee, to a roomithin the facility except to attend work, school, scheduled medicalppointments, meals, legal
      visits, training programs and community service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 4558, 4569-70 (May 17, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>