<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-6311</num>
  <heading>HEARING PROCEDURES (ยง 14-6311)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6311.1.</num>
    <text>At the hearing, the complainant shall make a showing of entitlement to the relief sought. If in the opinion of the hearing officer the complainant fails to do so, the hearing officer may render a decision in favor of DCHA without further presentation
      of evidence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6311.2.</num>
    <text>If the hearing officer decides the complainant has made a sufficient showing, DCHA shall justify the action or inaction against which the complaint is directed or the proposed deposition in its answer to the complaint.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6311.3.</num>
    <text>Both parties to the hearing may present evidence and arguments in support of their positions, controvert evidence and cross-examine all witnesses for the other side.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6311.4.</num>
    <text>The hearing shall be conducted informally by the hearing officer, and oral or documentary evidence relevant to the facts and issues raised by the complaint and answer may be received without regard to admissibility under the rules of evidence applicable
      to judicial proceedings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6311.5.</num>
    <text>The hearing officer shall require DCHA, the complainant, counsel, and other participants or spectators to conduct themselves in an orderly manner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6311.6.</num>
    <text>Failure to comply with the directions of the hearing officer to obtain order may result in exclusion from the hearing or in a decision adverse to the interest of the disorderly party and granting or denial of the relief sought, as appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 7973, 8017 (December 26, 1986); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 2455 (March 15, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>