<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-6302</num>
  <heading>INFORMAL SETTLEMENT OF COMPLAINTS (§ 14-6302)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6302.1.</num>
    <text>Within three (3) working days of receipt of the complaint, DCHA shall schedule a conference with the complainant to informally discuss the complaint with the objective of reaching a settlement without a formal hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6302.2.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall convene the informal settlement conference within ten (10) working days of the date the complaint was filed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6302.3.</num>
    <text>If a settlement is reached, within ten (10) working days of the conference, the terms of the settlement shall be put in writing by DCHA, signed by each party, and made a part of the complainant’s DCHA file. A copy of the settlement shall be given
      to the complainant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6302.4.</num>
    <text>If a settlement cannot be reached, DCHA shall prepare and serve on the complainant a written answer to the complaint within ten (10) working days of the conference with the complainant. The answer shall specify the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The DCHA’s proposed disposition of the complaint and the specific reasons therefore;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The right of the complainant to a hearing, and the procedure for requesting a hearing; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The time allowed to request a hearing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6302.5.</num>
    <text>The answer shall be served upon the complainant as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Where the complainant is a resident, by personally serving the answer on the complainant or leaving a copy at the dwelling unit with a person of suitable age, or posting on the door of complainant’s unit if no one is at home; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Where the complainant is an applicant, by sending the answer by first class mail, postage prepaid, to complainant’s address as it appears in the records of DCHA.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 7973, 8014 (December 26, 1986); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 2291, 2292 (April 3, 1992); and Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 2455 (March 15, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>