<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-6303</num>
  <heading>REQUEST FOR HEARING (§ 14-6303)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6303.1.</num>
    <text>If the complainant is not satisfied with the proposed disposition of his or her complaint, he or she may submit in person or by mail a written request for a hearing. Upon request, DCHA will assist a complainant in putting his or her complaint in writing.
      The written request shall be provided:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>To the Office of Fair Hearings (OFH); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>To the OFH through the office of the property in which the complainant resides.</text>
    </level>
    <text>On determinations of ineligibility for applicants for public housing, the notice will include the complaint form by which families can request a hearing and return it to DCHA. The complaint form will also be available to applicants and residents at
      all DCHA offices.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6303.2.</num>
    <text>A complainant’s request for a hearing, which shall be in writing, shall be filed as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If the complainant is a resident, within seven (7) working days from the date the answer is served; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the complainant is an applicant, within ten (10) working days from the date the answer is mailed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6303.3.</num>
    <text>If the complainant does not request a hearing within the specified time, DCHA’s disposition of the complaint under § 6302.4 shall become final. This shall not constitute a waiver of the complainant’s right to contest DCHA’s actions in an appropriate
      judicial proceeding.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6303.4.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of a request for a hearing, OFH shall assign a hearing officer to the complaint from the hearing panel, on a rotating basis to the extent possible.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6303.5.</num>
    <text>Within fifteen (15) working days, the hearing officer shall schedule a hearing time, date and place, reasonably convenient to both the complainant and the DCHA, and shall notify the complainant and DCHA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6303.6.</num>
    <text>Within thirty (30) days of the date the hearing is scheduled, OFH shall convene the hearing, unless rescheduled for good cause by the assigned hearing officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 7973, 8013-14 (December 26, 1986); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 2291, 2292 (April 3, 1992); and Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 2455-56 (March 15, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>