<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-6307</num>
  <heading>RIGHTS OF COMPLAINANTS (ยง 14-6307)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6307.1.</num>
    <text>The complainant shall be afforded a fair hearing providing the basic safeguards of due process, which shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The right to be represented by counsel or another person chosen as a representative;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The right to a private hearing, unless the complainant requests a public hearing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The opportunity to examine, before the hearing, documents, records, and regulations of DCHA that are relevant to the hearing. Any document not so made available after a request for the document has been made by the complainant may not be used as
        evidence by DCHA at the hearing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>When requested, DCHA shall provide to the complainant, at no charge, fifty (50) pages of documents, records, and unpublished regulations of DCHA relevant to the hearing. A reasonable charge of not more than twenty five (25) cents per page may be
        assessed for reproducing material in excess of fifty (50) pages requested by the complainant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The right to present evidence and arguments in support of his or her complaint, to controvert evidence relied on by DCHA, and to confront and cross-examine all witnesses on whose testimony or information DCHA relies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The right to a decision based solely upon the facts presented at the hearing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The right to arrange, in advance, and at his or her expense, to receive a transcript of the hearing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The right to request a reasonable accommodation for a disability.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 7973, 8015 (December 26, 1986); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 2455, 2457 (March 15, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>