<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-4725</num>
  <heading>THE CONTRACTING OFFICERS RESPONSIBILITY FOR CONTRACT ADMINISTRATION (§ 27-4725)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4725.1.</num>
    <text>The Contracting Officer for a particular contract has overall responsibility for the contract’s administration. Among other things, this requires the Contracting Officer to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Monitor whether goods or services are delivered or completed on schedule and conform to contract requirements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Ensure that any contractually required inspection or acceptance procedures are followed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Monitor the contractor’s compliance with any subcontracting requirements contained in the contract;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Identify and attempt to resolve issues or problems that arise during contract performance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Monitor whether the contractor is complying with First Source hiring requirements, CBE Utilization requirements and other similar economic inclusion requirements in the contract.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4725.2.</num>
    <text>The Contracting Officer is the only representative of the Department with the authority to take the following actions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Authorize contract payments;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Exercise contract options;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Terminate the contract; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Modify the contract.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4725.3.</num>
    <text>Prior to terminating a contract, the Contracting Officer shall first obtain the approval of the CCO.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4725.4.</num>
    <text>No representative of the Department, including a Contracting Officer, shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Act in a manner that misleads a contractor regarding the limits of his or her authority; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Direct or encourage a contractor to perform work that has not been properly authorized.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DC 8805 (October 14, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 985, 1010 (February 10, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>