<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-4703</num>
  <heading>DELEGATION OF AUTHORITY TO CONTRACTING OFFICERS (§ 27-4703)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4703.1.</num>
    <text>The CCO may delegate his or her contracting authority to employees of the Department, or employees of the District of Columbia government acting on behalf of the Department, who shall be designated as “Contracting Officers.” Any such delegation shall
      be in writing and shall specify any limits on a Contracting Officer’s delegated authority (for example, limits on the dollar value of contracts the individual is authorized to award). In no case shall a Contracting Officer’s authority exceed the
      CCO’s authority. All such delegations shall be made publicly available on the Department’s website.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4703.2.</num>
    <text>In delegating his or her contracting authority, the CCO shall ensure that each delegated Contracting Officer has the experience, knowledge, and judgment necessary to fulfill the duties of a Contracting Officer, including a solid understanding of the
      Department’s procurement rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4703.3.</num>
    <text>Subject to compliance with these rules, Contracting Officers have wide latitude to exercise business judgment in conducting procurements.</text>
    <text>Consequently, the ability to exercise that discretion wisely and responsibly is an important job qualification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4703.4.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall ensure that Contracting Officers and other contracting personnel periodically receive training to strengthen and update their skills and knowledge concerning contracting and procurement matters.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 8805 (October 14, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 985, 988 (February 10, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>