<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-605</num>
  <heading>AGREEMENTS WITH PARTICIPATING EMPLOYERS (ยง 7-605)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>605.1.</num>
    <text>Participating employers shall enter into a formal agreement with the Director in order to be eligible to receive the reimbursement incentives in ยง604.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>605.2.</num>
    <text>The agreement shall contain the employer&amp;#8217;s concurrence to hire into jobs approved by the Director only eligible individuals referred by the D.C. Government&amp;#8217;s Public Employment Service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>605.3.</num>
    <text>The Agreement shall certify the employer&amp;#8217;s intention to do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Hire participant-employees for a full fifty-two (52) weeks of subsidized on the job training; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Retain in employment successful participant-employees after the completion of the one (1) year of program participation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>605.4.</num>
    <text>In addition, the participation agreement shall contain as a minimum the following elements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A brief training outline;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The method and maximum amount of reimbursement for on-the-job training;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The amount of participant-employees to be trained;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A job description and specification of participant-employees wage rates;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A requirement that employers are to maintain payroll records, time and attendance records and job duties statements related to participant-employees; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>An assurance that the employer will comply with the Act and rules or regulations issued under the Act.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>605.5.</num>
    <text>The Director shall agree to reimburse a participating employer as frequently as every thirty (30) days based upon the submission by the employer of a certified invoice/report in the form specified by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>605.6.</num>
    <text>The Director shall exercise his or her authority with respect to contracts and grant agreements in accordance with the delegation contained in Commissioner&amp;#8217;s Order No. 74-144.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>