<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2700</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 14-2700)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2700.1.</num>
    <text>The purpose of the First Right Purchase Assistance Program (also referred to in this chapter as the “Program”) shall be to increase the homeownership opportunities available to low-income and moderate-income District residents threatened with displacement
      by providing financial assistance to enable tenants to exercise their right to purchase their housing accommodations pursuant to D.C. Law 3-86, the “Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980,” D.C. Official Code §§ 42-3401.01 et seq. (2001).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.2.</num>
    <text>The objective of the Program shall be to provide affordable financing in the form of interest-bearing and non-interest-bearing loans, and loan guarantees, to assist the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Individual households with the financing of pre-purchase and down payment costs for single family, cooperative, and condominium housing; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Tenant associations with the financing of the development costs (acquisition, rehabilitation, and marketing) associated with the conversion of multi-unit rental housing to cooperatives and condominiums.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.3.</num>
    <text>The Director of the Department of Housing and Community Development (also referred to in this chapter as the “Department” or “DHCD”) may waive, in writing, the provisions of § 2702.2, § 2703.2 through § 2703.5, and § 2706.5 of this chapter within
      the limits of applicable federal and District of Columbia laws and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.4.</num>
    <text>Individual households applying for First Right Purchase Assistance shall comply with the rules of the D.C. Home Purchase Assistance Program, except that the definition of household set forth in § 2799 shall apply.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is subsection 5(d) of the District of Columbia Community Development Act of 1975, D.C. Law 1-39, 22 DCR 3436 (January 5, 1976) (codified at D.C. Official Code § 6-1004(d)(2001) and Mayor’s Order
        76-111, dated May 3, 1976, published at 22 DCR 6367 (May 14, 1976).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 903, 905, 909 (February 27, 1981); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 30 DCR 811 (February 13, 1983).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>