<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-700</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (ยง 16-700)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>700.1.</num>
    <text>No household goods contractor shall engage in the business of the transportation of household goods unless that contractor is registered with the Mayor as provided in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>700.2.</num>
    <text>Except for transactions in which the total consideration actually to be paid by an owner is less than fifty dollars ($ 50), no household goods contractor shall begin the transportation of household goods for an owner until after the understanding
      between the owner and the contractor with respect to the work has been incorporated into a written contract complying with the provisions of ยง 702.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>700.3.</num>
    <text>The functions of the Mayor under this chapter, and the implementation and enforcement of the provisions of this chapter, are vested in the Director of the D.C. Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs (also referred to in this chapter as the
      &amp;#8220;Department&amp;#8221;). The Director of the Department, or the Director&amp;#8217;s representative or designee, are also referred to in this chapter as the &amp;#8220;Director.&amp;#8221;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>700.4.</num>
    <text>The Mayor is authorized to promulgate such procedural rules as may be necessary to govern the conduct of the hearings required under the provisions of ยง 705.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>700.5.</num>
    <text>Any person who violates any provision of this chapter shall, upon conviction, be punished by a fine not more than three hundred dollars ($ 300), or imprisonment for not more than ten (10) days, or both, for each and every separate violation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>700.6.</num>
    <text>Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of this regulation pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction
      of this regulation shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>