<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-209</num>
  <heading>PERMIT AND ENDORSEMENT FEES (§ 23-209)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>209.1.</num>
    <text>The fee for each Importation permit shall be five dollars ($5).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>209.2.</num>
    <text>The annual fee for a Tasting permit for Class A Retailer licensees shall be one hundred and thirty dollars ($130).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>209.3.</num>
    <text>The annual fee for a Brew Pub permit shall be three thousand nine hundred dollars ($3,900).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>209.4.</num>
    <text>The annual fee for a Storage Facility permit shall be three hundred dollars ($300).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>209.5.</num>
    <text>The annual fee for an Off-Premises Storage permit shall be twenty five dollars ($25).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>209.6.</num>
    <text>The fee for an amendment to a license which results in an inspection to the licensed premises shall be fifty dollars ($50).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>209.7.</num>
    <text>The annual fee for a sidewalk café or summer garden endorsement shall be seventy five dollars ($75).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>209.8.</num>
    <text>The annual fee for an entertainment endorsement shall be twenty percent (20%) of the base license fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>209.9.</num>
    <text>The annual fee for a certification provider permit shall be one hundred dollars ($100).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>209.10.</num>
    <text>The fee for a personal auction permit or a nonprofit corporation auction permit shall be thirty dollars ($30).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>209.11.</num>
    <text>The fee for a wine and beer purchasing permit shall be thirty five dollars ($35).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>209.12</num>
    <text>209.12 The annual fee for a Wine Pub permit shall be five thousand dollars ($ 5,000).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11580 (August 9, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>