<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-601</num>
  <heading>DECLARATION OF CANDIDACY AND AFFIDAVIT OF QUALIFICATIONS (§ 3-601)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>601.1.</num>
    <text>Each candidate for nomination shall declare his or her candidacy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.2.</num>
    <text>The affidavit (after this, &amp;#8220;Declaration of Candidacy&amp;#8221;) shall be on a form provided by the Board of Elections and Ethics.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.3.</num>
    <text>The Declaration of Candidacy filed by the candidate shall contain the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and telephone number of the candidate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The office which the candidate seeks;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The date of the election; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The ward, Advisory Neighborhood Commission Single-Member District, or school district from which the candidate seeks election, where applicable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The candidate’s party affiliation, where applicable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The candidate’s residence addresses for the past three (3) years;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The candidate’s designation of how he or she would like his or her name to be listed on the ballot, in accordance with § 702 of this title; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>A statement that the candidate meets the qualifications for holding office.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.4.</num>
    <text>The Declaration of Candidacy form shall contain a notice of the penalties for making false representation(s) as to one’s qualifications for holding elective office.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.5.</num>
    <text>Each candidate shall swear or affirm upon oath before a District notary or Board official that the information provided in the Declaration is true to the best of the candidate’s knowledge and belief.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 D.C. Reg. 11722 (December 28, 2001) and amended at 49 D.C. Reg. 2737 (March 22, 2002).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 D.C. Reg. 8633-34 (December 17, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 48 D.C. Reg. 11722 (December 28, 2001); and further amended at 49 D.C. Reg. 2737 (March 22, 2002).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL NOTE</heading>
      <text>Prior to December 17, 1993, the Board of Elections and Ethics published Final Rulemaking notices at 27 D.C. Reg. 3805 (August 29, 1980), incorporating the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 27 D.C. Reg. 2768, 2769-70 (June 27, 1980); at 30
        D.C. Reg. 5289, 5295 (October 14, 1983); and further amended by Final Rulemaking published at 31 D.C. Reg. 4524 (September 14, 1984).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>