<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-710</num>
  <heading>DISTRIBUTORSHIPS (§ 27-710)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>710.1.</num>
    <text>In determining whether an applicant meets the requirements for minority participation in the sheltered market as set forth in D.C. Code §1-1148(a) (1981), and to ensure compliance with the performance requirements for bona fide MBE&amp;#8217;s set
      forth in D.C. Code, §1-1147(c) and (d) (1981), the Commission shall review the extent to which a bona fide minority participant qualifies as a &amp;#8220;distributorships.&amp;#8221;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>710.2.</num>
    <text>For purposes of §710, the term &amp;#8220;distributorship&amp;#8221; means any legal entity organized in any form, other than a joint venture, to engage in lawful commercial transactions involving the sale of goods or services for resale; or any entity
      which sells chiefly to other vendors, retailers, industrial, institutional, or commercial users for resale or business use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>710.3.</num>
    <text>The term &amp;#8220;distributorship&amp;#8221; includes a business which owns, operates, or maintains an establishment that produces on the premises the materials, goods, articles, or equipment of the character in which the applicant claims to be
      a distributorship; but the term does not include a business which only performs minimal operation on or minimal assembly of items being procured.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>710.4.</num>
    <text>In order to qualify as a distributorship, an applicant shall meet the following minimum eligibility requirements in addition to certification requirements stipulated in §702 of this chapter:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Maintain an establishment in which materials, goods, articles, or equipment of the character in which the applicant claims to be a distributorship are bought, kept in stock, and sold to wholesale or retail customers on a recurring basis in the usual
        course of business; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Demonstrate that its business is an established and on-going concern regularly dealing in the particular materials, goods, articles, or equipment of the character offered to the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 5659, 5662 (September 12, 1986). 4, 1983).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>