<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-707</num>
  <heading>DENIAL OF RECERTIFICATION (§ 27-707)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>707.1.</num>
    <text>The Commission may deny recertification of an MBE on one or more of the grounds set forth in §703.2 or §706.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.2.</num>
    <text>If recertification is denied, the Commission shall notify the applicant of the denial in writing along with the grounds and specific reasons for the denial. Notice of denial of recertification shall also include notice of the right to a hearing and
      hearing procedures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.3.</num>
    <text>A hearing before the Commission to contest the denial of recertification may be obtained by filing a written request for a hearing within ten (10) days of the receipt of the notice of denial. A written response to the grounds and reasons for denial
      may be filed with the hearing request or at any time prior to the conclusion of the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.4.</num>
    <text>Hearings shall be conducted in accordance with the procedures set forth in §708.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.5.</num>
    <text>Upon the denial of recertification of a MBE by the Commission on one or more grounds set forth in §703.2 or §706.1, or for any other reason, the Commission shall not accept, review, or evaluate for a period of one (1) year from the date the MBE receives
      notice of the Commission&amp;#8217;s final decision to deny recertification, unless the MBE requests and receives a hearing in accordance with §708 of this chapter, either of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>New information on, amendments to, or the recertification application; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>New certification applications from the applicant, its agent(s), representative(s), or other members of the public on the applicant&amp;#8217;s behalf.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.6.</num>
    <text>If the MBE receives a hearing in accordance with §708, the one (1) year waiting period commences on the date the MBE receives notice of the Commission&amp;#8217;s final decision on the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.7.</num>
    <text>The one (1) year waiting period constitutes a moratorium on further review of the MBE&amp;#8217;s file for purposes of recertification and participation in the sheltered market program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.8.</num>
    <text>Hearings shall be conducted in accordance with the procedures set forth in §708 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 26 DCR 2771, 2787 (December 21, 1979); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 5659, 5662 (September 12, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>