<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-709</num>
  <heading>TEMPORARY CERTIFICATION (§ 27-709)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>709.1.</num>
    <text>The Staff Director of the Commission may issue to an applicant a temporary certification for bidding purposes only when all of the following requirements are satisfied:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The applicant has submitted a completed application for certification under §700 of this chapter.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The completed application is scheduled to be reviewed by the Commission at its next scheduled meeting;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The application is certifiable under §700 based on staff review and recommendation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Staff Director determines, given the character of the contract at issue, the likelihood of such a contract being offered again in the sheltered market, and the amount of the contract, that the applicant&amp;#8217;s inability to bid on the contract
        would have a detrimental effect on the development of MBE&amp;#8217;s in the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The Staff Director has the approval of at least four (4) Commissioners for temporary certification for bidding purposes.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>709.2.</num>
    <text>Temporary certification for bidding shall have no significance in the Commission&amp;#8217;s review of the application for certification under §700 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>709.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant who has received temporary certification for bidding may only bid on contracts placed in the sheltered market. An applicant shall not be qualified as a MBE to be awarded a contract placed in the sheltered market until the applicant is
      certified pursuant to §700 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 5664, 5666 (September 12, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>