<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4606</num>
  <heading>CONTINUING EDUCATION REQUIREMENTS FOR NONPRACTICING PHYSICIANS (ยง 17-4606)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4606.1.</num>
    <text>This section shall apply to the renewal of a license, the reactivation of the license of a physician in inactive status, or reinstatement of an expired license of an applicant who is not actively practicing medicine.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4606.2.</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4606.3.</num>
    <text>Repealed</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4606.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant for renewal, reactivation, or reinstatement of a license who has not been actively practicing medicine for a period of one (1) to five (5) years shall submit proof pursuant to ยง 4606.7 that the applicant has completed acceptable continuing
      medical education for each year after December 31, 1988, that the applicant has not been actively practicing medicine as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Twenty-five (25) hours of credit in continuing medical education meeting the requirements of Category 1;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Twenty-five (25) hours of credit in continuing medical education meeting the requirements of either Category 1 or Category 2.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4606.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant for reactivation of an inactive license who has not been actively practicing medicine for five (5) or more years after December 31, 1988, shall submit proof pursuant to ยง 4606.7 that the applicant has completed, during a two-year (2)
      period immediately preceding the date of application, acceptable continuing medical education as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>One (1) year of clinical training in a program accredited by the ACGME or the AOA; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>One hundred fifty (150) hours of credit in continuing medical education meeting the requirements of Category 1; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>One hundred fifty (150) hours of credit in continuing medical education meeting the requirements of either Category 1 or Category 2.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4606.6.</num>
    <text>After December 31, 1990, a physician whose license has expired for five (5) or more years shall meet the requirements for obtaining an initial license under this chapter and the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4606.7.</num>
    <text>An applicant under this section shall prove completion of required continuing education credits by submitting with the application the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>For claims for Category 1 credit:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name of the program, its location, a description of the subject matter covered;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The dates on which the applicant attended the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The hours of credit claimed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Verification by the sponsor of completion, by signature or stamp.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For claims for Category 2 credit:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A description of the program or activity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The dates on which the applicant attended the program or activity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The location of the program or activity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The hours of credit claimed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Verification by the applicant of attendance.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 5999, 6005 (August 5, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 4796 (June 16, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>