<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4612</num>
  <heading>STANDARDS OF CONDUCT (§ 17-4612)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4612.1.</num>
    <text>A licensed physician shall maintain a record for each patient that accurately reflects the evaluation and treatment of each patient. These records shall be kept for three (3) years after last seeing the patient, or three (3) years after a minor patient
      reaches eighteen (18) years of age.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4612.2.</num>
    <text>Subject to §§ 4612.3 and 4612.4, a licensed physician shall provide to a patient or the patient&amp;#8217;s representative a copy of the patient&amp;#8217;s medical record at the request of the patient or the patient&amp;#8217;s representative within
      30 days of the request according to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A licensed physician may provide a summary report of the patient&amp;#8217;s medical record in Lieu of copying the record if the patient consents.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A licensed physician may charge a reasonable fee for duplicating records and the fee may be required prior to providing the records in non-emergency situations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4612.3.</num>
    <text>If a patient&amp;#8217;s record contains mental health information, as defined by § 101(11) of the District of Columbia Mental Health Information Act of 1978, D.C. Code § 6-2001(11), a licensed physician shall comply with the requirements of the Act
      in making a patient&amp;#8217;s records available to a patient or the patient&amp;#8217;s representative.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4612.4.</num>
    <text>A licensed physician shall not make available to a parent, guardian, or representative of a minor child a record of a minor child the disclosure of which without the child&amp;#8217;s consent is prohibited by law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4612.5.</num>
    <text>A licensed physician shall not accept or perform professional responsibilities which the licensed physician is not competent to perform.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4612.6.</num>
    <text>A licensed physician shall not abandon a patient whose care a licensed physician has undertaken without giving notice to the patient far enough in advance of the discontinuation to allow the patient time to secure appropriate substitute care.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4612.7.</num>
    <text>A licensed physician shall not wilfully or carelessly disregard the health, welfare, or safety of a patient.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4612.8.</num>
    <text>A licensed physician shall conform to the prevailing standards of acceptable medical practice as determined by the Board or a peer review panel appointed by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 5999, 6011 (August 5, 1988); as amended by:</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 6837 (July 22, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>