<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4607</num>
  <heading>APPROVED CONTINUING EDUCATION PROGRAMS AND ACTIVITIES (§ 17-4607)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4607.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may, in its discretion, approve continuing education programs and activities that contribute to the knowledge, skills, and professional performance and relationships that a physician uses to provide services to patients, the public or the
      profession and which meet the other requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4607.2.</num>
    <text>To be acceptable for credit, a continuing medical education program or activity shall be limited in content to that body of knowledge and skills generally recognized and accepted by the medical profession as within the basic medical sciences, the
      discipline of clinical medicine, or the provision of health care to the public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4607.3.</num>
    <text>The Board may approve continuing education program and activities for Category 1 credit, according to the following conditions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The programs and activities meet the requirements of §§ 4607.1 and 4607.2; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The programs and activities are through providers approved by:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Accreditation Council for Continuing Medical Education (ACCME);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A state medical society; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A sponsoring organization or the American Osteopathic Association (AOA) that awards the program or activity with an American Medical Association Physicians Recognition Award (AWRA).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4607.4.</num>
    <text>Repealed</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 5999, 6007 (August 5, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 6835 (July 22, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>