<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-2820</num>
  <heading>DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA LIFELINE SERVICE PROGRAM (§ 15-2820)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2820.1.</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Lifeline Service Program is a program designed to operate in conjunction with the Federal Lifeline Program, to provide a low monthly recurring rate to qualifying residential subscribers for basic local exchange service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2820.2.</num>
    <text>In order to qualify for the Lifeline service, customers must show that they either:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Fall below the highest available income level authorized by the Federal Low Income Energy Assistance Program or 150% of the Federal Poverty income guidelines for a household of that size; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Participate in one of the following federal assistance programs:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Medicaid; Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program; Supplemental Security Income; Federal Public Housing Assistance (Section 8); Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Program; National School Lunch Program’s free lunch program; or Temporary Assistance
      for Needy Families.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2820.3.</num>
    <text>Each ETC shall file tariffs implementing a Lifeline service that is consistent with both FCC and Commission regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2820.4.</num>
    <text>Lifeline subsidies shall not be available to customers on a retroactive basis.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2820.5.</num>
    <text>When the entity responsible for certifying Lifeline customers notifies an ETC that a list of customers no longer qualifies for Lifeline service and when the Commission orders termination of Lifeline service for those customers, the Lifeline rate will
      revert to the serving ETC’s standard tariffed retail rate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2820.6.</num>
    <text>Lifeline service is only available at the qualifying customer’s principal residence. An applicant for Lifeline service may report only one (1) address in the District of Columbia as the principal place of residence.</text>
    <text>Post office boxes are not acceptable designations of residence. Where applicable, an apartment number must be provided.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2820.7.</num>
    <text>Each household receiving lifeline service is limited to one (1) lifeline service. The lifeline service is non-transferable to any other person or household.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2820.8.</num>
    <text>Participants in the District’s Lifeline Program are eligible to receive Toll Restriction Service at no charge.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2820.9.</num>
    <text>District of Columbia residents who meet all eligibility requirements shall not be denied Lifeline service because of unpaid toll charges.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 8198 (October 3, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 7644 (September 25, 2009); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 8585, 8594 (October 7, 2011); as amended
        by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 12141 (October 19, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>