<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-2819</num>
  <heading>TELECOMMUNICATIONS RELAY SERVICE (§ 15-2819)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2819.1.</num>
    <text>Provision of TRS in the District shall be administered by the Fund Administrator.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Fund Administrator shall monitor service levels to ensure that minimum service requirements specified in this chapter are satisfied.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Fund Administrator shall attempt to resolve any complaints regarding TRS in a reasonable timeframe. If unable to do so, the Fund Administrator shall refer the complaint to the Commission.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Fund Administrator shall draft the Application for Recertification to be submitted to the FCC every five (5) years, submitting the draft for review by the Commission no later than twelve (12) months prior to expiration of the current certification.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2819.2.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall select the TRS provider through a competitive bidding process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2819.3.</num>
    <text>A TRS Advisory Board, established by the Commission and comprised of community, industry and governmental representatives, shall monitor the provision of TRS in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2819.4.</num>
    <text>The Board shall meet at least once every six months and provide input to the Fund Administrator and to the TRS provider regarding operation of TRS in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2819.5.</num>
    <text>The Commission representative shall:</text>
    <text>Serve as facilitator to the Advisory Board;</text>
    <text>Schedule meetings and provide notice of the meetings to members;</text>
    <text>Take minutes and circulate the minutes to members; and</text>
    <text>Report urgent matters to the Fund Administrator when necessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2819.6.</num>
    <text>The TRS provider shall meet the requirements of 47 C.F.R. §§ 64.601, et seq. and any other requirements specified in FCC rules and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 8198 (October 3, 2003); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 8585, 8593 (October 7, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>