<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-2807</num>
  <heading>RELINQUISHMENT OF DC USTF SUPPORT ELIGIBILITY (§ 15-2807)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2807.1.</num>
    <text>A local exchange carrier may seek to relinquish its ETC designation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2807.2.</num>
    <text>If the District of Columbia is served by more than one (1) ETC, the Commission may permit a carrier to relinquish its designation as an ETC upon:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Written notification not less than ninety (90) days prior to the proposed effective date that the carrier seeks to relinquish its designation as an ETC;</text>
    </level>
    <text>Determination by the Commission that the remaining eligible telecommunications carrier or carriers can offer federally and District of Columbia supported services to the relinquishing ETC’s customers; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Determination by the Commission that sufficient notice of relinquishment has been provided to permit the purchase or construction of adequate facilities by any remaining eligible telecommunications carrier or carriers necessary to serve the supported
        customers of the relinquishing ETC prior to the effective date.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2807.3.</num>
    <text>If the District is served by only one (1) local exchange carrier that is the only ETC, the Commission may permit it to relinquish its ETC designation upon:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Written notification not less than ninety (90) days prior to the proposed effective date that the LEC seeks to relinquish its designation as an ETC; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Commission approval and designation of another ETC.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 8198 (October 3, 2003); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 8585, 8588 (October 7, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>