<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-1101</num>
  <heading>PURPOSE (§ 1-1101)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1101.1.</num>
    <text>The purpose of these Guidelines is to implement the authority delegated to the Board by establishing an effective, efficient, and fair system of independent review and resolution of reported violations of the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1101.2.</num>
    <text>The purpose of the Board is to advise and make recommendations to the Mayor, the Chief Financial Officer (&amp;#8220;CFO&amp;#8221;), the Inspector General (&amp;#8220;IG&amp;#8221;), and the Council of the District of Columbia (&amp;#8220;Council&amp;#8221;)
      with respect to reported anti-deficiency violations by officers and employees of the government of the District of Columbia (&amp;#8220;District&amp;#8221;). Because maintaining the fiscal integrity of the District government is of paramount importance,
      it is critical that reports of violations of the Act be evaluated by a credible, independent investigative board, which will assess culpability and recommend appropriate action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1101.3.</num>
    <text>The Act does not grant the Board the authority to review, investigate, determine violations of or recommend action regarding violations of the District&amp;#8217;s procurement laws. In addition, although several of the prohibited actions contained
      in the federal Anti-Deficiency Act, 31 U.S.C. §§ 1341, 1342, 1349-1351, 1511-1519 (2006), are repeated in the Act, the Act does not grant the Board the authority to review, investigate, determine violations of or recommend action regarding violations
      of the federal Anti-Deficiency Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 7968 (August 13, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 4402 (May 11, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>