<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-1108</num>
  <heading>ADMINISTRATION (ยง 1-1108)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1108.1.</num>
    <text>The Office of the Chief Financial Officer (&amp;#8220;OCFO&amp;#8221;) shall provide administrative and staff support to the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.2.</num>
    <text>The OCFO shall designate an OCFO employee to serve as Staff Director of the Board. The Staff Director may designate an OCFO employee to serve as Secretary of the Board, as well as to coordinate administrative and substantive support from other District
      employees to the Board. Board staff will assist the Board in carrying out its duties and responsibilities, including providing the necessary support to the Board to obtain information needed to perform its review. The Board, however, shall not delegate
      core responsibilities, such as the assessment of culpability, the determination of any justification for a violation, the determination that no violation actually occurred or the recommendation of disciplinary or other action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.3.</num>
    <text>The Secretary shall be responsible for keeping accurate minutes of the proceedings of all meetings of the Board. This includes providing administrative support associated with the needs of the Board, such as arranging meetings, and providing notices
      of meetings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.4.</num>
    <text>Upon majority vote of the Members present at a duly called meeting at which a quorum is present, the Staff Director and the Secretary of the Board may be removed from these positions at any time, without cause.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.5.</num>
    <text>The Board shall continuously maintain in the District a principal office at such place as may be designated by the Members.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.6.</num>
    <text>The Board staff shall create a case file for each report, designate a case number, and enter the case in a database. The Chairperson or his or her designee will notify the Members when a report of a violation has been received and will schedule, in
      consultation with Members, the earliest possible date for the Members to meet.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 7968 (August 13, 2004) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 4402 (May 11, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>