<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-1402</num>
  <heading>DISAPPROVAL OF APPLICATION OR CANCELLATION OF PERMIT (§ 1-1402)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1402.1.</num>
    <text>The Building Manager, FMD, shall disapprove any application or cancel an issued permit for use of a public area if the proposed use:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Involves an activity set forth in § 1401.5;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Obstructs the free entrance and exit of the users of the public area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>May result in damages to the public building or property within the public building;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>May cause or disrupt the official business of the agency or agencies occupying the public building;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Interferes with the tenant’s quiet enjoyment of leasehold;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Interferes with a previously approved use of the public area by another member or members of the public;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Is obscene within the meaning of obscenity in 18 U.S.C. §§ 1461-1465;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Pertains to any judicial or quasi-judicial proceeding then pending in the public building and the use is intended to influence or impede that proceeding;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Is in violation of any law of the District of Columbia or the United States; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Is being conducted with a permit obtained by submitting an intentionally false or incomplete application.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1402.2.</num>
    <text>Upon disapproving an application or canceling an issued permit, the Building Manager, FMD, shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Promptly notify the applicant or permittee in writing of the reasons for disapproval or cancellation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Inform the applicant of his or her right to appeal the disapproval or cancellation to the Administrator, Facility Management Division (“FMD”), under § 1403.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 1316, 1318-19 (February 17, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>