<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-1406</num>
  <heading>RESTRICTION ON BEHAVIOR (ยง 1-1406)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1406.1.</num>
    <text>The permittee shall be subject to the rules and regulations governing public buildings and grounds. In addition, a permittee shall not:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Misrepresent its identity in public;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Distribute any item without the prior approval of the Building Manager, FMD, under ยง 1401 of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Leave leaflets or other materials unattended at any place on OPM-controlled property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Conduct any activities in a misleading or fraudulent manner;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Discriminate on the basis of race, color, religion, national origin, sex, age, marital status, personal appearance, sexual orientation, family responsibility, physical handicap, matriculation, political affiliation, source of income, or place of
        residence or business of any individual in conducting the permitted activities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Engage in activities that would interfere with the preference afforded blind licensees under the Randolph-Sheppard Act (20 U.S.C. ยง 107) and parallel District of Columbia law(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Indulge or allow participants to indulge in the use of alcohol or drugs; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Damage or destroy government property.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1406.2.</num>
    <text>Permittees engaging in the solicitation of funds shall wear an identification badge at all times on OPM-controlled property containing the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Name;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Address;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Telephone number; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Name of group or organization.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 1316, 1320-21 (February 17, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>