<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-1516</num>
  <heading>TRANSFER OF RECORDS TO A RECORDS CENTER OR OTHER APPROVED STORAGE FACILITY (ยง-1516)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1516.1.</num>
    <text>The Administrator shall issue instructions for the transfer of records to a records center or other approved depository in accordance with this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1516.2.</num>
    <text>Any agency may transfer records to an approved records center or other storage facility, subject to the following conditions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The records are properly scheduled;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the records are not scheduled for final disposition, an exception to this regulation shall be obtained from the Administrator by means of a request for courtesy storage;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Courtesy storage shall not be used to store records indefinitely in a records center. The agency granted permission for courtesy storage shall submit an approved disposition authority for the records within two (2) years;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The records are not authorized for disposal less than two (2) years after the transfer to the records center or other approved depository; unless excepted from this restriction by the Administrator; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Facilities for storing and providing reference on the records are available.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1516.3.</num>
    <text>The transfer of records to the Washington National Records Center and the transfer of personnel and payroll records to the National Personnel Records Center shall be in accordance with procedures specified by the National Archives and Records Administration,
      by the Administrator, and by the Committee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 7001, 7015-16 (October 30, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>