<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-1532</num>
  <heading>USE AND STORAGE OF MICROCOPIES (ยง 1-1532)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1532.1.</num>
    <text>The master microcopy of permanent records and of temporary records having a retention period of ten (10) years or longer, shall not be used for reference purposes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1532.2.</num>
    <text>Duplicate copies shall be used for reference purposes and for further duplication on a recurring basis or for large-scale duplication such as for distribution of records in microform.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1532.3.</num>
    <text>In cases where it is necessary to make duplicates from the master copy, procedures shall ensure that the master copy remains clean and undamaged during the duplication process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1532.4.</num>
    <text>The Administrator shall establish and issue standards, guidelines, and procedures for the secure storage of the master microcopy of permanent records and of temporary records having a retention period of ten (10) years or longer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1532.5.</num>
    <text>The Administrator may establish a centralized micrographic service for the benefit of District agencies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1532.6.</num>
    <text>Such a service shall provide the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Technical advice and assistance in designing and implementing agency microcopying projects and programs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Reimbursable microcopying services including the preparation, indexing, and filming of records, inspection of film, quality testing of microcopies, and other services; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Such other services as the Administrator may specify.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 7001, 7022 (October 30, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>