<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-1501</num>
  <heading>RECORDS DISPOSITION COMMITTEE (§ 1-1501)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1501.1.</num>
    <text>Members of the Records Disposition Committee shall serve without compensation, but appropriate expenses may be reimbursed by the Public Records Administrator from the funds of the Office of Public Records, if authorized in advance by the Administrator.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1501.2.</num>
    <text>In accordance with section 6(b) of the Act, the Records Disposition Committee shall convene when called by the chairperson or any 3 members to do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Review and act upon agency Records Retention Schedules, General Records Schedules, and Disposal Lists submitted for consideration by the Administrator;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Review and act upon requests for exceptions from the provisions of agency Records Retention Schedules or General Records Schedules;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Accept for the Archives nonpublic records of historic significance on the recommendation of the Administrator; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Consider and resolve policy and other matters affecting the District records disposition program.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1501.3.</num>
    <text>In accordance with section 7(a)(1) of the Act, records of the District may only be transferred, destroyed or disposed of as prescribed by schedules or disposal lists that have been approved by the Committee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1501.4.</num>
    <text>In accordance with section 6(c) of the Act, the concurrence of the Administrator shall be required for the destruction of any public record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1501.5.</num>
    <text>The Committee’s approval for the disposition of records in accordance with this chapter, concurred in by the Administrator if required, shall be the final agency decision of the District of Columbia on records disposition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1501.6.</num>
    <text>The decisions of the Committee may be appealed to the D.C. Court of Appeals in accordance with the provisions of the D.C. Administrative Procedure Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1501.7.</num>
    <text>If advised in writing of an intention to appeal the authorization for the destruction of public records, the Administrator shall assure that the records subject to destruction are not destroyed for sixty (60) days; and, if a timely appeal is filed,
      until the court has decided the appeal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 7001, 7002 (October 30, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>