<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-1510</num>
  <heading>DISPOSAL LISTS (ยง 1-1510)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1510.1.</num>
    <text>Until updated General Records Schedules for the District have been issued, agencies shall comply with the terms of D.C. Schedule 40, sections 1 through 8 and sections 10 through 31.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1510.2.</num>
    <text>Agencies may request, on a form specified by the Administrator, a one-time authorization to dispose of records that no longer accumulate and have no further operational or other value. This Disposal List, once approved, shall be applied to the records
      listed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1510.3.</num>
    <text>A Disposal List shall give the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Title and content of each records series and dates;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Quantity of records;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Finding aids, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Restrictions on access, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Physical characteristics of the records if they are nontextual records; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The action requested, such as immediate destruction, direct accessioning into Archives, destruction after a period of time, or other disposition.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1510.4.</num>
    <text>Disposal Lists shall be approved in the same manner as agency Records Retention Schedules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1510.5.</num>
    <text>The Archivist may initiate Disposal Lists for records of defunct agencies, for unscheduled or inappropriately scheduled records in the Washington National Records Center or District Records Center, and for other purposes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 7001, 7012 (October 30, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>