<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-1517</num>
  <heading>TRANSFER OF RECORDS TO THE ARCHIVES (ยง 1-1517)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1517.1.</num>
    <text>Records listed as permanent on an approved schedule or Disposal List shall be offered to the Archives at the time specified in the schedule or list.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1517.2.</num>
    <text>Agencies and the Records Center shall submit to the Archivist on a form specified by the Administrator a request to transfer permanent records and shall follow all guidelines and procedures specified by the Archivist.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1517.3.</num>
    <text>The Archivist may disapprove a transfer of records for the following reasons:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Lack of space or staff preclude the proper care of the records;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Finding aids necessary for the use of the records are not transferred at the same time as the records;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Restrictions on the records are such that they preclude use of the records by the public;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The records are in such disarray and disorder that they cannot be used practically for research purposes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The percentage of nonrecord and nonpermanent material intermingled with permanent records is so high that the costs of screening the records outweighs the benefits;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The records are incorrectly described in the request for transfer; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>For other sufficient reasons as determined by the Archivist.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1517.4.</num>
    <text>Records appraised as permanent that are disapproved for transfer because of restrictions on access may be stored in the Records Center.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1517.5.</num>
    <text>The Archivist may accept the transfer of permanent records earlier than the time specified in an approved schedule or Disposal List.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 7001, 7016-17 (October 30, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>