<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-1504</num>
  <heading>RESPONSIBILITIES OF RECORDS MANAGEMENT OFFICERS (§ 1-1504)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1504.1.</num>
    <text>The responsibilities of Records Management Officers shall include, but not necessarily be limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Serve as liaison with the Administrator;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Develop and carry out the records management program of the agency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Comply with all rules, regulations, guidelines, standards, and procedures issued by the Administrator;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Prepare agency Records Retention Schedules, amendments to agency Records Retention Schedules, and Disposal Lists in accordance with standards and procedures issued by the Administrator;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Inventory agency records stored in the Washington National Records Center, or District Records Center, to ensure that such records are scheduled properly. In cases where agency records are not covered by an agency Records Retention Schedule or General
        Records Schedule, the agency Records Officer shall submit an appropriate request for records disposition authority;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Arrange for transfers of inactive records to the Archives, Records Center, or other approved depository;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Oversee the implementation by the agency of Records Retention Schedules, General Records Schedules, and Disposal Lists;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Review annually the agency Records Retention Schedule and initiate such deletions, changes, or additions as may be necessary to update the schedule;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Prepare such reports as the Administrator may require for the administration of the District’s records management program; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Carry out related functions as assigned by the agency head or required by the Administrator.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 7001, 7005-06 (October 30, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>