<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-2407</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION PROCESS (§ 1-2407)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2407.1.</num>
    <text>Each applicant shall submit a completed application package, provided by the Administrator, which includes the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An Application for Assistance Form that contains information about:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The applicant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The applicant’s bar admission status;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The applicant’s residency; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Other available loan forgiveness programs and applicable scholarship service obligations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Loan Information Forms that contain specific information about the applicant’s educational debt;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Lender Certification Forms, completed by the applicant and the lender, that verify the details of the applicant’s educational debt;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>An Employer Certification Form, completed by the applicant and his or her employer, that establishes the applicant’s salary and that demonstrates the eligibility of the employment under § 2405;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Proof, such as copies of filed federal or District income tax returns, provided by the applicant, of the applicant’s adjusted gross annual income; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Any other relevant information required by the Administrator.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2407.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall be ineligible for loan repayment assistance if the application is incomplete, if it is determined that the applicant made false statements in the application packet, or if any of the eligibility requirements set forth in § 2404
      are not met.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2407.3.</num>
    <text>The Administrator shall complete its review of the application, determine the applicant’s eligibility, and notify the applicant in writing of its decision within forty-five (45) days after the application deadline.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2407.4.</num>
    <text>If additional funds are available, the Administrator may accept mid-year applications. The Administrator shall complete its review of the application, determine the applicant’s eligibility, and notify the applicant in writing of its decision within
      forty-five (45) days after its acceptance of a mid-year application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 1025 (February 2, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>