<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-2827</num>
  <heading>TRANSCRIPTS; CITATION AND COSTS (§ 1-2827)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2827.1.</num>
    <text>All proceedings, except for mediations, shall be recorded. The recording is the official record of what occurred at the proceeding.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2827.2.</num>
    <text>Any party may obtain a copy of the recording of a hearing at the party’s expense.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2827.3.</num>
    <text>Transcripts of the recording of the proceedings shall be prepared by a qualified reporter or transcriber who shall personally certify that he or she is not a party or counsel to a party or otherwise related to or employed by a party or counsel in
      the case; that he or she has no material interest in the outcome of the case; and that the transcript represents the testimony and proceedings of the case as recorded.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2827.4.</num>
    <text>In filings, a party may only rely upon a transcript prepared according to this Section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2827.5.</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise stipulated by the parties or ordered by an Administrative Law Judge, if a party cites to a portion of a transcript, the entire transcript of the case must be filed at OAH, and a copy must be served on all parties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2827.6.</num>
    <text>In any case in which a party files a petition for review in the District of Columbia Court of Appeals, OAH will arrange for the preparation and filing of a transcript without charge only if the Court of Appeals has permitted the Petitioner to proceed
      in forma pauperis. In all other cases, OAH will arrange for preparation and filing of a transcript only after OAH receives payment for the cost of preparing the transcript.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 6399 (June 25, 2004); as amended by Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 8420 (September 9, 2005) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 11090 (December 23, 2005); as amended
        by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 12541, 12562 (December 31, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>