<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-2899</num>
  <heading>GENERAL DEFINITIONS (§ 1-2899)
    <text>For the purposes of this Chapter the term:</text>
    <text>Act means the Office of Administrative Hearings Establishment Act of 2001, D.C.fficial Code §§ 2-1831.01, et seq.</text>
    <text>Agency shall have the meaning provided that term in D.C. Official Code §-502(3).</text>
    <text>Civil Infractions Act means the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairsivil Infractions Act of 1985, D.C. Official Code §§ 2-1801.01, et seq.</text>
    <text>Clerk means the OAH Clerk of Court or authorized designee.</text>
    <text>Commercial carrier means a business that accepts and delivers parcels, such asederal Express or the United Parcel Service.</text>
    <text>Government means the District of Columbia, or any government agency authorizedy law to prosecute cases before OAH and whose administrative litigation fallsnder the jurisdiction of OAH, but does not include OAH.</text>
    <text>Litter Control Administration Act means the Litter Control Administration Act of985, D.C. Official Code §§ 8-801, et seq.</text>
    <text>Paper means pleadings, motions, exhibit and witness lists, or any other writtenubmission filed with OAH.</text>
    <text>Party means persons or entities who begin a case at OAH or the persons orntities on the other side.</text>
    <text>Presiding Administrative Law Judge means an Administrative Law Judge assigned to particular case.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 6399 (June 25, 2004); as amendedy Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 8595 (September 3, 2004); as amended byinal Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 8606 (September 3, 2004); as amended bymergency and Proposed Rulemaking
        published at 51 DCR 9322 (October 1, 2004)EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 5675 (June 17,005); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 12541, 12573December 31, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>