<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-2977</num>
  <heading>PUBLIC BENEFITS CASES &amp;#8211; DEADLINES (ยง 1-2977)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2977.1</num>
    <text>2977.1 As required by Federal law, 7 C.F.R. 273.15(c), decisions in cases involving SNAP (formerly Food Stamps) benefits shall be issued and served on the parties within sixty (60) calendar days of receipt of the hearing request, except that in Intentional
      Program Violation cases, as required by 7 C.F.R. 273.16(e)(2)(iv), the decisions shall be issued and served within ninety (90) calendar days after a hearing notice has been issued.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2977.2</num>
    <text>2977.2 As required by the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act, D.C. Official Code ยง 4-210.12(a), decisions shall be issued and served on the parties within sixty (60) calendar days of receipt of the hearing request in cases involving the following
      public benefit programs: Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF); Interim Disability Assistance; General Assistance for Children; Program on Work, Employment and Responsibility (POWER); and Medicaid.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2977.3</num>
    <text>2977.3 As required by the Homeless Services Reform Act of 2005, D.C. Official Code</text>
    <text>ยง 4-1601.25(f)(3)(C), decisions in cases involving shelter or other services provided for homeless persons shall be issued and served on the parties within fifteen (15) calendar days of the completion of the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2977.4.</num>
    <text>If a postponement of the hearing date is granted to the party requesting a hearing, the deadline for the issuance and service of the decision shall be extended for as many days as the hearing is postponed. In Intentional Program Violation cases, the
      deadline shall be extended only if the Respondent requested the postponement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 2009, 2015 (March 17, 2006); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 12541, 12590 (December 31, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>