<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-2935</num>
  <heading>RENTAL HOUSING CASES &amp;#8211; REPRESENTATION (ยง 1-2935)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2935.1</num>
    <text>2935.1 Persons authorized to appear before OAH by Sections 2833 and 2835 mayepresent parties in rental housing cases.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2935.2</num>
    <text>2935.2 A tenant association may represent one or more tenants in any proceedings follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A statement must be filed with OAH stating that the tenant consents toepresentation by the tenant association and the tenant association consents toepresent the tenant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A tenant or a tenant association may revoke the consent by filing atatement to that effect;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A tenant association shall designate one (1) or more members or attorneys toepresent the association and any of the tenants it represents;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A tenant association may elect to proceed only in a representative capacityithout being listed as a party or listed in the caption.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2935.3</num>
    <text>2935.3 The provisions of Sections 2833 and 2835 concerning discipline ofersons appearing before OAH apply to all representatives in rental housingases.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2935.4</num>
    <text>2935.4 If an Administrative Law Judge decides that a proceeding is so complex,r the potential liability so great that a party should be represented by aawyer, the Administrative Law Judge shall explain to the party the advantagesf obtaining a lawyer
      and offer to continue the case to give the party anpportunity to obtain a lawyer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 5674, 5680 (July 14, 2006); asmended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 12541, 12581 (December1, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>