<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-2970</num>
  <heading>PUBLIC BENEFITS CASES &amp;#8211; SCOPE (§ 1-2970)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2970.1.</num>
    <text>Sections 2970 through 2978 contain the Rules for OAH hearings requested by individuals, other than service providers, concerning the following kinds of benefits:</text>
    <text>Medicaid, Healthcare Alliance, or other healthcare programs administered by the District of Columbia;</text>
    <text>Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF);</text>
    <text>Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) (formerly Food Stamps);</text>
    <text>Interim Disability Assistance;</text>
    <text>Shelter and services for homeless persons;</text>
    <text>Rental Assistance programs;</text>
    <text>General Assistance for Children;</text>
    <text>Child Care Subsidy;</text>
    <text>Program on Work, Employment, and Responsibility (POWER);</text>
    <text>Burial Assistance;</text>
    <text>Any other benefits provided by the Department of Human Services; and</text>
    <text>Low Income Home Energy Assistance Program benefits provided by the District of Columbia Energy Office.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2970.2</num>
    <text>2970.2 Sections 2970 through 2978 also apply to hearings requested by the Department of Human Services when it seeks to disqualify someone from receiving SNAP (formerly Food Stamps) benefits due to an intentional program violation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2970.3</num>
    <text>2970.3 If Sections 2970 through 2978 do not address a procedural issue, the Rules in Chapter 28 apply.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2970.4</num>
    <text>2970.4 If there is a conflict between any federal law or regulation and anything in these Rules, the federal law or regulation shall control.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2970.5</num>
    <text>2970.5 If there is a conflict between any District of Columbia statute and anything in these Rules, the District of Columbia statute shall control.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2970.6</num>
    <text>2970.6 If there is a conflict between any other agency’s procedural rules or regulations and these Rules, these Rules shall control.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 2009 (March 17, 2006); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 12541, 12584 (December 31, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>