<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-309</num>
  <heading>PROPOSED RULEMAKING NOTICES (§ 1-309)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>309.1.</num>
    <text>A Proposed Rulemaking that is submitted for publication, including rulemakings that give notice of intent to adopt a new rule, amend an existing rule, or repeal an existing rule, shall be filed in accordance with the provisions of this section, and
      any other applicable provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>309.2.</num>
    <text>The heading of each proposed rulemaking document shall state, in bold upper case print, the name of the agency promulgating the proposed rule and the phrase “NOTICE OF PROPOSED RULEMAKING.”</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>309.3.</num>
    <text>The text of the proposed rule(s) shall be preceded by a notice that shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name of the promulgating official or body authorized to issue rules;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A citation to the rule(s) amended or repealed or the proposed citation of the new rule(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If the proposed rulemaking is being re-published, pursuant to §310.5, a citation to the previous notice(s) of proposed rulemaking published in the D.C. Register;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A brief description or title of the proposed rule(s); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A statement of intent to adopt, amend, or repeal the rule(s) in not less than thirty (30) days from the date of publication of the notice in the D.C. Register. A longer period may be stated if required by law or adopted by the agency.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>309.4.</num>
    <text>The text of the proposed rule(s) shall be followed by a notice that indicates the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The manner in which public comments will be received, including an email address, telephone number, and other pertinent information;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The manner in which a copy of the proposed rule(s) may be obtained, upon request, including a requirement for payment of a reasonable fee, if applicable; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The date that the notice period begins. The date the notice period begins is the date of publication of a proposed rule.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>309.5.</num>
    <text>In the event there are substantive changes to a proposed rulemaking, the rulemaking must be republished in full as a proposed rulemaking for a length of time determined by the Administrator, but in no case fewer than seven (7) days, and shall include
      the information required in §309.4 (a), (b), and (c).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>309.6.</num>
    <text>If the last day of the comment period falls on a Saturday, Sunday, or legal holiday, the last day is extended to the next business day.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>309.7.</num>
    <text>Proposed rules that are re-submitted for publication, pursuant to §310.5, shall indicate those portions of the text that have been substantially altered by setting forth the previously published text in brackets [....] and underlining the new text
      that has been altered; Provided, that this requirement shall not apply to a Notice of Proposed Rulemaking which completely supersedes a previously published notice, so long as the rules were never adopted. The new notice shall cite the earlier notice
      and indicate that it has been superseded.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 9855, 9869 (May 4, 1979); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 4091, 4105 (September 18, 1981); and as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 271, 285 (January 9, 2009); as amended by Notice
        of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 6316 (June 1, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>