<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-304</num>
  <heading>AGENCY REPRESENTATIVES (§ 1-304)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>304.1.</num>
    <text>Each agency, department, office, or other governmental entity that submits documents for publication in the D.C. Register shall designate, from its Director&amp;#8217;s office or General Counsel’s office, a representative and alternate to service
      as a liaison to the Office of Documents and Administrative Issuances. All representatives shall be called “agency liaisons.”</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>304.2.</num>
    <text>Agency liaisons and Directors shall be the main contact persons in matters relating to the publication of documents in the D.C. Register. All documents submitted by an agency for publication, including notices and rulemaking documents must be submitted
      through the agency liaison or Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>304.3.</num>
    <text>Designation of an agency liaison does not exempt an agency from the required review of the substance of rulemaking documents and legal certification by the Office of the Attoney General. Legal certification by agency counsel must be approved by the
      Administrator.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>304.5.</num>
    <text>Each agency liaison shall be responsible for the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Representation of the agency in all matters relating to compliance with the provisions of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Responding to inquiries from the Office of Documents and Administrative Issuances concerning documents or notices submitted by the agency for publication;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Ensuring that the agency head or other official authorized by law to promulgate rules or attest to the promulgation of rules has reviewed all rulemaking notices and the rulemaking text, and has signed the required transmittal form, either in hard-copy
        or electronically, in accordance with the provisions of § ;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Ensuring that the required legal certification is set forth on the transmittal form in accordance with the provisions of §307; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Ensuring that all other documents are in compliance with the Rules of the Office of Documents and Administrative Issuances prior to submission for publication.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 9855, 9859 (May 4, 1979); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 4091, 4095 (September 18, 1981); and Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 271, 275 (January 9, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>