<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-310</num>
  <heading>FINAL RULEMAKING NOTICES (§ 1-310)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>310.1.</num>
    <text>A Final Rulemaking that is submitted for publication, including rulemakings that give notice of the adoption of a new rule, the amendment of an existing rule, or the repeal of an existing rule, shall be filed in accordance with the provisions of this
      section, and any other applicable provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>310.2.</num>
    <text>The heading of each final rulemaking document shall state, in bold type or upper case print, the name of the agency promulgating the rule and the phrase “NOTICE OF FINAL RULEMAKING.”</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>310.3.</num>
    <text>The text of the final rule(s) shall be preceded by a notice that shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name of the promulgating official or body authorized to issue rules:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The date on which the final action was taken;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A brief description or title of the rule(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A citation to the notice(s) of proposed rulemaking previously published in the D.C. Register; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The effective date of the final rule(s). If no effective date is stated, it will be presumed that the rule(s) will become effective upon publication of the notice of final rulemaking in the D.C. Register.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>310.4.</num>
    <text>The Administrator of ODAI may omit publication of the entire text of a final rulemaking document if the final text is identical to the text published with the notice of proposed rulemaking;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>310.5.</num>
    <text>If the text of a rulemaking document is substantially altered from the text published with the notice of proposed rulemaking, the promulgating agency must re-submit the text as a proposed rule, pursuant to §309. An agency does not have to wait the
      full notice period before re-filing an altered proposed rule. A new notice period begins upon re-publication.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>310.6.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this chapter, “substantial alteration” of the text shall not include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Re-arrangement or renumbering of portions of the text;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Re-wording to correct errors in format or style;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Re-wording of the document, including the addition or deletion of material, that serves to clarify the intent, meaning, or application of the rule(s) and that does not substantially change the intent, meaning, or application of the proposed rule(s)
        or exceed the scope of the rule(s) as published with the notice of proposed rulemaking, as determined by ODAI.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 9855, 9870 (May 5, 1979); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 4091, 4106 (September 18, 1981); and as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 271, 286 (January 9, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>