<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-502</num>
  <heading>SERVICE OF PAPERS, METHODS, PROOF (§ 1-502)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>502.1.</num>
    <text>Any paper required to be served upon a party shall be served upon the party or upon the representative designated by the party or by law to receive service of papers. When a party has appeared through a representative, service may be made upon the
      representative of record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>502.2.</num>
    <text>Service may be made by personal delivery, by mail, or as otherwise directed by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>502.3.</num>
    <text>Service upon a party shall be completed by any of the following methods:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>By personal delivery, or handing the paper to the person, or leaving it at the person’s office with a clerk or other person in charge, or, if the office is closed or the person to be served has no office, leaving it at his or her usual place of
        residence with some person of suitable discretion sixteen (16) years of age or older residing there; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>By mail, on deposit in the United States Mail, properly stamped and addressed; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>In conformity with an order of the Board made in any proceeding.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>502.4.</num>
    <text>Proof of service, stating the name and address of the person on whom service is made and the manner and date of service, may be shown by any of the following methods:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Written acknowledgment of the party served or by his or her representative; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The certificate of the serving party or that party’s representative or attorney; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A return receipt if served by registered or certified mail.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 3665 (June 27, 1997), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 2934, 2935-36 (May 16, 1997).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>