<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-1531</num>
  <heading>NAVAL OBSERVATORY PRECINCT OVERLAY DISTRICT (NO) (ยง 11-1531)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1531.1.</num>
    <text>The Naval Observatory Precinct (NO) Overlay District is established to promote the public health, safety, and general welfare on land adjacent to or in close proximity to the highly sensitive and historically important Naval Observatory, in keeping
      with the goals and policies of the Federal and District elements of the Comprehensive Plan and the adopted Master Plan for that facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1531.2.</num>
    <text>Public land within the NO Overlay District shall be used in a manner consistent with the historic or ceremonial importance and special missions of the Naval Observatory.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1531.3.</num>
    <text>The land use controls embodied in this title for land adjacent to the Naval Observatory reflect the importance of the Naval Observatory to the District of Columbia and the Nation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1531.4.</num>
    <text>The NO Overlay District is intended to provide additional controls on private land, in order to protect recognized Federal interest concerns. The concerns include the critical scientific mission performed at the Naval Observatory and the security
      needs of the Vice-President&amp;#8217;s residence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1531.5.</num>
    <text>The NO Overlay District shall act to further restrict the development controls permitted in existing districts to reduce or eliminate any possible harm or restrictions on the mission of the Federal establishment within the NO Overlay District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1531.6.</num>
    <text>The NO Overlay District shall be mapped in combination with any underlying zone district and not instead of the underlying zoning.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1531.7.</num>
    <text>All uses, buildings, and structures permitted in accordance with the appropriate sections of this chapter for the respective districts with which the mapped NO Overlay District is combined shall be permitted in those districts, except as specifically
      modified by this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1531.8.</num>
    <text>All restrictions or prohibitions applicable to either of the districts combined pursuant to this chapter shall apply in the NO Overlay District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 2745 (April 17, 1992); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8460 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>