<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-1402</num>
  <heading>HEIGHT AND BULK PROVISIONS (RC) (ยง 11-1402)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1402.1.</num>
    <text>The maximum height permitted in the RC Overlay District shall not exceed forty feet (40 ft.) plus roof structure as defined in this title; provided, that in the RC/C-2-B Overlay District, a maximum height of fifty feet (50 ft.), plus roof structures,
      shall be permitted to provide for the on-site construction of low and moderate income household units, as those households are defined by the Inclusionary Zoning Regulations of Chapter 26 for a total gross floor area equal to fifty percent (50%)
      of the additional gross floor area made possible by the height bonus.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1402.2.</num>
    <text>For the purpose of this chapter, no Planned Unit Development shall exceed the matter-of-right height, bulk, and area requirements of the underlying district.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1402.3</num>
    <text>1402.3ย Notwithstanding ยง 1402.2, the Zoning Commission, as part of a planned unit development permitting a hotel integrating the First Church Christ Scientist building on a new lot created by combining Lots 872, 875, and 127 of Square 2560, may permit
      a building height on former Lots 875 and 127 not to exceed 72 feet measured from Euclid Street, and an overall building density not to exceed 3.99 FAR.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 38 DCR 2384, 2387 (April 26, 1991); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8448 (October 20,
        2000); as amended by 54 DCR 6943, 6948 (July 20, 2007); as corrected by Errata Notice published at 58 DCR 4314, 4315 (May 20, 2011); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 3635 (March 15, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>