<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-1326</num>
  <heading>PLANNED UNIT DEVELOPMENT AND INCLUSIONARY ZONING PROVISIONS (HS) (§ 11-1326)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1326.1.</num>
    <text>A planned unit development (PUD) in the HS Overlay District shall be subject to the following provisions in addition to those of Chapter 24 of this Title:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The additional height and floor area above that permitted as a matter-of-right shall be used only for housing or the preferred uses listed in §§ 1322.2 and 1323.2 and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The PUD process shall not be used to reduce requirements in this Chapter for designated uses, specifically retail, service, entertainment, and arts uses.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1326.2.</num>
    <text>The minimum area included within the proposed PUD, including the area of public streets or alleys proposed to be closed, shall be ten thousand square feet (10,000 ft.2).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1326.3.</num>
    <text>Developments properties subject to the set-aside requirements of Chapter 26 Inclusionary Zoning may use the Height and Lot Occupancy and Bonus to Base Zone FAR in the following table: as the basis of calculating the set-aside requirements of § 2603:</text>
    <text>Base Zone</text>
    <text>IZ Bonus</text>
    <text>Bonus FAR</text>
    <text>Lot Occupancy</text>
    <text>Maximum Height</text>
    <text>H Street</text>
    <text>C-2-A</text>
    <text>C-2-B</text>
    <text>C-2-C</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>0.5</num>
    <text>0.5</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>0.7</num>
    <text>0.7</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1.2</num>
    <text>1.2</text>
    <text>75%</text>
    <text>80%</text>
    <text>80%</text>
    <text>50</text>
    <text>70</text>
    <text>100</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1326.4.</num>
    <text>The use of bonus density by a property also eligible to use the bonus provided for in § 1324.3 shall be deemed to first utilize the bonus authorized in § 1326.3.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1326.5.</num>
    <text>Use of the bonus authorized in § 1324.3 shall not count towards the set-aside requirements of § 2603. Bonus density achieved through § 1324.3 of the HS Overlay that is in addition to the above table shall not count toward the set-aside requirements
      of § 2603.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 1708, 1714 (March 10, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 2611 (March 14, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>