<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-1808</num>
  <heading>ZONING COMMISSION REVIEW STANDARDS (SEFC) (§ 11-1808)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1808.1.</num>
    <text>In addition to proving that the proposed uses, buildings, or structures meet the standards set forth in § 3104.1, the applicant for Zoning Commission approval of a use or structure within the SEFC Overlay District shall further demonstrate conformance
      to the following standards:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The use, building, or structure will help achieve the objectives of the SEFC Overlay District as set forth in § 1802;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The proposed building or structure shall be designed with a height, bulk, and siting that provide for openness of view and vistas to and from the waterfront and, where feasible, shall maintain views of federal monumental buildings, particularly
        along the New Jersey Avenue, S.E. corridor; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>On or above-grade parking adjacent to, or visible from, the street shall be limited. Where parking cannot be placed underground, other uses such as retail or residential shall separate parking areas from the street, or where this is not possible,
        green landscaping or architectural treatment of facades shall adequately screen parking from the street and adjacent development.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1808.2.</num>
    <text>In evaluating the application, the Commission also may consider:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Compatibility with buildings in the surrounding area through overall massing, siting, details, and landscaping;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Use of high standards of environmental design that promote the achievement of sustainable development goals;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Facade articulation that minimizes or eliminates the visibility of unarticulated blank walls from public spaces;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Landscaping which complements the building;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>For buildings that include preferred uses in accordance with §§ 1803.3 or 1804.3, the Commission may consider the balance and location of preferred uses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>In connection with its review pursuant to § 1804.2, the Commission may consider the effect of the proposed use on the predominantly residential character of the R-5-D and/or R-5-E portion of the SEFC; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>For development within or adjacent to the SEFC/W-0 District, the Commission may consider whether the project is consistent with the following goals:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Providing a wide variety of active and passive recreational uses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Encouraging uses that open to, overlook, and benefit the waterfront park;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Utilizing siting and design of buildings and uses to improve the natural ecology, to illustrate the importance of natural systems, and/or to interpret the historically important maritime context of the site.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 6850 (July 9, 2004); as corrected by Errata Notice published at 58 DCR 4314, 4316 (May 20, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>