<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-1901</num>
  <heading>USE PROVISIONS (ARTS) (§ 11-1901)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1901.1.</num>
    <text>Retail and service uses listed in § 1907 and arts and arts-related uses listed in § 1908 shall occupy no less than fifty percent (50%) of the ground level of each building on a lot that fronts on 14th Street, U Street, or 7th Street; or on Florida
      Avenue between 7th and 9th Streets; provided, this requirement shall not apply to a building located on a lot less than fifty feet (50 ft.) in width, measured along the property line that abuts the public street, if the building is used as an apartment
      house, multiple dwelling, or hotel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1901.2.</num>
    <text>A hotel shall be a permitted use; provided, no other hotel is located within five hundred feet (500 ft.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1901.3.</num>
    <text>No drive-through accessory to any use shall be permitted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1901.4.</num>
    <text>A use that exists on the February 23, 1990, having a certificate of occupancy for a use first permitted in a C-M District, shall be permitted to expand if approved by the Board of Zoning Adjustment as a special exception, subject to the requirements
      of § 3104 and the following conditions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>There shall be no outdoor storage of materials, nor any outdoor processing, fabricating, or repairs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>There shall be adequate off-street parking for trucks and other service vehicles;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The use shall not create objectionable effects on the character of the neighborhood because of its operations, traffic, or other conditions; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Board may impose requirements that apply to the design, appearance, or screening of the site or any other requirement that it deems necessary to protect neighboring or adjacent property.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1901.5.</num>
    <text>Required parking spaces may be shared by time of day with other uses specified in this subsection to meet all or a portion of the parking requirement for the uses on a lot; provided:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The eligible evening uses shall be restaurant, legitimate theater, movie theater, dinner theater, or cabaret;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The eligible daytime uses shall be office use and the arts uses and arts-related uses listed in § 1908, with the exception of the evening uses listed in paragraph (a) of this subsection; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The respective property owners shall execute an agreement that identifies the designated parking spaces and provides that use of the spaces for permitted daytime uses shall cease at no later than 6:00 p.m., Monday through Saturday, and shall be
        available for parking by the specified evening uses as agreed to by the parties involved. This agreement shall be filed with the Zoning Administrator to be maintained as part of the certificate of occupancy file on each affected property.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1901.6.</num>
    <text>Eating establishments, drinking establishments, or eating and drinking establishments (“eating/drinking establishments”) shall be subject to the following limitations:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>No portion of an eating/drinking establishment located on the ground floor is permitted to occupy more than fifty percent (50%) of the linear frontage of each individual square, as set forth below:</text>
    </level>
    <text>14th Street, N.W.</text>
    <text>U Street, N.W.</text>
    <text>Square</text>
    <text>Frontage (feet)</text>
    <text>Square</text>
    <text>Frontage (feet)</text>
    <text>202</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>222.5</num>
    <text>222.5</text>
    <text>204</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.3</num>
    <text>305.3</text>
    <text>203</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>310.0</num>
    <text>310.0</text>
    <text>205</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>618.0</num>
    <text>618.0</text>
    <text>204</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>320.0</num>
    <text>320.0</text>
    <text>236</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>523.4</num>
    <text>523.4</text>
    <text>205</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>430.6</num>
    <text>430.6</text>
    <text>237</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>538.5</num>
    <text>538.5</text>
    <text>206</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>399.8</num>
    <text>399.8</text>
    <text>273</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>225.3</num>
    <text>225.3</text>
    <text>207</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>450.1</num>
    <text>450.1</text>
    <text>274</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>340.9</num>
    <text>340.9</text>
    <text>208</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>400.0</num>
    <text>400.0</text>
    <text>304</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>192.2</num>
    <text>192.2</text>
    <text>209</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>380.0</num>
    <text>380.0</text>
    <text>305</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>186.0</num>
    <text>186.0</text>
    <text>210</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>203.5</num>
    <text>203.5</text>
    <text>332</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>189.7</num>
    <text>189.7</text>
    <text>211</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>304.2</num>
    <text>304.2</text>
    <text>333</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>187.7</num>
    <text>187.7</text>
    <text>234</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>253.1</num>
    <text>253.1</text>
    <text>359</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>96.8</num>
    <text>96.8</text>
    <text>235</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>310.0</num>
    <text>310.0</text>
    <text>360</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>230.4</num>
    <text>230.4</text>
    <text>236</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>320.0</num>
    <text>320.0</text>
    <text>361</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>251.7</num>
    <text>251.7</text>
    <text>237</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>380.0</num>
    <text>380.0</text>
    <text>238</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>450.0</num>
    <text>450.0</text>
    <text>239</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>200.0</num>
    <text>200.0</text>
    <text>240</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>391.0</num>
    <text>391.0</text>
    <text>241</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>450.0</num>
    <text>450.0</text>
    <text>242</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>363.1</num>
    <text>363.1</text>
    <text>242N</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>154.5</num>
    <text>154.5</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An eating/drinking establishment not located on the ground (street) level of a building shall not count towards the fifty percent (50%) limit; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An entrance to an eating/drinking establishment that is not located on the ground (street) level shall not count towards the fifty percent (50%) limit.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1901.7.</num>
    <text>A building permit granted for a use as an eating/drinking establishment issued in accordance with § 3202 authorizes the subsequent issuance of a certificate of occupancy for the specified eating/drinking establishment; provided that the Zoning Administrator
      has determined that the use complies with § 1901.6 at the time the building permit is issued and that construction has been completed in accordance with the subject building permit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 1392, 1396 (February 23, 1990); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 8323, 8324 (November 13, 1992); and Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference
        the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8492 (October 20, 2000); amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 7679, 7683 (August 20, 2010), as corrected by Errata Notice published at 58 DCR 4314, 4316 (May 20, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>