<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-1606</num>
  <heading>BUILDINGS, STRUCTURES, AND USES ON FIRST STREET S.E, SOUTH OF M STREET S.E. (CG)§ 11-1606)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1606.1.</num>
    <text>The following provisions apply to new buildings, structures, or uses with frontage on First Street S.E. south of M Street S.E., within the CG Overlay.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1606.2.</num>
    <text>Each new building shall devote not less than seventy-five percent (75%) of the gross floor area of the ground floor to retail, service, entertainment, or arts uses (&amp;#8220;preferred uses&amp;#8221;) as permitted in §§ 701.1 through 701.5 and §§
      721.1 through 721.6 of this Title; provided, that the following uses shall not be permitted: automobile, laundry, drive-through accessory to any use, gasoline service stations, and office uses (other than those accessory to the administration, maintenance,
      or leasing of the building).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1606.3.</num>
    <text>Preferred uses shall occupy 100% of the building&amp;#8217;s street frontage along First Street S.E., except for space devoted to building entrances or required to be devoted to fire control.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1606.4.</num>
    <text>The minimum floor-to-ceiling clear height for portions of the ground floor level devoted to preferred uses shall be fourteen (14) feet.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1606.5.</num>
    <text>For good cause shown, the Zoning Commission may authorize interim occupancy of the preferred use space required by § 1606.2 by non-preferred uses for up to a five (5) year period; provided, that the ground floor space is suitably designed for future
      occupancy by the preferred uses.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1606.6.</num>
    <text>Where preferred use retail space is required under this section and provided, the requirement of 11 DCMR § 633 to provide public space at ground level shall not apply.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 1587-1592 (February 16, 2007); as corrected by Errata Notice published at 58 DCR 4314, 4315 (May 20, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>