<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-213</num>
  <heading>PARKING LOTS (R-1) (ยง 11-213)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>213.1.</num>
    <text>Use as a parking lot shall be permitted as a special exception in an R-1 District if approved by the Board of Zoning Adjustment under ยง 3104, subject to the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>213.2.</num>
    <text>A parking lot shall be located in its entirety within two hundred feet (200 ft.) of an existing Commercial or Industrial District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>213.3.</num>
    <text>A parking lot shall be contiguous to or separated only by an alley from a Commercial or Industrial District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>213.4.</num>
    <text>All provisions of chapter 23 of this title shall be complied with.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>213.5.</num>
    <text>No dangerous or otherwise objectionable traffic conditions shall result from the establishment of the use, and the present character and future development of the neighborhood will not be affected adversely.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>213.6.</num>
    <text>The parking lot shall be reasonably necessary and convenient to other uses in the vicinity, so that the likely result will be a reduction in overspill parking on neighborhood streets.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>213.7.</num>
    <text>A majority of the parking spaces shall serve residential uses or short-term parking needs of retail, service, and public facility uses in the vicinity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>213.8.</num>
    <text>Before taking final action on an application for use as a parking lot, the Board shall submit the application to the D.C. Department of Transportation for review and report.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>ยง 3101.48 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as renumbered by Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 6916, 6918 (September 16, 1988); Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 1509, 1517 (February 24, 1989); and as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 47 DCR 9741 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8351 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>