<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2301</num>
  <heading>PARKING GARAGES (ยง 11-2301)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2301.1.</num>
    <text>A building erected, altered, converted, or reconstructed for use as a parking garage shall be subject to the provisions in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2301.2.</num>
    <text>A parking garage that is an accessory use may be located as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>As an accessory building in any district subject to the general provisions for accessory buildings as specified in ยง 2500; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Within the main building; provided:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The entrance or exit to the garage shall be accessible and, when it opens onto an alley, the entrance or exit shall be set back at least twelve feet (12 ft.) from the center line of the alley; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>That portion of the garage beneath a side yard, rear yard, or court shall not obstruct required light and ventilation and shall be designed so that the area above it can be used for an unobstructed level open terrace.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2301.3.</num>
    <text>A parking garage erected, altered, converted, or reconstructed as a principal use shall have no vehicular entrance or exit nearer than forty feet (40 ft.) to a street intersection as measured from the intersection of the curb lines extended. The entrance
      or exit to the garage shall be accessible and, when it opens onto an alley, the entrance or exit shall be set back at least twelve feet (12 ft.) from the center line of the alley.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>ยง 7402.1 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 6585, 6626 (December 28, 1984); and Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text
        of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8511 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>