<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2607</num>
  <heading>OFF-SITE COMPLIANCE (§ 11-2607)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2607.1.</num>
    <text>The Board of Zoning Adjustment is authorized to permit some or all of the set-aside requirements of § 2603 to be constructed off-site upon proof, based upon a specific economic analysis, that compliance on-site would impose an economic hardship. Among
      the factors that may be considered by the BZA in determining the existence of economic hardship are:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Exceptionally high fees in condominium developments that cannot be reduced to levels affordable to eligible households;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The inclusion of expensive and specialized social or health services in a retirement housing development or a development that principally provides housing for the disabled, if such services are not severable from the provision of housing and render
        units in the development unaffordable to eligible households; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>For a rental development the owner of which wishes to change the property&amp;#8217;s use to one listed in § 2602.3, proof that continuation of the rental use is no longer economically feasible.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2607.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant who has demonstrated the existence of economic hardship shall further demonstrate that the off-site development:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Is located within the same census tract as the inclusionary development;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Consists of new construction for which no certificate of occupancy has been issued;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Is at a location suitable for residential development;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Has complied with or will comply with all on-site requirements of this Chapter as are applicable to it;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Has not received any development subsidies from federal or District government programs established to provide affordable housing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Will provide inclusionary units comparable in type to the market-rate units being created in their place, with gross floor areas of not less than 95% of the gross floor area of such market-rate units, and of a number no fewer than the number of
        units that would otherwise have been required on-site;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Will not have more than 30% of its gross floor area occupied by inclusionary units that satisfy the set-aside requirement of other properties, including the property that is the subject of the BZA application; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Has not utilized bonus density beyond that provided by § 2604.1</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2607.3.</num>
    <text>The requirement of § 2607.2 (a) may be waived upon a showing that the off-site development is owned by the Applicant, is located in the District of Columbia, and meets the requirements of § 2607.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2607.4.</num>
    <text>Inclusionary units constructed off-site shall not be counted toward any set-aside requirement separately applicable to the off-site development pursuant to § 2603.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2607.5.</num>
    <text>No order granting off-site compliance shall become effective until a covenant, found legally sufficient by the Office of the Attorney General, has been recorded in the land records of the District of Columbia between the owner of the off-site development
      and the Mayor. A draft covenant, executed by the owner of the offsite property, shall be attached to an application for relief under this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2607.6.</num>
    <text>The covenant shall bind the owner and all future owners of the off-site development to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Construct and reserve the number of inclusionary units allowed to be accounted for off-site, in accordance with the plans approved by the Board and the conditions of the Board&amp;#8217;s order;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Sell or rent, as applicable, such units in accordance with the provisions of this Chapter and the Act for so long as the off-site development remains in existence;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Neither apply for nor accept any development subsidies from federal or District government programs established to provide affordable housing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Acknowledge that the owners are legally responsible for the set-aside requirement accepted as if the requirement had been imposed directly on the off-site development; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Not request special exception or variance relief with respect to the obligations accepted or its own obligations under this Chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2607.7.</num>
    <text>Upon the recordation of the covenant, the set-aside requirements permitted to be accounted off-site shall be deemed to be the legal obligation of the current and future owners of the off-site development. All dwelling units as are required to be reserved
      in the off-site development in accordance with the BZA order shall be deemed inclusionary units for the purposes of this Chapter and the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2607.8.</num>
    <text>No application for a certificate of occupancy for a market-rate unit on the inclusionary development shall be granted unless construction of the off-site inclusionary units is progressing at a rate roughly proportional to the construction of the on-site
      market-rate units.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 7013 (August 25, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 2604 (March 14, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>