<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2117</num>
  <heading>ACCESS, MAINTENANCE, AND-OPERATION (§ 11-2117)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2117.1.</num>
    <text>The parking spaces required by this chapter shall be provided and maintained so long as the structure that the parking spaces are designed to serve exists.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2117.2.</num>
    <text>Required parking spaces shall not be reduced in total extent after their provision except upon approval of the Board of Zoning Adjustment and then only after proof that the parking spaces provided are no longer needed by reason of a reduction of employees,
      seats, gross floor area, dwelling units, or any other standard applicable to the use set forth in the regulations; provided the Board may impose any condition it deems necessary to ensure the addition of parking spaces in case of a subsequent increase
      in employees, seats, gross floor area, dwelling units, or any other unit of measurement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2117.3.</num>
    <text>All required parking spaces shall be clearly striped and lined according to the dimensions specified in § 2115. Durable materials that are all-weather shall be used. Striping shall be maintained for as long as the parking spaces requiring the striping
      are in existence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2117.4.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in §§ 2117.5 and 2117.6, each required parking space shall be accessible at all times directly from improved alleys with a minimum width of ten feet (10 ft) or improved public streets via graded and unobstructed private driveways
      that form an all-weather surface.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2117.5.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in §§ 2115.9 through 2115.18 and 2117.6, when required parking spaces are so arranged that an aisle is required for accessibility or maneuvering space between rows of two (2) or more parking spaces, or between a row of two (2) or
      more parking spaces and the perimeter of the area devoted to parking spaces, the aisle shall have a clear width of not less than twenty feet (20 ft.) or ninety degree (90°) angle parking, and not less than seventeen feet (17 ft.) for angle parking
      that is sixty degrees (60°) or less as measured from the center line of the aisle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2117.6.</num>
    <text>Aisle widths as prescribed in § 2117.5 serving compact car spaces exclusively shall have a clear width of not less than twenty feet (20 ft.) for ninety degree (90°) angle parking and not less than sixteen feet (16 ft.) for angle parking that is sixty
      degrees (60°) or less as measured from the center line of the aisle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2117.7.</num>
    <text>The public rights-of-way as well as private walkways and driveways shall be protected from vehicular encroachment from all parking spaces by wheel bumper guards, curbs, guard rails, or screening between the property line and the perimeter of the parking
      area. Parking shall be designed so that no vehicle or any part thereof shall project over any lot line or building line.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2117.8.</num>
    <text>A driveway that provides access to required parking spaces shall meet the following standards:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>It shall have a maximum grade of not more than twelve percent (12%) with a vertical transition at the property line;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A driveway serving a one-family dwelling or flat or that otherwise serves only one parking space shall be not less than seven feet (7 ft.) in width;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A driveway serving any use other than a one-family dwelling or flat or serving more than one (1) parking space shall be as follows:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Not less than twenty-five feet (25 ft.) from a street intersection as measured from the intersection of the curb line extended;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Not less than twelve feet (12 ft.) in width if designed for one-way circulation or fourteen feet (14 ft.) if designed for two-way circulation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Not more than twenty-five feet (25 ft.) in width.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A driveway that provides access directly from a street to a row dwelling or a flat shall be a minimum of twenty-eight feet (28 ft.) from all adjacent driveways that provide access directly from a street to a row dwelling or a flat, as measured from
        the nearest edge of each such driveway opening.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2117.9.</num>
    <text>Driveways and parking for row dwellings shall be governed by the following special provisions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>In the case of two (2) or more row dwellings that are constructed concurrently on adjacent lots and that have direct access only from the street, each two (2) row dwellings shall provide access to the required off-street parking spaces through adjacent
        driveways that share one (1) driveway opening. The width of each driveway shall not exceed seven feet (7 ft.) on each lot;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>In the case of a row dwelling located on a lot where there are as many as three (3) row dwellings located on that lot or contiguous lots facing the same street, where access to the required parking space is only available directly from a street
        and no alternative access is available through existing or proposed alleys or private driveways, and where the driveway dimensional requirements stipulated in § 2117.8(d) cannot be met, the required parking spaces need not be provided;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Board of Zoning Adjustment may allow the parking spaces required for one (1) or more row dwellings to be located on a separate lot in accordance with the requirements of § 3104 for special exceptions, provided:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There is no alternative access to on-site parking spaces through existing or proposed paved alleys or private driveways that meet the Design Standards of the D.C. Department of Transportation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The parking spaces are so located as to furnish reasonable and convenient parking facilities for the occupants or guests of the building or structure that they are designed to serve;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Board determines that the separate parking does not impose any adverse impact on the surrounding neighborhood;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any application for the separate parking shall be submitted to the D.C. Department of Transportation for review and report; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The Board may impose conditions as to screening, coping, setbacks, fences, the location of entrances or exits, or any other requirement it deems necessary to protect adjacent or nearby property. It may also impose such other conditions as it deems
        necessary to ensure the continued provision and maintenance of the spaces.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2117.10.</num>
    <text>All open parking spaces, including access aisles, driveways, and ramp areas shall be surfaced and maintained with an all-weather surface. In addition to traditional impervious surfaces, allowable all weather surfaces include porous (or pervious) concrete,
      porous asphalt, and/or mechanically-reinforced grass, excluding grass or gravel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2117.11.</num>
    <text>Landscaping with trees and shrubs shall be provided for all open parking spaces provided on a lot where there are more than ten (10) open parking spaces provided collectively as accessory to any building or structure. The landscaping shall cover a
      minimum of five percent (5%) of the total area devoted to parking, including aisles and driveways. The landscaping shall be maintained in a healthy, growing condition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2117.12.</num>
    <text>The open parking spaces shall be screened from all contiguous residential property located in an R-1, R-2, R-3, R-4, R-5-A, or SP District by a solid brick or stone wall at least twelve inches (12 in.) thick and forty-two inches (42 in.) high or by
      evergreen hedges or evergreen growing trees that are thickly planted and maintained and that are at least forty-two inches (42 in.) in height when planted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2117.13.</num>
    <text>Any lighting used to illuminate open parking spaces shall be so arranged that all direct rays of lighting are confined to the surface of the paved area devoted to parking.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2117.14.</num>
    <text>Detailed plans shall be submitted to the D.C. Department of Transportation for approval of all curb cuts and driveway openings, to ensure that compliance with these regulations does not conflict with the responsibility of the Department to protect
      safety in the public space.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2117.15.</num>
    <text>Required parking spaces for a gasoline service station permitted as a matter of right may be arranged so that all spaces are not accessible at all times. All parking spaces provided under this subsection shall be designed and operated so that sufficient
      access and maneuvering space is available to permit the parking and removal of any vehicle without moving any other vehicle onto public space.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2117.16.</num>
    <text>Required parking spaces for a Police Department General Facility or Police Department Local Facility may be arranged so that all spaces are not accessible at all times.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 6585, 6604 (December 28, 1984); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 5898 (September 26, 1986); and Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the
        text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8502-04 (October 20, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4778 (May 7, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 856 (February 10, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>