<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2810</num>
  <heading>YARDS AND LOT SIZE (HE) (§ 11-2810)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2810.1.</num>
    <text>No side yard shall be required. If a side yard is provided, its minimum width shall be eight feet (8 ft).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2810.2.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § 2810.3, no rear yard shall be required for wholly non-residential buildings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2810.3.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding § 2801.2, an entirely non-residential building shall have a rear yard if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The building’s rear wall faces a wall of a residential building;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The distance between the rear wall of the non-residential building and a wall of the residential buildings is forty feet (40 ft.) or less; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A window located on the non-residential building’s rear wall would afford a direct view into the interior of the residential building through one or more of the latter’s windows.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2810.4.</num>
    <text>The rear yard required by § 2810 shall have a depth equal to the distance between the rear wall of the non-residential building and the facing wall of the residential building.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2810.5.</num>
    <text>All residential buildings shall provide a rear yard in accordance with either § 2810.6 or § 2810.7.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2810.6.</num>
    <text>When the residential portion of a building begins at or below grade, the building shall provide a rear yard with a minimum depth of three inches (3 in.) per foot of vertical distance from the mean finished grade at the middle of the rear of the structure
      to the highest point of the main roof, but not less than twelve feet (12ft.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2810.7.</num>
    <text>When the residential portion of a building begins above grade, the building shall provide a rear yard with a minimum depth of three inches (3in.) per foot of vertical distance from the horizontal plane at which the residential use begins to the highest
      point of the main roof, but not less than twelve feet (12ft.). The rear yard shall be provided at and above the horizontal plane at which residential use begins.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2810.8.</num>
    <text>The minimum lot area for row dwellings shall be eighteen hundred square feet (1,800 ft.2) with a minimum lot width of eighteen feet (18 ft.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking and Order No. 04-05 published at 56 DCR 6181 (August 7, 2009); as corrected by Errata Notice published at 58 DCR 4314, 4316 (May 20, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>