<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2703</num>
  <heading>GROUND MOUNTED ANTENNAS (§ 11-2703)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2703.1.</num>
    <text>All ground mounted antennas, except those regulated by § 2706 or exempted by § 2707, shall comply with the following conditions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>In any Residence (R), Special Purpose (SP), Mixed Use (CR), or Waterfront (W) zone district only one antenna may be located per lot and may not exceed a mounted height of twelve feet (12 ft.) at its highest point above the ground on which it is
        located;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>In any Commercial (C) or Industrial (CM or M) zone district an antenna may not exceed a mounted height of twenty feet (20 ft.) at its highest point above the ground on which it is located;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The antenna shall be located in either the rear yard or the side yard of the principal building on the lot, except that in the case of a corner lot no antenna may be located in the yard between the principal building structure and a street;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Each part of the antenna shall be removed from all lot lines by a minimum distance of ten feet (10 ft.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Each antenna installation shall be located or screened such that its visibility is minimized to the greatest practical extent from any:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Public park that is within the Central Employment Area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Street that the lot abuts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Public spaces;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Navigable waterways;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Historic landmarks; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>National monuments;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The antenna, to the greatest practical extent, shall be constructed of materials and colors that blend with the surroundings; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The antenna installation shall be as small as is practical for its intended use.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2703.2.</num>
    <text>The term &amp;#8220;ground&amp;#8221; as used in §§ 2703.2 (a) and (b) does not include artificially elevated terrain such as berms or planter boxes but may include graded lawns, terraced landscapes that are formed from the natural grade, and at-grade
      patios.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2703.3.</num>
    <text>A proposed ground mounted antenna that does not comply with the above requirements or numeric limit may be permitted through the special exception process set forth in § 2712.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 34 (January 4, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>