<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2110</num>
  <heading>TEMPORARY SURFACE PARKING LOTS AND SPACES FOR THE BALLPARK (§ 11-2110)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2110.1.</num>
    <text>Permitted Use &amp;#8211; Notwithstanding §§ 602.1 and 902.1 and not subject to any otherwise applicable proximity requirement, a temporary surface parking lot accessory to the Ballpark shall be permitted as a temporary use on Squares 603, 605, 657,
      658, 660, 661, 662, 662E, 664, 664E, 665, 700, 701, 707, 708, 708E, 708S, 744S, and 882; Square 658, Lot 7; and Square 767, Lots 44 &amp;#8211; 47; Square 768, Lots 19 &amp;#8211; 22; and Square 769, Lots 18 &amp;#8211; 21 (“the subject squares”)
      in accordance with §§ 2110.3 through 2110.5 and the following provisions:</text>
    <text>The cumulative total of all temporary surface parking spaces for which a valid Building Permit has been issued pursuant to this section shall not exceed three thousand seven hundred seventy-five (3,775) parking spaces;</text>
    <text>Any certificate of occupancy issued pursuant to this subsection shall expire no later than April 1, 2018;</text>
    <text>The application for a building permit for matter of right construction shall include a detailed accounting demonstrating that the circumstances described in § 2110.2 do not apply;</text>
    <text>No certificates of occupancy for this use shall be issued until the District Department of Transportation (DDOT) has approved a traffic routing plan for the lot, which shall include the impact of other proposed lots if required by DDOT; and</text>
    <text>The traffic routing plan described in § 2110.1(d) shall not direct traffic through I Street, S.W., P Street, S.W., or 4th Street, S.W.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2110.2.</num>
    <text>Special Exception &amp;#8211; If and when valid building permits issued pursuant to § 2110.1 authorize an aggregate of three thousand seven hundred seventy-five (3,775) or more parking spaces, the construction and use of additional temporary spaces
      on any of the subject squares shall require approval of the Board of Zoning Adjustment (BZA) pursuant to § 3104, and in accordance with §§ 2110.3 through 2110.5 and the following provisions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Any certificate of occupancy issued pursuant to this subsection shall expire no later than April 1, 2018; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The BZA application shall include a detailed accounting of the number and locations of temporary parking spaces provided pursuant to § 2110.1; and shall also include a traffic study assessing the impacts of the proposed additional parking spaces
        on local traffic patterns for referral to and comment by DDOT.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2110.3.</num>
    <text>Any parking lot authorized shall be available for exclusive use of attendees at any baseball game or other public event described in §1612.3 for a time period extending from one and a half (1.5) hours prior to the scheduled start time of the event,
      to 3 hours after the event. At all other times, the parking lot may be used for:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Parking on a general basis for &amp;#8220;non-commercial motor vehicles&amp;#8221; as that term is defined by 18 DCMR § 1312.3 (c), except vehicles equipped to serve as temporary or permanent living quarters; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A seasonal or occasional market for produce, arts or crafts with non-permanent structures.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2110.4.</num>
    <text>No use, other than permitted in this section shall be conducted from or upon the premises, and no structure other than an attendant&amp;#8217;s shelter shall be erected or used upon the premises unless the use or structure is otherwise permitted in
      the District in which the parking lot is located.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2110.5.</num>
    <text>A temporary surface parking lot provided in accordance with this section shall comply with the following standards:</text>
    <text>A full size automobile parking space shall be a minimum of nine feet (9 ft.) in width and nineteen feet (19 ft.) in length, exclusive of access drives or aisles. A compact car parking space shall be a minimum of eight feet (8 ft.) in width and sixteen
      feet (16 ft.) in length exclusive of access drives or aisles, and shall be visibly marked as a &amp;#8220;compact car&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;small car&amp;#8221; parking space;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Parking shall be designed so that no vehicle or any part thereof shall project over any lot line or building line. All parking areas and spaces shall be designed and operated so that sufficient access and maneuvering space is available to permit
        the parking and removal of any vehicle without moving any other vehicle onto public space;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>When parking spaces are so arranged that an aisle is required for accessibility or maneuvering space between rows of 2 or more parking spaces, or between a row of 2 or more parking spaces and the perimeter of the area devoted to parking spaces,
        the aisle shall have a clear width of not less than twenty feet (20 ft.) or ninety degree (90°) angle parking, and not less than seventeen feet (17 ft.) for angle parking that is sixty degrees (60°) or less as measured from the center line of
        the aisle;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Aisle widths serving compact car spaces -exclusively shall have a clear width of not less than twenty feet (20 ft.) for ninety degree (90°) angle parking and not less than sixteen feet (16 ft.) for angle parking that is sixty degrees (60°) or less
        as measured from the center line of the aisle;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Compliance with the requirements of §§ 2110.5 (c) and (d) is not required if the parking is managed during a specified twelve (12) hour peak period to be determined by the District Department of Transportation by employed attendants who park the
        vehicles using the parking facility; in which case a permanent sign shall be posted at each entrance in full view of the public that states: &amp;#8220;Attendant assisted parking is required by the District of Columbia Zoning Regulations.&amp;#8221;
        The sign shall also state the hours during which attendant parking is required. The sign shall have a white background, with black lettering that is no less than two inches (2 in.) in height;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A driveway that provides access to required parking spaces shall:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Have a maximum grade of not more than twelve percent (12%) with a vertical transition at the property line;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Be not less than twenty-five feet (25 ft.) from a street intersection as measured from the intersection of the curb line extended;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Be not less than twelve feet (12 ft.) in width if designed for one-way circulation or fourteen feet (14 ft.) if designed for two-way circulation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Be not more than twenty-five feet (25 ft.) in width;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>All parking spaces, including access aisles, driveways, and ramp areas shall be surfaced and maintained with an all-weather surface. In addition to traditional impervious surfaces, allowable all weather surfaces include porous (or pervious) concrete,
        porous asphalt, and/or mechanically-reinforced grass, excluding grass or gravel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The parking lot shall be kept free of refuse and debris and shall be landscaped. Landscaping shall be maintained in a healthy growing condition and in a neat and orderly appearance. Landscaping with trees and shrubs shall cover a minimum of five
        percent (5%) of the total area of the parking lot, or an area as determined by the Board of Zoning Adjustment for a parking lot requiring Board approval;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Any lighting used to illuminate a parking lot or its accessory building shall be so arranged that all direct rays of lighting are confined to the surface of the paved area devoted to parking; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>A minimum of 5% of parking spaces shall be reserved for a registered and recognized, publicly accessible car/ride-share program with a significant District user base and a mandate that is not commuter-oriented, such as GoLoco. These car/ride share
        spaces shall be provided in premium, visible, bannered locations and will be available, for a fee, exclusively for this use until the start of the event on that day.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 8976 (September 14, 2007); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 10300 (October 26, 2007); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 7308 (July 4, 2008); as corrected by Errata Notice published
        at 58 DCR 4314, 4317 (May 20, 2011); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 15091 (December 28, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>