<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2003</num>
  <heading>CHANGING USES WITHIN STRUCTURES (§ 11-2003)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2003.1.</num>
    <text>If approved by the Board of Zoning Adjustment, as authorized in §§ 3103 and 3104 for variances and special exceptions, a nonconforming use may be changed to a use that is permitted as a matter of right in the most restrictive district in which the
      existing nonconforming use is permitted as a matter of right, subject to the conditions set forth in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2003.2.</num>
    <text>The proposed use shall not adversely affect the present character or future development of the surrounding area in accordance with this title. The surrounding area shall be deemed to encompass the existing uses and structures within at least three
      hundred feet (300 ft.) in all directions from the nonconforming use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2003.3.</num>
    <text>The proposed use shall not create any deleterious external effects, including but not limited to noise, traffic, parking and loading considerations, illumination, vibration, odor, and design and siting effects.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2003.4.</num>
    <text>When an existing nonconforming use has been changed to a conforming or more restrictive use, it shall not be changed back to a nonconforming use or less restrictive use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2003.5.</num>
    <text>In Residence Districts, the proposed use shall be either a dwelling, flat, apartment house, or a neighborhood facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2003.6.</num>
    <text>For the purpose of this section, the districts established by this title are listed in the following order of decreased use restriction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>W-0, R-1-A, R-1-B, R-2, R-3, R-5-A, R-4, R-5-B, R-5-C, R-5-D, and R-5-E;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>SP-1 and SP-2;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>C-1, C-2-A, C-2-B, C-2-C, C-3-A, C-3-B, C-3-C, C-4, and C-5 (PAD);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>W-1, W-2, and W-3;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>CR; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>C-M-1, C-M-2, C-M-3, and M.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2003.7.</num>
    <text>The Board may require the provision of or direct changes, modifications, or amendments to any design, plan, screening, landscaping, type of lighting, nature of any sign, pedestrian or vehicular access, parking and loading, hours of operation, or any
      other restriction or safeguard it deems necessary to protect the value, utilization, or enjoyment of property in the neighborhood.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE §§ 7103.1 and 7104.2 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by:</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 30 DCR 3922, 3925-26 (August 5, 1983); Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 8305, 8309 (November 13, 1992); and Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of
        Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8497 (October 20, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 3440 (April 2, 2004) and 52 DCR 6358 (July 8, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>