<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2523</num>
  <heading>WATER TOWER ON THE EAST CAMPUS OF SAINT ELIZABETHS (§ 11-2523)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2523.1.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Title, a water tower or elevated water tank (“Water Tower”) owned and operated by the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority may be established on unzoned property owned by the District of Columbia
      and located on the East Campus of Saint Elizabeths Hospital.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2523.2.</num>
    <text>No building permit to construct a Water Tower in excess of ninety (90) feet in height may be issued unless the Zoning Commission finds that said tower, as designed, meets the standards of § 3104 and is not inconsistent with the Comprehensive Plan,
      small area plan(s), and other adopted planning studies that pertain to the site.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2523.3.</num>
    <text>An application pursuant to § 2523.2 shall include such plans and illustrations necessary to adequately represent the final proposed appearance of the tower, including its materials, final elevation, and location on the East Campus. The application
      shall also identify how the proposed design meets the standard for approval set forth in § 2523.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2523.4</num>
    <text>2523.4 An application shall be included as a “Final Action” item for a Zoning Commission meeting scheduled after the completion of the thirty (30) day review period allowed the affected ANC(s). The notice to the affected ANC(s) shall include the date
      of the final action and a tentative public hearing date.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2523.5.</num>
    <text>The only motion that can be made at that time is for approval of the application in accordance with § 3028 and without the need for a public hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2523.6.</num>
    <text>If no motion is made, or if the motion fails, the matter shall be moved to the “Hearing Actions” portion of the agenda, at which point the Commission may take any of the actions authorized by §§ 3011.3 through 3011.6.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2523.7.</num>
    <text>The Office of Planning may submit a report as to whether the Commission should approve the application. Any such report should be filed no later than ten (10) days prior to the date of the public meeting at which the final action item will be considered.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2523.8.</num>
    <text>A request to modify an approved design shall be subject to the same review criteria and approval process as set forth in this section for the original application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking &amp;#038; Order No. 09-10 published at 57 DCR 3487 (April 23, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>