<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2910</num>
  <heading>BICYCLE PARKING (ยง 11-2910)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2910.1.</num>
    <text>Bicycle parking spaces shall be provided at a minimum as follows:</text>
    <text>Type of use</text>
    <text>Indoor Spaces</text>
    <text>Outdoor spaces</text>
    <text>Residential</text>
    <text>One for every three units</text>
    <text>One for every twenty units, with a minimum of two</text>
    <text>Non-residential</text>
    <text>One for every 10,000 square feet of gross floor area, with a minimum of two</text>
    <text>One for every 40,000 square feet of gross floor area, with a minimum of two</text>
    <text>Retail/service</text>
    <text>One for every 10,000 square feet of gross floor area, with a minimum of two</text>
    <text>One for every 5,000 square feet of gross floor area, with a minimum of two</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2910.2.</num>
    <text>All bicycle parking spaces shall be well lit and provide convenient access to the uses they are intended to serve.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2910.3.</num>
    <text>Outdoor spaces may be provided in public space subject to the approval of the District Department of Transportation (DDOT).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2910.4.</num>
    <text>All required bicycle parking spaces shall be a minimum of two feet (2 ft.) in width and six feet (6 ft.) in length.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2910.5.</num>
    <text>An aisle five feet (5 ft.) in width shall be provided between rows of bicycle parking spaces and the perimeter of the area devoted to bicycle parking.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2910.6.</num>
    <text>If a room or common locker not divided into individual spaces is used to meet these requirements, twelve square feet (12 sq. ft.) of floor area shall be considered the equivalent of one (1) bicycle parking space. Where manufactured metal lockers or
      racks are provided, each locker or stall devoted to bicycle parking shall be counted as one (1) bicycle parking space.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2910.7.</num>
    <text>Signs shall be posted stating where bicycle parking spaces are located in each building or structure where bicycle parking spaces are required. The signs shall be located in a prominent place at each entrance to the building or structure. The sign
      shall have a white background with black lettering that is no less than two inches (2 in.) in height.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 4788, 4799 (June 3, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>