<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-216</num>
  <heading>CHURCH PROGRAMS (R-1) (ยง 11-216)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>216.1.</num>
    <text>Use for a program conducted by a church congregation or group of churches shall be permitted as a special exception in an R-1 District if approved by the Board of Zoning Adjustment under ยง 3104, subject to the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>216.2.</num>
    <text>The church program shall not be organized for profit, but shall be organized exclusively for the promotion of the social welfare of the community.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>216.3.</num>
    <text>The part of the church program conducted on the property shall be carried on within the existing church building(s) or structure(s).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>216.4.</num>
    <text>The staff conducting the program shall be composed of persons, at least seventy-five percent (75%) of whom volunteer their time and services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>216.5.</num>
    <text>The operation of the program shall be such that it is not likely to become objectionable in the Residence District because of noise and traffic.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>216.6.</num>
    <text>No signs or display indicating the location of the church program shall be located on the outside of the building or the grounds.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>216.7.</num>
    <text>Any authorization by the Board shall be limited to a period of three (3) years, but may be renewed at the discretion of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>ยง 3101.411 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; renumbered by Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 6916, 6918 (September 16, 1988); Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 1509, 1517 (February 24, 1989); and as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 47 DCR 9741 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8351 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>