<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2120</num>
  <heading>PARKING FOR HISTORIC BUILDINGS (§ 11-2120)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2120.1.</num>
    <text>This section sets forth the circumstances under which existing and new uses in historic resources and additions thereto are exempt from providing parking and shall not apply to new unattached structures constructed on the same lot as a historic resource.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2120.2.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, a historic resource is a building or structure listed in the District of Columbia Inventory of Historic Sites or a building or structure certified in writing by the State Historic Preservation Officer as contributing
      to the character of the historic district in which it is located.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2120.3.</num>
    <text>A historic resource and any additions thereto are exempt from the requirement of § 2100.4 to provide additional parking as a result of a change of use and from the requirement of § 2100.6 to provide additional parking as a result of an increase of
      intensity of use, except that parking shall be required for any addition where:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The gross floor area of the historic resource is being increased by 50% or more, and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The parking requirement attributable to the increase in gross floor area is at least four (4) spaces.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2120.4.</num>
    <text>Any parking provided for a historic resource in excess of that which existed at the time the historic resource was listed in the District of Columbia Inventory of Historic Sites or the historic district was created shall be exempt from § 2115, and
      §§ 2117.5 and 2117.6.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2120.5.</num>
    <text>Parking spaces provided for a historic resource shall be a minimum of eight feet (8 ft.) in width and sixteen feet (16 ft.) in length exclusive of access drives, aisles, ramps, columns, and office and work areas. All required parking spaces shall
      be clearly striped and lined. Durable all-weather materials shall be used. Striping shall be maintained for as long as the parking spaces requiring the striping are in existence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2120.6.</num>
    <text>The Board of Zoning Adjustment may grant relief from all or part of the parking requirements of this section if the owner of the property demonstrates that, as a result of the nature or location of the historic resource, providing the required parking
      will result in significant architectural or structural difficulty in maintaining the historic integrity and appearance of the historic resource. The Board shall grant only the amount of relief needed to alleviate the difficulty proved. The applicant
      shall also demonstrate compliance with the general special exception standard set forth in § 3104 and shall address each of the following criteria as part of its presentation to the Board:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Maximum number of students, employees, guests, customers, or clients who can reasonably be expected to use the proposed building or structure at one time;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Amount of traffic congestion existing and/or that the redevelopment of the historic resource can reasonably be expected to add to the neighborhood;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Quantity of existing public, commercial, or private parking, other than curb parking, on the property or in the neighborhood that can reasonably be expected to be available when the redevelopment is complete; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Proximity to public transportation, particularly Metrorail stations, and availability of either public transportation service in the area, or a ride sharing program approved by the District of Columbia Department of Transportation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2120.7.</num>
    <text>Prior to taking final action on an application, the Board shall refer the application to the D.C. Department of Transportation for review and report.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 8959 (September 14, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>