<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2505</num>
  <heading>EXCAVATION OF ROCK, CLAY, SAND, OR GRAVEL (§ 11-2505)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2505.1.</num>
    <text>The excavation of rock for commercial purposes or the operation of a rock quarry shall be expressly prohibited in any district.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.2.</num>
    <text>Clay, sand, or gravel may be excavated for commercial purposes in a C-M or M District, subject to the standards of external effects for a C-M District in § 804.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.3.</num>
    <text>If approved by the Board of Zoning Adjustment as a special exception under § 3104, clay, sand, or gravel may be excavated for commercial purposes in a Residence or Commercial District; provided, that the requirements of §§ 2505.4 through 2505.12 shall
      be met.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.4.</num>
    <text>The applicant for Board approval under § 2505.3 shall submit with the application a site plan showing the:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Proposed area of operation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Distance between any excavation operation and existing streets, alleys, and lot lines of the lot upon which the use will be located;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>All existing underground utilities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Proposed manner of operation, including the routing of trucking to and from the site; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Proposed rehabilitation or improvement of the site when operations cease.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.5.</num>
    <text>The following shall be prohibited:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Cement plants or rock crushers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Other crushing, grinding, or polishing machinery; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Other processing equipment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.6.</num>
    <text>Dirt or dust shall not be permitted to escape or be discharged in objectionable amounts from the lot upon which the excavation is conducted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.7.</num>
    <text>All private access roads shall be provided with a dustless surface.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.8.</num>
    <text>The lot upon which the excavation is conducted shall be enclosed by a fence of a type and to a height to be prescribed by the Board, unless expressly waived by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.9.</num>
    <text>Excavation operations shall be restricted to the hours from 7:00 a.m. to 7:00 p.m., with no operations conducted on Sundays or legal holidays.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.10.</num>
    <text>The excavation operations shall be subject to any requirements for setback, screening, or other requirement that the Board deems necessary for the protection of neighboring or adjacent property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.11.</num>
    <text>The Board may require the execution of a bond to secure the performance of all conditions imposed on the excavation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.12.</num>
    <text>Upon cessation of any excavation operations approved under § 2505.3, the site devoted to that use shall be rehabilitated in the following manner:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The final slope or wall of any excavation or pit shall not exceed the normal limiting angle of repose or slippage, and shall be planted to prevent erosion;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The site shall be left in a condition so that it will not unreasonably interfere with the future development of neighboring or adjacent property, or any street or alley for which an approved line and grade have been established; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any other conditions that the Board deems necessary to preserve the sightlines of the site or the requirements of safety.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§ 7505 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958 (renumbered § 7604 in the April 1981 edition of the Zoning Regulations); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text
        of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8526-27 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>