<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-353</num>
  <heading>NEW RESIDENTIAL DEVELOPMENTS (R-5-A) (ยง 11-353)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>353.1.</num>
    <text>In R-5-A Districts, all new residential developments, except those comprising all one-family detached and semi-detached dwellings, shall be reviewed by the Board of Zoning Adjustment as special exceptions under ยง 3104 in accordance with the standards
      and requirements in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>353.2.</num>
    <text>The Board shall refer the application to the D.C. Board of Education for comment and recommendation as to the adequacy of existing and planned area schools to accommodate the numbers of students that can be expected to reside in the project.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>353.3.</num>
    <text>The Board shall refer the application to the D.C. Departments of Transportation and Housing and Community Development for comment and recommendation as to the adequacy of public streets, recreation, and other services to accommodate the residents
      of the project and the relationship of the proposed project to public plans and projects.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>353.4.</num>
    <text>The Board shall refer the application to the D.C. Office of Planning for comment and recommendation on the site plan, arrangement of buildings and structures, and provisions of light, air, parking, recreation, landscaping, and grading as they relate
      to the future residents of the project and the surrounding neighborhood.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>353.5.</num>
    <text>In addition to other filing requirements, the developer shall submit to the Board with the application, four (4) site plans and two (2) sets of typical floor plans and elevations, grading plans (existing and final), landscaping plans, and plans for
      all new rights-of-way and easements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>ยง 3105.42 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8362-63 (October 20,
        2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 3074(April 6, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>