<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-3006</num>
  <heading>EVIDENCE (ยง 11-3006)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3006.1.</num>
    <text>Exhibits may be offered in evidence at the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3006.2.</num>
    <text>Exhibits may be in the form of photographs, models, graphs, or other appropriate visual displays.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3006.3.</num>
    <text>Any exhibit that exceeds a size suitable for inclusion in the record shall be reduced or folded to a size not to exceed legal size of eight and one-half by fourteen inches (81/2 in. x 14 in.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3006.4.</num>
    <text>No material that exceeds legal size shall be submitted for the record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3006.5.</num>
    <text>If models are used, photographs of the models not exceeding legal size shall be supplied at the public hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3006.6.</num>
    <text>The Zoning Act of 1938, the Zoning Regulations (including appendices and the official Zoning Map), and this chapter shall be a part of the record of every proceeding before the Commission, and it shall not be necessary for any party or person formally
      to move their introduction into evidence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3006.7.</num>
    <text>The applicant, a public agency representative, a party, or a person may appear as a witness and offer evidence at a hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3006.8.</num>
    <text>In a contested case under ยง 3022, witnesses may be examined or cross-examined by the Commission, the applicant, or any party so determined by the Commission under this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3006.9.</num>
    <text>In a rulemaking case under ยง 3021, only the Commission may examine witnesses.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3006.10.</num>
    <text>In any case, any authorized representative of any public agency may pose a question to a witness through the presiding officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7855, 7860-61 (October 1, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8539 (October
        20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>