<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-3014</num>
  <heading>NOTICE OF HEARINGS[COLON] GENERAL (§ 11-3014)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3014.1.</num>
    <text>Notice of a hearing pursuant to the rulemaking provisions of § 3021 or the contested case provisions of § 3022, other than a hearing for a § 2523 application, shall be given by:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Publishing notice of the hearing in the D.C. Register at least forty (40) days in advance of the hearing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Posting a copy of the notice of the public hearing in the Office of Zoning at least forty (40) days prior to the hearing; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Providing copies of the notice of the public hearing to the public library system and the appropriate Advisory Neighborhood Commission(s) for posting in appropriate locations. These copies of the notice shall be mailed or delivered at least forty
        (40) days prior to the hearing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.2.</num>
    <text>Each notice shall include a general summary of the application or petition under consideration, and shall state the time and place of the public hearing, the name of the applicant or petitioner, the action of the Commission prayed for, and whether
      the proceedings will be conducted pursuant to §§ 3021 or 3022.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.3.</num>
    <text>For hearings to amend the Zoning Map pursuant to § 3021, the petitioner shall post the street frontage of each square affected by the rezoning proposal with a notice of public hearing. This information shall be posted at least forty (40) days in advance
      of the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.4.</num>
    <text>The notice required by § 3014.3 shall be supplied by the Director of the Office of Zoning showing the:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Calendar number of the petition;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Nature of the petition;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Name of the petitioner;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Property involved; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Location, time, and date of the public hearing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.5.</num>
    <text>The petitioner shall comply with the requirements of §§ 3015.7 through 3015.9 regarding filing of a sworn affidavit and maintenance of the posting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3014.6.</num>
    <text>The Commission may give any additional notice of the hearing, including notice in the manner prescribed in § 3015, as it deems necessary or appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7855, 7868 (October 1, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8544 (October
        20, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking and Order No. 09-10 published at 57 DCR 3487 (April 23, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>