<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-3305</num>
  <heading>PREFERRED USE REQUIREMENTS (§ 11-3305)
    <text>Preferred uses shall include any use within the Arts, Design &amp; Creation; Food#038; Alcohol Services; Retail; or Service use categories described in §303.1.</text>
    <text>Each building that faces the following streets or locations in the followingubdistricts shall devote not less than fifty percent (50%) of the gross floorrea of the ground floor to preferred uses:</text>
    <text>StE-3, facing Martin Luther King Jr. Avenue S.E., Cypress Street S.E., orycamore Street S.E., and the park;</text>
    <text>StE-7, facing Martin Luther King Jr. Avenue S.E., Cypress Street S.E., orogwood Drive S.E., or Oak Drive S.E.;</text>
    <text>StE-14b, facing Dogwood Drive S.E., Oak Drive S.E., or the southwest corner;</text>
    <text>StE-15, facing Dogwood Drive S.E., 13th Street S.E., Oak Drive S.E., or theark;</text>
    <text>StE-16, facing 13th Street S.E. and the southwest corner; and</text>
    <text>StE-17, facing Dogwood Drive S.E., 13th Street S.E., or Oak Drive S.E.</text>
    <text>Not less than fifty percent (50%) of the surface area of the street wall,ncluding building entrances, of those building frontages described in § 3305.2hall be devoted to doors or display windows having clear or low emissivitylass.</text>
    <text>Preferred uses shall provide direct, exterior access to the ground level.</text>
    <text>The minimum floor-to-ceiling height for portions of the ground floor levelevoted to preferred uses shall be fourteen feet (14 ft.).</text>
    <text>Ground floor area required for preferred uses may not be transferred to anyther lot through the Combined Lot Development procedures of § 3307.</text>
    <text>For good cause shown, the Board of Zoning Adjustment may authorize interimccupancy of the preferred use space required under § 3305.2 by other usesermitted in the StE District for up to a five (5) year period, provided that:</text>
    <text>The ground-floor space is suitably designed for future occupancy by preferredses;</text>
    <text>The proposed use is compatible with the surrounding uses; and</text>
    <text>It can be demonstrated that a preferred use cannot be accommodated due to marketonditions.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 4834 (March 29, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>