<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-3021</num>
  <heading>RULEMAKING HEARINGS (§ 11-3021)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3021.1.</num>
    <text>The rules of procedure in this section shall apply to rulemaking proceedings, including petitions for amendments to the text of the Zoning Regulations pursuant to § 102 and to certain applications for a change in the Zoning Maps of the District designated
      by the Commission pursuant to § 3010.7 as coming within the Commission&amp;#8217;s rulemaking power.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3021.2.</num>
    <text>The rules in this section shall supplement the rules in §§ 3010, 3011, 3013, 3014, 3015, 3020, and 3024.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3021.3.</num>
    <text>Any person may appear at a hearing in a rulemaking proceeding, and may present, within the time limits determined by the Commission, evidence, testimony, or argument that is relevant and not unduly repetitious.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3021.4.</num>
    <text>No person shall have the standing of a party in a rulemaking proceeding.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3021.5.</num>
    <text>The order of procedure at the hearing shall be as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Call to order and opening statement by the presiding officer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Introductory statement by Commission staff;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Consideration of pending motions and procedural matters;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Applicant&amp;#8217;s or petitioner&amp;#8217;s case;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Reports or statements by the Office of Planning and other public agency representatives;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Affected Advisory Neighborhood Commissions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Persons in support of the application or petition; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Persons in opposition to the application or petition.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7855, 7873 (October 1, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8546 (October
        20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>