<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-3302</num>
  <heading>PURPOSES (§ 11-3302)
    <text>The StE District is intended to provide for the development of this site with aix of uses, achieved through the adaptive reuse of existing buildings as wells new construction.</text>
    <text>The StE District is intended to provide for a broad mix of uses, includingesidential, commercial, hospitality, educational, and civic uses consistentith the Master Plan, with a target of approximately four million two hundredhousand (4,200,000) square
      feet of development, exclusive of the StE-2, StE-18,nd StE-19 subdistricts and specified above-grade parking.</text>
    <text>The purposes of the StE District are to:</text>
    <text>Improve community connectivity and access to and through the campus;</text>
    <text>Enhance the unique and historic identity of the campus;</text>
    <text>Reinvigorate the campus as an important neighborhood center;</text>
    <text>Preserve and adaptively reuse the historic resources;</text>
    <text>Embody the District’s design and sustainability goals;</text>
    <text>Create a safe public realm and enhanced pedestrian experience;</text>
    <text>Enhance multi-modal transportation networks;</text>
    <text>Support wider economic development initiatives; and</text>
    <text>Ensure a parking supply that meets the needs of the St Elizabeths site whileinimizing impacts on surrounding neighborhoods and incurring acceptable impactsn the surrounding road network.</text>
    <text>Land Use and Urban Design principles for the StE District include:</text>
    <text>Create a safe environment by providing for a mix of uses and open spaces thatre capable of being programmed to ensure vitality and social activity;</text>
    <text>Create a desirable development opportunity by providing for flexibility in usesnd appropriate building heights and densities;</text>
    <text>Provide street-activating uses such as retail on the ground floor of buildingslong designated public streets;</text>
    <text>Recognize the unique and historic characteristics of the site and provide forhe appropriate reuse of the historic buildings and new development that willespect the site’s historic nature;</text>
    <text>Design and site new development sensitively to preserve existing gateways,istas, and campus landmarks;</text>
    <text>Create focal points to help establish a unique sense of place and orientation;</text>
    <text>Provide for significant open space, including community parks, plazas, andatural open space on the site;</text>
    <text>Provide for the preservation of the existing ravine within subdistrict StE-19 ints current, natural state; and</text>
    <text>Promote the use of best practice environmental and stormwater management design.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 4834 (March 29, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>