<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-3115</num>
  <heading>ADVISORY NEIGHBORHOOD COMMISSIONS[COLON] REPORTS AND NOTICE (§ 11-3115)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3115.1.</num>
    <text>The written report of the ANC prepared in response to a notice of application provided pursuant to § 3115.5 shall be submitted to the Board at least seven (7) days in advance of the hearing and shall contain the following information:</text>
    <text>An identification of the appeal or application;</text>
    <text>When the public meeting of the ANC to consider the appeal or application was held;</text>
    <text>Whether proper notice of that meeting was given by the ANC;</text>
    <text>The number of members of the ANC that constitute a quorum and the number of members present at the meeting;</text>
    <text>The issues and concerns of the ANC about the appeal or application as related to the standards of the Zoning Regulations against which the appeal or application must be judged;</text>
    <text>The recommendation, if any, of the ANC as to the disposition of the appeal or application;</text>
    <text>The vote on the motion to adopt the report to the Board;</text>
    <text>The name of the person authorized by the ANC to present the report; and</text>
    <text>The signature of the ANC chairperson or vice-chairperson.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3115.2.</num>
    <text>The Board shall give &amp;#8220;great weight&amp;#8221; to the written report of the ANC, as required by § 3 of the Comprehensive Advisory Neighborhood Commissions Reform Amendment Act of 2000, effective June 27, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-135, 47 DCR 5519
      (2000) (codified at D.C. Official Code § 1-309.10(d)(3)(A)(2001).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3115.3.</num>
    <text>In the event the ANC submits its report on the basis of understandings, agreements, or meetings with the appellant or applicant that later are modified by the appellant or applicant, the designated ANC representative may comment orally concerning
      the specific inconsistencies. No other new matters may be presented orally by the designated ANC representative.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3115.4.</num>
    <text>Any notice required by D.C. Official Code § 1-309.10(c)(4) to be provided to affected Advisory Neighborhood Commissions, the Commissioner representing the affected single member district, and the Office of Advisory Neighborhood Commissions (“notice
      recipients”) may be provided by electronic or first-class mail; provided, that the notice shall be by first-class mail unless a notice recipient agrees in writing to receive future notifications through electronic mail.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3115.5.</num>
    <text>A notice of an application shall constitute the notice required by D.C. Official Code § 1-309.10(b) and starts the time period for the affected Commission to review the application and submit its written report pursuant to D.C. Official Code §1-309.10(d).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7853, 7905-06 (October 1, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8565 (October
        20, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 9736, 9737 (October 15, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>