<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-350</num>
  <heading>R-5 DISTRICTS[COLON] GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 11-350)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>350.1.</num>
    <text>The R-5 Districts are General ResidenceDistricts designed to permit flexibility of design by permitting ina single district, except as provided in Â§Â§350 through 361, all types of urban residential development if theyconform to the height, density,
      and area requirements establishedfor these districts under chapter 4 of this title. The R-5Districts shall also permit the construction of those institutionaland semi-public buildings that would be compatible with adjoiningresidential uses and that
      are excluded from the more restrictiveResidence Districts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>350.2.</num>
    <text>The R-5 Districts are subdivided intoR-5-A, R-5-B, R-5-C, R-5-D, and R-5-E Districts. In R-5-ADistricts, only a low height and density shall be permitted; inR-5-B, a moderate height and density shall be permitted; in R-5-C,a medium height and density
      shall be permitted; and in R-5-D andR-5-E, a relatively high height and medium-high density shall bepermitted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>350.3.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in chapters 20 through25 of this title, in any R-5 District, no building or premisesshall be used and no building shall be erected or altered that isarranged, intended, or designed to be used except for one (1) ormore of the uses
      listed in Â§Â§ 350 through361.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>350.4.</num>
    <text>The following uses shall be permitted as amatter of right in an R-5 District: (a) Any use permitted in theR-4 District subject to the requirements of Â§ 353; (b)Child/Elderly development center or adult day treatment facility inR-5-D and R-5-E Districts;
      provided, that the center shall belimited to no more than twenty-five (25) individuals; (c) FireDepartment Support Facility, communications services only; (d)Greenhouse or horticultural nursery; (e) Hotel, only in R-5-B,R-5-C, R-5-D, or R-5-E Districts,
      in existence as of May 16, 1980,with a valid Certificate of Occupancy or a valid application for abuilding permit; provided, that the gross floor area of the hotelmay not be increased and the total area within the hotel devoted tofunction rooms,
      exhibit space, and commercial adjuncts may not beincreased. An existing hotel may be repaired, renovated, remodeled,or structurally altered; (f) Multiple dwellings, subject to therequirements of Â§ 353; provided, that in an apartmenthouse, accommodations
      may be provided only to residents who stay atthe premises a minimum of one (1) month; (g) Recreation building,park, playground, swimming pool, athletic field, ice rink, or othersimilar athletic facility, public or private, operated on and usinglocal
      or federal land and approved by a joint federal-localjurisdictional transfer agreement; subject to the following: Nopart of any use is nearer than seventy feet (70 ft.) to the nearestresidential structure;Â The uses shall not be organized forprofit;
      All parking areas shall be shared by all uses on a lot;Scoreboards shall be installed such that the highest point is notaller than twenty-five feet (25 ft.) above grade; and Any lightingused to illuminate a park, playground, athletic field, trail
      orother outdoor space, shall be so arranged that all direct rays oflighting are confined to the boundaries of the lot;Â (h)Residence for teachers or staff of private schools; (i) Temporarysurface parking lot accessory to the Ballpark shall be permitted
      onSquare 882 in accordance with Â§ 2110. In the event thatthe cumulative parking limit established in Â§ 2110.1(a)is met, additional temporary surface parking spaces accessory tothe Ballpark on Square 882 shall be permitted as a specialexception
      use if approved by the Board of Zoning Adjustmentpursuant to Â§ 2110.2; and (j) Youth residential carehome, community residence facility, or health care facility forseven (7) to fifteen (15) persons, not including residentsupervisors or staff and
      their families; provided, that there is noproperty containing an existing community-based residentialfacility for seven (7) or more persons either in the same square orwithin a radius of five hundred feet (500 ft.) from any portion ofthe subject
      property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>350.5.</num>
    <text>A parking garage on an alley lot sorecorded on the records of the Surveyor, District of Columbia, orrecorded on the records of the D.C. Office of Tax and Revenue, onor before November 1, 1957, shall be permitted as a matter of rightin an R-5 District;
      provided: (a) No part of the garage shall belocated within seventy-five feet (75 ft.) of any building line; and(b) Vehicular entrances and exits shall open directly onto analley.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>350.6.</num>
    <text>A chancery is a permitted use in R-5-D orR-5-E Districts, subject to disapproval by the Board of ZoningAdjustment in accordance with the requirements of chapter 10 ofthis title. SOURCE: Â§Â§ 3105.1, 3105.2, 3105.3of the Zoning Regulations, effective
      May 12, 1958; as amended: byFinal Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 2066, 2068 (May 16, 1980);Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 3482, 3496 (August 7, 1981);Final Rulemaking published at 29 DCR 4913, 4919 (November 5, 1982);Final Rulemaking published
      at 30 DCR 3270, 3271 (July 1, 1983);Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 7625, 7626 (November 3. 1989);Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 8305 (November 13, 1992);Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 726 (January 22, 1993); FinalRulemaking published
      at 46 DCR 8284 8288 (October 15, 1999); FinalRulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000),incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemakingpublished at 47 DCR 8335, 8361-62 (October 20, 2000); as amended byFinal Rulemaking
      published at 52 DCR 9155(October 14, 2005); asamended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 10085(December 22,2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR3074(April 6, 2007); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54DCR 8980(September
      14, 2007); as amended by Notice of FinalRulemaking published at 58 DCR 7820, 7821 (September 2,2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>