<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-510</num>
  <heading>ACCESSORY PARKING SPACES (SP) (ยง 11-510)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>510.1.</num>
    <text>Accessory parking spaces elsewhere than on the same lot or part of the lot on which any principal SP use is permitted, except for a one-family dwelling, when the parking spaces will be established within the square in which the principal use is located,
      shall be permitted in an SP District if approved by the Board of Zoning Adjustment as a special exception under ยง 3104, subject to the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>510.2.</num>
    <text>[DELETED]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>510.3.</num>
    <text>The total number of parking spaces provided for the principal use shall not exceed the minimum number of spaces required for the principal use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>510.4.</num>
    <text>It shall be considered economically impracticable or unsafe to locate the parking spaces within the principal building or on the same lot on which the building or use is permitted because of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Strip zoning or shallow zoning depth;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Restricted size of lot caused by adverse adjoining ownership or substantial improvements adjoining or on the lot;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Unusual topography, grades, shape, size, or dimensions of the lot;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The lack of an alley or the lack of appropriate ingress or egress through existing or proposed alleys or streets; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Traffic hazards caused by unusual street grades or other conditions.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>510.5.</num>
    <text>The parking spaces shall be located and all facilities in relation to the parking spaces shall be designed so that they are not likely to become objectionable to adjoining or nearby property because of noise, traffic, or other objectionable conditions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>ยง 4101.46 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8374 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>