<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-505</num>
  <heading>PARKING LOTS (SP) (ยง 11-505)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>505.1.</num>
    <text>A parking lot in existence on October 5, 1978, under approval by the Board of Zoning Adjustment, may be permitted by the Board to continue in existence for a period not to exceed twenty (20) years from the date of expiration of the Certificate of
      Occupancy in effect on October 5, 1978, if approved by the Board as a special exception under ยง 3104, subject to the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>505.2.</num>
    <text>[DELETED]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>505.3.</num>
    <text>Each application shall be referred to the National Capital Planning Commission for review and comment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>505.4.</num>
    <text>Each parking lot shall be located and all facilities of the lot shall be designed so that they are not likely to become objectionable to adjoining and nearby property because of noise, traffic, or other objectionable conditions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>505.5.</num>
    <text>The present character and future development of the neighborhood shall not be affected adversely by the use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>505.6.</num>
    <text>The parking facility shall serve either residential uses or provide short-term parking for retail, service, and public facility uses, but shall not provide all-day commuter parking.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>505.7.</num>
    <text>The Board shall not have authority under this section to approve the establishment of any new parking lot.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE ยง 4101,41 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by:</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 2570 (September 22, 1978); Final Rulemaking published at 30 DCR 2110 (May 5, 1983); Final Rulemaking published at 32 DCR 6890 (November 29, 1985); Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 6369 (October 5, 1990);
        and Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8373 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>