<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-501</num>
  <heading>USES AS A MATTER OF RIGHT (SP) (§ 11-501)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>501.1.</num>
    <text>The following uses shall be permitted as a matter of right in an SP District:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Any use permitted in any R-5 District under §§ 350.4 and 350.5, except a hotel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Antenna, subject to the standards and procedure which apply pursuant chapter 27 of this title;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Art gallery;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Car-sharing spaces, none of which may be a required parking space for any use on site;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Child/Elderly development center; or adult day treatment facility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Community center building;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Driver&amp;#8217;s License Road Test Facility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Park, playground, swimming pool, or athletic field operated by a local community organization;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Police Department General Facility, except as provided in § 504;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Private school, including kindergarten, elementary, secondary, trade, or any other school;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Public School, subject to the provisions of chapter 21 of this title;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Religious reading room; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Ticket office.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.2.</num>
    <text>An artist studio shall be permitted as a matter of right in an SP District, subject to the following criteria:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>All operations and storage of materials shall occur inside the building;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Sales of art work produced by the occupants of the studio shall be permitted within the studio; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The artist may teach the art to one or more persons.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.3.</num>
    <text>General office use, including chancery, shall be permitted in an SP District as a replacement for office use for international organization, non-profit organization, labor union, architect, dentist, doctor, engineer, lawyer, or similar professional
      person existing and approved by the Board of Zoning Adjustment or the Zoning Commission or authorized by a validly issued certificate of occupancy prior to January 29, 1999.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE § 4101.3 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958, as added by Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 2757 (September 22, 1981); amended by:</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 29 DCR 4913, 4919 (November 5, 1982); Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 465 (January 22, 1988); Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 812 (January 29, 1999); and Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December
        8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8372, 8378 (October 20, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4778 (May 7, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52
        DCR 7259 (August 5, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 9580 (December 1, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 10085 (December 22, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 0034 (January
        4, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking and Order No. 09-16 published at 57 DCR 2961 (April 2, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>