<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-606</num>
  <heading>HOSPITALS AND CLINICS (CR) (ยง 11-606)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>606.1.</num>
    <text>Hospital or clinic use shall be permitted in a CR District as a special exception when authorized by the Board of Zoning Adjustment under ยง 3104, if the Board considers that this use is appropriate in furthering the objectives of the CR Districts,
      subject to the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>606.2.</num>
    <text>The hospital or clinic use shall be located so that it is not likely to become objectionable to surrounding and nearby property because of noise, traffic, or parking.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>606.3.</num>
    <text>There shall be a demonstrated need for the facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>606.4.</num>
    <text>The applicant shall submit to the Board a detailed plan for the hospital or clinic and accessory facilities, showing the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Location, height, and bulk of all improvements, including but not limited to buildings, parking and loading facilities, screening, signs, and public utility facilities; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A description of the activities to be carried on at the hospital or clinic, including the capacities of the various facilities within the hospital or clinic.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>606.5.</num>
    <text>Before taking final action on an application for hospital or clinic use, the Board shall refer the application to the D.C. Office of Planning for coordination, review, and report, including review and report by the Department of Human Services on
      the need for the facility as well as the specific design of the facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>606.6.</num>
    <text>The report of the D.C. Office of Planning shall include the reports and recommendations of the D.C. Department of Transportation, as well as other departments and agencies of the District of Columbia government as appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>606.7.</num>
    <text>[DELETED]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>ยง 4502.31 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8381-82 (October 20,
        2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>