<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-609</num>
  <heading>BOWLING ALLEYS (CR) (ยง 11-609)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>609.1.</num>
    <text>Use as a bowling alley shall be permitted in a CR District as a special exception when authorized by the Board of Zoning Adjustment under ยง 3104, if the Board considers that this use is appropriate in furthering the objectives of the CR Districts,
      subject to the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>609.2.</num>
    <text>Bowling alley use shall not be within twenty-five feet (25 ft.) of a Residence District unless separated from such district by a street or alley.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>609.3.</num>
    <text>Soundproofing to the extent deemed necessary for the protection of adjoining and nearby property shall be required.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>609.4.</num>
    <text>Accessory off-street parking spaces shall be required as for places of public assembly as provided in ยง 2101.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>609.5.</num>
    <text>Before taking final action on an application for bowling alley use, the Board shall refer the application to the D.C. Office of Planning for coordination, review, and report.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>609.6.</num>
    <text>The report of the D.C. Office of Planning shall include the reports and recommendations of the D.C. Department of Transportation, and of other departments and agencies of the District of Columbia as appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>609.7.</num>
    <text>The Board may impose requirements pertaining to design, appearance, screening, lighting, additional off-street parking spaces, signs, or any other requirements it deems necessary for the protection of neighboring or adjacent property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>ยง 4502.34 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 6585, 6586 (December 28, 1984); and Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text
        of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8382 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>