<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-614</num>
  <heading>VEHICLE SALES OR REPAIR (CR) (ยง 11-614)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>614.1.</num>
    <text>Use for automobile or motorcycle sales or repair shall be permitted in a CR District as a special exception when authorized by the Board of Zoning Adjustment under ยง 3104, if the Board considers that this use is appropriate in furthering the objectives
      of the CR Districts, subject to the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>614.2.</num>
    <text>Use for vehicle sales or repair shall be located so that it is not objectionable to other uses on the same or neighboring property because of noise, fumes, or other conditions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>614.3.</num>
    <text>Use for vehicle sales or repair shall not result in dangerous or otherwise objectionable traffic conditions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>614.4.</num>
    <text>The use for vehicle sales or repair, and all its accessory facilities, including automobile storage, shall be located within a building.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>614.5.</num>
    <text>No portion of a building use for vehicle sales or repair shall be used within fifty feet (50 ft.) of a Residence District or Special Purpose District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>614.6.</num>
    <text>The Board may impose additional requirements pertaining to location of buildings or other structures, entrances, exits, or soundproofing, or other requirements as the Board deems necessary to protect adjacent or nearby property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>614.7.</num>
    <text>Before taking final action on an application for use for vehicle sales or repair, the Board shall refer the application to the D.C. Office of Planning for coordination, review, and report.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>614.8.</num>
    <text>The report of the D.C. Office of Planning shall include the reports and recommendations of the D.C. Department of Transportation, and of other departments and agencies of the District of Columbia as appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>ยง 4502.39 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8384 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>