<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-768</num>
  <heading>BONUS INCENTIVE PROCEDURES (C-5 (PAD)) (§ 11-768)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>768.1.</num>
    <text>Application, review, and award under the Bonus Incentive System shall be made to the Board of Zoning Adjustment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>768.2.</num>
    <text>The Board shall process the application in accordance with its normal rules of procedure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>768.3.</num>
    <text>Application shall be filed with the Board, which shall include the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A statement describing the amenity to be provided and the bonus requested, including a detailed statement showing how the application meets the requirements of regulations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A finished site plan showing the location and external dimensions of all buildings and other structures, utilities and other easements, walkways, driveways, plazas, planting, and any other open space;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A landscape plan showing all existing contour lines and landscaping to be retained and all new contours, planting, and landscaping;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A circulation plan, including pedestrian and vehicular access ways and areas devoted to parking and loading;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Floor plan of the level upon which a bonus element is proposed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Architectural elevations for all open sides of the proposed building;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A computation of gross floor area and floor area ratio of the proposed bonus element; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>A development schedule for the total site showing:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Total lot area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Total floor area ratio;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Gross floor area devoted to each use;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Total number of type of residential uses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Total number of off-street parking spaces; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Total number of off-street loading berths.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>768.4.</num>
    <text>The Board shall review the application made under the Bonus Incentive System and may award additional square feet in an amount not to exceed the limitations in § 762.4, applying the criteria in §§ 763 through 767; provided, that the requirements of
      §§ 768.5 through 768.9 shall be met.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>768.5.</num>
    <text>The application shall be consistent with the intent and purpose of the C-5 (PAD) District and encourage improved pedestrian circulation and activities, mixture of uses, and more attractive urban design.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>768.6.</num>
    <text>The application shall have received the approval of the Pennsylvania Avenue Development Corporation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>768.7.</num>
    <text>The proposed development under a bonus award shall not significantly and adversely impact upon adjoining property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>768.8.</num>
    <text>Upon receiving an application for an approval under § 768.4, the Board shall submit the application to the D.C. Office of Planning for coordination, review, report, and impact assessment, along with review in writing of all relevant District of Columbia
      departments and agencies including the Departments of Transportation and Housing and Community Development, and, if a historic district or historic landmark is involved, the State Historic Preservation Officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>768.9.</num>
    <text>The Board of Zoning Adjustment may require other special conditions as it deems necessary to protect neighboring or adjacent property and to generally promote the public health, safety, and welfare.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 24 DCR 10769, 10784 (June 16, 1978); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8408-09 (October
        20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>