<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-744</num>
  <heading>SEXUALLY-ORIENTED BUSINESSES (C-3) (§ 11-744)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>744.1.</num>
    <text>A sexually-oriented business establishment shall be permitted in C-3-C Districts as a special exception only if approved by the Board of Zoning Adjustment under § 3104, subject to the requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>744.2.</num>
    <text>No portion of the establishment shall be located within six hundred feet (600 ft.) of a Residence or Special Purpose District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>744.3.</num>
    <text>No portion of the establishment shall be located within six hundred feet (600 ft.) of a church, school, library, playground, or the area under the jurisdiction of the Commission of Fine Arts pursuant to the Shipstead-Luce Act, approved May 16, 1930
      (46 Stat. 366, as amended; D.C. Official Code § 6-611.01 (formerly codified at D.C. Code § 5-410 (1994 Repl.))).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>744.4.</num>
    <text>No portion of the establishment shall be located within three hundred feet (300 ft.) of any other sexually-oriented business establishment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>744.5.</num>
    <text>There shall be no display of goods or services visible from the exterior of the premises.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>744.6.</num>
    <text>The establishment shall be compatible with other uses in the area.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>744.7.</num>
    <text>The use shall not become objectionable because of its effect on the character of the neighborhood or because of noise, traffic, or other conditions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>744.8.</num>
    <text>The establishment shall not have an adverse impact on religious, educational, or governmental facilities located in the area.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§ 5103.47 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 24 DCR 5144, 5156 (December 16, 1977); and Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text
        of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8402 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>