<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-765</num>
  <heading>THROUGH SQUARE CONNECTION CRITERIA (C-5 (PAD)) (ยง 11-765)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>765.1.</num>
    <text>Where a through square connection is provided in the C-5 (PAD) District, the space created within the square as the connection shall meet the criteria of this section before additional gross square feet shall be awarded increasing the gross floor
      area of the building as specified in ยง 762.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>765.2.</num>
    <text>The exterior entrances of a through square connection shall be at the same level as the street it adjoins.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>765.3.</num>
    <text>A through square connection may be enclosed in whole or in part and shall have an average width of at least twenty feet (20 ft.), but at no point shall the width be less than fifteen feet (15 ft.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>765.4.</num>
    <text>A through square connection shall have a minimum height of twenty feet (20 ft.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>765.5.</num>
    <text>Except for a building or other structure occupying a through lot or corner lot bounded by three (3) streets, no bonus incentive for a through square connection shall be awarded unless the Board of Zoning Adjustment has determined that the requirement
      of a continuous connection through the square can be accomplished.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>765.6.</num>
    <text>In the C-5 (PAD) District, a through square connection shall only be permitted between two (2) parallel or opposite streets.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>765.7.</num>
    <text>A through square connection shall be appropriately lighted and open to the public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>765.8.</num>
    <text>A through square connection may contain ornamental fountains, sculptures, displays, or kiosks; provided, that pedestrian circulation shall be barrier-free and shall not be hampered by the features.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>765.9.</num>
    <text>Only retail and service uses shall be provided along the through square connection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>765.10.</num>
    <text>A through square connection may be created by linking one (1) or more of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Open arcade;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Portico;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Plaza;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Interior space or lobby of a building;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Court;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Rear yard;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Side yard; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Enclosed pedestrian space.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>765.11.</num>
    <text>The floor areas of the features listed in ยง 765.10 shall not be included in computing the floor area of the through square connection for determining the bonus incentive award under ยง 762.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 24 DCR 10769, 10782 (June 6, 1978); Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8407-08 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>