<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-763</num>
  <heading>OPEN ARCADE CRITERIA (C-5 (PAD)) (ยง 11-763)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>763.1.</num>
    <text>Where an open arcade is provided, it shall meet the criteria of this section to qualify for the award of the bonus specified in ยง 762.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>763.2.</num>
    <text>An open arcade for its entire length shall be along the perimeter of a building and shall adjoin a street.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>763.3.</num>
    <text>An open arcade shall also be open to the street it adjoins, except for structural piers, columns, or arches.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>763.4.</num>
    <text>An open arcade shall have an unobstructed and continuous passageway for its entire length of no less than ten feet (10 ft.) in width at any point.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>763.5.</num>
    <text>An open arcade shall be no less than fifteen feet (15 ft.) in height at any point within the arcade.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>763.6.</num>
    <text>An open arcade shall have its floor at the same level and continuous with the sidewalks, and shall connect to existing adjoining open arcades or shall be constructed to permit the connection in the future.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>763.7.</num>
    <text>The use of the area within an open arcade shall be restricted essentially to pedestrian uses. Vehicular access to or through an open arcade shall be minimized.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>763.8.</num>
    <text>An open arcade shall have retail and service uses fronting on it, with those uses directly accessible from the open arcade and the adjoining street.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>763.9.</num>
    <text>The floor area bonus awarded for the provision of an open arcade shall be computed on the basis of the floor area embraced within the boundary of the open arcade.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>763.10.</num>
    <text>Where vehicular access is permitted across an open arcade, that portion of the open arcade used as vehicular access space shall be excluded from the computation of the floor area of the open arcade for the purpose of determining the bonus incentive
      award under ยง 762.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 24 DCR 10769, 10781 (June 16, 1978); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8407 (October
        20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>