<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-741</num>
  <heading>USES AS A MATTER OF RIGHT (C-3) (§ 11-741)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>741.1.</num>
    <text>Any use permitted in C-2 Districts under § 721 shall be permitted in a C-3 District as a matter of right.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>741.2.</num>
    <text>In addition to the uses permitted in C-2 Districts by § 721.1, the following service establishments shall be permitted in a C-3 District as a matter of right:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Amusement enterprise, including penny arcade or shooting gallery;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Laundry or dry cleaning establishment, not exceeding five thousand square feet (5,000 ft.2) of gross floor area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Gasoline service station as an accessory use to a mechanical parking garage, subject to the conditions for the accessory use in § 701.1(i); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Printing, lithographing, or photoengraving establishment, with no limitation on gross floor area.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>741.3.</num>
    <text>In addition to the uses permitted in C-2 Districts by § 721.3, the following retail establishments shall be permitted in a C-3 District as a matter of right:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Motorcycle sales and repair, only in C-3-C Districts; provided:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The use and all its accessory facilities shall be located within a building; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>No portion of a building used for motorcycle sales or repair shall be located within fifty feet (50 ft.) of a Residence or Special Purpose District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any establishment that has as a principal use the administration of massages, only in C-3-C Districts; provided, that no portion of the establishment shall be located within two hundred feet (200 ft.) of a Residence District; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Fast food establishment or food delivery service; provided, that in a C-3-A District, no part of the lot on which the use is located shall be within twenty- five feet (25 ft.) of a Residence District, unless separated therefrom by a street or alley.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>741.4.</num>
    <text>Other service or retail use similar to that allowed in §§ 741.2 and 741.3 shall be permitted in a C-3 District, including assemblage and repair clearly incidental to the conduct of a permitted service or retail establishment on the premises.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>741.5.</num>
    <text>The following uses shall also be permitted as a matter of right in a C-3 District:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Mechanical parking garage, only in C-3-C Districts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Public swimming pool; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Community-based residential facility.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Temporary surface parking lot accessory to the Ballpark shall be permitted on Square 769, Lot 21 and those portions of Lots 18 and 20 within the C-3-C District, in accordance with § 2110.1 (a). In the event that the cumulative parking limit established
        in § 2110.1 (b) is met, additional temporary surface parking spaces accessory to the Ballpark on Square 769, Lot 21 and those portions of Lots 18 and 20 within the C-3-C District, shall be permitted as a special exception if approved by the Board
        of Zoning Adjustment pursuant to § 2110.2.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>741.6.</num>
    <text>[Deleted]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>741.7.</num>
    <text>[Deleted]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>741.8.</num>
    <text>Electronic Equipment Facility (EEF) use under either or both of the following circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The EEF use occupies no more than twenty-five percent (25%) of the above ground constructed gross floor area of the building; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The EEF use is located below ground floor.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE § 5103.31 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by: Final Rulemaking published at 22 DCR 1901, 1902 (October 14, 1975); Final Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 2066, 2071 (May 16, 1980); Final Rulemaking published at
        27 DCR 2226, 2228 (May 23, 1980); Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 3482, 3505 (August 7, 1981); Final Rulemaking at 32 DCR 4374, 4377 (July 26, 1985); Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 7499 (December 20, 1985); Final Rulemaking published
        at 36 DCR 1509, 1517 (February 24, 1989); Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 3744, 3747 (June 11, 1993); Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at
        47 DCR 8335, 8399-8400 (October 20, 2000); Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 9830, 9832 (October 26, 2001); Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 1655 (February 22, 2002), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published
        at 48 DCR 11159, 11160 (December 7, 2001); as amended by: Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 8976 (September 14, 2007); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 9393 (September 28, 2007);as amended by:</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at January 4, 2008 (55 DCR 34).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>