<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-739</num>
  <heading>ANIMAL SHELTER (C-2) (ยง 11-739)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>739.1.</num>
    <text>An animal shelter may be permitted as a special exception if approved by the Board of Zoning Adjustment under ยง3104, subject to the requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>739.2.</num>
    <text>The animal shelter shall be located and designed to create no objectionable condition to adjacent properties resulting from animal noise, odor, or waste.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>739.3.</num>
    <text>The animal shelter shall utilize industry standard sound-absorbing materials, such as acoustical floor and ceiling panels, acoustical concrete and masonry, and acoustical landscaping.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>739.4.</num>
    <text>All animal waste shall be placed in closed waste disposal containers and shall utilize a qualified waste disposal company to collect and dispose of all animal waste at least weekly. Odor shall be controlled by means of an air filtration system or
      an equivalently effective odor control system.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>739.5.</num>
    <text>The animal shelter shall not abut an existing residential use or a Residence District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>739.6.</num>
    <text>External yards or other external facilities for the keeping of animals shall not be permitted unless the entire yard is located a minimum of two hundred (200) feet from an existing residential use or Residence District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>739.7.</num>
    <text>The Board may impose additional requirements as it deems necessary to protect adjacent or nearby properties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 8943 (September 14, 2007), as corrected by Errata Notice published at 58 DCR 4314 (May 20, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>