<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-906</num>
  <heading>HOSPITALS AND CLINICS (W-1, W-2, AND W-3) (ยง 11-906)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>906.1.</num>
    <text>If the Board of Zoning Adjustment considers that it is appropriate in furthering the objectives of the Waterfront District, a hospital or clinic shall be permitted as a special exception in the W-1, W-2, and W-3 Districts when authorized by the Board
      under ยง 3104, subject to the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>906.2.</num>
    <text>The facility shall be designed to enhance the visual and recreational opportunities offered by the Waterfront.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>906.3.</num>
    <text>The facility shall be located so that it is not likely to become objectionable to surrounding and nearby property because of noise, traffic, or parking.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>906.4.</num>
    <text>There shall be a demonstrated need for the facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>906.5.</num>
    <text>The applicant shall submit to the Board a detailed plan for the hospital or clinic and accessory facilities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>906.6.</num>
    <text>The plan required in ยง 906.5 shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Location, height, and bulk of all improvements, but not limited to buildings, parking, and loading facilities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Screening, signs, and public utility facilities; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A description of the activities to be carried on at the hospital or clinic, including the capacities of the various facilities within the hospital or clinic.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>906.7.</num>
    <text>Before taking final action on an application for use as a hospital or clinic, the Board shall refer the application to the D.C. Office of Planning for coordination, review, and report. The application shall include reports and recommendations from
      all appropriate District agencies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>ยง 4402.31 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8431 (October 20, 2000);
        as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 3440 (April 2, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 6358 (July 8, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>