<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-935</num>
  <heading>COURTS (W) (ยง 11-935)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>935.1.</num>
    <text>Where a court is provided in a Waterfront District, the court shall have the following minimum dimensions:</text>
    <text>STRUCTURE</text>
    <text>MINIMUM WIDTH OFOPEN COURT</text>
    <text>MINIMUM WIDTH AND AREAOF CLOSED COURT</text>
    <text>Residential building</text>
    <text>4 in. per foot of height;</text>
    <text>Width: 4 in. per foot of height;</text>
    <text>Minimum: 10 ft.</text>
    <text>Minimum: 15 ft.</text>
    <text>Area: 2 x square of required width;</text>
    <text>Minimum: 350 ft.2</text>
    <text>Hotel and but</text>
    <text>3 in. per foot of height;</text>
    <text>Same as above</text>
    <text>Minimum: 10 ft.</text>
    <text>Other structure</text>
    <text>21/2 in. per foot of height;</text>
    <text>Width: 21/2 in. pr foot of height;</text>
    <text>Minimum: 6 ft.</text>
    <text>Area: 2 x square of required width;</text>
    <text>Minimum: 250 ft.2</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>935.2.</num>
    <text>In the case of a building devoted to both residential and nonresidential uses, the minimum width and area of a court shall be computed as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>When the residential and nonresidential uses are located on different floors of the building, the width and area requirements shall be computed for each use at the plane of each floor of the building; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>When the residential and nonresidential uses are located on the same floor of the building, the width and area requirements for that plane shall be computed based on the requirements for a residential building in ยง 936.1.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>935.3.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, &amp;#8220;residential building&amp;#8221; shall include dwellings, flats, multiple dwellings, rooming and boarding houses, hospitals, and community-based residential facilities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>935.4.</num>
    <text>No required opening for the admission of light and natural ventilation shall open onto a court niche where the ratio between the width and depth of the court niche is less than two to one (2:1).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>935.5.</num>
    <text>No portion of a court niche shall be further than three feet (3 ft.) from a point where the court niche is less than three feet (3 ft.) wide.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>ยง 4406.4 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 6585, 6586 (December 28, 1984); and Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text
        of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8435 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>