<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-915</num>
  <heading>MISCELLANEOUS USES (W-1, W-2, AND W-3) (§ 11-915)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>915.1.</num>
    <text>If the Board of Zoning Adjustment considers that they are appropriate in furthering the objectives of the Waterfront District, other uses not specified in §§ 902, 906 through 914, and 916 shall be permitted as special exceptions in the W-1, W-2, and
      W-3 Districts when authorized by the Board under § 3104, subject to the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>915.2.</num>
    <text>The facility shall be designed to enhance the visual and recreational opportunities offered by the Waterfront.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>915.3.</num>
    <text>The use shall not adversely affect the present character or future development of the neighborhood.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>915.4.</num>
    <text>No dangerous or otherwise objectionable traffic conditions shall result from the establishment of the use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>915.5.</num>
    <text>The Board may impose requirements pertaining to the design, appearance, and screening, and other requirements as it deems necessary for the protection of neighboring or adjacent property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>915.6.</num>
    <text>Before taking final action on an application for the use, the Board shall refer the application to the D.C. Office of Planning for coordination, review, and report. The report shall include the recommendations of all appropriate District agencies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§ 4402.38 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9725, 9736 (December 8, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 3440 (April 2, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 52 DCR 6358 (July 8, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>