<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-928</num>
  <heading>SPECIAL EXCEPTION APPLICATION REQUIREMENTS (W-0) (ยง 11-928)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>928.1.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a special exception shall provide a survey plan showing:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Existing vertical contours at two-foot intervals;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The 100-year floodplain and all existing streams, wetlands, and bodies of water, as well as general drainage patterns with arrows indicating the directions of major drainage flow;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Existing vegetation, including a listing of most abundant species; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>All existing disturbed areas, including the locations of utilities, paved areas, streets, culverts, storm water management systems, and bridges.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>928.2.</num>
    <text>The applicant shall provide a proposed site plan showing:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The proposed location, height, bulk, and design of all improvements, including buildings, structures, pedestrian and vehicular access, parking, piers and wharves, berths, utilities, paved areas, culverts, storm water management, and bridges;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Suitable open space treatment of a waterfront setback area, as required in ยง 938, for uses such as walkway, bikeway, passive or active recreation; and including provisions assuring private maintenance of the space, convenient and public access to
        the space, and suitable connections to adjacent public space along the waterfront;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Proposed grading, including a calculation of the amount of cutting from and filling to natural grade;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Proposed landscaping, including riverbank treatment/restoration; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The location and design of fencing, gates, screening, exterior lighting, and signage.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>928.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a special exception shall provide a parking plan showing:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The location and design of parking spaces, access driveways, and other impervious surface landscaping;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The location and design of emergency vehicle access to all buildings, structures, and active public spaces; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>For boathouse, marina, and yacht club facilities, a parking management plan for special events (such as regattas).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>928.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a special exception shall provide a description of activities proposed to be conducted at the site.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 3440 (April 2, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 6358 (July 8, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>