<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-926</num>
  <heading>PARKING SPACES (W-0) (ยง 11-926)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>926.1.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding ยง 2116.1. of this Title, parking spaces for boathouses, marinas, yacht clubs, or other recreational uses to be located elsewhere than on the same lot or part of the lot on which the principal use is located, may be permitted as a special
      exception, if the applicant proves that compliance with this parking requirement would be unsafe or economically impractical and:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The parking spaces will be located to furnish reasonable and convenient parking for patrons of the principal building;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any support facility in relation to the parking spaces is designed so as not likely to become objectionable to adjoining or nearby property, park space, or the waterfront because of noise, traffic, or other objectionable conditions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The parking spaces will be adequately screened from adjacent park space and from the waterfront, and shall be designed to prevent storm water run-off directly into the river; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>All other requirements of Chapter 21 will be met.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>926.2.</num>
    <text>The applicant shall prove that compliance would be unsafe or economically impractical by showing that one or more of the following applies:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The lack of street frontage or the separation of the use from any publicly- accessible street by public park space;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Unusual topography, grades, shape, size, or dimensions of the lot;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The lack of appropriate ingress or egress through existing or proposed streets;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Strip zoning or shallow zoning depth;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Restricted size of lot caused by adverse adjoining ownership or substantial improvements adjoining or on the lot; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Traffic hazards caused by unusual street grades or other conditions.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>926.3.</num>
    <text>All or a portion of required parking spaces for a boathouse may be reduced or eliminated by special exception if the applicant proves that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The provision of parking would result in significant adverse impacts on adjacent park land;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The type or location of the associated principal use results in diminished need for parking from what would otherwise be required by zoning regulations; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Reasonable and conveniently-located alternatives to the required parking exist and are available to the boathouse users with minimal impact on adjacent land or development.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 3440 (April 2, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 6358 (July 8, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>