<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-1404</num>
  <heading>EXTENSION-SPECIAL OR UNUSUAL CIRCUMSTANCES (ยง 14-1404)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1404.1.</num>
    <text>An applicant may be granted an extension to comply with the deficiency notice for any of the following reasons:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The District Government has performed all the required services but due to extenuating circumstances the applicant is unable, through no fault of his or her own, to bring the property into compliance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Other special or unusual circumstances as determined by the Director.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1404.2.</num>
    <text>All requests for extensions shall be made in writing and addressed to the Director, Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1404.3.</num>
    <text>All requests for extensions shall be filed fifteen (15) working days prior to the expiration of the prescribed time period. The request shall specify the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The basis for the request including the details of all efforts on the part of the applicant to bring the property for which an exemption is requested into compliance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The facts which support the request in sufficient detail to enable the Director to make an informed judgment; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any other information as the Director may require.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1404.4.</num>
    <text>The exemption requested shall be either granted or denied by the Director as soon as practicable after receipt of all required information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1404.5.</num>
    <text>The decision to grant or deny the exemption shall be delivered to the applicant in writing by certified mail or personal service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1404.6.</num>
    <text>A decision to grant an exemption shall set forth the extended period of time by which compliance shall be achieved.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1404.7.</num>
    <text>If a reinspection is required, the applicant shall receive an extension of time equal to the additional time required for the reinspection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 29 DCR 5571, 5573 (December 17, 1982).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>