<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-100</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 14-100)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>100.1.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this Subtitle A (chapters 1-13) shall apply to every premises or part of any premises occupied (including those owned by the District of Columbia government), used, or held out for use as a place of abode for human beings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>100.2.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this subtitle are promulgated for the purpose of preserving and promoting the public health, safety, welfare, and morals through the abatement of certain conditions affecting residential buildings and areas, including dilapidation,
      inadequate maintenance, overcrowding, inadequate toilet facilities, inadequate bathing or washing facilities, inadequate heating, insufficient protection against fire hazards, inadequate lighting and ventilation, and other unsanitary or unsafe conditions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>100.3.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, the Mayor may delegate the authority to enforce these regulations to any agency that he or she deems appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>100.4.</num>
    <text>Whenever any officer or department of the District government is referred to in this subtitle, the term shall include the agents of that officer or department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>100.5.</num>
    <text>Each section and subsection of this subtitle shall be independent of and severable from every other section or subsection, and the finding or holding of any section or subsection to be void, invalid, or ineffective for any cause shall not be deemed
      to affect any other section or subsection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is contained at paragraphs 28 and 46 of section 7 of An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending
        June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and three, and for other purposes (“Act of 1902”), Public, No.218, 32 Stat. 590, approved July 1, 1902, as amended by:</heading>
      <text>An Act approved July 1, 1932 to amend section 7 [of the Act of 1902], 47 Stat. 550; and An Act approved July 22, 1947, Public Law 215, 61 Stat. 402.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>The Housing Regulations of the District of Columbia, 5G DCRR §§ 1104, 2101 and 2102, Commissioners’ Order 55-1503 (August 11, 1955); as amended by section 6 of the Regulation Enforcement and Fire Safety Amendment Act of 1979, D.C. Law 3-42, 26 DCR
        2082, 2085-86 (November 9, 1979).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>