<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-1201</num>
  <heading>NON-RESIDENT LICENSEES (§ 14-1201)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1201.1.</num>
    <text>No license to operate an apartment house business shall be issued to a person not a resident of the District of Columbia, unless that non-resident, as a condition of receiving and maintaining the license, does one of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Maintains an office in the District of Columbia; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Appoints or employs and maintains an attorney-in-fact, general agent or manager who is a resident of the District or who maintains an office in the District, and notifies the Director of that appointment or employment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.2.</num>
    <text>A non-resident licensee shall notify the Director of any change in the appointment or employment of his or her attorney-in-fact, general agent, or manager within five (5) business days of the change.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.3.</num>
    <text>In all cases of a non-resident licensee, notice of any action to be taken with respect to the license issued to the licensee may be served upon the attorney-in-fact, general agent, or manager appointed or employed by that non-resident licensee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.4.</num>
    <text>Upon certification to the Director by an officer of the District required to serve notices in connection with the operation of an apartment house business that a licensee (or the attorney-in-fact, general agent, or manager of that licensee) cannot
      be found after reasonable search, proceedings against the licensee may be instituted by serving notice, in the manner prescribed in § 105.4 of this title, upon either the licensee or any person who has been designated by the licensee as attorney-in-fact,
      general agent, or manager, and whose designation has not been rescinded by the licensee in a written notice of rescission sent to the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>The Housing Regulations of the District of Columbia, 5G DCRR § 6103, Commissioners’ Order 55-1503 (August 11, 1955); as amended by Commissioners’ Order 57-1023 (June 6, 1957).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>