<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2204</num>
  <heading>INCLUSIONARY DEVELOPMENT COVENANT (ยง 14-2204)
    <text>The Inclusionary Development Covenant shall be in a form found legallyufficient by the Office of Attorney General and shall bind all persons with aroperty interest in any or all of the Inclusionary Development, and allssignees, mortgagees, purchasers,
      and other successors in interest, to sucheclarations as the Department of Housing and Community Development may require,ut, at a minimum, shall include:</text>
    <text>A provision requiring that the present and all future Owners of a Rentalnclusionary Development shall construct or maintain and reserve Inclusionarynits at such affordability levels and in such number, square footage, andomparable level of finish
      as indicated on the Certificate of Inclusionaryoning Compliance and shall rent such Inclusionary Units in accordance with thenclusionary Zoning Program and the Certificate of Inclusionary Zoningompliance;</text>
    <text>A provision requiring that the present and all future Owners of a For Salenclusionary Development shall construct and maintain Inclusionary Units at suchffordability levels and in such number, and square footage as indicated on theertificate of Inclusionary
      Zoning Compliance and shall sell each Inclusionarynit in accordance with the Inclusionary Zoning Program and the Certificate ofnclusionary Zoning Compliance;</text>
    <text>A provision binding all assignees, mortgagees, purchasers, and other successorsn interest to the Inclusionary Development Covenant; and</text>
    <text>A provision providing for the release or extinguishment of the Inclusionaryevelopment Covenant only upon the reasonable approval of the Department ofousing and Community Development Inclusionary Zoning Administrator.</text>
    <text>A provision requiring that the sale or resale of an Inclusionary Unit shall benly to a Household selected by the Department of Housing and Communityevelopment or otherwise authorized by this Chapter, at a price that does notxceed the Maximum Resale
      Price established in accordance with ยง 2218.</text>
    <text>The lease rider shall be attached as an Exhibit to the lease for a Rentalnclusionary Unit and shall be executed by the Inclusionary Development Ownernd each Inclusionary Unit Tenant, including any occupant of a Rentalnclusionary Unit that is eighteen
      (18) years old or older.</text>
    <text>The Department of Housing and Community Development may require, in its soleiscretion, the use of a deed of trust to ensure compliance by an Inclusionaryevelopment Owner with the Inclusionary Development Covenant.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 3907 (May 15, 2009); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 9295, 9301 (December 11, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>