<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2213</num>
  <heading>VERIFICATION OF HOUSEHOLD ELIGIBILITY; REQUIRED CERTIFICATIONS (§ 14-2213)
    <text>In order to be eligible to rent or purchase an Inclusionary Unit, a Householdhall provide to the Owner of the Inclusionary Unit a Declaration of Eligibilitynd a Certification of Income, Affordability, and Housing Size.</text>
    <text>Except as set forth in § 2208.1(a), an Owner shall sell or rent annclusionary Unit only to a Household which:</text>
    <text>Has provided a Certification of Income, Affordability, and Housing Size,btained from a Certifying Entity, that complies with the requirements of thisection; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Has executed and provided a Declaration of Eligibility that complies withhe requirements of this section.</text>
    </level>
    <text>A Declaration of Eligibility required by this section shall be made on a formromulgated by the Department of Housing and Community Development and shallnclude a notarized statement of the Household and sworn under penalty oferjury that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Certification of Income, Affordability, and Household Size provided tohe Owner was obtained from a Certifying Entity approved by the Department ofousing and Community Development;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Household provided accurate and complete information to the Certifyingntity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Each member of the Household will occupy the Inclusionary Unit as itsrincipal residence;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Household does not have an ownership interest in any other housing orill divest such interest before closing on the purchase of, or signing theease for, the Inclusionary Unit;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The Household has satisfactorily completed a housing counseling class foromebuyers or renters approved by the Department of Housing and Communityevelopment and evidence of such satisfactory completion is attached to theeclaration of Eligibility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The Household understands, its rights and obligations under the Inclusionaryovenant or lease riders required pursuant to § 2216.1; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Any other representations required by the Department of Housing andommunity Development as part of the form.</text>
    </level>
    <text>The Inclusionary Unit Owner shall provide the Inclusionary Covenant or leaseiders to the Household within ten (10) days after a request from the Household.</text>
    <text>A Certification of Income, Affordability, and Housing Size required by thisection means a document signed by an authorized representative of a Certifyingntity approved by the Department of Housing and Community Development,ertifying:</text>
    <text>The Household’s Annual Income;</text>
    <text>That the Household’s Annual Income qualifies it as being either a Low-Incomeousehold or Moderate-Income Household;</text>
    <text>That the Household’s Annual Income does not exceed the limit imposed by thenclusionary Development Covenant applicable to the Inclusionary Unit;</text>
    <text>The Household’s size;</text>
    <text>That the Household’s size is within the size range applicable to thenclusionary Unit under § 2206.3;</text>
    <text>For a For Sale Inclusionary Unit, that the Household will not expend more thanorty-one percent (41%) of the its Annual Income on mortgage payments,nsurance, taxes, and condominium and homeowner association fees for thepplicable Inclusionary Unit;
      and</text>
    <text>For a Rental Inclusionary Unit, that the Household will not expend more thanhirty-eight percent (38%) of its Annual Income on rent and utilities if notncluded in the rent for the applicable Inclusionary Unit.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 3907 (May 15, 2009); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 9295, 9311 (December 11, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>