<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2224</num>
  <heading>APPLICABILITY (§ 14-2224)
    <text>These rules shall become applicable immediately.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <num>2224.2</num>
    <text>2224.2 In accordance with the Zoning Commission’s Inclusionary Zoningegulations (Title 11 DCMR, Chapter 26), these rules and the provisions of thenclusionary Zoning Act shall not apply to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Hotels, motels, inns, or dormitories;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Housing developed by or on behalf of a local college or universityxclusively for its students, faculty, or staff;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Housing that is owned or leased by foreign missions exclusively foriplomatic staff;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Rooming houses, boarding houses, community-based residential facilities, oringle room occupancy developments;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Properties located in any of the following areas:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The Downtown Development or Southeast Federal Center Overlay Districts;</text>
    </level>
    <text>(ii) The Downtown East, New Downtown, North Capitol, Southwest, or Capitol Southeceiving Zones, as such areas were defined on February 12, 2007;</text>
    <text>(iii) The W-2 zoned portions of the Georgetown Historic District;</text>
    <text>(iv) The R-3 zoned portions of the Anacostia Historic District;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(v)</num>
      <text>The C-2-A zoned portion of the Naval Observatory Precinct District; and</text>
    </level>
    <text>(vi) The Eighth Street Overlay;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A building for which the application for a building permit was authorized byn order of the Board of Zoning Adjustment promulgated prior to the date thathe first Maximum Rent and Price Schedule is published in the D.C. Register,ubject to the requirements
        of 11 DCMR § 3202.6.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A building approved by the Zoning Commission pursuant to Chapter 24 of Title4 DCMR, if the approved application was set down for hearing by the Zoningommission for the District of Columbia prior to March 14, 2008.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Any other building for which a building permit was filed prior to the datehat the first Maximum Rent and Price Schedule is published in the D.C. Registerubject to the further requirements of 11 DCMR § 3202.4.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 3907 (May 15, 2009) (asection 2225); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 9295, 9320December 11, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>