<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2211</num>
  <heading>DISTRICT LOTTERY – NOTIFICATION OF HOUSEHOLDS AND OWNERS (§ 14-2211)
    <text>No later than seventeen (17) days after a lottery is held, the Department ofousing and Community Development shall provide to the Owner a written list ofhe Households selected pursuant to the lottery, along with the lottery rank ofach Household.</text>
    <text>Not later than seventeen (17) days after a lottery is held, the Department ofousing and Community Development shall provide a notice to each of theouseholds selected in the lottery of their selection and shall provide to eachousehold their rank, the
      address, unit type, and maximum rent or purchase pricef the Inclusionary Unit for which the lottery was held and the means by whichhe Household may provide to the Owner the confirmation and information requiredy § 2211.3.</text>
    <text>The notice provided pursuant to § 2211.2 shall inform each Household that theousehold is required to confirm its interest in the Unit to the Owner withineventeen (17) days after the date of the notice and to provide the following tohe Owner within
      forty-five (45) days after the date of the notice:</text>
    <text>A Declaration of Eligibility, as described in § 2213;</text>
    <text>A Certification of Income, Affordability, and Housing Size, as described in 2213;</text>
    <text>If purchasing a For Sale Inclusionary Unit, a pre-qualification letter from aender indicating the Household’s credit worthiness and ability to afford theurchase price; and</text>
    <text>Any other documents requested by the Department of Housing and Communityevelopment.</text>
    <text>The notice shall also state that the Household must execute a pre-sale contractr lease for the Inclusionary Unit no later than sixty (60) days after the datef the notice.</text>
    <text>A Household that fails to meet a deadline set forth in § 2211.3 or § 2211.4hall be ineligible to purchase or rent the Inclusionary Unit, unless the Ownerxtends the deadline.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 3907 (May 15, 2009); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 9295, 9310 (December 11, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>