<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2208</num>
  <heading>METHOD OF SELECTION OF HOUSEHOLDS (§ 14-2208)
    <text>Except as provided in § 2208.3, a Household shall be selected for the initialr subsequent sale and for the initial lease of an Inclusionary Unit through aottery conducted pursuant to § 2210.</text>
    <text>No lottery is required for the initial or subsequent sale or the initial leasef an Inclusionary Unit if the Inclusionary Development is to be:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Leased or sold to a household displaced from and entitled by law to returno the Inclusionary Unit;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Leased or sold as a replacement unit as part of the New Communitiesnitiative; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Sold by an Inclusionary Unit Owner to the Inclusionary Unit Owner’spouse, domestic partner, parent, trust for the benefit of a child, child who isubject to a guardianship, or child who is eighteen (18) years of age or older,f the spouse, domestic
        partner, parent, or child submits the information andocuments required by § 2213.1.</text>
    </level>
    <text>A Household may be selected for the subsequent lease of a Rental Inclusionarynit through:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A lottery conducted pursuant to § 2210;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A method described in § 2208.2(b) or (c) (and set forth in the Notice ofvailability pursuant to § 2206.6(g)); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A method established by the Owner (and set forth in the Notice ofvailability pursuant to § 2206.6(g)), if the method meets the followingtandards:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Owner maintains a selection list or waiting list (“Owner List”) forhe Inclusionary Unit or the Inclusionary Development in which the Inclusionarynit is located that is open to the general public and includes the informationisted in § 2209.3;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Owner markets the Inclusionary Unit to the first four (4) Households onhe Owner List that qualify for the Inclusionary Unit based on Household sizend Household income, as ranked in the following order:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Households residing in the District of Columbia, who shall then be ranked byhe length of time each has been on the Owner List;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Households with a least one (1) member employed in the District of Columbia,ho shall then be ranked by the length of time each has been on the Owner List;nd</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Other Households, who shall then be ranked by the length of time each haseen on the Owner List.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Owner allows each Household at least seventeen (17) days to indicate itsnterest in leasing the Inclusionary Unit.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Owner does not lease the Inclusionary Unit before thirty (30) days afterhe Owner begins to market the Inclusionary Unit to the four (4) Households,nless the Inclusionary Unit is leased to the highest-ranked Household that hasndicated its interest
        in leasing the Inclusionary Unit.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>After the thirty (30) day period designated in subparagraph (4) of thisubsection, the Owner may lease the Inclusionary Unit to any of the four (4)ouseholds; provided, if there are two (2) or more such Households that areeady and eligible to lease
        the Inclusionary Unit, and meet the Owner’son-income based rental or sale criteria, the Owner shall lease the Inclusionarynit to the highest-ranked such Household.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>If none of the first four (4) Households leases the unit after a reasonableeriod of time, the Owner may market the Inclusionary Unit to the next four (4)ouseholds ranked in the same order as set forth in paragraph (b) of thisubsection and lease
        the Inclusionary Unit pursuant to the standards establishedy subparagraphs (1) through (5) of this subsection.</text>
    </level>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 3907 (May 15, 2009); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 9295, 9305 (December 11, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>