<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-202</num>
  <heading>INSPECTION OF PREMISES (§ 14-202)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>202.1.</num>
    <text>As a condition of licensure, a licensee shall allow the Department, and any other District government agency responsible for enforcement of the housing and building regulations, to inspect its housing business premises.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.2.</num>
    <text>A licensee shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Comply with all statutes and regulations relating to:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The presence of rodents, waste storage and disposal, and maintenance of waste containers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Maintenance of the common areas of the housing business under the licensee’s control so that they are free of trash and debris; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Ensuring that grass or weeds are maintained at a height of less than ten (10) inches;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Maintain the premises in a manner that complies with the applicable provisions of the D.C. Official Code, the District Property Maintenance Code (subtitle G of 12 DCMR), and the District fire prevention and control laws and regulations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Comply with all other District and federal statutes and regulations that govern housing businesses.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.3</num>
    <text>202.3 The Director shall determine whether a licensee is in compliance with all applicable provisions of the business license laws and regulations and shall require that the building or part of the building to be licensed complies with the applicable
      building and housing laws and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.4.</num>
    <text>In accordance with § 202.1, the Director may develop a housing inspection program establishing a regular system of inspections for licensees, with more frequent inspections for any licensee found to be in violation of the applicable building and housing
      statutes or regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>The Housing Regulations of the District of Columbia, 5G DCRR § 3106, Commissioners’ Order 55-1503 (August 11, 1955); as replaced by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 7487, 7489 (June 22, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>