<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2218</num>
  <heading>DETERMINATION OF MAXIMUM RESALE PRICE (§ 14-2218)
    <text>The Maximum Resale Price (“MRP”) for a subsequent sale of a For Salenclusionary Unit shall be determined through use of the formula MRP = (P x F) + V (“Formula”), where:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>P = the price the Owner paid for the Inclusionary Unit;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>V = the sum of the value of the Eligible Capital Improvements and Eligibleeplacement and Repair Costs, as determined by the Department of Housing andommunity Development pursuant to this section; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>F = the sum of the Ten Year Compound Annual Growth Rates of the Area Medianncome (“AMI”) from the year of the Owner’s purchase of the Inclusionarynit to the year of the sale of the Inclusionary Unit by the Owner. This sumay be expressed:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>As the result of the formula F = (1 + [((AMI Year m /AMI Year m-10) ^ (1/10)1) +…((AMI Year k /AMI year k-10) ^ (1/10) -1) / n]) ^ n, where m = the yearn which the Inclusionary Unit was purchased by the Owner, k = the year in whichhe Inclusionary
        Unit is sold by the Owner, and n = the number of years thenclusionary Unit is owned by the Owner; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>As published by the Department of Housing and Community Development.</text>
    </level>
    <text>For the purposes of determining the value of “V” in the Formula, theollowing improvements made to an Inclusionary Unit after the date of purchaseay be included at the percentage of cost indicated, to the extent they areermanent in nature and add to
      the market value of the property:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Eligible Capital Improvements, which will be valued at 100% of reasonableost, as determined by the Department of Housing and Community Development; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Eligible Replacement and Repair Costs, which shall be valued at 50% ofeasonable cost, as determined by the Department of Housing and Communityevelopment.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Ineligible costs shall not be included in the determining the value of “V”n the Formula.</text>
    <text>The value of improvements may be determined by the Department of Housing andommunity Development based upon documentation provided by the Inclusionary Unitwner or, if not provided, upon a standard value established by the Departmentf Housing and Community
      Development.</text>
    <text>The Department of Housing and Community Development may disallow an Eligibleapital Improvement or Eligible Replacement and Repair Cost if the Department ofousing and Community Development finds that the improvement diminished or didot increase the
      fair market value of the Inclusionary Unit.</text>
    <text>The Department of Housing and Community Development may reduce the value of aapital improvement if there is evidence of abnormal physical deterioration of,r abnormal wear and tear to, the capital improvement.</text>
    <text>The Owner shall permit a representative of the Department of Housing andommunity Development to inspect the Inclusionary Unit upon request to verifyhe existence and value of any capital improvements that are claimed by thewner.</text>
    <text>No allowance shall be made in the Maximum Resale Price for the payment of realstate brokerage fees associated with the sale of the Inclusionary Unit.</text>
    <text>The value of personal property transferred to a purchaser in connection with theesale of a For Sale Inclusionary Unit shall not be considered part of the salesrice of the For Sale Inclusionary Unit for the purposes of determining whetherhe sales price
      of the For Sale Inclusionary Unit exceeds the MRP.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 3907 (May 15, 2009); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 9295, 9316 (December 11, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>