<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2001</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION FOR SUBSIDY ALLOCATIONS TO HOUSING UNITS (ยง 14-2001)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2001.1.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall make known to the public, including housing providers and housing developers, the availability of Tenant Assistance Program funding to eligible housing unit types.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.2.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall receive applications for funding from housing providers or housing developers when funding is available in one of the following ways:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Issuance of a Request for Proposals (RFP) within a prescribed period of time;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Issuance of an application to a specific housing provider or developer at any time, but only in connection with another application for financial assistance under another program that is pending action at DCHA or another District agency or department;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Receipt of an application for a property which has received a hardship rent increase from the Rent Administrator of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs; provided, that the Rent Administrator certifies to DCHA that the rent increases
        approved are not affordable by existing lower income tenants in the property; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Other fair and equitable methods as may be determined by DCHA, provided that DCHA provides public notice of such method and the opportunity to apply.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.3.</num>
    <text>When DCHA issues a Request for Proposals (RFP), the RFP shall indicate the selective factors to be used in reviewing and evaluating applications for selection and funding. Selective factors may include priority criteria for funding specific types
      of housing units or properties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.4.</num>
    <text>Applications shall be in a form specified by DCHA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.5.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall review each application for completeness and eligibility. DCHA shall notify each applicant of its determination of approval or disapproval. Applications that are approvable, but for which sufficient funding is not available, may be held
      until funding is available.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.6.</num>
    <text>The DCHA approval may be conditioned on satisfaction of requirements prior to the receipt of assistance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.7.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall give priority consideration to applications received under the Designated Housing Unit Tenant Assistance Program to properties receiving assistance under the Distressed Properties Improvement Program consistent with ยง 804(d) of the Act,
      D.C. Official Code ยง 42-3508.04 (2001).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 4396, 4432 (July 25, 1986); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 4472, 4483 (June 23, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>