<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2202</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION FOR CERTIFICATE OF INCLUSIONARY ZONING COMPLIANCE (§ 14-2202)
    <text>The Inclusionary Development Owner shall file a written application for aertificate of Inclusionary Zoning Compliance with the Department of Consumernd Regulatory Affairs no later than the date upon which the first applicationor a building permit
      is filed for the Inclusionary Development.</text>
    <text>The Inclusionary Development Owner shall include with its application for aertificate of Inclusionary Zoning Compliance payment of an application fee ofwo hundred fifty dollars ($250).</text>
    <text>The Inclusionary Development Owner shall file its application for a Certificatef Inclusionary Zoning Compliance on a form prescribed by the Department ofonsumer and Regulatory Affairs and shall provide such information as isequested on the form.</text>
    <text>The application form for a Certificate of Inclusionary Zoning Compliance shallnclude:</text>
    <text>The name of the Inclusionary Development, its marketing name if different, andhe apartment house or condominium name, if applicable;</text>
    <text>The street address of the Inclusionary Development;</text>
    <text>The zone district and, if applicable, overlay district in which thenclusionary Development is located;</text>
    <text>The current and proposed square, suffix, and lot numbers on which thenclusionary Development will be located;</text>
    <text>A list of all Inclusionary Units in the Inclusionary Development. Eachnclusionary Unit shall be identified by unit number, net square footage, andhe number of bedrooms. The list shall also include, and separately identify,ny Inclusionary Units that
      will serve as the location for the offsiteompliance of another Inclusionary Development, as approved by the Board ofoning Adjustment, together with a copy of the Board of Zoning Adjustment orderpproving the offsite compliance;</text>
    <text>A certification from the Inclusionary Development’s architect or engineer thathe size of each Inclusionary Unit is at least ninety-eight percent (98%) of theverage size of the same type of Market Rate Unit in the development or at leastinety-eight
      percent (98%) of the size indicated in the following table,hichever is lesser:</text>
    <text>Types of Dwelling</text>
    <text>Type of Unit</text>
    <text>Minimum Unit Size (square feet)</text>
    <text>Multiple Family Dwelling</text>
    <text>Studio/ Efficiency</text>
    <text>400</text>
    <text>One Bedroom</text>
    <text>550</text>
    <text>Two Bedroom</text>
    <text>800</text>
    <text>Three Bedroom</text>
    <text>1000</text>
    <text>Four Bedroom</text>
    <text>1050</text>
    <text>One or Two Household Dwellings</text>
    <text>Two Bedroom</text>
    <text>1000</text>
    <text>Three Bedroom</text>
    <text>1200</text>
    <text>Four Bedroom</text>
    <text>1400</text>
    <text>A copy of the site plan, front elevation or block face, and all residentialloor plans for the Inclusionary Development. The floor plans shall show theocation of each Inclusionary Unit and each Market Rate Unit and shall identifyach by unit number;</text>
    <text>A copy of the building plat, if required by the Department of Consumer andegulatory Affairs pursuant to 12A DCMR § 106.1.12;</text>
    <text>A plan for the phasing of construction that demonstrates compliance with 11CMR § 2605.5, which requires that all Inclusionary Units in an Inclusionaryevelopment be constructed prior to or concurrently with the construction ofarket Rate Units, except
      that in a phased development, the Inclusionary Unitshall be constructed at a pace that is proportional with the construction of thearket Rate Units;</text>
    <text>The total land area of all of the lots included in the Inclusionaryevelopment;</text>
    <text>The total gross square footage of the Inclusionary Units in the Inclusionaryevelopment, the net residential square footage of the Inclusionary Development,nd the gross residential square footage of the Inclusionary Development;</text>
    <text>The total net floor area that will be set aside for Inclusionary Units asalculated by multiplying the total gross square footage of the Inclusionarynits required by 11 DCMR § 2603 by the ratio of the net residential squareootage to the gross residential
      square footage of the Inclusionary Development;</text>
    <text>The total gross floor area of Inclusionary Units that will be set aside for Lownd Moderate Income Households, if such Inclusionary Units are required by 11CMR § 2603.3, calculated pursuant to the method set forth in paragraph (n) ofhis subsection;</text>
    <text>A proposed schedule of standard finishes, fixtures, equipment, and appliancesor both Inclusionary Units and Market Rate Units;</text>
    <text>For each Inclusionary Unit, the approximate date by which the Inclusionaryevelopment Owner will provide a Notice of Availability pursuant to § 2206;</text>
    <text>If construction of the Inclusionary Development will result in the temporaryisplacement of tenants who are entitled by law to return to comparable units, aist of the Inclusionary Units for which a right of return exists; and</text>
    <text>Such other information as may be requested by the Department of Consumer andegulatory Affairs.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 3907 (May 15, 2009); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 9295, 9298 (December 11, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>