<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2900</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 14-2900)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2900.1.</num>
    <text>The purposes of the Homestead Housing Preservation Program (the “Program”) shall be as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>To provide home ownership opportunities to residents of the District of Columbia, or individuals newly employed by the District of Columbia Government, of low and moderate income;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>To enable organized groups of low and moderate income District residents to obtain skills in the repair, maintenance and management of residential property; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>To give highly motivated low and moderate income residents of the District of Columbia the opportunity to participate fully in the rehabilitation of their own decent and affordable homes.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2900.2.</num>
    <text>The objective of the Program is to reduce the critical shortage of decent and affordable low and moderate income housing stock by acquiring deteriorated tax delinquent residential properties and conveying them primarily to low and moderate income
      individuals and groups who agree to promptly bring the properties into a state of good repair and to reside in them for a period of five (5) years from the date of conveyance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2900.3.</num>
    <text>The Program is authorized by the Homestead Housing Preservation Act of 1986, as amended, D.C. Law 6-135, D. C. Official Code §§ 42-2101 et seq. (2001)(the “Act”).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2900.4.</num>
    <text>The Director of the D.C. Department of Housing and Community Development (the “Director”) may waive, for good cause and stated in writing, any of the rules set forth in this chapter within the limits of applicable laws and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2900.5.</num>
    <text>The Director may allocate D.C. Department of Housing and Community Development funds and resources to the Program as, in his or her discretion, are deemed necessary to achieve the purposes of the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is section 5 of the Homestead Housing Preservation Act of 1986, D.C. Law 6-135, D.C. Official Code § 42-2104 (2001); as amended by subsection 5 of the Technical Amendments Act of 1986, D.C.
        Law 6-192 § 5, 33 DCR 7838 (December 19, 1986).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 4947, 4948 (July 31, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>