<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-2219</num>
  <heading>RENTAL OF A FOR SALE INCLUSIONARY UNIT (§ 14-2219)
    <text>An Inclusionary Unit Owner may temporarily lease a For Sale Inclusionary Unit to Household referred to it by the Department of Housing and Communityevelopment in accordance with the provisions of this section if such lease isot prohibited by applicable
      cooperative, condominium, or homeowner associationules.</text>
    <text>Except as set forth in § 2219.6, the lease term may not exceed twelve (12)onths and may not be renewed.</text>
    <text>Except as set forth in § 2219.6, no more than one (1) temporary rental mayccur with a five (5) year period.</text>
    <text>The Owner and Department of Housing and Community Development shall follow theotice of availability, website registration, and Household selection,otification, referral, and verification processes set forth in § 2206 and§ 2209 through 2213.</text>
    <text>The maximum rent shall be the rent set forth in the Rent and Price Schedule inlace on the date that the Notice of Availability for the Inclusionary Unit isiled.</text>
    <text>Upon written submission of a request substantiating substantial hardship, theepartment of Housing and Community Development may grant an extension of thewelve (12)-month period established by § 2219.2 or the one (1)-timeimitation established by § 2219.3.
      The Department of Housing and Communityevelopment shall approve or disapprove the request, in its sole discretionased on the evidence before it, within a reasonable time period. Substantialardship may include military service, Peace Corps service,
      or another reasonausing the Owner to be required to leave the District metropolitan areaemporarily.</text>
    <text>A condominium fee or assessment that a lessee of an Inclusionary Unit Ownereased under this section is required to pay shall be considered part of theent of the lessee when determining whether the rent charged is consistent withhe Maximum Rent and
      Purchase Price Schedule.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 3907 (May 15, 2009); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 9295, 9318 (December 11, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>