<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-3005</num>
  <heading>FINANCIAL ASSISTANCE TO BE PROVIDED (§ 14-3005)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3005.1.</num>
    <text>The Department shall provide either amortized or deferred payment loans to eligible senior citizen homeowner applicants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3005.2.</num>
    <text>The maximum loan principal for an amortized or deferred loan shall be five thousand dollars ($5,000) per property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3005.3.</num>
    <text>The maximum loan term for an amortized loan shall be twenty (20) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3005.4.</num>
    <text>An amortized loan shall be repaid with interest at an annual rate not to exceed three percent (3%).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3005.5.</num>
    <text>An amortized loan shall be repaid on a monthly schedule until paid in full.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3005.6.</num>
    <text>The outstanding principal balance of an amortized loan shall be paid in full upon sale or transfer of the property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3005.7.</num>
    <text>The Director may waive any of the requirements of this section, if the Director determines the repayment schedule creates an economic hardship on the homeowner receiving the loan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3005.8.</num>
    <text>An amortized loan repayment shall be considered an economic hardship if the applicant’s average monthly housing expenses for principal, interest, taxes, insurance and the cost of the amortized loan exceeds twenty-eight percent (28%) of the applicant’s
      gross monthly income.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3005.9.</num>
    <text>If the applicant’s monthly housing expenses exceed the standard established in § 3005.8, the applicant shall be eligible to receive a deferred payment loan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3005.10.</num>
    <text>The deferred payment loan shall be due and payable if the borrower moves from the property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3005.11.</num>
    <text>The deferred payment loan shall be repaid to the Department upon sale of the property to another owner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3005.12.</num>
    <text>In the case of transfer of ownership, a repayment schedule may be renegotiated with the new owner based upon the ability of the new owner to meet the criteria established in § 3005.8.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3005.13.</num>
    <text>Amortized and deferred payment loans may be subordinated to existing debt secured by the property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3005.14.</num>
    <text>All DHCD loans shall be secured by a recorded lien on the rehabilitated property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3005.15.</num>
    <text>All loan funds shall be used for correction of housing deficiencies identified by DHCD.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 7621, 7625 (December 7, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>