<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-3914</num>
  <heading>ARBITRATION (§ 14-3914)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3914.1.</num>
    <text>By mutual agreement, both the housing provider and the tenant(s) who are parties to a dispute under this Act, may file with the Rent Administrator, on a form provided by the Rent Administrator, a request for arbitration of any dispute not satisfactorily
      conciliated under § 503 of the Act and § 3913 of this subtitle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3914.2.</num>
    <text>Parties may waive the conciliation process and mutually agree to have the dispute arbitrated pursuant to this section and § 504 of the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3914.3.</num>
    <text>An arbitration recommendation, issued pursuant to the Arbitration Panel’s recommendation, shall not be binding on the parties unless both parties demonstrate their acceptance by signing it. The Rent Administrator shall approve agreements entered into
      by the parties under the panel’s recommendation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3914.4.</num>
    <text>The Rent Administrator shall designate three (3) members of the RACD staff, other than those who heard the dispute under § 503 of the Act, to serve as members of the Arbitration Panel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3914.5.</num>
    <text>The Arbitration Panel shall schedule and conduct an arbitration hearing at a time convenient to the parties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3914.6.</num>
    <text>The Arbitration Panel shall issue a written recommendation to resolve the dispute within ten (10) days of the arbitration request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3914.7.</num>
    <text>Any agreement accepted and entered into by the parties, pursuant to the Arbitration Panel’s recommendation, shall not be appealable to the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3914.8.</num>
    <text>Any arbitration agreement accepted and entered into by the parties, pursuant to the Arbitration Panel’s recommendation, shall be enforceable by a court of competent jurisdiction, upon application by the Rent Administrator or the parties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 1336, 1359-60 (March 7, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>