<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-3003</num>
  <heading>ELIGIBILITY (§ 14-3003)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3003.1.</num>
    <text>Persons eligible for assistance under the Program shall satisfy the following qualifications:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The person shall be a lower or moderate income senior citizen;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The person shall be a resident of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The person shall own and occupy the property which:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Is eligible for assistance under § 3003.3; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Has been the applicant’s principal place of residence for at least three (3) years prior to the date of application for assistance under the Program; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The person shall show evidence of ownership of the property by title, deed, or recorded land installment contract.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3003.2.</num>
    <text>Lower income applicants shall be given priority consideration for program participation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3003.3.</num>
    <text>Properties eligible for assistance under the Program shall meet the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be a dwelling unit;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be located in the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Have housing deficiencies as determined by DHCD, which present a threat to the health and safety of the occupants.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3003.4.</num>
    <text>The types of eligible work items shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Roofing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Heating, ventilation, air conditioning and other energy related repairs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Electrical system;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Plumbing system;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Exterior or interior stairs/ramps;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Porches; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Foundations, walls, ceilings, and floors.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 7621, 7623 (December 7, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>