<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-3004</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION FOR ASSISTANCE (§ 14-3004)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3004.1.</num>
    <text>All persons who desire assistance under the Program shall submit applications to the Director in a form prescribed by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3004.2.</num>
    <text>Each application for assistance shall be accompanied by proof of ownership of the property by the eligible senior citizen which shall consist of a notarized copy of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The title to the property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The deed to the property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A recorded land installment contract or purchase contract; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Other title documents, purchase or sales contracts that the Director finds acceptable.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3004.3.</num>
    <text>The Director shall review each application for completeness and compliance with eligibility standards.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3004.4.</num>
    <text>The Director shall reject applicants who are determined to be ineligible for the Program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3004.5.</num>
    <text>The Director may reject applications that are incomplete.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3004.6.</num>
    <text>The approval or disapproval of applications shall be the sole decision of the Director. The Director shall notify all applicants in writing of the final decision regarding application approval.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3004.7.</num>
    <text>Each applicant shall agree to permit inspections of the property to identify work items and other inspections as DHCD deems necessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3004.8.</num>
    <text>In approving each application, the DHCD Director may take into consideration applications for DHCD grant programs that are complementary to the Senior Citizens’ Home Repair and Improvement Program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 7621, 7624 (December 7, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>