<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-3900</num>
  <heading>THE RENT ADMINISTRATOR (§ 14-3900)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3900.1.</num>
    <text>The Rent Administrator shall, in addition to other duties, carry out the administration of the rent stabilization program, including the receipt of complaints, applications, and petitions arising under Titles II, IV, V, VI, and IX of the Act, and
      Title V of the Rental Housing Act of 1980 that may be disposed of through administrative proceedings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3900.2.</num>
    <text>The Rent Administrator shall establish internal operating procedures for the handling of RACD business.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3900.3.</num>
    <text>The Rent Administrator shall issue written delegations of authority pursuant to § 204(d) of the Act to hearing examiners to hear administrative petitions and issue decisions and final orders on those petitions; provided, that the Rent Administrator
      shall delegate authority to issue final decisions and orders only with the formal concurrence of the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3900.4.</num>
    <text>The RACD shall be open daily from 8:30 a.m. to 3:30 p.m., except Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3900.5.</num>
    <text>The Rent Administrator shall operate a “Tenant Hot Line” telephone service to provide assistance primarily to low and moderate income tenants in accordance with the provisions of § 705 of the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is Section 202(a)(1) of the Rental Housing Act of 1985, D.C. Law 6-10, § 202(a)(1), effective July 17, 1985 (codified at D.C. Official Code § 42-3502.02(a)(1) (2001)).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 1336, 1351 (March 7, 1986); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 2657 (May 2, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>