<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-3001</num>
  <heading>ORGANIZATION OF THE DHCD SENIOR CITIZENS HOME REPAIR AND IMPROVEMENT PROGRAMUND (ยง 14-3001)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3001.1.</num>
    <text>DHCD shall organize and administer the Fund to facilitate home improvement activities for the citizens of the District of Columbia through the provision of financial assistance to eligible senior citizen homeowners.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3001.2.</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be a permanent proprietary revolving fund of identified, renewable, and segregated capital.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3001.3.</num>
    <text>There shall be deposited in the Fund the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Appropriated amounts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Grants, fees, donations, gifts, investments, or other deposits from public and private sources;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Repayments of principal and interest on loans provided from the Fund;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Proceeds realized from the liquidation of any security interest held by the District under the terms of any assistance provided from the Fund;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Interest earned from the deposit or investment of monies from the Fund;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Available Community Development Block Grant funds;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>All revenues, receipts, and fees derived from the operation of the Fund; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Any such other funds as may be designated for this purpose by Council action.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 7621, 7622 (December 7, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>