<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-3602</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION PROCESS (ยง 14-3602)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3602.1.</num>
    <text>DHCD shall have the authority to establish a time period for the receipt of applications for assistance under the Employer-Assisted Housing Program. Applications for Downpayment Matching Funds, a Loan or both, shall be in the form prescribed by DHCD.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3602.2.</num>
    <text>Applicants shall meet the requirements specified in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3602.3.</num>
    <text>Each application for Downpayment Matching Funds shall be accompanied by the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Verification of personal savings of not less than $2,500.00;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Savings plan, if applicable, identifying the amount to be saved within a Specified period of time, subject to the approval of DHCD;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Application form(s) from a financial institution for an allotment consistent with the proposed savings plan;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Verification of District government employment in good standing. An employee in good standing shall be an employee against whom no adverse action has been taken, as set forth in the District Personnel Manual, Chapter 16, subpart 2, within the three
        (3) years immediately prior to applying to the Program; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Newly hired District of Columbia police officers, firefighters, emergency medical technicians, or teachers in a public or public charter school shall provide verification that he or she has been otherwise employed as a District government employee
        in good standing for at least 3 years prior to application or verification that he or she has been a resident of the District for at least 1 year prior to application.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 155, 156 (January 8, 1993); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 9853 (November 1, 2002); as amended by D.C. Act 15-199, 50 DCR 9827 (November 21, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>