<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-3801</num>
  <heading>PLEADINGS AND OTHER DOCUMENTS (§ 14-3801)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3801.1.</num>
    <text>All pleadings and other documents to be filed with the Commission shall be filed by delivering them in person to the Commission’s staff at 941 North Capitol Street, N.E., Suite 9200, Washington, D.C. 20002, or by mail to Post Office Box 37200, Washington,
      D.C. 20002, unless otherwise directed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3801.2.</num>
    <text>No pleading or other documents shall be deemed filed until actually received at the Commission’s office and compliance with time requirements shall be calculated from the date of actual receipt.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3801.3.</num>
    <text>All pleadings and other documents filed with the Commission shall be promptly date-stamped by the Commission staff and entered into the Commission’s daily log.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3801.4.</num>
    <text>All pleadings and other documents filed by mail shall be accompanied by a self-addressed postage paid envelope and one (1) copy in addition to the copies required by § 3801.7 for mailing to the filing party by the Commission staff.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3801.5.</num>
    <text>The Commission’s daily log shall be available for public inspection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3801.6.</num>
    <text>The receipt of a pleading or other document which is not timely or which does not comply with the substantive requirements of this title shall not constitute a waiver of the requirements of this title; and any such pleading or document may be rejected
      by the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3801.7.</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise required, all pleadings and other documents shall be filed in an original and four (4) identical copies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3801.8.</num>
    <text>All pleadings and other documents shall be served on the opposing party or parties prior to or at the same time as filed with the Commission and shall contain proof of service as required by § 3803.7.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3801.9.</num>
    <text>No fees shall be charged for the filing of any papers with the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3801.10.</num>
    <text>The forms contained in the Appendix of Forms when properly completed are sufficient under this title and are intended to indicate the simplicity and brevity of statement which this title contemplates.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 1336-37 (March 7, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>