<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-4905</num>
  <heading>MODERATE REHABILITATION (§ 14-4905)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4905.1.</num>
    <text>The following provisions of the Administrative Plan shall not apply to the Moderate Rehabilitation program, as defined at 24 C.F.R. § 882:</text>
    <text>14 DCMR chapter 52 – Briefing of Families and Issuance of Vouchers;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>14 DCMR § 5103 &amp;#8211; Mandatory Social Security Numbers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>14 DCMR § 5107 &amp;#8211; Family Consent to Release of Information;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>14 DCMR chapter 55 &amp;#8211; Portability; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>14 DCMR chapter 85 – Housing Choice Voucher Program: Participant Moves.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4905.2.</num>
    <text>The following annual and special rent adjustments policies shall apply:</text>
    <text>DCHA shall adjust the Contract Rent upon receipt of a revised Contract Rent schedule from the owner, provided that each unit is in decent, safe, and sanitary condition and that the owner is otherwise in compliance with the terms of the Lease and HUD
      Tenancy Addendum;</text>
    <text>The Annual Adjustment Factors which HUD publishes shall be utilized in calculating the Family’s rent. On or after each annual anniversary date of the Contract, the Contract Rent may be adjusted in accordance with HUD procedures, effective for the
      month following the submittal by the Owner of a revised schedule of Contract Rents. The changes in rent as a result of the adjustment cannot exceed the amount established by multiplying the Annual Adjustment Factor by the base rents;</text>
    <text>Approved rent adjustments as provided in this section shall not result in material differences between the rents charged for assisted and comparable unassisted units;</text>
    <text>The participant’s Security Deposit shall be the lesser of the Total Tenant Payment (TTP) or fifty dollars ($50), which is the maximum permissible security deposit;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>DHCA shall pay vacancy claims for up to sixty (60) Days at eighty percent (80%) of the Housing Assistance Payment (HAP) of the previous tenant; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>DCHA does not pay any claims for damages.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 7856, 7861 (June 29, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>