<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-4710</num>
  <heading>DETERMINATION OF INCOME ELIGIBILITY (§ 14-4710)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4710.1.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, the term “income” means all payments from all sources received by the head of the household (even if temporarily absent) and each additional member of the household who is not a minor. Income shall include, but not be
      limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The gross amount of wages, salaries, overtime pay, commissions, fees, tips and bonuses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The net income from the operation of a business or profession or from rental, real or personal property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Interest or dividends;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Full amount of periodic payments received from Social Security, annuities, insurance policies, retirement funds, pensions, disability or death benefits and other types of periodic receipts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Payments in lieu of earnings (unemployment and disability compensations, severance pay and workmen’s compensation); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Any other sources of income as defined in the Section 8 Housing Assistance Payments Program &amp;#8211; Existing Housing, 24 CFR 889.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4710.2.</num>
    <text>The value of assets, in addition to income, shall be a factor in determining whether a displaced tenant’s resources enable him or her to qualify for a housing assistance payment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4710.3.</num>
    <text>Assets shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The equity in real property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Savings, stocks, bonds and other forms of capital investments; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Sums in checking accounts, safe deposit boxes and cash on hand which the applicant has elect not to put into deposit accounts.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4710.4.</num>
    <text>Income eligibility shall be determined by computing a household’s total gross income plus the greater of either income from assets or ten percent (10%) of the value of assets, less the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Five percent (5%) of annual gross income, or ten percent (10%) of annual gross income if the head of household is an elderly person;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Annual child-care expenses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Three hundred dollars ($300) for each minor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Three hundred dollars ($300) for each secondary wage earner; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Average annual medical expense in excess of three percent (3%) of annual gross income.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4710.5.</num>
    <text>Low income tenants shall be required to furnish a listing of all income and assets from which an adjusted annual gross income will be determined using the deduction allowances cited in § 4710.4. This resulting figure shall be used to qualify a household
      as low-income by comparing it to current HUD Section 8 lower income limits for the appropriate-sized household.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4710.6.</num>
    <text>The current HUD Section 8 limits shall be as follows (subject to change):</text>
    <text>Number of persons</text>
    <text>in Household Maximum Income</text>
    <text>1 $15,100</text>
    <text>2 $17,300</text>
    <text>3 $19,470</text>
    <text>4 $21,600</text>
    <text>5 $22,950</text>
    <text>6 $24,300</text>
    <text>7 $25,650</text>
    <text>8 or more $27,000</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4710.7.</num>
    <text>For a household to qualify as an eligible low income elderly household, the resulting figure from § 4710.4 shall be less than thirty thousand dollars ($30,000).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4710.8.</num>
    <text>Any application for eligibility determination shall be signed and notarized.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4710.9.</num>
    <text>Age and financial information submitted shall be confidential.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4710.10.</num>
    <text>A low income tenant who is to be displaced by a conversion may apply for housing assistance. Upon locating a new unit, the tenant shall provide a copy of the lease or other evidence of the amount of the rent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4710.11.</num>
    <text>To qualify for housing assistance payments, the tenant shall relocate within the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4710.12.</num>
    <text>The tenant shall be recertified on the anniversary date of relocation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4710.13.</num>
    <text>Special consideration shall be given in the computation of income eligibility in unusual or special circumstances.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 2443 (May 29, 1981), incorporating by reference the text of Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 694, 704-706 (February 13, 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>