<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-4015</num>
  <heading>SHOW CAUSE HEARINGS (§ 14-4015)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4015.1.</num>
    <text>A show cause hearing is a hearing which is initiated by the Rent Administrator after an investigation by the Rent Administrator has resulted in a determination that there are substantial grounds to believe that violations of the Act may have occurred.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4015.2.</num>
    <text>The investigation of possible violations of the Act may be conducted as a result of the review of the records of the RACD or the records of federal or District courts and agencies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4015.3.</num>
    <text>Investigations of possible violations may also be conducted on the basis of complaints and allegations received orally or in writing by the Rent Administrator.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4015.4.</num>
    <text>If an investigation by the Rent Administrator finds substantial grounds to believe that possible violations of the Act have occurred, a notice of a show cause hearing shall be prepared and served on the alleged violator.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4015.5.</num>
    <text>The notice of a show cause hearing shall state clearly the section of the Act or this subtitle which has allegedly been violated, along with a brief statement of the evidence found during the investigation that supports the determination that an alleged
      violation has occurred.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4015.6.</num>
    <text>The notice shall also set forth the proposed corrective action to be taken against the alleged violator.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4015.7.</num>
    <text>Notice of a show cause hearing shall be served on the alleged violator in accordance with the provisions of § 904 of the Act, not less than fifteen (15) days before the hearing, and shall contain the date, time, and place of the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4015.8.</num>
    <text>At a show cause hearing, the burden of proof shall be upon the Enforcement Division of RACD.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4015.9.</num>
    <text>Show cause hearings shall be conducted consistent with the provisions of this chapter for the conduct of hearings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4015.10.</num>
    <text>The issues in a show cause hearing shall be disposed of in a final decision and order of the Rent Administrator that may be appealed to the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4015.11.</num>
    <text>There shall be no intervenors as a “matter of right” in a show cause hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4015.12.</num>
    <text>A request to intervene may be made by motion to the hearing examiner in accordance with § 3907.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4015.13.</num>
    <text>Affected housing providers, tenants and other persons with relevant evidence shall be permitted to testify as witnesses at show cause hearings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 1336, 1370-71 (March 7, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>