<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-4200</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 14-4200)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4200.1.</num>
    <text>The rent ceiling establishes the maximum amount of rent that a housing provider may legally demand or receive for a rental unit covered by the Rent Stabilization Program of the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4200.2.</num>
    <text>Each rental unit covered by the Rent Stabilization Program shall have an initial rent ceiling established pursuant to § 206(a) of the Act and § 4201; provided, that no rent ceiling shall be established for any rental unit exempt from the program pursuant
      to § 205(a) of the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4200.3.</num>
    <text>If a rental unit has a rent ceiling, the rent for that unit may legally be equal to or less than the rent ceiling, but the rent shall not be more than the rent ceiling.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4200.4.</num>
    <text>The Act regulates rent ceilings by determining which rental units shall have a rent ceiling, and by setting the terms and conditions for every increase or decrease in the rent ceiling of a rental unit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4200.5.</num>
    <text>A rent ceiling adjustment is any increase or decrease in a rent ceiling that is authorized by the Act, and taken and perfected by the housing provider in accordance with § 4204.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4200.6.</num>
    <text>The Act regulates the rent for each rental unit under the Rent Stabilization Program by requiring that the rent shall always be less than, or equal to, the rent ceiling, and by setting terms and conditions for every increase or decrease in rent for
      a rental unit covered by the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4200.7.</num>
    <text>A rent adjustment is any increase or decrease in rent required or permitted by the Act and this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4200.8.</num>
    <text>An increase in the rent for a rental unit shall be authorized only by an increase in the rent ceiling taken and perfected pursuant to § 4204 and under the following conditions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>At the election of the housing provider, pursuant to §§ 4206 and 4207;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Under an order of the Rent Administrator issued pursuant to §§ 4209, 4210, 4211 or 4212;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Under a voluntary agreement approved by the Rent Administrator pursuant to § 4213; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Under any prior rent control law and the regulations, if any, promulgated under that prior law.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is the Rental Housing Act of 1985, D.C. Law 6-10, effective July 17, 1985 (codified at D. C. Official Code §§ 42-3501.01 et seq. (2001).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 1336, 1384 (March 7, 1986); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 2656, 2662-2663 (May 2, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>