<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-4902</num>
  <heading>PROGRAM DESCRIPTION (ยง 14-4902)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4902.1</num>
    <text>4902.1 The HCVP is designed to achieve four major objectives:</text>
    <text>To provide improved living conditions for very low-income families while maintaining their rent payments at an affordable level;</text>
    <text>To promote freedom of housing choice and spatial deconcentration of lower income and minority families;</text>
    <text>To provide decent, safe, and sanitary housing for eligible participants; and</text>
    <text>To provide incentives to private property owners to rent to lower income families by offering timely assistance payments and protection against unpaid rent, damages, and vacancy loss.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4902.2.</num>
    <text>HUD chose DCHA as a Moving-to-Work (MTW) agency and has a HUD-approved MTW plan that shall be updated every two (2) years. This program has been named Making an IMPACT. This Administrative Plan is designed to implement the MTW goals applicable to
      the HCVP. These goals are to:</text>
    <text>Develop enhanced housing opportunities;</text>
    <text>Sustain quality property management;</text>
    <text>Achieve effective customer support services; and</text>
    <text>Organize efficient businesslike operating systems.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4902.3.</num>
    <text>DCHA is responsible for complying with all subsequent changes in HUD regulations pertaining to the HCVP-administered programs. If such changes conflict with this Plan, HUD regulations shall control.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4902.4.</num>
    <text>DCHA is legally permitted to enter into contracts within the jurisdictional boundaries known as the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 7856, 7857 (June 29, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>