<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-5501</num>
  <heading>DENYING FAMILY REQUEST TO MOVE UNDER PORTABILITY (§ 14-5501)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5501.1.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall deny a Family’s request to move under portability, subject to the protections in the VAWA, Fair Housing Act (FHA), and District of Columbia Human Rights Act (DCHRA) if:</text>
    <text>The Family is an applicant Family coming off the waiting list and has not been assisted in DCHA’s jurisdiction for twelve (12) months;</text>
    <text>The Family is currently under termination procedures;</text>
    <text>The Family is in a repayment agreement with DCHA, and has not paid it off;</text>
    <text>The Family has moved from its current unit in violation of the lease;</text>
    <text>The Family has not lived in DCHA jurisdiction for at least twelve (12) months since being admitted into the Program;</text>
    <text>The requested move is not in compliance with chapter 85 of this title of the DCMR; or</text>
    <text>DCHA does not have the sufficient funding for continued assistance to support the move.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5501.2.</num>
    <text>If DCHA denies a Family portability for any of the reasons in § 5501.1, within ten (10) days of the decision, DCHA shall provide written notice to the participant or applicant of the specific basis for the denial and of its right to an informal hearing
      or review in accordance with chapter 89 of this title of the DCMR.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5501.3</num>
    <text>5501.3 If a Family requests portability under the protections of VAWA, DCHA shall request that the Family provide one (1) of the following documents:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The HUD-approved certification HUD Form-50066;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Federal, state, tribal, territorial, or local police record;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Documentation signed by an employee, agent, or volunteer of a victim service provider, or an attorney or medical provider from whom the victim has sought assistance in the situation; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Other acceptable documentation in order to verify the Family’s claim that the request to move is prompted by an instance or incidences of abuse.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 7926 (June 29, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>