<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-5405</num>
  <heading>FAMILY RELATIONSHIPS (ยง 14-5405)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5405.1.</num>
    <text>Applicants and program participants shall identify the relationship of each household member to the Head of Household with the following types of documents:</text>
    <text>Marriage:</text>
    <text>Marriage Certificate;</text>
    <text>Marriage License;</text>
    <text>Proof of Common Law Marriage Recognition; or</text>
    <text>Official IRS Tax Records;</text>
    <text>Separation or Divorce:</text>
    <text>Certified Copy of Divorce Decree;</text>
    <text>Court Record documenting separation;</text>
    <text>Evidence of annulment; or</text>
    <text>If there is no court order, documentation from clergy, social service providers or other community members;</text>
    <text>To prove the absence of a Family member, the Family shall supply verification in accordance with ยง 5318.3 and ยง 5318.4;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>To prove that a Family has been abandoned by the Head of Household, a remaining household member must provide one of the following types of documents:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Certification from a social service agency;</text>
    </level>
    <text>Information from child support enforcement agency;</text>
    <text>Documentation of legal action against parent or guardian;</text>
    <text>Documentation that the Head of Household is incarcerated; or</text>
    <text>Other acceptable documentation as determined by DCHA on a case-by-case basis; or</text>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>To prove the existence of a foster relationship, the Head of Household shall provide one (1) of the following forms of documentation:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Verification from the state or local government agency responsible for the placement of the individual with the Family is required; or</text>
    <text>Written verification from a biological parent sufficient to show a Family or custodial relationship with the participant and the child or children.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 7916, 7921 (June 29, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>