<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-5808</num>
  <heading>FAMILY OBLIGATIONS TO AVOID TERMINATION (§ 14-5808)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5808.1.</num>
    <text>The Family shall:</text>
    <text>Supply such certification, release, information or documentation as DCHA or HUD determines to be necessary, including submission of required evidence of citizenship or eligible alien status, and submissions required for an annual or interim recertification
      of Family income and composition;</text>
    <text>Allow DCHA to inspect the dwelling unit at reasonable times and after reasonable notice;</text>
    <text>Notify DCHA before vacating the dwelling unit;</text>
    <text>Use the dwelling unit solely for residence by the Family, and as the Family’s principal place of residence; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Promptly give DCHA a copy of a Writ of Restitution received when an Owner seeks to remove the family from the unit within ten (10) days of the date of the notice.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5808.2.</num>
    <text>The Family shall not:</text>
    <text>Own or have any interest in the unit except for participants in the Home Ownership Assistance Program (HOAP) as further explained in chapter 92 of this title of the DCMR, other than in a cooperative;</text>
    <text>Commit any fraud in connection with the HCVP;</text>
    <text>Receive duplicative housing assistance under the HCVP while occupying, or receiving housing assistance for occupancy of, any other unit assisted under any Federal housing assistance program (including any Section 8 program); or</text>
    <text>Sublease or assign the lease or transfer the unit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5808.4.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall terminate assistance if:</text>
    <text>A Family fails to submit required documentation within the required timeframe concerning any Family member’s citizenship or immigration status as enumerated in chapter 54 of this title of the DCMR;</text>
    <text>A Family submits evidence of citizenship and eligible immigration status in a timely manner, but USCIS primary and secondary verification does not verify eligible immigration status of the Family;</text>
    <text>A Family member, as determined by DCHA, has knowingly permitted another individual who is not eligible for assistance to reside (on a permanent basis) in the unit.</text>
    <text>A Family is not receiving HAP assistance for more than twelve (12) months due to an increase in income; or</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5808.5.</num>
    <text>For § 5908.4(c), such termination shall be for a period of at least twenty-four (24) months. This does not apply to ineligible noncitizens already in the household where the Family’s assistance has been prorated.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5808.6.</num>
    <text>A Family shall not receive HCVP assistance while residing in a unit owned by a parent, child, grandparent, grandchild, sister, or brother of any member of the Family, except as a reasonable accommodation that DCHA approves.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5808.7.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall determine if a Family has committed serious or repeated violations of the lease based on available evidence, including but not limited to, a court-ordered eviction or a writ of possession. Such violations may include, but are not limited
      to:</text>
    <text>Nonpayment of rent;</text>
    <text>Disturbance of neighbors;</text>
    <text>Destruction of property;</text>
    <text>Living or housekeeping habits that cause damage to the unit or premises; and</text>
    <text>Criminal activity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 7942, 7950 (June 29, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>