<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-5103</num>
  <heading>MANDATORY SOCIAL SECURITY NUMBERS (ยง 14-5103)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5103.1.</num>
    <text>Each Family member claiming U.S. citizenship or eligible immigration status shall be required to disclose and verify a Social Security Number (SSN) prior to admission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5103.2.</num>
    <text>Applicant families who cannot disclose and verify SSNs for all Family members claiming citizenship or eligible immigration status shall be allowed to retain their position on the waiting list. A Family shall not be admitted into the HCVP until all
      Family members claiming U.S. citizenship or eligible immigration status have disclosed and verified SSNs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5103.3.</num>
    <text>U.S. citizens and lawfully present noncitizens who state that they have not been assigned a SSN by the Social Security Administration (SSA) shall make such declaration in writing and under penalties of perjury to DCHA. DCHA shall maintain the declaration
      in the participant file until a SSN is assigned.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5103.4.</num>
    <text>Applicant families who will receive assistance under the Moderate Rehabilitation Single Room Occupancy Program shall have ninety (90) days after admission into the Program to provide appropriate documentation of their SSN.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5103.5.</num>
    <text>For families currently participating, the Family shall be required to disclose and verify SSNs for all Family members claiming U.S. citizenship or eligible immigration status at the time of their next interim recertification or regular recertification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5103.6.</num>
    <text>The only HUD-approved forms of verification of Social Security Numbers are:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An original SSN card issued by SSA;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An original SSA-issued document that contains the name and SSN of the individual; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An original document issued by a federal, state, or local government agency that contains the name and SSN of the individual.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5103.7.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall use an Alternate ID (ALTD ID) to generate a unique identifier for those individuals who do not have or unable to disclose a SSN.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 7867, 7871 (June 29, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>