<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-511</num>
  <heading>REFRIGERATION AND AIR CONDITIONING PERMIT FEES (§ 14-511)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>511.1.</num>
    <text>For purposes of the fee schedule, refrigeration systems shall be classified according to the net refrigeration effect in British thermal units (B.T.U.) per hour developed by the system as certified by the manufacturer. The following schedule of fees
      shall apply to refrigeration and air conditioning permits:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Class A &amp;#8211; system developing a net refrigeration effect of two million four hundred thousand (2,400,000) B.T.U. per hour or more $225.00;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Class B &amp;#8211; system developing a net effect of one million two hundred thousand (1,200,000) or more B.T.U. per hour but less than two million four hundred thousand (2,440,000) B.T.U. per hour $139.00;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Class C &amp;#8211; system developing a net refrigeration effect of six hundred thousand (600,000) or more B.T.U. per hour but less than one million two hundred thousand (1,200,000) B.T.U. per hour $105.00;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Class D &amp;#8211; system developing a net refrigeration effect of one hundred twenty thousand (120,000) or more B.T.U. per hour $42.00; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Class E &amp;#8211; system developing a net refrigeration effect of less than one hundred twenty thousand (120,000) B.T.U. per hour $22.00.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>511.2.</num>
    <text>A refund of permit fees shall be made as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>When no work has been done under authority of permit, the fee in excess of the cost of inspection to verify no work having been done, based on thirteen dollars per inspector hour ($13.00/hr), the cost of any engineering examination time previously
        devoted to approval of plans, based on twenty dollars per hour ($20.00/hr.), plus nineteen dollars ($19.00) administrative costs of “issuance and refund,” shall be refunded at nineteen dollars ($19.00) per hour;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>When work authorized by permit has been only partially done and when the District is satisfied that no more work will be done under the permit, the fee in excess of the cost of any engineering plans examination based on twenty dollars per hour ($20.00/hr.),
        plus nineteen dollars ($19.00) administrative costs of “issuance and refund,” shall be refunded at nineteen dollars ($19.00) per hour; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If a request for refund is made within six (6) months from date of issuance and the permit and receipt are returned to the Permit Branch.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>511.3.</num>
    <text>The penalty for a permit to abate notice of doing work without a permit shall be fifty percent (50%) of the fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>511.4.</num>
    <text>No permit fee shall be charged when supported by evidence indicating that the applicant is under contract or subcontract to perform the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Work done exclusively for the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Work done under contract for the District; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Work done exclusively for agencies of the United States Government.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 3326, 3329 (August 1, 1980).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>