<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-6124</num>
  <heading>INITIAL FAMILY COMPOSITION GUIDELINES FOR HOUSING CHOICE VOUCHER APPLICANTS (§4-6124)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6124.1.</num>
    <text>Individuals named and listed in the pre-application shall determine the initial composition of an assisted Family and be confirmed at the full application stage of the application process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6124.2.</num>
    <text>Each applicant Family shall identify a single Head of Household. The Head of Household shall ensure that the Family complies with all program rules and Family obligations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6124.3</num>
    <text>6124.3 The Head of Household is the only person allowed to request informal hearings or informal reviews on behalf of the Family.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6124.4</num>
    <text>6124.4 Nothing in this section shall limit the responsibilities of the Spouse or other adult Family members to comply with all Family obligations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6124.5</num>
    <text>6124.5 A Family may not designate a Family member as Head of Household solely to qualify the Family as an Elderly Household.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6124.6.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall not assign any other adults of household composition as a “co-Head of Household.”</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6124.7</num>
    <text>6124.7 The Spouse shall not be considered “co-Head of Household.”</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6124.8.</num>
    <text>A marriage relationship created by agreement and cohabitation rather than by ceremony or certificate shall be recognized. The Spouse shall comply with all Family obligations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6124.9.</num>
    <text>Other adult Family members are required to comply with all Family obligations. Other Adult is defined in § 5999.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6124.10.</num>
    <text>Dependents who are subject to a joint custody arrangement shall be considered a member of the Family if they live with the applicant or participant Family fifty-one percent (51%) or more of the time or are otherwise designated by a Shared Parenting
      Agreement to the parent who maintains primary residence of the child or children.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6124.11</num>
    <text>6124.11 Individuals with joint custody arrangements for a dependent child or children shall be required to provide documentation of joint custody or evidence of the primary residence of a child or the children.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6124.12.</num>
    <text>When more than one (1) Family claims the same dependents as Family members, the Family with primary custody or primary residence as set forth in a judgment or court decision at the time of the initial examination or recertification shall be able to
      claim the dependents as members of their Family for purposes of HCVP eligibility and benefits.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6124.13.</num>
    <text>If there is no relevant judgment or court decision establishing that Family member’s primary custody or primary residence, then DCHA shall make the determination based on other available documents such as:</text>
    <text>Court orders;</text>
    <text>School enrollment records;</text>
    <text>Benefit/subsidy records; or</text>
    <text>Internal Revenue Service (IRS) tax return showing which Family has claimed the child for income tax purposes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 7963 (June 29, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>