<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-6202</num>
  <heading>EXCESS UTILITY CHARGES (§ 14-6202)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6202.1.</num>
    <text>Tenants who do not pay for their own electricity shall be charged reasonable amounts for electricity consumed as a result of major electrical appliances which are not provided by DCHA. Major electrical appliances include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Clothes dryer(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Food freezer(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Additional refrigerator/freezer(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Air conditioner(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Washing machine(s); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Dish washers.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6202.2.</num>
    <text>Excess utility charges for air conditioners shall only be applied during the months of May, June, July, August and September.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6202.3.</num>
    <text>Excess utility charges and any revisions to these charges, shall be established by DCHA on the basis of the provisions of § 6201 of this chapter, including consumption calculations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6202.4.</num>
    <text>It is the responsibility of the tenant to obtain the approval of DCHA prior to the installation of any electrical appliance listed in § 6202. 1. Excess utility charges shall be incurred at the start of the month following installation. DCHA shall
      prepare and execute a special supplement to the lease to reflect excess utility charges.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6202.5.</num>
    <text>Excess utility charges required under §§ 6202.1 and 6202.7 shall not become due and collectible until the first (1st) day of the second month following the month in which the charge is incurred.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6202.6.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of a report from a tenant indicating an appliance is inoperable in his or her unit, DCHA shall assess the applicable charge until such time as the appliance in question is removed from the dwelling unit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6202.7.</num>
    <text>Tenants who do not pay for their own utilities, but who occupy a unit with a checkmeter system for individual units, shall be charged reasonable amounts for utility consumption in excess of the appropriate utility allowance established by DCHA for
      that unit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6202.8.</num>
    <text>Where DCHA converts a specific property to a checkmeter system, there shall be a transition period of at least six (6) months during which no excess utility charges shall be charged against the tenant. During this transition period, DCHA shall do
      the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Advise the tenant of the amounts which would be charged, based on checkmeter readings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Advise tenants with high utility consumption rates on methods for reducing their usage; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Give specific thirty (30) day notice to the tenant of the effective date after which utility charges shall be assessed. DCHA shall prepare and execute a special supplement to the lease to implement excess utility charges related to checkmeter systems.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 7973, 8005-8006 (December 26, 1986); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 9814 (October 26, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>