<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-6116</num>
  <heading>MOVE-IN REQUIREMENTS (§ 14-6116)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6116.1.</num>
    <text>Applicants from the waiting list who accept a unit shall pay one (1) month’s tenant rent and a security deposit prior to signing the dwelling lease. All rent and security deposits shall be paid by check or money order only.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6116.2.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall determine if the applicant&amp;#8217;s application is current, shall schedule an appointment with the applicant, and at the appointment shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Review and complete all required certifications of eligibility and the dwelling lease; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Obtain the applicant&amp;#8217;s signature on all required documents.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6116.3.</num>
    <text>The tenant shall attend any training required by DCHA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6116.4.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall schedule a move-in date for the new tenant upon execution of the documents described in Subsection 6114.2 and shall provide the new tenant with copies. DCHA shall also conduct a move-in inspection in accordance with Section 6505 of this
      Subtitle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 603 (January 22, 1999), incorporating by reference the text of Notice of Proposed Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 7913, 7914 (November 6, 1998); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at
        50 DCR 5739 (July 18, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 10347 (December 5, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 8104 (August 20, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 9184 (September
        24, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>