<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-6110</num>
  <heading>OCCUPANCY STANDARDS (ยง 14-6110)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6110.1.</num>
    <text>Standards for admission and continued occupancy shall be established to avoid overcrowding and wasted space, and each dwelling unit shall be leased in accordance with the standards of this Subtitle and Subtitle A of this Title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6110.2.</num>
    <text>Tenants shall be assigned to dwelling units which consist of the number of rooms necessary to provide decent, safe and sanitary accommodations without overcrowding or wasting space. The following standards for unit size at admission, and for continued
      occupancy, shall apply:</text>
    <text>Unit Size(Number of Bedrooms)</text>
    <text>Minimum Number ofPersons in Unit</text>
    <text>Maximum Number ofPersons in Unit</text>
    <text>0</text>
    <text>1</text>
    <text>1</text>
    <text>1</text>
    <text>1</text>
    <text>2</text>
    <text>2</text>
    <text>2</text>
    <text>4</text>
    <text>3</text>
    <text>4</text>
    <text>6</text>
    <text>4</text>
    <text>6</text>
    <text>8</text>
    <text>5</text>
    <text>8</text>
    <text>10</text>
    <text>6</text>
    <text>10</text>
    <text>12</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6110.3.</num>
    <text>Dwelling units shall be assigned in a manner that will eliminate the need for persons of the opposite sex, other than husband and wife, to occupy the same bedroom.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6110.4.</num>
    <text>Every member of the family, regardless of age, shall be considered a person when applying the standards for admission and continued occupancy. In accordance with Chapter 74, DCHA will consider unit assignment to a larger size to provide a separate
      bedroom for a disabled person, if verified as medically necessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6110.5.</num>
    <text>Each dwelling unit shall be used solely as a residence for the tenant and the tenant&amp;#8217;s family as represented in the application for housing, and the dwelling lease.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6110.6.</num>
    <text>When possible, occupancy shall be restricted at admission to minimum requirements to allow for family growth.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6110.7.</num>
    <text>Application of occupancy requirements for continued occupancy shall be consistent with Subsection 6114.7 and Subsection 6205.2 of this Subtitle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 7973, 7999 (December 26, 1986); and Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 603 (January 22, 1999), incorporating by reference the text of Notice of Proposed Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 7913,
        7914 (November 6, 1998); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 5739 (July 18, 2003); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 10361 (December 5, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>