<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-6000</num>
  <heading>SCOPE OF PROGRAM (§ 14-6000)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6000.1.</num>
    <text>Chapters 60 through 65 set forth rules which govern the operation of low rent housing in the District of Columbia, under the authority of the District of Columbia Housing Authority Act of 1999, D.C. Official Code §§ 6-201- 6-225 (2001).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6000.2.</num>
    <text>Principal funding for the operation of low rent housing in the District of Columbia is provided by the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (“HUD”) under the United States Housing Act of 1937 (42 U.S.C. §§ 1437 et seq.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6000.3.</num>
    <text>The provision of such funding requires compliance with Federal law and the applicable provisions of the Code of Federal Regulations relating to low rent housing. Any change in Federal law or regulation shall be complied with under the terms of the
      Annual Contributions Contract between the District of Columbia Housing Authority and HUD.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6000.4.</num>
    <text>Rules set forth in chapters 60 through 65 shall reflect the requirements of Federal law as detailed by HUD in the Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is the District of Columbia Alley Dwelling Act, as amended, Public, No. 307, 47 Stat. 930, approved June 12, 1934; Executive Order 11401 effective March 13, 1968, 33 F.R. 4559 (March 15, 1968);
        section 5 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1975, 21 DCR 2793 (April 21, 1975); and subsection III.B.(1) of Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1987, December 15, 1987.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 7973 (December 26, 1986); and Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 603 (January 22, 1999), incorporating by reference the text of Notice of Proposed Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 7913 (November
        6, 1998).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR’S NOTE</heading>
      <text>The rules governing low income housing in the District of Columbia which implement the District of Columbia Alley Dwelling Act of 1934 were originally adopted by the Director of the District of Columbia Department of Housing and Community Development
        (“DHCD”) acting on behalf the National Capital Housing Authority pursuant to Reorganization Plan 3 of 1975. See Preamble to Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 7973 (December 26, 1986). Under Part III.B.(1) of Reorganization Plan No.
        1 of 1987, the National Capital Housing Authority was abolished and all of its functions under the District of Columbia Alley Dwelling Act of 1934 were transferred to the Department of Public and Assisted Housing (“DPAH”). DPAH operated low rent
        housing through the Housing Management Administration (“HMA”). D.C. Law 10-243, the “District of Columbia Housing Authority Act of 1994,” abolished DPAH and established the District of Columbia Housing Authority (DCHA) as a corporate body and
        legal instrumentality of the government of the District of Columbia. Pursuant to D.C. Law 10-243, all of DPAH’s functions under the District of Columbia Alley Dwelling Act were transferred to DCHA. D.C. Law 13-105, the “District of Columbia Housing
        Authority Act of 1999,” repealed D.C. Law 10-243 and re-established the DCHA as an independent authority of the District government and the successor in interest to the former housing authority. Accordingly, the acronyms “DHCD,” “DPAH” or “HMA”
        which appeared in chapters 60 through 65 of the July 1991 edition of this title have been substituted with “DCHA.”</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>