<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-6211</num>
  <heading>PET OWNERSHIP IN PUBLIC HOUSING (ยง 14-6211)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6211.1.</num>
    <text>Pets Generally Prohibited. Pets are not generally permitted at DCHA properties, except as provided in subsection 6211.2 and 6211.3 herein.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6211.2.</num>
    <text>Prior Ownership. Residents of Elderly-only and Mixed population properties who own a pet that resides in their unit prior to May 1, 2005, may continue to own a pet that is otherwise not prohibited under Subsection 6211.3(a) below, provided the resident
      complies with the requirements of Subsections 6211.4(a) and (c) on or before July 1, 2005.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6211.3.</num>
    <text>Animal Limitations.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Under no circumstances shall animals whose natural protective mechanisms pose a risk of serious bites and lacerations, or are considered to be, or are found to be, dangerous, aggressive, vicious, intimidating or detrimental to the health and safety
        of other residents or employees, be permitted as pets. Snakes or other types of undomesticated animals are not permitted as pets.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Dogs in excess of 25 pounds are only permitted if they are:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Approved as a service animal in accordance with Chapter 74 of this title as a reasonable accommodation; or</text>
    </level>
    <text>(ii) Otherwise are eligible under the prior ownership provisions of Section 6211.2(a).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6211.4.</num>
    <text>Registration Requirements. Residents at any DCHA-owned property who are permitted to have a pet under the provisions of 6211.2 may keep an animal, subject to the restrictions in Subsection 6211.3, provided they also comply with the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Register the animal with the property manager;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Update the registration for the animal annually;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Provide proof the animal has been inoculated in accordance with applicable local law;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Execute a lease addendum providing for the proper care and maintenance of the animal and the unit occupied by the animal in accordance with DCHA rules; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Continuously provide the proper maintenance and care for the animal and assure that the animal does not otherwise impair the peaceful enjoyment of the property by other residents.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6211.5.</num>
    <text>After the effective date of these regulations, no pet shall be brought to reside on any DCHA property prior to registration and compliance with the requirements of Subsections 6211.4(a), (c) and (d).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6211.6.</num>
    <text>A request to register a pet in public housing under the provisions of 6211.2 above that is denied for any reason is subject to the grievance procedure provided in Chapter 63 of this Title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 4214 (April 29, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>