<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-6106</num>
  <heading>ELIGIBILITY (§ 14-6106)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6106.1.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall consider an applicant eligible for selection for public housing or the Housing Choice Voucher Program if the applicant meets the following criteria:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Qualifies as a family, as defined in Section 6099 of this Chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Annual income does not exceed the income limits for admission under Section 6108 of this Chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Family meets applicant family selection criteria under Section 6109 of this Chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Family size meets the occupancy standards established by DCHA under Section 6110 of this Chapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Family provides all required information and signs all required documentation, including proof of citizenship or eligible immigrant status.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.2.</num>
    <text>As applicants near the top of the waiting list, the Client Placement Division will mail written notice to the last address provided in order to obtain information needed for a determination of eligibility. The letter will state:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The date and time of the eligibility interview;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The location where the eligibility interview will be held; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The documents the applicant should bring to the eligibility interview.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.3.</num>
    <text>A family or applicant may make one request to reschedule an eligibility interview for the convenience of the applicant up to thirty (30) days after the scheduled eligibility interview date. However, DCHA will reschedule an eligibility interview as
      a reasonable accommodation if the applicant can demonstrate that a disability prevented them from rescheduling within the prescribed time period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.4.</num>
    <text>If an applicant does not respond to notice of an eligibility interview and does not request an alternate appointment in advance of the scheduled interview date, then the applicant shall be deemed inactive on the waiting list for the type housing assistance
      offered. If the applicant informs DCHA that the applicant remains in need of the housing assistance at any time after the scheduled interview date, then the applicant shall be restored to active status on the waiting list for the relevant type of
      housing assistance with the applicant&amp;#8217;s original application date. The applicant shall be scheduled for another eligibility interview based on the restored application date and any updated applicant information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.5.</num>
    <text>The eligibility interview will be held in order to collect eligibility data, determine eligibility and identify any special problems or needs. As part of the eligibility determination, an applicant will be provided the opportunity to complete a reasonable
      accommodation request. All information shall be verified as a part of the eligibility determination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.6.</num>
    <text>During the eligibility interview, the Client Placement Division shall assist the applicant in completing any forms necessary. The following forms are to be completed or signed by the applicant:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Privacy Act Notice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Asset Certification Form – only assets with a value greater that $15,000 or which generate a net income of greater than $1,000 per year must be reported and documented. DCHA will rely on applicants certification as to value of assets and whether
        net income from assets exceeds the threshold established above;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Verification of Date of Birth for each Household Member;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Social Security Number Certifications:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Social Security Numbers for each Household Member 6 year old or older; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Certification of inability to meet the documentation requirement where an applicant has a Social Security Number but no documentation; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Certification that Social Security Numbers have not been issued.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Picture ID for family members age eighteen (18) or older;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Declaration of Section 214 Status (Non-citizen Rule);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Verification of Preference or Admission Category;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Verification of Full-time Student Status Form;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Certification of Disability Form;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Statement of Child Care Expense Form;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Zero Income Statement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Verification of Income from Assets;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Statement of Child Support;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>Income Verification (Employment, Public Assistance, Social Security); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>Other Forms as may be required.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.7.</num>
    <text>At the end of the eligibility interview, the Client Placement Division shall provide the applicant with written notification of any missing or incomplete forms, information on how to determine if any debt remains unpaid to DCHA or any HCVP landlord,
      or any additional information which is to be provided by the applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.8.</num>
    <text>If an applicant cannot complete all the necessary forms at the time of the interview, the interviewer may request that any additional required forms be completed by the applicant within a specified timeframe not to exceed ten (10) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.9.</num>
    <text>A written receipt shall be provided to the applicant for any additional information provided.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.10.</num>
    <text>Applicants who do not provide the additional items requested by DCHA pursuant to Subsection 6106.8 within ten (10) days, may request one (1) extension of time not to exceed ten (10) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.11.</num>
    <text>Applicants who do not provide additional items requested by DCHA pursuant to Subsection 6106.8 within ten (10) days, or within any additional period allowed under Subsection 6106.9, shall be removed from the waiting list.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6106.12.</num>
    <text>If an applicant experiences difficulty in securing verification in the prescribed form, DCHA may accept other documents to expedite the certification process (for example, baptismal or school records could be used as proof of birth).</text>
    <text>6106. 13 BRIEFINGS</text>
    <text>Applicants must attend a full briefing prior to issuance of a Housing Choice Voucher unless this requirement is waived by the Executive Director in emergency cases.</text>
    <text>DCHA will mail notice of the briefing via U.S. mail to the last address provided by the applicant or existing participant.</text>
    <text>Families or applicants who provide prior notice of inability to attend a briefing will automatically be scheduled for the next available briefing and notified by mail of its date and time. If a family or applicant fails to attend a scheduled briefing
      another notice will be mailed for a second briefing date.</text>
    <text>If an applicant fails to attend two (2) scheduled briefings, and does not notify DCHA in advance of their inability to attend the second briefing appointment, then the applicant shall be deemed inactive on the waiting list. If the applicant informs
      DCHA that the applicant remains in need of the housing assistance at any time after becoming inactive then the applicant shall be restored to active status on the waiting list with the applicant&amp;#8217;s original application date.</text>
    <text>If vouchers of the type that would have been issued to the applicant at the missed briefings are still available and the inactive applicant asserts the need for housing assistance less than thirty (30) days after initial eligibility determination
      then a new briefing appointment shall be made with the applicant.</text>
    <text>If the inactive applicant requests assistance more than thirty (30) days after the initial eligibility determination by DCHA, and vouchers of the type that would have been issued to the applicant at the missed briefings are still available; DCHA shall
      schedule the restored applicant for another eligibility interview. If the applicant is determined to be eligible, the applicant shall be scheduled for a full briefing. If vouchers of the type that would have been issued are not available, the applicant
      will be restored to the waiting list as an active applicant with the date and time of the original application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 7973, 7990 (December 26, 1986); and Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 603 (January 22, 1999), incorporating by reference the text of Notice of Proposed Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 7913,
        7914 (November 6, 1998); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 10308 (November 15, 2002); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 5739 (July 18, 2003); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published
        at 50 DCR 10352 (December 5, 2003), as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 2720 (April 10, 2009); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 8233, 8234 (September 23, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>