<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-6109</num>
  <heading>APPLICANT FAMILY SELECTION CRITERIA (§ 14-6109)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6109.1.</num>
    <text>This Section applies to applicants for public housing and to applicants for the Housing Choice Voucher Program. All Subsections of this Section are applicable to applicants for public housing. Only Subsections 6109.3, 6109.4, 6109.6, 6109.7 and 6109.8
      apply to both applicants for public housing and the Housing Choice Voucher Program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6109.2.</num>
    <text>Information that will be considered in screening an applicant shall be reasonably related to assessing the applicant and other applicant family members listed on the application. The applicant&amp;#8217;s history (e.g., employment history, personal
      habits or practices, and/or rental or personal credit history) must demonstrate the capacity to comply with the terms of the DCHA lease. If the applicant requires support (e.g., live-in aide) to enable him/her to meet the standards identified below,
      the applicant must demonstrate that the necessary support would be available at the time of admission. Additionally, the applicant, including the applicant&amp;#8217;s family must be willing to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Not interfere with other residents in such a manner as to diminish their peaceful enjoyment of the premises by adversely affecting the health, safety, or welfare of the other residents or the community;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Enhance and/or maintain the physical environment or financial stability of the project;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Help create an environment where young people, especially children, can live, learn, and develop into productive and responsible citizens;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Attend and complete DCHA’s Community Living Training Program, prior to admission; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Comply with the terms and conditions of the DCHA lease.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6109.3.</num>
    <text>DCHA will utilize the following methods in determining an applicant&amp;#8217;s eligibility for admission: reference checks, including current and/or previous landlords, consultations with current and/or former neighbors, conducting home visits, reviewing
      police reports and/or criminal background checks of each member of the applicant family, including juveniles, as may be permitted by law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6109.4.</num>
    <text>Relevant information respecting personal habits or practices to be considered in the admission process, may include, but is not limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A reasonable cause to believe, supported by signed documentation, that any family member&amp;#8217;s illegal use (or pattern of illegal use) of a controlled substance, or abuse (or pattern of abuse) of alcohol, may interfere with the health, safety,
        or right to peaceful enjoyment of any DCHA programs by other residents, employees or community members; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An applicant&amp;#8217;s past performance in meeting financial obligations, especially rental payment obligations. An applicant who is responsible for any debt to DCHA, any other housing authority, or any landlord participant in any federally assisted
        housing program (e.g., the Housing Choice Voucher Program) may not be admitted or readmitted until the debt is paid or otherwise satisfied; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A record of respecting the rights of others, as defined in the DCHA lease; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The conviction of any applicant family member for a crime involving physical violence against persons or property or other criminal convictions that may adversely affect the health, safety, or welfare of other DCHA residents, staff, or other members
        of the community, e.g., distribution or manufacture of illegal drugs or controlled substances, possession of an unlicensed firearm and/or ammunition, or child molestation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A determination that the applicant has committed fraud in connection with any Federal housing assistance program or any local housing assistance program; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>An applicant&amp;#8217;s misrepresentation of any information related to eligibility, including, but not limited to, the award of a preference for admission, family composition, or income.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6109.5.</num>
    <text>If an applicant is determined eligible and qualified for admission, the applicant will be referred to a public housing property for housing, consistent with Section 6111 of this Title. Notwithstanding, prior to the applicant signing a DCHA lease,
      if the relevant property manager uncovers information regarding the applicant that would lead a reasonable person to believe that housing the applicant on the relevant property would interfere with the other residents&amp;#8217; peaceful enjoyment
      of the premises by adversely affecting the health, safety, or welfare of the other residents or the community, the property manager shall so advise the Client Placement Division and refer the application for further consideration. The Client Placement
      Division will then conduct a further review of the application, taking into consideration the information provided.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6109.6.</num>
    <text>If unfavorable information is received as a result of the investigation conducted pursuant to Subsections 6109.2 or 6109.4 above, consideration shall be given to the time, nature, and extent of the applicant family&amp;#8217;s conduct, and to factors
      which might indicate a reasonable probability of favorable future conduct or financial prospects. Mitigating circumstances might include, but are not limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Evidence of favorable changes in the applicant&amp;#8217;s pattern of behavior including the length of time since an offense or behavior was committed; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Evidence of successful rehabilitation, e.g., evidence that the responsible member of the applicant family is not likely to repeat the prior criminal behavior, evidence that neither the applicant nor any member of the applicant family is likely to
        cause harm to the other public housing or Housing Choice Voucher Program residents, DCHA staff, or other members of the community; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Evidence of the applicant&amp;#8217;s participation in or willingness to participate in relevant social service activities or other appropriate counseling services; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Evidence of the applicant&amp;#8217;s modification of previous disqualifying behavior, with indications of continuing support intended to assist the applicant in modifying the disqualifying behaviors.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6109.7.</num>
    <text>With respect to criminal conviction(s) or activity:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The DCHA may deny admission to public housing or the Housing Choice Voucher Program to any applicant:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If any adult member of the applicant&amp;#8217;s family (or any non-adult member who has been convicted of a crime as an adult) has been convicted of a felony, or a misdemeanor involving destruction of property or acts of violence against another
        person; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the applicant or a member of the applicant&amp;#8217;s family has participated in violent criminal behavior within the last five years for which he/she has not been convicted. This violent criminal behavior must be documented by an arrest record,
        parole violation report, law enforcement criminal history report, or other official law enforcement record.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>DCHA shall deny admission to any applicant who has been evicted from housing assisted under the United States Housing Act, for drug-related criminal activity for a three year period beginning from the date of the eviction.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>In determining whether an applicant, as identified in Subparagraphs (a) and/or (b) will be admitted into public housing or the Housing Choice Voucher Program, DCHA shall make an assessment of the applicant&amp;#8217;s (or the relevant member of
        the applicant&amp;#8217;s family) behavior to determine whether he/she currently demonstrates that he/she has been rehabilitated. Factors that DCHA may consider include, but are not limited to, the following: acknowledgment of culpability; adequate
        and suitable employment or participation in a generally recognized training program; substance abuse treatment, if necessary; successful completion of therapy directed at correcting the behavior that lead to the criminal activity; and existence
        of a support network or support systems.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>In collecting relevant information necessary to make the assessment described in Subparagraph (c) above, DCHA shall, at its sole discretion, determine the extent and depth of the verification for each applicant. Information may be requested from
        various sources, including, but not limited to, the applicant (by interview and/or home visit), landlords, clergy, employers, family members, social workers, parole officers, court records, drug treatment counselors, neighbors, and/or police department
        records.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>DCHA shall prohibit admission of any family that includes any individual who is subject to a lifetime registration requirement under any sex offender registration program (e.g., state, local or international). DCHA shall, upon request, provide the
        tenant or applicant with a copy of the registration information and an opportunity to dispute the accuracy and relevance of that information.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>DCHA shall prohibit admission for any individual that has ever been convicted of drug-related criminal activity for the manufacture or production of methamphetamine or production of methamphetamine on the premises of federally assisted housing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6109.8.</num>
    <text>Care and consideration shall be used in soliciting personal information concerning the applicant and his/her family members, and appropriate authorizations shall be obtained for the release of information, as necessary, from each applicant family.
      Any information received regarding an individual applicant will be used solely for the purpose of determining eligibility and will not be released for any other use, unless such release is required by law. Failure to sign the required release forms
      or the failure to submit information determined necessary to establish eligibility, shall result in the applicant&amp;#8217;s removal from the waiting list. If the applicant is removed from the waiting list because of such a failure, the informal
      conference procedures set forth in Section 6107 shall not apply.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6109.9.</num>
    <text>The DCHA Applicant Family Selection Criteria will not be used to determine eligibility of residents for continuing occupancy in the same public housing unit. Eligibility for continuing occupancy in the same unit will be made in accordance with the
      terms and conditions of the DCHA lease.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6109.10.</num>
    <text>Resident requests for transfers will be subject to this Section &amp;#8211; Applicant Family Selection Criteria- and shall be a requirement for transfer of residents and the execution of new leases. This Section will not be applicable to DCHA initiated
      transfers or approved emergency medical transfers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 7973, 7998 (December 26, 1986); and Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 603 (January 22, 1999), incorporating by reference the text of Notice of Proposed Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 7913,
        7914 (November 6, 1998); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 5739 (July 18, 2003); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 10357 (December 5, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>