<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-6119</num>
  <heading>REPORTING CHANGE OF INCOME AND INTERIM RECERTIFICATION (ยง 14-6119)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6119.1.</num>
    <text>It shall be the Lessee&amp;#8217;s responsibility to report to DCHA complete and accurate information of all members of the family, including any change in family circumstances, within thirty (30) days of the change. Changes in family circumstances
      include but are not limited to changes in family size, such as additions or removals of household members, and income. The Lessee&amp;#8217;s responsibility to report any change in family circumstances, includes but is not limited to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Lessee shall provide to DCHA proof of educational enrollment in an educational facility of any household member that Lessee is seeking to add pursuant to Chapter 61 of this Title;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Lessee shall obtain all supplemental information and required signatures as DCHA may reasonably require, from other household members;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Lessees who wish to remove a household member from the household shall have the burden of proof that such person has permanently vacated the Leased Premises and must submit documentation satisfactory to DCHA that the household member is residing
        elsewhere including but not limited to any one or a combination of the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A lease for another unit;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A utility bill for another unit;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Government issued ID issued after the date the household member vacated the leased premises;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>U.S. Postal Service change of address form;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>School records;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Government benefit records; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Other documentary proof satisfactory to the DCHA;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>If the lessee is unable to produce documentation satisfactory to the DCHA, the DCHA shall remove the individual from the Household Composition upon Lessee&amp;#8217;s submission of a form: (1) attesting under the penalty of perjury that the individual
        has permanently vacated he Leased Premises; (2) stating that the Lessee has been unable to provide the written documentation of the member&amp;#8217;s absence and requiring the Lessee to explain why he or she was unable to do so; and (3) stating
        that the DCHA reserves the right to inspect the unit for the next 90 days if necessary to verify the household member&amp;#8217;s absence from the unit;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any household member who begins employment or begins to receive any benefits or other source of income;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>DCHA shall have the right to require the Lessee to attend a rent review meeting upon written request. Lessee may request a rent review through the manager of his property at any time upon written request. Lessee shall attend any meetings held to
        conduct the rent review at the time and place specified by DCHA or, if requested by the Lessee, at an alternative time during normal DCHA hours. Lessee shall provide to DCHA complete and accurate information, including documentation, as specified
        by DCHA; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>If the Lessee has failed to comply with this subsection, including but not limited to misrepresentation or failure to submit timely to DCHA any facts used in the determination of rent, whether intentionally or by mistake, DCHA may charge and collect
        as rent the difference between the rent actually paid and the rent which would have been due had the proper information been submitted timely by the Lessee. This amount shall be posted to the Lessee&amp;#8217;s account. Lessee shall receive written
        notice of the new amount which shall be due as stated in the notice, but not less than thirty (30) days from the date of the notice. A failure to accurately report income, deductions, family composition, or any other information may result in
        legal action being taken by DCHA or law enforcement agencies.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 603 (January 22, 1999), incorporating by reference the text of Notice of Proposed Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 7913, 7914 (November 6, 1998); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at
        50 DCR 5739 (July 18, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 10347 (December 5, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 8104 (August 20, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 9184 (September
        24, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 12303 (December 21, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>