<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-6118</num>
  <heading>RECERTIFICATION (§ 14-6118)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6118.1</num>
    <text>6118.1 Lessee shall recertify, biennially, and shall be responsible forroviding to DCHA a completed application for continued occupancy, including theppropriate verification forms. The forms are those provided by or otherwiseuthorized by DCHA. The
      Lessee’s responsibility to provide a completedpplication for continued occupancy, including the appropriate verificationorms shall include but is not limited to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Lessees shall be required to return the recertification package includingny required substantiating documentation or verification forms to DCHA withinhirty (30) days of receipt of the recertification package;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Lessee shall obtain from other household members any information,ocumentation and signatures, as DCHA may require, when submitting a completedpplication for continued occupancy, including the appropriate verificationorms as DCHA may require;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Lessee shall provide DCHA, for each household member, to DCHA a listingf the exact amount of income or benefits, from whatever source and the exactource of the income or benefit;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Lessee shall provide certification from all adult household members thatheir income has been accurately reported;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Lessee shall provide the full name, gender, Social Security Number and datef birth for each household member;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Lessee shall provide to DCHA proof of the Lessee&amp;#8217;s and/or anyousehold member&amp;#8217;s enrollment in an educational facility and shall providehis information for any household member that Lessee is seeking to add;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Lessee&amp;#8217;s who wish to remove a household member from the householdhall have the burden of proof that such person has permanently vacated theeased Premises and must submit documents satisfactory to DCHA, in accordanceith Subsection 6119.1,
        that the household member is residing elsewhere; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>If the Lessee has misrepresented or failed to submit timely to DCHA anyacts used in the determination of rent, whether intentionally or by mistake,CHA may charge and collect as rent the difference between the rent actuallyaid and the rent which
        would have been due had the proper information beenubmitted timely by the Lessee. This amount, the basis for the charge, andotice of the Lessee&amp;#8217;s grievance rights will be made available to lesseen writing by DCHA. This amount shall be
        posted to the Lessee&amp;#8217;s accountnd rent statement. Lessee shall receive written notice of the new amount whichhall be due as stated in the notice, but not less than thirty (30) days fromhe date of the notice A failure to accurately report
        income, deductions, familyomposition, or any other information may result in legal action being taken byCHA or law enforcement agencies.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 603 (January 22, 1999),ncorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 45 DCR913, 7914 (November 6, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50CR 5739 (July 18, 2003); as amended
        by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR0347 (December 5, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR104 (August 20, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 9184September 24, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 54 DCR 12303December 21, 2007); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 16066November 22, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>