<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-7138</num>
  <heading>PROGRESSIVE DISCIPLINE (§ 14-7138)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7138.1.</num>
    <text>Progressive disciplinary action against an employee is short of removal and must provide notice to the employee and the possible consequences of such discipline. The Disciplinary Action Notice must delineate the problem, the employee’s required action
      to correct the behavior, and the consequences if corrective action is not taken. Written warnings and corrective actions must be discussed with the employee. Supervisors must give employees one (1) corrective action warning for violations of policy,
      departmental rules or regulations, HUD rules and regulations, or acts of misconduct, as a means of progressive discipline, prior to issuing a Disciplinary Action Notice. However, under appropriate circumstances, immediate dismissal may be warranted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7138.2.</num>
    <text>The following offenses shall be cause for progressive discipline whenever practicable:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Unauthorized absence from duty under circumstances different from those authorized by this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Failure to observe safety regulations, other than as authorized by this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Sexual harassment which has the effect of unreasonably interfering with an employee’s work performance or which creates an intimidating, hostile, or offensive working environment, and which does not involve the effects described in § 7141(r);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Habitual tardiness;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Abuse of sick leave;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Failure to maintain a satisfactory working relationship with other employees, the public or residents;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Failure to do assigned work which includes, but is not limited to, the failure of supervisors to conduct performance reviews or file the “end of probationary period” notification in a timely manner;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Discourtesy and rudeness toward residents, the public, or co-workers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Unauthorized operation or use of any vehicles, machines or equipment of the Authority;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Neglect in care or use of Authority property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Unauthorized performance of work by non-exempt employees outside of established work schedules without the supervisor’s knowledge or approval;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Driving an Authority vehicle or personal vehicle when performing Authority business if employee is uninsurable under Authority insurance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Failure to report an accident, involving a DCHA vehicle, to the Metropolitan Police Department and to the appropriate supervisor in accordance with DCHA’s Fleet Management Policy and Procedures Manual;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>Failure of supervisor to take the necessary and appropriate steps to discipline an employee in the normal chain of command, when conduct requires such action;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>Gambling during duty hours or on Authority property, other than that permitted by law or regulation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(p)</num>
      <text>Failure to achieve “fully successful” performance after being placed on disciplinary performance probation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(q)</num>
      <text>Any other cause, including the good of the Authority.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 42 DCR 6914, 6933-6934 (December 8, 1995).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>