<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-7104</num>
  <heading>JOB POSTING, RECRUITMENT, AND SELECTION (§ 14-7104)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7104.1.</num>
    <text>The purpose of this chapter is to outline the procedures involved in filling position vacancies in all departments.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7104.2.</num>
    <text>No persons, including DCHA residents recruited for a specific vacancy, may begin work nor may anyone be hired and placed on the Authority payroll without the written approval of the Executive Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7104.3.</num>
    <text>It is the general policy of the Authority to give current employees and DCHA residents first notice of all job vacancies (except where collective bargaining agreements specify otherwise).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7104.4.</num>
    <text>Job vacancy/promotional opportunity notices will be posted at work sites throughout the Authority for a period of five (5) working days for internal recruitment before external recruitment begins.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7104.5.</num>
    <text>Job vacancies for external recruitment will be advertised for a period of ten (10) working days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7104.6.</num>
    <text>Internal and external recruitment may occur simultaneously, in unusual circumstances, with the approval of the Executive Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7104.7.</num>
    <text>The Authority will select persons to fill job vacancies with the strongest combination of qualifications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7104.8.</num>
    <text>All employees are hired, assigned, transferred, promoted, upgraded, and compensated solely on the basis of merit, ability, and job performance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7104.9.</num>
    <text>To the maximum possible extent, promotion to vacant positions will be made from within the Authority and shall be based solely on merit, skill, ability, and previous job performance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7104.10.</num>
    <text>The department shall be responsible for noting revisions, if any, to the job description, initiating the request to fill the job vacancy, and following personnel procedures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7104.11.</num>
    <text>The DCHA Office of Human Resource Management shall be responsible for updating the official job descriptions and maintaining the correct salary scales and position titles, and for coordinating the recruitment and selection process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7104.12.</num>
    <text>During the five (5) workday period of the job posting, a written application for the vacant position must be received by the Office of Human Resource Management. Consideration will be given to all applications that meet the advertised deadline, including
      applications that are postmarked on the closing date.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7104.13.</num>
    <text>The Authority reserves the right at any time, to verify the accuracy of former employment. DCHA may review police reports, personal references, and any other verifications. Any dishonesty or falsification in completing the application will be grounds
      to disqualify the individual for hire or will be a basis for terminating an employee’s service with the Authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7104.14.</num>
    <text>Applications shall be assessed by a human resource specialist. The evaluation process includes an analysis of minimum qualifications, including any selective factors, and may be supplemented by written tests, interviews, performance tests, background
      investigations, or medical examinations, as appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7104.15.</num>
    <text>District of Columbia residency is preferred for appointees to the DCHA at the time of appointment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7104.16.</num>
    <text>All hiring will be conducted in conformance with the provisions of the Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986, 8 U.S.C. § 1324a.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 42 DCR 6914, 6917-6918 (December 8, 1995).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>