<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-7602</num>
  <heading>INCOME ELIGIBILITY AND TARGETING (ยง 14-7602)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7602.1.</num>
    <text>Income Eligibility. All applicants must meet income eligibility requirements as established by the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development, but generally household income under fifty percent (50%) of Area Median Income as defined by HUD (AMI)
      is required, as further limited as described below in this Section 7602. In certain limited situations where a family receives a voucher in connection with a property that is leaving the federal program, the income may be as high as ninety-five
      percent (95%) of AMI. Any exception to these requirements must have been previously approved by the HUD Field Office.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7602.2.</num>
    <text>Income Targeting. A minimum of seventy-five percent (75%) of the families admitted to the HCVP during each fiscal year must be extremely low-income families. An extremely low-income family is one whose annual income does not exceed thirty percent
      (30%) of AMI.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7602.3.</num>
    <text>Admission Income Monitoring. DCHA does not give an automatic preference for extremely low-income families. However, DCHA does monitor HCVP income- targeting requirements for admissions throughout the fiscal year, and take the following steps:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If at any time the extremely low-income families make up less than seventy- five percent (75%) of the admissions from the waiting list for the fiscal year to date, DCHA shall thereafter give priority to extremely low-income families in each of the
        established preference categories until extremely low-income admissions again make up seventy-five percent (75%) of admissions for that fiscal year;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If there are not enough extremely low-income families on the waiting list, DCHA shall conduct outreach on a non-discriminatory basis to attract extremely low-income families to reach the statutory requirement.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 11120 (August 20, 2004); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 1153 (February 17, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>