<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-9701</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 14-9701)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>9701.1.</num>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Abandoned Vehicle&amp;#8221; shall mean any motor vehicle, trailer, or semi-trailer that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Is inoperable and left unattended on public property for more than 72 hours;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Has remained illegally on public property for more than 72 hours;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Has remained on public property for more than 72 hours and is:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Not displaying current valid registration; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Displaying registration of another vehicle;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Has remained on DCHA property for more than 72 hours and is inoperable in that one or more of its major mechanical components, including, but not limited to, engine, transmission, drive train or wheels, is missing or not functional unless such vehicle
        is kept in an enclosed building completely shielded from view of individuals on the adjoining properties; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Has remained unclaimed on DCHA property for 72 hours after proper notice as provided for in Section 9704.3 below.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9701.2.</num>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Junk Vehicle&amp;#8221; shall mean any motor vehicle, trailer, or semi-trailer that is wrecked, dismantled, or in irreparable condition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9701.3.</num>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Nuisance Vehicle&amp;#8221; shall mean any motor vehicle, trailer, or semi-trailer that is a danger to the public health, safety, and welfare of residents or employees including, but not limited to, vehicles that are on cinder blocks/bricks,
      harbors rats, snakes or other vermin, have open and accessible interior or trunk, or exhibits broken windows, torn sheet metal, or exposed sharp metal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9701.4.</num>
    <text>&amp;#8220;DCHA Property&amp;#8221; shall mean all property, including parking lots, sidewalks or internal DCHA driveways or streets owned or leased by DCHA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9701.5.</num>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Public Property&amp;#8221; shall mean all property, including public streets, alleys, parking lots or other real property owned by the District of Columbia government.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 2112 -2113 (February 27, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>