<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-9403</num>
  <heading>APPLICATIONS FOR FINANCIAL ASSISTANCE; ANNOUNCEMENT OF AVAILABILITY OF FINANCIALSSISTANCE (ยง 14-9403)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>9403.1.</num>
    <text>A person may be eligible to make application for financial assistance if the person:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Consists of one or more individuals, corporations, partnerships, limited liability companies or other privately-controlled legal entities; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Can establish to the satisfaction of DCHA its reasonable capacity to meet the requirements applicable to receipt of financial assistance under this Chapter, applicable law and the applicable announcement; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Can establish to the satisfaction of DCHA that such person holds valid legal title to the property; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Is not on the U.S. General Services Administration List of Parties Excluded from Federal Procurement and Nonprocurement Programs; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Can demonstrate to the satisfaction of DCHA an effective plan to minimize the interruption of occupancy of the property by, and the duration of relocation of, tenants holding Housing Choice Vouchers.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9403.2.</num>
    <text>DCHA may periodically announce the availability of financial assistance and a summary of the requirements for application and approval for financial assistance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9403.3.</num>
    <text>In an announcement, DCHA will provide general information, in a form prescribed by DCHA, which may include, but is not limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The deadline for submission of applications;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The method and location for requesting an application;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Application fees, if any, payable by applicants;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A detailed description of the financial assistance available and the type of project and project costs eligible for financial assistance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Criteria that will be used to evaluate applications and grant financial assistance.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9403.4.</num>
    <text>DCHA&amp;#8217;s announcement and summary of application requirements will be published in at least one (1) newspaper of general circulation in the District of Columbia, in at least one (1) newspaper serving minority communities in the District of
      Columbia, and in at least one (1) bi-lingual newspaper circulated in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 10637 (November 2, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>