<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-9599</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 14-9599)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>9599.1.</num>
    <text>Area Median Income</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>For a household of 4 persons: the area median income for a household of 4 persons in the Washington Metropolitan Statistical Area as set forth in the periodic calculation provided by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For a household of 3 persons: 90% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>For a household of 2 persons: 80% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>For a household of 1 person: 70% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>For a household of more than 4 persons: the area median income for a household of 4 persons, increased by 10% of the area median income for a family of 4 persons for each household member exceeding 4 persons (e.g., the area median income for a family
        of 5 shall be 110% of the area median income for a family of 4; the area median income for a household of 6 shall be 120% of the area median income for a family of 4.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9599.2.</num>
    <text>Extremely Low Income Household &amp;#8211; an individual or family whose gross income does not exceed 30% of the Area Median Income, as adjusted for size of household.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9599.3.</num>
    <text>Housing Choice Voucher Program &amp;#8211; the. federal housing program authorized by Section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937, approved September 1, 1937 (50 Stat. 888); 42 U.S.C. ยง 1737(f) et seq.; as administered by the District of Columbia
      Housing Authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9599.4.</num>
    <text>Housing Provider &amp;#8211; an entity or its affiliate that owns and/or operates a unit receiving LRSP funds.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9599.5.</num>
    <text>Local Rent Supplement Program (LRSP) &amp;#8211; the program established under Title II of the Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2006, effective August 8, 2006 (D.C. Act A16-0476; 53 DCR 7068), which is the D.C. Housing Authority Rent
      Supplement Act of 2006, to provide housing assistance to Extremely Low-Income residents in the District of Columbia, including, but not limited to, those who are homeless and those in need of supportive services, such as elderly individuals or those
      with disabilities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9599.6.</num>
    <text>Long Term Subsidy Contract &amp;#8211; a long term housing assistance payment contract between DCHA and the owner of building(s) or the Housing Provider receiving LRSP housing assistance; and shall mean the same as the Housing Assistance Payment contract
      under the HCVP rules and regulations unless specified otherwise in this Chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9599.7.</num>
    <text>Project-Based Housing Assistance &amp;#8211; LRSP funds allocated under a Long Term Subsidy Contract and attached to units in a particular building, or set of buildings, owned and operated by a private or non-profit Housing Provider; and shall have
      the same meaning as &amp;#8220;Project-based assistance&amp;#8221; under the HCVP rules and regulations unless specified otherwise in this Chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9599.8.</num>
    <text>Rent Supplement Voucher &amp;#8211; a document issued by DCHA to households selected for admission to LRSP and shall mean the same as the &amp;#8220;Housing Choice Voucher&amp;#8221; under the HCVP rules and regulations unless specified otherwise
      in this Chapter. This document describes the LRSP, the procedures for DCHA&amp;#8217;s approval of the dwelling unit selected by the household, and shall state the obligations of the household under the LRSP.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9599.9.</num>
    <text>Sponsor-Based Housing Assistance &amp;#8211; LRSP funds allocated under a Long Term Subsidy Contract to a particular private or non-profit Housing Provider to subsidize the rent, in units owned and operated by the provider, for the number of households
      established by the contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9599.10.</num>
    <text>Supportive Housing &amp;#8211; housing provided in connection with voluntary services designed primarily to help tenants maintain housing, including, but not limited to, coordination/case management, physical and mental health, substance use management
      and recovery support, job training, literacy, and education, youth and children&amp;#8217;s programs, and money management.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9599.11.</num>
    <text>Tenant-Based Housing Assistance &amp;#8211; LRSP funds allocated for an individual or family holding a Rent Supplement Voucher issued by DCHA to the individual or family selected for admission by HCVP and shall have the same meaning as &amp;#8220;Tenant-Based
      assistance&amp;#8221; under the HCVP rules and regulations unless specified otherwise in this Chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 10313 (December 29, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>