<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-9508</num>
  <heading>ELIGIBILITY AND ADMISSIONS, CRIMINAL HISTORY AND DETERMINATION OF RENTPPLICABLE TO SPONSOR-BASED HOUSING ASSISTANCE (§ 14-9508)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>9508.1</num>
    <text>9508.1 The regulations set forth below in this Section shall govern eligibility and admissions, criminal history and determination of rent for Sponsor-Based Assistance under the LRSP. Except as provided in Chapter 9500 et seq., the rules and regulations
      applicable to the HCVP shall govern eligibility and admission, review of criminal history and determination of rent for the Sponsor-Based Assistance under the LRSP.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9508.2</num>
    <text>9508.2 DCHA shall determine eligibility of applicants to be housed by a Sponsor with sponsor-based assistance under LRSP. In order to determine eligibility, DCHA will review the following documents which shall be executed and/or completed, as appropriate
      by the applicant and submitted by or on behalf of an applicant to DCHA’s Client Placement Division:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>    Privacy Act Notice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>   Social Security Number Certifications:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>   Social Security Numbers for each Household Member 6 years old or older; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>  Certification of inability to meet the documentation requirement where an applicant has a Social Security Number but no documentation; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>  Certification that Social Security Numbers have not been issued;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>    Verification of Date of Birth for each Household Member in the form of any of the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Birth certificate; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Valid government issued identification which includes the date of birth; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Other evidence of birth.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>   Government issued ID for family members age eighteen (18) or older;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>    Statement of Child Care Expense Form;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>    Verification of Full-time Student Status Form;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>   Certification of Disability Form;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Evidence and Verification of Income:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Documentation evidencing employment, pension, retirement or other income</text>
    </level>
    <text>to the extent applicable to the applicant; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Income Maintenance Administration and/or Social Security Administration; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Electronic Database Checks.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Verification of residency in the District of Columbia. The applicant shall provide evidence to demonstrate the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Applicant has resided in the District of Columbia at least six (6) months prior to application for LRSP as demonstrated by any valid, non-expired government identification (e.g. DMV, IMA identification, passport) issued at least six (6) months prior
        to application; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Applicant has lived in the District of Columbia during any six (6) of the last twelve (12) months, prior to LRSP application. Any of the following documents shall demonstrate residency within the District of Columbia for this time period:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Benefit records addressed to a District of Columbia address; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Medicaid records or medical records; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Bank records; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Employment records; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Tax records; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>Housing or lease records; or</text>
    </level>
    <text>Affidavit of homeless shelter, social service provider, non-profit organization or religious organization where the applicant has been residing or with which they have been engaged.</text>
    <text>To the extent that an applicant who is referred by a sponsor receiving sponsor-based assistance, cannot submit documentation set forth in Section 9508.2(i) above, DCHA shall accept referrals for eligibility and may deem eligible in accordance with
      the applicable rules set forth above, applicants who are residents of the District of Columbia as defined in DC Code Section 4-205.03. With respect to each sponsor, the number of applicants admitted under this subsection shall not exceed ten percent
      (10%) of the total number of vouchers allotted to such sponsor on an annual basis.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Release of information form; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Such other forms as may be required by DCHA.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9508.3</num>
    <text>9508.3 An applicant who is referred by a sponsor receiving sponsor-based assistance and owes a debt arising out of a past participation in a federally funded housing program under Section 6109.4 (b) shall not be deemed ineligible for participation
      in the LRSP. Any subsequent application for assistance under a federally funded housing program or a locally funded program under than sponsor-based LRSP by a person previously deemed eligible under the rules governing the LRSP shall be governed
      by the then existing laws, rules and regulations governing eligibility for the applicable federal or local program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9508.4</num>
    <text>9508.4 In the event unfavorable information is received as a result of the investigation conducted regarding an applicant’s criminal history during the eligibility process, and the applicant cannot satisfactorily meet the mitigation factors set forth
      in Section 6109.6, a felony conviction shall not bar the applicant from being deemed eligible for assistance under the Sponsor-Based assistance under the following circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Sponsor seeking to house the applicant agrees to provide appropriate supportive services tailored towards the offense committed by the applicant; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The applicant demonstrates in writing a willingness to receive and participate in relevant case management services related to the offense for which the applicant was convicted.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9508.5.</num>
    <text>In the event that the applicant has ever been convicted of drug-related criminal activity for manufacture or production of methamphetamine on the premises of federally assisted housing, and the applicant can satisfactorily meet the mitigation factors
      set forth in Section 6109.6, the applicant shall not be barred from being deemed eligible for assistance under the Sponsor-Based assistance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9508.6</num>
    <text>9508.6 No mitigation in accordance with Section 6109.6 shall be required for offenses less than a felony conviction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9508.7.</num>
    <text>DCHA may on an annual basis adopt a payment standard for sponsor-based assistance under the LRSP that exceeds the payment standard adopted for DCHA’s federally funded HCVP programs in accordance with Section 8300.3.</text>
    <text>Such payment standard for sponsor-based assistance shall in no event exceed the submarket rents established in accordance with Section 8301.3. In the event that the DCHA Board of Commissioners does not adopt a separate standard for any given fiscal
      year applicable to sponsor-based assistance, then the federal payment standard adopted pursuant to Section 8300.3 for DCHA’s federally funded HCVP programs shall apply to sponsor-based assistance under the LRSP.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Final Rulemaking at 56 DCR 5101 (May 22, 2009)</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>