<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-9815</num>
  <heading>MAINTENANCE ESCROW ACCOUNT (§ 14-9815)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>9815.1</num>
    <text>9815.1 DCHA will establish a Maintenance Escrow Account for each AYBL Family for the maintenance to the AYBL Family’s unit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9815.2</num>
    <text>9815.2 Maintenance escrow funds shall be utilized to pay for the maintenance/repair of the AYBL Family’s Rewards Property unit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9815.3</num>
    <text>9815.3 The amount paid into a maintenance escrow account for AYBL Families shall be two percent (2%) of the AYBL participant’s earned income and shall be adjusted to reflect any changes in the AYBL participant’s earned income. See Interim Recertification
      policies in this chapter for additional related AYBL program requirements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9815.4</num>
    <text>9815.4 DCHA shall deposit the Maintenance escrow funds of all AYBL Families into one (1) or more HUD approved investment accounts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9815.5</num>
    <text>9815.5 The total of the Maintenance Escrow Account funds shall be supported in the DCHA accounting records by a subsidiary ledger showing the balance applicable to each AYBL participant. During the term of the Contract of Participation, DCHA shall
      credit monthly, but not less than quarterly, to each AYBL participants Maintenance escrow account, the amount of the AYBL participant Maintenance Escrow payment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9815.6</num>
    <text>9815.6 DCHA will work with the AYBL Families to contract out the maintenance/repair of Rewards Property units.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9815.7</num>
    <text>9815.7 When a condition requiring maintenance/repair is identified by the AYBL Family and reported to DCHA or identified by DCHA, the AYBL Family head of household will work with DCHA to identify one of the DCHA designated maintenance contractors
      to perform the work and estimate the related cost of work to be performed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9815.8</num>
    <text>9815.8 The AYBL Family with the assistance of DCHA, will oversee the work and sign-off on the satisfactory completion of the work. Once the invoice for the completed work is received by the AYBL Family, the AYBL Family shall submit a request to DCHA
      for disbursement of funds from the maintenance escrow account to pay for the work performed by the contractor. Requests for maintenance disbursements must be submitted in writing and include an invoice for the work completed by the contractor. Disbursements
      to pay for maintenance/repair on an AYBL unit shall be made by DCHA on behalf of the AYBL Family in accordance with terms of the Contract of Participation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9815.9.</num>
    <text>If the cost associated with the repair exceeds the balance of the maintenance escrow account, DCHA will charge the entire cost of the repair to the maintenance escrow account creating a negative balance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9815.10.</num>
    <text>If a negative balance in the maintenance escrow account is greater than two times the AYBL Family’s monthly escrow account payment, and if the majority of the charges are due to tenant caused damage, DCHA will deduct the funds required to make up
      the balance from the savings escrow account. As a result of the withdrawal from the savings escrow account, DCHA will issue Notice of non-compliance to the AYBL Family.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9815.11.</num>
    <text>An AYBL Family may contribute additional funds to the maintenance escrow account to make up any shortages to eliminate a negative balance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9815.12</num>
    <text>9815.12 At the end of AYBL program participation, any maintenance escrow monies not applied toward the AYBL Family’s unit maintenance/repair will be transferred to the DCHA project based budget for the Rewards Property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9815.13.</num>
    <text>DCHA will send monthly statements to the AYBL Families reflecting all deposits and withdrawals/charges to the savings and maintenance escrow accounts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9815.14</num>
    <text>9815.14 Maintenance Escrow payments are due by the first (1st) of the month and will be treated as late payments if not received by the tenth (10th) of the month.</text>
    <text>.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 2460, 2471 (March 18, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>