<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-103</num>
  <heading>INFORMAL COMPLAINTS AND HEARINGS (§ 15-103)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>103.1.</num>
    <text>Each informal complaint, including complaints under Chapter 3 of this title, shall initially be referred to the Commission&amp;#8217;s Office of the General Counsel for investigation, unless otherwise directed by the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.2.</num>
    <text>Upon conclusion of an investigation, the Staff shall file its written findings and recommendations with the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.3.</num>
    <text>Upon review of the Staff’s findings and recommendations, the Commission may either attempt to resolve the matter informally or transfer it to the Formal Docket.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.4.</num>
    <text>When an informal complaint is docketed as a formal complaint, the Commission shall issue an Order setting forth the issues and procedural schedule.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.5.</num>
    <text>If a formal pleading in the nature of a complaint, including formal complaints pursuant to the Consumer Bill of Rights, is of a nature conducive to informal resolution, the Commission may refer the matter for informal resolution under this section
      unless the complaint specifically alleges that the matter has previously been brought to the attention of the General Counsel Staff.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.6.</num>
    <text>The Commission may, from time-to-time, order informal hearings to obtain information necessary or helpful in the determination of its policies, the carrying out of its duties, the formulation or amendment of rules and regulations, or the disposition
      of informal complaints.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.7.</num>
    <text>Informal hearings may be public or non-public as the Commission may direct, and the procedure may be informal to any extent which the Commission may deem appropriate and expedient.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.8.</num>
    <text>The Commission may require the attendance of witnesses and the production of evidence as in a formal hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.9.</num>
    <text>Informal complaints shall be in writing and may conform to the other requirements for formal pleadings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 2984, 2988 (July 3, 1981); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 5117, 5118 (July 10, 1992).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>