<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-1401</num>
  <heading>COMMISSION DETERMINATIONS OF AGENCY FUND REQUIREMENTS (ยง 15-1401)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1401.1.</num>
    <text>When any proceeding is initiated by the Commission, or any member, the Commission, or member, shall, prior to the issuance of any special franchise tax deposit order for that proceeding, issue a Notice of Agency Fund Requirements for that proceeding
      setting forth the reasonable and necessary expenditures required by the Commission, or member, to carry out its statutory responsibilities with regard to the proceeding.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1401.2.</num>
    <text>A Notice of Agency Fund Requirements shall contain the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The total amount sought from each affected utility and the dates on which payment is requested to be made by each utility:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name of each contractor to be hired;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A brief description of the qualifications of each contractor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A brief description of the work to be performed by each contractor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The number of persons to be employed by the contractor on the contract;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The rate of compensation on an hourly basis for each person so employed by the contractor; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The actual or estimated amount of each contract.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1401.3.</num>
    <text>In determining its agency fund requirements, the Commission shall consider the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The nature of the proceeding;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The expertise, reputation, and ability of the contractor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The quality of the contractor&amp;#8217;s prior work before the Commission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The customary expenditures required for services in similar proceedings before the Commission or elsewhere; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The level of assistance required by the Commission to discharge its statutory responsibilities with the respect to the proceeding.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 893 (February 14, 1986); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 1857 (March 21, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>