<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-1301</num>
  <heading>DETERMINATION OF REIMBURSEMENTS (§ 15-1301)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1301.1.</num>
    <text>Each public utility, competitive electric supplier, competitive natural gas supplier, and competitive local exchange carrier (CLEC) shall be assessed according to D.C. Official Code §34-912(b) (2011 Supp.) for the reimbursable budgets of the Commission
      and the Office of the People&amp;#8217;s Counsel in the following manner:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>For CLECs, competitive electric suppliers, and competitive natural gas suppliers (collectively &amp;#8220;alternative providers&amp;#8221;), the assessments shall be equal to the ratio of the alternative provider&amp;#8217;s calendar year gross
        revenues to the sum of the calendar year gross revenues of all public utilities and all alternative providers times the budgets of the Commission and the Office of the People’s Counsel; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For public utilities, the assessment shall be the utility&amp;#8217;s proportionate share of the calendar year gross revenues of all public utilities times the budgets of the Commission and the Office of the People’s Counsel less the amount to be
        reimbursed by the alternative providers in paragraph (a).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1301.2.</num>
    <text>On April 15th of each year, each utility, competitive electric supplier, competitive natural gas supplier, and CLEC shall file its gross jurisdictional revenue figures for the preceding calendar year ending December 31st.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 29 DCR 3245, 3246 (July 30, 1982; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 4141 (May 19, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 8486 (October 20, 2006); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking
        published at 59 DCR 4230 (May 4, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>