<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-144</num>
  <heading>DECLARATORY ORDERS (ยง 15-144)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>144.1.</num>
    <text>Upon written petition of any interested person, the Commission, within its discretion, may issue a declaratory order regarding the applicability of any rule, regulation, or statute enforceable by it, to terminate a controversy (other than a contested
      case) or to remove uncertainty.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>144.2.</num>
    <text>A declaratory order, as provided in this section, shall be binding between the Commission and the petitioner as to a particular set of facts and circumstances unless such order is altered or set aside by a court.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>144.3.</num>
    <text>A declaratory order is subject to review in the manner provided in D.C. Code, title 43, Chapter 9 for the review of orders and decisions, except that the refusal of the Commission to issue a declaratory order shall not be subject to review.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>144.4.</num>
    <text>Each petition shall contain the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of petitioner;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A clear and concise statement of facts and issues upon which the petition is based, and the position and interest of the petitioner;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A reference to the specific section or sections of the statute, rule, or regulation, for which a declaratory order is sought;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Signature of petitioner; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The signatory&amp;#8217;s address and telephone number.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>144.5.</num>
    <text>The Commission may decline to issue a declaratory order in its discretion and will not consider requests based upon hypothetical facts, past transactions, or nameless parties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 2034 (March 27, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>