<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-1600</num>
  <heading>PURPOSE, STANDARDS, AND FILING REQUIREMENTS (ยง 15-1600)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1600.1.</num>
    <text>This chapter shall implement the Commission&amp;#8217;s regulatory authority over the rates, terms and conditions for cable television use of existing utility company rights-of-way located within the District of Columbia, including the use of existing
      utility poles and underground conduits. This chapter also provides procedures for prompt processing of complaints regarding the rates, terms and conditions of such use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.2.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall regulate the matters described in ยง1600.1 in accordance with District of Columbia law, federal law, and to the extent applicable, Federal Communications Commission rules and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.3.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall ensure that all rates, terms and conditions prescribed in accordance with this chapter are just and reasonable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.4.</num>
    <text>Any utility company under the jurisdiction of the Commission entering into a pole attachment or conduit agreement shall submit the agreement for Commission review and approval. The Commission shall review the pole attachment or conduit placement as
      well as the rates for the pole attachment or conduit placement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.5.</num>
    <text>One (1) original and twenty (20) copies of the pole attachment or conduit agreement shall be filed with the Commission Secretary not later than fourteen (14) days after final execution of the agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.6.</num>
    <text>Within sixty (60) days, the Commission may take any one of the following actions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Request additional information or data from the parties to the agreement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Schedule an evidentiary hearing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Issue an order approving the agreement; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Issue an order rejecting the agreement.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is ยง9 of the Cable Television Communications Act of 1981, D.C. Law 4-142, D.C. Code ยง43-1808 (1981 Ed.).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 6496 (December 21, 1984); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 5667 (September 12, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>