<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-105</num>
  <heading>ANSWERS, CROSS-COMPLAINTS AND MOTIONS (ยง 15-105)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>105.1.</num>
    <text>Any party upon whom a copy of a petition, formal complaint, cross complaint, order or investigation, or order to show cause has been served shall answer and file the same with the Commission within ten (10) days after service of that complaint, petition,
      or order, or within such time as extended by the Commission, or within a lesser time fixed by the Commission for good reason stated.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.2.</num>
    <text>Any party specified by ยง105.1 who fails to answer a service within the period prescribed shall be deemed in default, except where the Commission shall waive the answer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.3.</num>
    <text>In the event the Commission shall waive the answer as to any party, the case shall be deemed at issue as to that party.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.4.</num>
    <text>Joint answers to the same complaint shall be allowed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.5.</num>
    <text>The purpose. of the answer is to fully advise the complainant and the Commission of the nature of the defense.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.6.</num>
    <text>The answer shall admit or deny each material allegation in the complaint and shall set forth any new matter constituting a defense. It shall also set forth any defects in the complaint which require amendment or clarification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.7.</num>
    <text>Cross complaints, if any, shall be filed by the respondent with the answer to the complaint. Cross complaints shall be subject to all rules relating to complaints.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.8.</num>
    <text>Written motions may be filed at any time in accordance with this chapter. Responses to a written motion shall be filed no later than ten (10) calendar days after a motion has been served.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.9.</num>
    <text>No rejoinders or replies to responses shall be accepted without leave of the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.10.</num>
    <text>The Commission may act without awaiting responses, when considered necessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 2984, 2989 (July 3, 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>