<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-114</num>
  <heading>SIGNING AND VERIFICATION OF PLEADINGS (ยง 15-114)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>114.1.</num>
    <text>The original of each application, petition, complaint, answer, or amendment shall be signed in ink by each party.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>114.2.</num>
    <text>If a party is a corporation or association, the pleading shall be signed and verified by an officer or other designated employee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>114.3.</num>
    <text>Any person who signs a pleading or brief, enters an appearance at a hearing, or transacts business with the Commission, represents by such act that he or she is authorized to do so.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>114.4.</num>
    <text>Any attorney for or representative of a party shall also sign the pleading, and show his or her address, telephone number, e-mail address, and Unified Bar Number, if applicable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>114.5.</num>
    <text>Motions, notices, briefs, and petitions for reconsideration need only be signed by an attorney or representative.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>114.6.</num>
    <text>Petitions or amendments to petitions (except petitions for reconsideration) shall be verified by each petitioner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>114.7.</num>
    <text>Applications or amendments to applications shall be verified by each applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>114.8.</num>
    <text>Complaints or amendments to complaints shall be verified by at least one (1) complainant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>114.9.</num>
    <text>Answers or amendments to answers shall be verified by at least one (1) of the respondents filing the answer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>114.10.</num>
    <text>Other pleadings need not be verified.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>114.11.</num>
    <text>Verification may be made before a notary public or by certification or declaration under the penalty of perjury.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 2984, 2997 (July 3, 1981); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 10631, 10632 (December 16, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>