<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-1399</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 15-1399)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1399.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have the meaning ascribed:</text>
    <text>Commission &amp;#8211; the Public Service Commission of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Competitive Electric Supplier &amp;#8211; a person, including an aggregator, broker or marketer, who generates electricity; sells electricity; or purchases, brokers, arranges, or markets electricity for sale to customers. The term excludes the following:</text>
    <text>Building owners, lessees, or managers who manage the internal distribution system serving such building and who supply electricity solely to occupants of the building for use by the occupants;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any person who purchases electricity for its own use or for the use of its subsidiaries or affiliates or Any apartment building or office building manager who aggregates electric service requirements for his or her building or buildings, and who
        does not:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Take title to electricity;</text>
    <text>Market electric services to the individually-metered tenants of his or her building; or</text>
    <text>Engage in the resale of electric services to others;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Property owners who supply small amounts of power, at cost, as an accommodation to lessors or licensees of the property; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A consolidator.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Competitive Local Exchange Carrier (CLEC) &amp;#8211; any provider of telecommunications service that was not an incumbent local exchange carrier on January 31,1996.</text>
    <text>Competitive Natural Gas Supplier &amp;#8211; a person including an aggregator, broker, or marketer, who sells natural gas or purchases, brokers, arranges or markets natural gas for sale to customers. The term shall not include a person that supplies
      natural gas exclusively for its own consumption or the consumption of one or more of its affiliates. The term shall not include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Building owners, lessees, or managers who manage the internal distribution system serving the building and who supply natural gas solely to occupants of the building for use by the occupants;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any person who purchases natural gas for its own use or for the use of its subsidiaries or affiliates or Any apartment building or office building manager who aggregates retail natural gas sales requirements for his or her building, and who does
        not:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Take title to natural gas;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Market retail natural gas sales to the individually-metered tenants of his or her building; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Engage in the resale of natural gas to others;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Property owners who supply small amounts of natural gas, at cost as an accommodation to lessors or licensees of the property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A consolidator; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The gas company.</text>
    </level>
    <text>District &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Office of the People&amp;#8217;s Counsel &amp;#8211; the Office of the People&amp;#8217;s Counsel of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Public Utility &amp;#8211; any public utility, as defined under D.C. Official Code ยง 34-214 (2010 Repl.), other than a common carrier.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 29 DCR 3245 (July 30, 1982); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 4141 (May 19, 2006); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 4230, 4232 (May 4, 2012); as corrected by Errata Notice
        published at 59 DCR 4772 (May 11, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>