<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-1502</num>
  <heading>NOTICE OF REVIEW (ยง 15-1502)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1502.1.</num>
    <text>Timely written notification of the beginning of the review shall be given by the Commission to all affected persons and to any person who has asked to be placed on the Commission&amp;#8217;s notification mailing list. Except as provided for in ยง1502.3,
      all notification shall be made by mail.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.2.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term &amp;#8220;affected person&amp;#8221; shall mean the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The person whose proposal is being reviewed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Office of the People&amp;#8217;s Counsel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Public utilities in the District of Columbia that provide similar services or that have similar facilities to those proposed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any public utility that, prior to the receipt of the application, indicated to the Commission its intention to provide similar services.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.3.</num>
    <text>Notification to the public shall be given by means of publication of a notice in at least one newspaper of general circulation in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.4.</num>
    <text>The notice of the beginning of the review shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The proposed schedule of the review;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The manner in which notification will be provided of the time and place of the public hearing; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The expected date of closure of the record.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.5.</num>
    <text>The review shall began at least thirty (30) days after the Notice of Review, and the hearing shall begin at least thirty (30) days after the notice of the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.6.</num>
    <text>The date of notification shall be the date on which the notice is mailed or the date the notice first appears in a newspaper, whichever is later.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 38 DCR 16, 20 (January 4, 1991).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>