<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-199</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 15-199)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>199.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have the meaning ascribed:</text>
    <text>Applicant &amp;#8211; a person who files an application for any action by the Commission.</text>
    <text>Commission &amp;#8211; the Public Service Commission of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Complainant &amp;#8211; a person who files a complaint with the Commission.</text>
    <text>Days &amp;#8211; calendar days, unless otherwise expressly defined.</text>
    <text>Ex Parte Communication &amp;#8211; an oral or written communication, not on the public record, which is relevant to the merits of a proceeding and with respect to which reasonable prior notice to all parties has not been given.</text>
    <text>Filing &amp;#8211; any pleading or other document requiring Commission action or attention which is presented to the Commission&amp;#8217;s Secretary, in accordance with this chapter, for placement in the Commission&amp;#8217;s General or Formal Docket.
      (39 DCR 5129)</text>
    <text>Full Settlement &amp;#8211; a settlement which addresses all of the issues in a contested case. (39 DCR 5129)</text>
    <text>Interested Person &amp;#8211; with respect to a proceeding means any person who is a party to a matter pending before the Commission or represents a party to any such matter.</text>
    <text>Intervenor &amp;#8211; a person whose petition to intervene in a proceeding has been granted.</text>
    <text>Nonunanimous Settlement &amp;#8211; a settlement that is opposed in whole or in part by any of the parties to the case in which such settlement is proposed for adoption by the Commission. (39 DCR 5129)</text>
    <text>Partial Settlement &amp;#8211; a settlement which addresses some, but not all, of the issues in a contested case. (39 DCR 5129)</text>
    <text>Party &amp;#8211; any person who is an applicant, complainant, petitioner, respondent, or intervenor in a proceeding.</text>
    <text>Person &amp;#8211; an individual, partnership, association, firm, corporation, body politic, municipal organization, governmental body, joint stock company, receiver, trustee, official acting in his or her official capacity, or any other organization
      or institution.</text>
    <text>Petitioner &amp;#8211; a person who files a petition with the Commission.</text>
    <text>Pleading &amp;#8211; complaints, cross complaints, amended and supplemental complaints, petitions, applications, answers, written motions, and amendments to any thereof.</text>
    <text>Respondent &amp;#8211; a person against whom a complaint is made or an order of investigation or an order to show cause is directed.</text>
    <text>Secretary &amp;#8211; that person appointed by the Commission to receive all filings and to execute all documents on behalf of the Commission.</text>
    <text>Settlement &amp;#8211; except as to full settlements presented under ยง130.11, proceedings in which parties have fully agreed to each other&amp;#8217;s positions and recommendations are not required to be considered settlements and may be expeditiously
      processed. (39 DCR 5129)</text>
    <text>Staff &amp;#8211; for purposes of matters before the Commission, the employees of the Commission, excluding those appointed to the Office of General Counsel and those assigned as personal assistants to the Commissioners.</text>
    <text>(</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 2984, 2985 (July 3, 1981); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 5117, 5129 (July 10, 1992).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>