<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-1802</num>
  <heading>DECISIONS AND APPEALS (§ 15-1802)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1802.1.</num>
    <text>Within twenty (20) days after the close of the hearing, the hearing officer shall issue a written decision which states the issues, summarizes the evidence and makes findings of fact, conclusions of law, and a proposed disposition of the matter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1802.2.</num>
    <text>In cases involving billing disputes in which the hearing officer has concluded that all or part of the amount in dispute is owed, the hearing officer may, for good cause stated in the decision, direct that the amount found outstanding be paid in installments.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1802.3.</num>
    <text>Copies of the hearing officer&amp;#8217;s decision shall be served upon the parties either personally or by regular mail on the day the decision is issued together with instructions on how to appeal the decision to the Commission and indicating the
      last date the appeal may be filed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1802.4.</num>
    <text>The decision of the hearing officer shall be final, if there is no appeal to the Commission within the time specified.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1802.5.</num>
    <text>Any party may appeal the hearing officer&amp;#8217;s decision to the Commission within thirty (30) days of personal service and thirty-five (35) days of service by mail of the decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1802.6.</num>
    <text>The appeal shall be signed by the party, identify the decision appealed from, and specify the grounds on which it is based.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1802.7.</num>
    <text>The Commission&amp;#8217;s Secretary shall serve a copy of any appeal filed upon the opposing party on the day it is filed. Service may be made personally or by first class mail.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1802.8.</num>
    <text>The opposing party&amp;#8217;s response or counter-appeal shall be filed within ten (10) days of personal service and fifteen (15) days of service by mail.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1802.9.</num>
    <text>Within twenty (20) days of the filing an appeal, the record shall be prepared for review by the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1802.10.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall review the decision within sixty (60) days after the record is prepared.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1802.11.</num>
    <text>Upon review of the record, and after giving consideration to the matters raised on appeal, the Commission shall do one of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Adopt the decision of the hearing officer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Issue a Commission decision;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Return the matter to the hearing officer for further proceedings; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Schedule the matter for hearing or argument before the Commission.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1802.12.</num>
    <text>Review of a final Commission decision shall be pursuant to D.C. Code §§43-904, 43-905 (1981 Ed.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 1925, 1929 (March 28, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>