<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-137</num>
  <heading>POST-HEARING BRIEFS (ยง 15-137)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>137.1.</num>
    <text>Post-hearing briefs shall be filed at such times as shall be fixed by the Commission or the presiding officer in each case.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>137.2.</num>
    <text>The applicant shall brief all issues designated by the Commission in the Report and Order on Pre-hearing Conference and any other issues designated by the Commission during the proceeding.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>137.3.</num>
    <text>All post-hearing briefs shall contain a title sheet clearly identifying the parties submitting the brief, including name and title, local address, and local telephone number.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>137.4.</num>
    <text>A subject index with page references and a list of all authorities cited alphabetically arranged with page references shall be included.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>137.5.</num>
    <text>Authorities most heavily relied upon shall be asterisked. Lengthy quotations from any records or from authorities shall not be included.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>137.6.</num>
    <text>The Commission may reject briefs unnecessarily prolix or which do not conform to the rules of the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>137.7.</num>
    <text>Each participant proposing adjustments to test year expenses, rate base, revenues or rate of return, shall include, as an appendix to the initial post-hearing brief or memorandum, a schedule listing each proposed adjustment beginning with the applicant&amp;#8217;s
      original unadjusted test year presentation, and including the accepted adjustments of all other participants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>137.8.</num>
    <text>The schedule shall specifically refer to evidence of record which reflects the details of all calculations that support the proposed adjustments. The schedule shall show the impact on the income deficiency or excess earnings, rate base and revenue
      requirement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>137.9.</num>
    <text>When an intervening participant submits testimony on a specific issue and does not adopt the evidence of other participants on the remaining issues, the intervening participant shall only prepare a schedule on the issues addressed in the participant&amp;#8217;s
      testimony and evidence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 2984, 3013 (July 3, 1981); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 5651 (August 4, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>