<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-1800</num>
  <heading>NON-RESIDENTIAL CUSTOMER INQUIRIES AND COMPLAINTS (§ 15-1800)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1800.1.</num>
    <text>A utility shall, in accordance with this section, establish procedures which will ensure the prompt, efficient, and thorough receipt, investigation, and where possible, resolution of all non-residential customer inquiries, service requests and complaints
      regarding commercial utility service and charges.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1800.2.</num>
    <text>Qualified utility personnel (customer service representatives) shall be available and prepared at all times during normal business hours to receive and discuss all non-residential customer inquiries, service requests and complaints.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1800.3.</num>
    <text>The utility shall make reasonable arrangements to ensure that foreign language-speaking service representatives are available for non-English-speaking customers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1800.4.</num>
    <text>Utility supervisory personnel shall be available during normal business hours to discuss non-residential customer complaintswhich are not resolved through contact with customer service representatives.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1800.5.</num>
    <text>Qualified personnel shall be available during normal business hours to respond to customer calls regarding interruption or termination of service or emergency conditions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1800.6.</num>
    <text>In every case of dispute between a non-residential customer and a utility, the first attempt at resolution shall be made directly between the parties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1800.7.</num>
    <text>When a non-residential customer/utility dispute cannot be resolved between the parties, after the complaint has proceeded through the utility&amp;#8217;s resolution process, the utility shall refer the complainant to the Commission&amp;#8217;s Office
      of Consumer Services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1800.8.</num>
    <text>When a non-residential customer contacts the Office of Consumer Services, the Office shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Answer inquiries regarding non-residential utility service and make information available concerning the procedures for resolving disputes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Assist in the informal resolution of non-residential customer complaints and disputes which have not been resolved under the utility&amp;#8217;s own procedures; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Adjudicate non-residential customer complaints concerning matters within the Commission&amp;#8217;s jurisdiction which cannot be resolved informally.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1800.9.</num>
    <text>Any present or prospective non-residential customer may file a complaint with the Commission regarding service, terms, and conditions of service, or a utility bill, within ninety (90) days from the date the utility refers the complainant to the Office
      of Consumer Services under §1800.7.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1800.10.</num>
    <text>In all cases where the complaint has not proceeded through the utility&amp;#8217;s resolution process, the matter shall be referred to the utility for an attempt at direct resolution. The utility shall report the results of such referrals to the Office
      of Consumer Services within fourteen (14) calendar days of the referral.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1800.11.</num>
    <text>If the complaint has not been resolved by the customer and the utility, the Office of Consumer Services shall review the efforts made by the utility to resolve the complaint and make a further effort through mediation to resolve it informally. This
      additional resolution effort shall not exceed five (5) business days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1800.12.</num>
    <text>If the complaint is not resolved informally, either by the utility&amp;#8217;s complaint process or by the Office of Consumer Services&amp;#8217; efforts, upon request by the customer, the matter shall be set for informal hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1800.13.</num>
    <text>The non-residential customer shall have fourteen (14) days after the mediation process to request an informal hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is Paragraph 97(b) of §8 of An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and fourteen, and
        for other purposes, approved March 4, 1913 (37 Stat. 977); as amended by §2 of the Public Utilities Amendment Act of 1989, D.C. Law 8-47, D.C. Code §43-501 (1981 Ed.).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 1925 (March 28, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>