<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-2205</num>
  <heading>CONTRACT ADMINISTRATION (ยง 15-2205)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2205.1.</num>
    <text>Responsibility. The Contracting Officer shall coordinate the monitoring of contractor performance. Commission staff are required to provide technical support in the monitoring process by evaluating the quality of contractor performance. The Contracting
      Officer shall be responsible for ensuring that appropriate action is taken to protect the rights of the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2205.2.</num>
    <text>Contract Modifications. The Commission, in its discretion, may modify, amend, or adjust any contract. All contract modifications and amendments must be approved by the Commission or the Contracting Officer and shall be made in writing prior to the
      effective date of the change. The term &amp;#8220;modify&amp;#8221; as used in this subsection shall not be construed to mean the incorporation of additional supplies, tasks, and duties that alter the scope of the contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2205.3.</num>
    <text>Terminations. The Commission, in its discretion, may terminate a contract for any reason prior to its completion under the following conditions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>For cause, if the Commission determines that the performance under the contract is unsatisfactory, the Contracting Officer may, upon written notice, terminate the contract. If the contract is terminated for cause, the contractor is not entitled
        to receive any compensation and shall be liable to the Commission for the costs entailed in securing another contract for supplies or services or for the cost of completion in a contract for construction; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For convenience, if the Contracting Officer determines that it is in the best interest of the Commission to terminate the contract, he or she may do so upon the approval of the Commission. Upon termination for convenience, the contractor maybe entitled
        to receive compensation only for services rendered.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 42 DCR 5126 (September 8, 1995); as amended by emergency Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 6356 (September 4, 1998) [EXPIRED]; as amended by emergency Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 913 (February 11, 2000) [EXPIRED]; as
        amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 2600 (April 14, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>