<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-2730</num>
  <heading>BILLING ERROR NOTIFICATION (§ 15-2730)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2730.1.</num>
    <text>Each telecommunications service provider must inform the Commission and the Office of the People’s Counsel when a billing error has affected one hundred (100) or more customers or the number of affected customers is equal to or more than two percent
      (2%) of the telecommunications service provider’s customer base. A telecommunications service provider with a customer base of less than one hundred (100) customers shall report errors when two (2) or more customers are affected.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2730.2.</num>
    <text>Each telecommunications service provider shall file a billing error report within three (3) business days of discovering or being notified of the error. The billing error report shall be filed with the Commission and served on the Office of the People’s
      Counsel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2730.3.</num>
    <text>The billing error report shall include the following:</text>
    <text>Type(s) of billing error(s);</text>
    <text>Date of the billing error(s);</text>
    <text>Number of customers affected;</text>
    <text>Cause of the error and status of any and all corrective action(s) taken; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Timeline for completing any and all other required corrective action(s).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2730.4.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of the billing error report, the Commission shall determine whether any further investigation is necessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 11993 (December 14, 2007); incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 9404 (September 28, 2007); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 9020, 9040 (October
        21, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>