<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-2605</num>
  <heading>FILING REQUESTS FOR MEDIATION PURSUANT TO 47 U.S.C. ยง 252(A)(2) (ยง 15-2605)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2605.1.</num>
    <text>Pursuant to 47 U.S.C. ยง 252(a)(2), any telecommunications carrier, including the incumbent local exchange carrier, participating in voluntary negotiation pursuant to 47 U.S.C. ยง 252(a)(1), may, at any point in the negotiation, file a request for the
      Commission to participate in the negotiation and to mediate any differences arising in the course of the negotiation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2605.2.</num>
    <text>A request for mediation shall be in writing and shall include, at a minimum, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and main telephone number of the telecommunications carrier requesting mediation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name, title, business address, telephone number, fax number, and e-mail address (if available) of the person(s) who will be representing the requesting carrier during the mediation process;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A complete list of all telecommunications carriers that participated in the negotiation that is the subject of the request for mediation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A statement of any issues that are unresolved by the mediating parties;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A statement of any issues that have been resolved by the mediating parties;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A statement of those issues for which the requesting carrier requests mediation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A statement outlining the positions of each mediating party regarding the unresolved issues, listing any areas of potential compromise.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2605.3.</num>
    <text>An original and fifteen (15) copies of a request for mediation shall be filed with the Office of the Commission Secretary. A request for mediation shall be served on the telecommunications carrier or carriers that participated in the negotiation that
      is the subject of the request for mediation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2605.4.</num>
    <text>The Commission&amp;#8217;s procedural rules shall not apply to the requests for mediation, except as provided in this Chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 5242 (June 23, 2000) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8315 (October 20, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 2905 (March 19, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>