<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-2806</num>
  <heading>ELIGIBILITY TO RECEIVE UNIVERSAL SERVICE FUNDING (§ 15-2806)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2806.1.</num>
    <text>Upon request by a local exchange carrier, and after notice and comment, the Commission shall consider designation of the requesting carrier as an ETC to receive funding from the DC USTF under the District of Columbia Telecommunications Competition
      Act of 1996, 47 U.S.C. § 214(e) and the FCC rules implementing 47 U.S.C. § 214(e). Interested parties may file comments within thirty (30) days after publication of the Commission’s Notice of Proposed Rulemaking, and reply comments within forty-five
      (45) days of publication.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2806.2.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall designate a requesting local exchange carrier as an ETC, provided:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The LEC is certificated by the Commission to provide local exchange service, and offers all universal services to all residential customers in the District in a nondiscriminatory manner;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The LEC has a compliant tariffed lifeline service in the District and advertises the availability and charges for lifeline service(s) it provides through multiple media of general distribution reasonably expected to reach eligible residents;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The LEC has been designated as an ETC for purposes of Federal Universal Service support, or such designation is granted concurrent with designation of eligibility for District funding;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The LEC can demonstrate that it is technically and financially capable of providing lifeline service; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The Commission determines that the designation is in the public interest and that the LEC complies with the appropriate Commission and FCC regulations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2806.3.</num>
    <text>In order to be designated as an ETC for purposes of Federal Universal Service support, the local exchange carrier shall meet the requirements of 47 U.S.C. § 214(e) and the FCC’s rules implementing 47 U.S.C. § 214(e).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 8198 (October 3, 2003); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 8585, 8587 (October 7, 2011); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 12141 (October 19, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>