<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-2199</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 15-2199)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2199.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have the meaning ascribed:</text>
    <text>Aesthetic Site &amp;#8211; a site whose aesthetic nature is of general public interest or is officially recognized by a District of Columbia or federal agency charged with responsibility to oversee the protection of the environment.</text>
    <text>Applicant &amp;#8211; any person seeking approval to construct facilities covered by this Chapter.</text>
    <text>Application &amp;#8211; a request for approval to construct facilities covered by this Chapter.</text>
    <text>Archaeological Site &amp;#8211; a site within the District of Columbia yielding artifacts, structural remains, or evidence of occupation or use before the year 1900 as designated by the agency or governmental unit with responsibility for archaeological
      sites.</text>
    <text>Certificate of Public Convenience and Necessity &amp;#8211; an order issued by the Commission on application of a person granting such person the right to construct an electric generating station or transmission line covered by this Chapter.</text>
    <text>Cogenerator &amp;#8211; a power producer that qualifies as a cogenerator under the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978.</text>
    <text>Commission &amp;#8211; Public Service Commission of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Committee &amp;#8211; the project coordinating committee.</text>
    <text>Construction &amp;#8211; any clearing of land, excavation, or other action that would affect the natural environment of the site or route of a bulk power supply facility. Construction is not a change needed for temporary use of a site or route for
      a non-utility purpose or for use in securing geological data, including borings necessary to ascertain foundation conditions.</text>
    <text>Current Situation &amp;#8211; another electric plant, overhead transmission line, other structure, facility or use which the proposed action will replace or otherwise affect.</text>
    <text>Electric Corporation &amp;#8211; pursuant to D.C. Code, 2001 Ed. ยง 34-207, an electric corporation includes an electric utility, cogenerator, small power producer, or independent power producer doing business in the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Electric Plant &amp;#8211; generating facilities or transmission lines to be used in connection with or to facilitate the generation, transmission, and distribution, sale or furnishing of electricity of sixty-nine thousand (69,000) volts or over,
      including cogeneration facilities, small power projects, independent power projects and PEPCO-owned electric plants.</text>
    <text>Environmental Impacts &amp;#8211; impacts upon the environment as defined by D.C. Code, 2001 Ed. ยง 34-2601 et seq.</text>
    <text>Externality &amp;#8211; any environmental impact that remains after mitigation.</text>
    <text>Generating Station &amp;#8211; property or facilities constituting an integral plant or unit for the production of electric energy, including any new production unit that would be added to an existing production plant.</text>
    <text>Greenhouse Gas &amp;#8211; any gas commonly deemed to contribute to global warming, including carbon dioxide (CO2), methane (CH4), chlorofluorocarbons (CFCs) and nitrous oxide (N2O).</text>
    <text>Historical Site &amp;#8211; a site within the District of Columbia duly registered by the: District of Columbia Historical Trust; National Register of Historic Places; National Register of Natural Landmarks; Register of National Historic Landmarks;
      and National Trust for Historic Preservation or any other agency as may be recognized by the Public Service Commission of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Independent Power Producer &amp;#8211; a non-traditional public utility which produces and sells electricity but has no significant market power; lacks significant market power as a supplier of energy and capacity because it does not have captive
      customers; and has limited or no control of transmission facilities essential to their customers; or as defined under applicable law(s).</text>
    <text>Pepco &amp;#8211; the Potomac Electric Power Company or any successor in interest.</text>
    <text>Person &amp;#8211; every individual, corporation, company, association, joint stock company, firm, partnership or other entity.</text>
    <text>Project &amp;#8211; a proposed generating station or overhead transmission line designed to carry voltage of sixty-nine thousand (69,000) volts or over.</text>
    <text>Small Power Producer &amp;#8211; a power producer that qualifies as a small power producer under the public utility regulatory policies act of 1978.</text>
    <text>Smaller-Scale Construction &amp;#8211; any construction project which involves providing electricity to a customer for which a Certificate of Public Convenience and Necessity is not required pursuant to this chapter.</text>
    <text>Socio-economic Impacts &amp;#8211; existing patterns of population concentration, distribution, or growth, and existing community or neighborhood characteristics, including traffic patterns and noise levels.</text>
    <text>Substation &amp;#8211; a plant that is used to alter the voltage of electricity. For the purposes of this chapter, substation must be connected to a transmission line of sixty-nine thousand (69,000) volts or greater.</text>
    <text>Transmission Line &amp;#8211; property or facilities constructed as an overhead transmission line designed to carry a voltage of sixty-nine thousand (69,000) volts or greater, or an underground transmission line designed to carry in excess of sixty-nine
      thousand (69,000) volts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 8359, 8382 (December 3, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 8657 (September 3, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 9455 (October 8, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>