<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-2315</num>
  <heading>GAS PROCUREMENT REPORT (§ 15-2315)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2315.1.</num>
    <text>On December 1st, biennially, the Washington Gas Light Company (WGL or Company), shall file a Gas Procurement Report (GPR) setting forth the Company&amp;#8217;s gas procurement strategies and practices.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2315.2.</num>
    <text>The GPR shall contain the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Actual and projected annual and monthly gas supply, billing determinants and costs, including weighted average cost of gas, as allocated to major classes of service by jurisdiction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Actual and projected margins for sales to flex rate interruptible and special contract customers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An outline of the efforts made to obtain and maintain a reliable gas supply at reasonable costs; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>An outline and discussion of the decision-making basis and planning procedures utilized by WGL in its gas procurement activities.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2315.3.</num>
    <text>The GPR shall consist of at least four (4) sections which address the directives in Commission Order No. 9793, as well as other considerations agreed upon by the members of the Gas Procurement Working Group (GPWG). The GPWG, which shall consist of
      representatives from the Staff of the Commission (Staff), the Office of the People’s Counsel (OPC) and WGL, shall meet periodically to discuss and refine the GPR. However, WGL, not the GPWG, shall formulate the GPR.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2315.4.</num>
    <text>The GPWG shall review and discuss gas procurement planning activities and strategies. The GPWG shall transfer technical knowledge to the Staff which will ultimately assist in the Commission&amp;#8217;s review and evaluation of the Company&amp;#8217;s
      planning activities and strategies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2315.5.</num>
    <text>OPC and the public may file comments not later than forty-five (45) days from the date of the GPR&amp;#8217;s submission to the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2315.6.</num>
    <text>The Staff shall review the proposed GPR and by March 1st shall submit a report to the Commission summarizing and evaluating the comments of public parties and OPC and providing its recommendations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2315.7.</num>
    <text>WGL should submit reply comments, if any, not later than fifteen (15) days from the submission of comments of OPC, Staff, or the public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2315.8.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall review the GPR, along with any public comments, OPC&amp;#8217;s comments and Staff&amp;#8217;s comments, and any reply comments and thereafter make public its evaluation of the GPR by April 1st.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 202 (January 14, 1994); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9346 (November 24, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 7 (January 4, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>