<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-2699</num>
  <heading>DEFINTIONS (§ 15-2699)
    <text>The following words and terms, when used in this Chapter, shall have theollowing definitions unless the context clearly states otherwise:</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Approved agreement&amp;#8221; means an agreement approved by the Commissionursuant to Section 252 of the Telecommunications Act of 1996, D.C. Code, 2001d. § 34-2002(h) and Section 2604.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Arbitrating party&amp;#8221; means one of the telecommunications carriersarticipating in the arbitration proceeding.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Arbitration agreement&amp;#8221; means the agreement or amended agreementeached by the arbitrating parties pursuant to the arbitration decision.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Arbitration decision&amp;#8221; means the signed decision of the arbitratorr the arbitration panel.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Arbitration petition&amp;#8221; means a petition filed by aelecommunications carrier requesting the Commission for arbitration pursuant to7 U.S.C. § 252(b).</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Commission&amp;#8221; means the Public Service Commission of the District ofolumbia.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Commission&amp;#8217;s procedural rules&amp;#8221; means the Commission&amp;#8217;sules of Practice and Procedure that are contained in Chapter 1 of Title 15CMR.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Days&amp;#8221; means calendar days, unless otherwise specified.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Enforcement petition&amp;#8221; means a petition to enforce an approvedgreement.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Ex parte communication&amp;#8221; means an oral or written communicationetween the arbitrator and a telecommunications carrier&amp;#8217;s representativeelating to the merits of the proceeding, which is made without providing allther telecommunications
      carriers participating in the arbitration proceedinghe opportunity to participate.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Incumbent local exchange carrier&amp;#8221; means, with respect to an area,he local exchange carrier that provided local exchange service in such an arean the date of enactment of the federal. Telecommunications Act of 1996 (P.L.04-104).</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Interpretation petition&amp;#8221; means a petition filed to interpret anpproved agreement.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Interpretation or enforcement decision&amp;#8221; means a signed decision ofhe Commission&amp;#8217;s agent in an interpretation or enforcement proceeding.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Interpretation or enforcement proceeding&amp;#8221; means a proceeding inhich the Commission interprets or enforces an approved agreement.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Local exchange carrier&amp;#8221; means any person or entity that is engagedn the provision of telephone exchange service or exchange access. The term doesot include a person or entity insofar as the person or entity is engaged in therovision
      of commercial mobile service.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Mediating party&amp;#8221; means a party participating in mediation.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Negotiated agreement&amp;#8221; means an agreement or amended agreementetween a telecommunications carrier and an incumbent local exchange carrierursuant to 47 U.S.C. § 252 arrived at through voluntary negotiation orediation. A negotiated
      agreement includes an interconnection agreement that waspted into by telecommunications service providers either in the District ofolumbia or another jurisdiction.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Party&amp;#8221; means a person, entity, individual, corporation,artnership, or association.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Petitioning carrier&amp;#8221; means a telecommunications carrier that files request for arbitration pursuant to 47 U.S.C. § 252(b) or that files aetition for enforcement and interpretation of an approved agreement.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Requesting carrier&amp;#8221; means a telecommunications carrier that files aequest for mediation pursuant to 47 U.S.C. § 252(a)(2).</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Responding carrier&amp;#8221; means a telecommunications carrier thatesponds to a request for mediation or an arbitration, enforcement, ornterpretation petition.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Telecommunications&amp;#8221; means the transmission, between or among pointspecified by the user, of information of the user&amp;#8217;s choosing, withouthange in the form or content of the information as sent and received.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Telecommunications carrier&amp;#8221; means any provider ofelecommunications services, except that the term does not include aggregatorsf telecommunications services as defined in 47 U.S.C. § 226.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Telecommunications service&amp;#8221; means the offering ofelecommunications for a fee directly to the public or to such classes of userss to be effectively available to the public, regardless of the facilities used.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 5242 (June 23, 2000)EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8315 (October 20,000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 140 (January 5, 2001);s amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 51 DCR 2905 (March 19, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>