<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-2107</num>
  <heading>COMMUNITY ADVISORY GROUP (ยง 15-2107)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2107.1.</num>
    <text>In order to inform and educate the community regarding the construction and operation of any proposed project, the applicant shall convene a community advisory group.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2107.2.</num>
    <text>The applicant shall notify the public of the opportunity to participate in the community advisory group by providing written notice to the Advisory Neighborhood Commission(s) in which the facility or transmission line is to be located. In addition,
      the Commission shall post the applicant&amp;#8217;s notice on the Commission&amp;#8217;s website.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2107.3.</num>
    <text>The membership of the community advisory group shall include the following representatives:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The applicant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Commission staff, which shall chair all meetings of the group;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Advisory Neighborhood Commission of the community where the power plant or power line is to be located;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Interested members of the public; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any other persons the Commission deems appropriate.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2107.4.</num>
    <text>The advisory group shall convene public meetings and disseminate information to the community regarding the construction and operation of the proposed project.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2107.5.</num>
    <text>The advisory group shall not be authorized to take any specific action with respect to the construction or operation of the proposed project.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 8644 (September 3, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>