<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-2505</num>
  <heading>CERTIFICATION BY WAIVER REQUIREMENTS (ยง 15-2505)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2505.1.</num>
    <text>The Commission may waive the experience and annual gross revenue requirements of Section 2504 of these Rules, if an applicant demonstrates in its Application that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The applicant has sufficient experience to ensure the continued provision of local exchange services within the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The applicant has the financial stability to ensure the continued provision of local exchange services within the District; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The public interest will be served by the applicant&amp;#8217;s entry into the local telecommunications marketplace within the District.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant will be deemed to have sufficient experience to ensure the continued provision of local exchange services within the District if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The applicant or its affiliate has at least three (3) years of experience providing telecommunications services pursuant to authorization(s) by the FCC or a state regulatory body;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The applicant employs individuals with: 1 ) substantial managerial experience in the telecommunications industry, and 2) adequate technical expertise to provide the telecommunications services proposed in the Application; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Application otherwise demonstrates that the applicant has sufficient experience to ensure the continued provision of local exchange services within the District.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant will be deemed to have the financial stability to ensure the continued provision of local exchange services within the District if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The applicant or its affiliate(s) derived at least $50 million in gross annual revenue from telecommunications services in any of the last three years preceding the Application;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The applicant has cash, a line of credit, or other resources sufficient to meet its anticipated capital requirements for operations in the District of Columbia for a minimum of three years;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The applicant demonstrates that: 1) an affiliate, in a notarized document, agrees to provide financial support sufficient to meet the applicant&amp;#8217;s anticipated capital requirements for a minimum of three years, and 2) the financial strength
        of that affiliate is sufficient to provide support; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Application otherwise demonstrates that the applicant has the financial stability to exercise staying power in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.4.</num>
    <text>The public interest will be served by an applicant&amp;#8217;s entry into the local telecommunications marketplace within the District when the applicant and its affiliate (if the applicant relies on an affiliate to demonstrate its financial stability
      and/or experience):</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Are deemed by the Commission as technically and financially qualified to provide local exchange service in the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If at any time ever certificated by any other state regulatory body to provide local exchange service, had a satisfactory history of regulatory compliance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Provide, either directly or through arrangements with others, at a minimum, the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Access to 911 and E911 services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Access to telecommunications relay services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Access to directory assistance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Access to operator services; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Interconnection on a non-discriminatory basis with other local exchange carriers.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.5.</num>
    <text>The Commission may waive the requirement that applicants provide all of the services listed in 2505.4(c) upon good cause shown.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 2601(April 14, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8112 (October 6, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>