<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-2607</num>
  <heading>DUTIES OF THE MEDIATOR (ยง 15-2607)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2607.1.</num>
    <text>The mediator functions to assist the parties to move toward a resolution of any differences arising in the course of the negotiation. The mediator may not compel agreement but shall provide assistance to the parties in reaching agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2607.2.</num>
    <text>The mediator shall have the authority to schedule meetings of the parties; direct the parties to prepare for those meetings; determine the need for written submissions; conduct the dispute resolution process; hold separate caucuses when appropriate;
      upon request, assist the parties in preparing a written agreement resolving any differences; and terminate the dispute resolution process, if no agreement is reached after such period of time as the mediator deems reasonable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2607.3.</num>
    <text>The mediator may take any actions deemed necessary to ensure the confidentiality of the mediation, including but not limited to excluding persons not parties to the mediation from the sessions and requiring that parties sign any confidentiality and/or
      proprietary agreement that is deemed reasonable by the mediator as a condition of participating in the mediation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2607.4.</num>
    <text>Within seven (7) business days of the conclusion of the mediation, the mediator shall submit a report to the Commission that lists each issue submitted by the parties for mediation and states the disposition of each issue.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 5242 (June 23, 2000) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8315 (October 20, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51DCR 2905 (March 19, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>