<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-2111</num>
  <heading>UNDERGROUND TRANSMISSION LINES IN EXCESS OF SIXTY-NINE THOUSAND VOLTS ANDUBSTATIONS CONNECTED TO SUCH LINES (§ 15-2111)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2111.1.</num>
    <text>An electric corporation which plans to construct inside the District of Columbia an underground transmission line in excess of sixty-nine thousand (69,000) volts, or substation connected to such line, shall file formal notice with the Commission six
      (6) months prior to the construction. This formal notice shall include a discussion of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the principal place of business of the electric corporation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name, title, and address of the person authorized to receive notices and communications with respect to the application;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The location or locations where the public may inspect or obtain a copy of the application;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A list of each District of Columbia, state, or federal government agency having authority to approve or disapprove the construction or operation of the project and containing the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A statement indicating whether the necessary approval from each agency has been obtained, with a copy of each approval or disapproval attached;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A statement indicating the circumstances under which any necessary approval has not been obtained; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A statement indicating whether any waiver or variance has been requested, with a copy of each approval or disapproval attached.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The proposed date construction is to be initiated;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The need for the underground transmission line or substation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The type and voltage level(s) of the underground transmission line or substation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Property or property right acquired or to be acquired;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Location of the proposed construction, including affected streets by name;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Duration of the proposed construction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Impact of the proposed project on affected neighborhood and community; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Possible mitigating measures which could be employed to minimize impact upon the affected neighborhood or community.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2111.2.</num>
    <text>Other provisions of this chapter shall not apply to underground substations and underground transmission lines.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2111.3.</num>
    <text>All information required in § 2111.1 shall be served on the affected Advisory Neighborhood Commission(s) and the Office of the People&amp;#8217;s Counsel on the same date it is filed with the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2111.4.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall entertain petitions filed by any interested person within ninety (90) days of the date of a formal notice provided under § 2111.1 for the Commission to investigate the reasonableness, safety and need for the underground transmission
      line or substation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2111.5.</num>
    <text>If the Commission initiates an investigation, the electric corporation shall submit a detailed analysis of the information required in § 2111.1. The electric corporation shall also submit the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An explanation of the need for and the cost-effectiveness of the project in meeting demand for service;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A description of the effect of the project on system stability and reliability;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A description of the consequences if the project is delayed or not approved;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A statement regarding the probability that the consequences of § 2111.5(c) will occur;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A description of the applicant&amp;#8217;s transmission planning criteria;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A description of one-line diagrams regarding the power flows relied upon which determined the need for the proposed line;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Engineering and construction features including the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Width, length, and total acreage of the right-of-way;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Line voltage;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Number of circuits;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Number of circuits per structure;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Structure type and dimensions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Conductor configuration and size;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Nominal capacity (MVA);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Nominal length of span between structures; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Description and dimensions of any related conduit.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Location and identification of all portions or the right-of-way requiring construction within the one hundred (100) year floodplain of any stream;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The description of each alternative route considered for the transmission line and alternative placement of a substation shall include the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An estimate of the capital and annual operating cost of each alternative route or placement; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A statement of the reason why each alternative route or placement was rejected.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>An analysis of potential impact upon the environment; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Engineering and construction features of the alternative underground transmission line including the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Width, length, and total acreage of the right-of-way,</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Line voltage;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Number of circuits;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Number of circuits per structure;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Structure type and dimensions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Conductor configuration and size;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Nominal capacity (MA);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Nominal length of span between structures; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Description and dimensions of any related conduit.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2111.6.</num>
    <text>If no petition is submitted prior to the proposed date of construction, the electric corporation may begin construction pursuant to permits its receives from other District of Columbia agencies such as the Department of Transportation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 8359, 8367 (December 3, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 8654 (September 3, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>