<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-2707</num>
  <heading>REPORTS (§ 15-2707)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2707.1.</num>
    <text>All telecommunications service providers in the District shall be required to file an annual report with the Commission on the Commission’s annual report form by April 15 of each year, including the following information:</text>
    <text>Type of services being provided to customers in the District as of the previous year ending December 31;</text>
    <text>Number of lines and customers, classified by residential category</text>
    <text>(single family or multi-family complex) and commercial category (business or government);</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Jurisdictional revenue for the previous year ending December 31;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Name, address, telephone number, fax number, and e-mail address, if available, of the regulatory and customer service contacts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The means by which the telecommunications service provider is providing service (such as, resale through the incumbent local exchange carrier, resale through another provider, facilities-based including lease of unbundled network elements, resale,
        and facilities-based, or other); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Such other information as the Commission may require.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2707.2.</num>
    <text>A telecommunications service provider requesting that its report, or any portion thereof, be treated as confidential shall follow the procedures outlined in 15 DCMR § 150 regarding confidential and proprietary information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 10001 (October 29, 2004); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 9020, 9036 (October 21, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>