<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-2304</num>
  <heading>PUBLIC AWARENESS (ยง 15-2304)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2304.1.</num>
    <text>A gas corporation shall provide notice to each customer at least twice annually, informing the customer of the hazards of leaking gas and instructing the customer in the procedures to be followed in reporting gas leaks. A sample odor indicator shall
      be included in each biennial notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.2.</num>
    <text>A gas corporation shall provide notice twice annually, through newspaper or other means of mass communication, to the general public of the hazards of leaking gas and instructing the general public in the procedures to be followed in reporting gas
      leaks.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.3.</num>
    <text>Notices shall include information regarding the possible entry of gas by various means, including leakage along routes where gas service is not provided.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.4.</num>
    <text>A gas corporation shall implement targeted distribution of print materials annually to residents located along transmission pipeline rights of way and places of public assembly. Materials shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Information regarding the purpose and reliability of the pipeline;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Hazards and prevention measures undertaken;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Damage prevention;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>One-call requirements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Leak recognition and response;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Pipeline location information;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>How to get additional information; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Availability of list of pipeline operators through the National Pipeline Mapping System (NPMS).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 7 (January 4, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>