<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-3604</num>
  <heading>BILLING ERROR NOTIFICATION (ยง 15-3604)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3604.1.</num>
    <text>The electric utility and all electricity suppliers must inform the Commission&amp;#8217;s Office of Engineering and the Office of the People&amp;#8217;s Counsel when a billing error has affected 100 or more customers or the number of affected customers
      is equal to or more than two (2) percent of the electric utility&amp;#8217;s or electricity supplier&amp;#8217;s customer base (whichever is less). The electric utility and electricity suppliers with a customer base of less than 100 customers shall
      report errors when two (2) or more customers are affected.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3604.2.</num>
    <text>The electric utility and all electricity suppliers shall file an initial billing error notification within one (1) business day of discovering or being notified of the error. After submitting the initial notification, the electric utility and electricity
      suppliers must submit a follow-up written report within fourteen (14) calendar days and a final written report within sixty (60) calendar days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3604.3.</num>
    <text>The initial billing error notification shall be sent by electronic mail to the Commission&amp;#8217;s Office of Engineering and to the Office of the People&amp;#8217;s Counsel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3604.4.</num>
    <text>The initial billing error notification shall contain the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The type(s) of billing error(s) found;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The date and time the billing error(s) was discovered;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>How the electric utility or electricity supplier discovered the error(s); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The approximate number of customers affected.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3604.5.</num>
    <text>The follow-up written report shall contain the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The type(s) of billing error(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The date and time of the billing error(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The number of customers affected;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The cause of the error and status of any and all corrective action(s) taken; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The timeline for completing any and all other required corrective action(s), which must include the provision of refunds and/or credits, no later than 60 days after the billing error(s) was discovered, as necessary to correct the billing error(s).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3604.6.</num>
    <text>The final written report shall contain the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The type(s) of billing error(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The date and time of billing error(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The number of customers affected and the dollar amount involved;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The duration of the billing error(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The corrective action(s) and preventative measure(s) taken; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The lessons learned, if any.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3604.7.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of the final written report, the Commission shall determine whether any further investigation is necessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 9376 (September 28, 2007); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 1943 (February 29, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>