<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-3108</num>
  <heading>APPOINTMENTS, INSTALLATION AND REPAIR (ยง 15-3108)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3108.1.</num>
    <text>Upon a request for a cable-related service that requires access to the subscriber&amp;#8217;s premises, a cable operator shall either offer a specific time or &amp;#8220;appointment window&amp;#8221; time block of not more than four (4) hours for
      the selection of the subscriber. The appointment window may be longer only if the subscriber consents. A cable operator may schedule appointments outside of normal business hours for the express convenience of the subscriber.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3108.2.</num>
    <text>A cable operator may not cancel an appointment after 5:00 p.m. on the day before a scheduled appointment, except for appointments scheduled within twelve (12) hours after the subscriber&amp;#8217;s call to establish the appointment. If a cable operator
      fails to comply with this provision, the cable operator shall grant to a subscriber a credit of at least $20.00 for each violation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3108.3.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section 3108, normal business hours shall be at least ten hours per day on weekdays and at least eight (8) hours in the aggregate on the weekend.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3108.4.</num>
    <text>The cable operator shall ensure that its records and work orders accurately reflect the appointment windows given to subscribers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3108.5.</num>
    <text>A cable operator shall inform a subscriber at the time an appointment is scheduled of its service procedures, required payments, foreseeable delays, and phone or field verification procedures, including those circumstances in which a cable operator
      may cancel the appointment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3108.6.</num>
    <text>A cable operator shall complete standard installations during a single appointment to the subscriber&amp;#8217;s address. If a subsequent appointment is needed to complete an unusual installation, a cable operator shall inform the subscriber and shall
      schedule the appointment for the earliest mutually available time period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3108.7.</num>
    <text>Within a reasonable time prior to an appointment period, a cable operator shall call the subscriber to confirm the appointment. If the subscriber does not answer the telephone call and the subscriber has an answering system, a cable operator shall
      leave a message.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3108.8.</num>
    <text>A cable operator shall not cancel or reschedule an appointment on the grounds that a subscriber is unavailable during the appointment window unless the cable operator has verified both over the phone and in person at the subscriber&amp;#8217;s address
      as described in this subsection that the subscriber or another authorized person is not available within the appointment window or at the specific appointment time. If a cable operator fails to comply with this provision or subsection, the cable
      operator shall grant a credit to the affected subscriber of at least twenty dollars ($20) for each violation. When a cable operator arrives at a subscriber&amp;#8217;s address for an appointment, the cable operator shall make a reasonable effort
      to verify that the subscriber or another authorized person is present at the address. The reasonable effort of the cable operator shall include, at a minimum, knocking on the door or using the doorbell to alert the subscriber. This subsection shall
      not preclude the operator from imposing a reasonable charge related to costs, if the subscriber is not present at the specified time or during the appointment window time block; provided, the charge shall not exceed twenty dollars ($20).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3108.9.</num>
    <text>If the subscriber is unavailable during the scheduled appointment time or window, a cable operator shall leave written notice, such as a door tag or similar notice, with the identity of the person leaving the notice, the appointment time, the time
      that the cable operator determined the subscriber was not present at the subscriber&amp;#8217;s address, and telephone number(s) both to contact the cable operator&amp;#8217;s dispatcher during the appointment window or to reschedule the appointment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 6797 (July 19, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>