<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-3102</num>
  <heading>SUBSCRIPTION INFORMATION (ยง 15-3102)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3102.1.</num>
    <text>A cable operator shall provide written information in a complete and comprehensible manner to all subscribers at least annually, at the time of installation of service, and upon request, in each of the following areas:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A listing and description of the cable services provided by the cable operator;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A list of channel locations for all cable services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A listing of all rates, terms, and conditions for each cable service and service tier, each type of equipment, and all other charges, including without limitation, charges for installation, connection of additional outlets, equipment deposits, reconnecting
        service, VCR connections, relocating cable outlets, and returned checks;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The location(s), hours of operation, and telephone number(s) for each customer service center;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The location(s) and hours of operation of each payment center;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The telephone number(s) and address of a cable operator&amp;#8217;s customer service department and corporate office, accompanied by a brief description of the services and information that may be obtained by dialing each number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The website address for a cable operator&amp;#8217;s website used for customer service purposes, accompanied by a brief description of the services and information that may be obtained by accessing the website;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Notice of the availability of subscriber terminal equipment and the procedure to obtain the equipment, including, but not limited to, wireless remote control devices, parental control devices, digital converters, and closed caption decoders;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>A general explanation of other communications devices that may be used in conjunction with the system, including, but not limited to, video cassette recorders, remote control devices, cable modems, v-chip technology, closed captioning decoders,
        and parental control devices;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Notice of the commercial availability of universal remotes and other compatible equipment clearly indicating that a list of specific brands and models, consistent with 47 CFR ยง 76.1622(b)(3) as amended from time to time, shall be provided to a subscriber
        upon request;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>The terms for rental equipment, including procedures for the return of equipment and the subscriber&amp;#8217;s liability for lost, stolen, or damaged equipment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>A description of a cable operator&amp;#8217;s billing and collection procedures, including an applicable policy for late fees, returned check charges, and credit balances;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>The steps for resubscribing to cable service after an involuntary termination of service;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>The policy governing service outages and repair service, including the time periods by which repairs for reception problems and other service problems shall be made;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>The procedure for the resolution of billing disputes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(p)</num>
      <text>A policy of a cable operator concerning credits for customer service violations, including outages and reception problems;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(q)</num>
      <text>The procedure for return of deposits;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(r)</num>
      <text>The procedure and charges, if any, for service changes, including, but not limited to upgrade, downgrade, or termination of cable services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(s)</num>
      <text>All installation and maintenance policies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(t)</num>
      <text>A notice that subscribers may pay bills in person at a cable operator&amp;#8217;s customer service center(s) in the District or other payment location(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(u)</num>
      <text>A listing of special services for customers with disabilities, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(v)</num>
      <text>A description of a cable operator&amp;#8217;s procedure for the resolution of subscriber complaints, including providing contact information (address, phone number, and website address) of OCT for unresolved complaints;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(w)</num>
      <text>The policy concerning subscriber privacy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(x)</num>
      <text>An announcement that all cable operator employees and contractors who come into contact with subscribers at the subscriber&amp;#8217;s premises wear an identification card that includes the employee&amp;#8217;s name and photograph; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(y)</num>
      <text>Additional information to subscribers required by applicable law or franchise agreement.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3102.2.</num>
    <text>A cable operator shall post on its website and shall display at customer service center(s) at least one copy of the information required by subsection 3102.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3102.3.</num>
    <text>A cable operator shall include on its monthly bill a notice that complaints or inquiries not satisfactorily handled by the cable operator may be referred to OCT.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3102.4.</num>
    <text>A cable operator shall provide a copy of all subscription and solicitation information to be distributed pursuant to subsection 3102.1 to OCT, at least ten (10) days before distributing it to the first subscriber for review and comment, so that OCT
      may ensure that the information contained therein complies with applicable law and is not misleading. OCT may order the cable operator to correct the subscription information if OCT determines that the information does not comply with applicable
      law or is misleading.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3102.5.</num>
    <text>All promotional materials advertising cable services to subscribers and the general public shall accurately disclose rates and terms.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3102.6.</num>
    <text>A cable operator shall clearly and accurately disclose to subscribers prices and terms for all services, including the prices of pay-per-view and pay-per-event programming before an order is accepted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3102.7.</num>
    <text>A cable operator shall provide a written confirmation of any order, detailing all prices and terms and conditions, as part of the subscriber&amp;#8217;s next bill.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3102.8.</num>
    <text>In order that subscribers are fully apprised of the charges they may incur, a cable operator shall note that advertised rates are subject to additional taxes and fees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 6797 (July 19, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>