<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-3703</num>
  <heading>REPORTING AND RESPONDING REQUIREMENTS FOR GAS EMERGENCIES (§ 15-3703)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3703.1.</num>
    <text>The natural gas utility shall immediately dispatch personnel to the site of the natural gas-related emergency, and shall arrive at the site within fifty (50) minutes of receiving an emergency call during normal business and non-business hours.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3703.2.</num>
    <text>All natural gas-related emergencies shall be reported by telephone and e-mail to OE and OPC at the earliest practicable time, but not later than thirty (30) minutes after the utility’s dispatch has been informed that an emergency has occurred, with
      as much detailed information as possible. The natural gas utility shall provide updates to the initial report as it receives more information. This reporting requirement applies to business and non-business hours.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3703.3.</num>
    <text>Each telephone and e-mail report of a gas-related emergency shall state clearly, at a minimum, the following information:</text>
    <text>The location of the gas-related emergency, person making the report and</text>
    <text>contact information;</text>
    <text>The ward(s) and/or quadrant(s) where the emergency occurred;</text>
    <text>The estimated number of customers impacted by the emergency, and street shutdowns, if known;</text>
    <text>A preliminary assessment as to the cause of the gas-related emergency, if known;</text>
    <text>The time between becoming aware of the emergency and responding (arriving at the emergency site) to the emergency, if known;</text>
    <text>The estimated time to clear the emergency, if known;</text>
    <text>The estimated time to repair pipeline facilities affected by the emergency, and/or restore service, if known; and</text>
    <text>A preliminary assessment as to any injuries, deaths, or personal property damage, if known.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3703.4</num>
    <text>3703.4 During the course of a natural gas-related emergency on the natural gas utility’s system, the utility shall report periodically by telephone and e-mail to OE and OPC, regarding the status of the natural gas emergency and the utility’s progress
      in clearing the emergency and making the site safe.</text>
    <text>The utility shall provide updates or progress on the gas-related emergency every hour until the emergency is resolved.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3703.5.</num>
    <text>Written reports concerning all natural gas-related emergencies shall be filed with OCMS and OPC within five (5) days of the event occurrence. The utility shall provide updates to its written report as it receives more information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3703.6.</num>
    <text>Each written report concerning a natural gas-related emergency shall state clearly, at a minimum, the following information:</text>
    <text>The location of the natural gas emergency;</text>
    <text>The date and time when the natural gas-related emergency started;</text>
    <text>The date and time when the emergency crew arrived at the scene;</text>
    <text>The date and time when the natural gas-related emergency ended;</text>
    <text>An assessment as to the cause, origin, and contributing factors of the natural gas related emergency; and</text>
    <text>The steps the utility is taking to minimize the possibility of a recurrence of the incident.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 7646 (September 25, 2009), incorporating text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 1827, 1839 (February 27, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>