<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-321</num>
  <heading>PUBLICATION OF CONSUMER PAMPHLET (§ 15-321)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>321.1.</num>
    <text>The Utilities, Energy Suppliers, and Telecommunications Service Providers shall each, individually prepare a pamphlet in English and Spanish in layman’s terms summarizing the rights and responsibilities of Customers in accordance with these and other
      applicable rules. The text of each pamphlet is subject to prior Commission approval and pre-publication comment of the People’s Counsel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>321.2.</num>
    <text>The pamphlet shall be available at every Utility, Energy Supplier and Telecommunications Service Provider location open to the general public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>321.3.</num>
    <text>The pamphlet will be provided upon request at no charge to Customers.</text>
    <text>Each new Customer shall be offered a pamphlet free of charge.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>321.4.</num>
    <text>The pamphlet shall cover, if applicable, the following items:</text>
    <text>Billing procedures and estimation standards;</text>
    <text>Methods for a Customer to verify billing accuracy;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Customer’s right to have Meter tested free of charge by the utility once every twelve (12) months as well as a referee Meter test pursuant to 15 DCMR §2368 et seq.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Customer payment standards and procedures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Security Deposit;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Disconnection and reconnection of service;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Inquiry, service and complaint procedures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Public Service Commission Consumer Complaint resolution procedures and the availability of assistance and legal representation by the Office of the People’s Counsel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The availability of DPA for payment of Bills or Deposits; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Customer access to information required to be made available to them.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>321.5.</num>
    <text>The cover of the pamphlet shall indicate conspicuously that the pamphlet is provided in accordance with the rules of the Commission and shall indicate in English and Spanish that a Spanish version is available upon request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>321.6.</num>
    <text>Each Utility, Energy Supplier, or Telecommunications Service Provider shall have accessible during business hours a Spanish-speaking interpreter or maintain a toll free or local telephone number for Spanish-speaking persons who seek information about
      the rights and responsibilities of Customers, services, and programs of the service provider.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 10381, 10412 (June 1, 1979); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 10014 (September 26, 2008); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12494 (December 12, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>