<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-3505</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 15-3505)
    <text>&amp;#8220;Applicant&amp;#8221; means entity regulated by the Commission that appliesor authority to issue or amend tariffs or issue stocks or other evidences ofndebtedness that are payable in more than one year pursuant to this Chapter.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Application&amp;#8221; means the application for authority to issue or amendariffs or issue stocks or other evidence of indebtedness filed pursuant to thishapter.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Application filing date&amp;#8221; means the date upon which an applicationor review of tariff issuance or amendment or issuance of stock or evidences ofndebtedness is filed with the Commission.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Commission&amp;#8221; means the Public Service Commission of the District ofolumbia.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Competitive local exchange carrier&amp;#8221; means a provider ofelecommunications service that was not an incumbent local exchange carrier onanuary 31, 1996 but that is now certificated to provide local exchange serviceithin the District.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Days&amp;#8221; means calendar days, unless otherwise indicated in specificections.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Incumbent local exchange carrier&amp;#8221; means, with respect to an area,he local exchange carrier that provided local exchange service in such an arean the date of enactment of the federal Telecommunications Act of 1996 (P.L.04-104).</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Local exchange carrier&amp;#8221; means any person or entity that is engagedn the provision of telephone exchange service or exchange access. The term doesot include a person or entity insofar as the person or entity is engaged in therovision
      of commercial mobile service.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Local exchange service&amp;#8221; means a telecommunications service providedithin an exchange area.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Objection&amp;#8221; means the written statement filed to oppose the use ofhis Chapter to review an application.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Party&amp;#8221; means an individual, corporation, partnership, orssociation.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Publication date&amp;#8221; means the date the application is published inhe D.C. Register.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8202 (October 13, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>