<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-3003</num>
  <heading>NOTICE OF INSTALLATION OF CABLE FACILITIES (§ 15-3003)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3003.1.</num>
    <text>Before installing cable television facilities or equipment or residential rental property, the cable operator shall serve written notice to the owner, or authorized agent of the property, of the cable operator&amp;#8217;s intent to install cable television
      facilities and equipment. The notice shall be served by certified mail fifteen (15) days before the schedule installation date.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3003.2.</num>
    <text>The following information shall be contained in the notice:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the cable television operator;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the owner or authorized agent of the property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The approximate date of the installation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A description of the proposed method of installation of sufficient detail to enable the owner to respond as required under §3004.1;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A copy of D.C. Code §43-1844.1 (1981 Ed.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A citation to this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A statement that the cable television operator, after notice to the owner or authorized agent of the property, has the right to enter the property to make surveys or conduct other investigations to prepare for installation and that the cable television
        operator shall be liable to the owner for any damages caused by the entry;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>A statement that installation of cable television facilities shall conform to those reasonable conditions and architectural controls set forth in writing by the owner as being necessary to protect the safety, functioning, appearance of the premises,
        and the convenience and well-being of other tenants;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>A statement that the cable television operator or the tenant or a combination thereof shall bear the cost of the installation, operation or removal of the facilities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>A statement that the cable television operator shall, upon request, indemnify the owner for any damage caused in connection with the installation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>A statement that, in compensation for the access authorized under D.C. Code §43-1844.1 (1981 Ed.), the amount of one dollar ($1) shall be tendered when an access agreement is signed or, if necessary, Office approval to proceed with the installation
        of cable facilities is obtained;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>A statement that the owner may waive compensation for permitting the installation of cable television facilities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>A statement that the owner may, within sixty (60) days of service of this notice that installation has been completed, apply for compensation in excess of one dollar ($1); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>A statement that a response from the owner or authorized agent of the property shall be served on the cable television operator within fifteen (15) days and that failure to respond may result in the installation of cable television facilities pursuant
        to the approval of the Office.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3003.3.</num>
    <text>The cable television operator shall determine the identity of the owner or authorized agent of the property in question.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3003.4.</num>
    <text>At any time after delivery of the notice specified in §3003.2, an owner or authorized agent of the property may waive compensation for permitting the installation of cable television facilities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3003.5.</num>
    <text>Every cable television operator that installs cable television services or facilities pursuant to this chapter shall serve upon the owner or authorized agent of the property notice that installation has been completed within five (5) days of the initiation
      of cable service to a tenant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 7175, 7177 (September 30, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>