<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-3101</num>
  <heading>NOTICE (ยง 15-3101)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3101.1.</num>
    <text>In addition to notice required elsewhere in this chapter 31, a cable operator shall provide written notice to the Office of Cable Television (&amp;#8220;OCT&amp;#8221;) and to all subscribers at least thirty (30) days prior to the effective date of
      any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A change in a programming service or channels including the discontinuation of an existing service, addition of a new service, change in the channel location of any service, or an increase or decrease in the number of hours a service is carried
        over the cable operator&amp;#8217;s system;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A change in the rates, charges, terms, or conditions for the receipt of service or equipment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A change in the location or hours of operation of a customer service center;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A change in billing practices; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A change of the policies or other information set forth pursuant to subsection 3102.1.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3101.2.</num>
    <text>Any notice required by subsection 3101.1 shall specify, as applicable, the service or services affected; the new rate, charge, term, or condition; the effect of the change; and the effective date of the change. A notice of a change in programming
      services or channel locations shall include a concise description of the new programming service and the specific channel location of that programming service. In addition, should the channel locations of other services be affected by the introduction
      of a new service, the information shall also be included in the notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3101.3.</num>
    <text>A cable operator shall provide to OCT annually, by no later than December 15 of each year, a listing of its closings or holidays for the upcoming year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3101.4.</num>
    <text>The initial notice to subscribers regarding a change subject to subsection 3101.1(a) and (b) shall include an advertisement placed in a daily periodical or newspaper of general distribution (for example, The Washington Post). The notice shall also
      be placed in a Spanish daily periodical. A cable operator shall also provide written notice of changes to subscribers in billing messages, inserts, or other communications prior to the date of the service change. A cable operator shall provide a
      copy of such notice to OCT upon the request of OCT.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3101.5.</num>
    <text>A cable operator shall post notice of the service changes at its customer service center and on its website at least thirty (30) days prior to the proposed change and shall maintain the notices until at least fourteen (14) days after the date of the
      service change.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3101.6.</num>
    <text>A cable operator may provide electronic notice (for example, scrolling messages) or advertisement spots of programming service changes or rate changes on local origination channels or on channels used for local advertisement insertions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 6797 (July 19, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>