<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-3301</num>
  <heading>ALLOCATION OF CHANNELS (ยง 15-3301)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3301.1.</num>
    <text>Subject to the restriction provided in subsection 3301.5, OCT may allocate channels to any entity, which may include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Mayor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Council;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Public Access Corporation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The University of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>District of Columbia Public Schools; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Other governmental agencies or institutions, nonprofit organizations, and educational institutions.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3301.2.</num>
    <text>In carrying out these objectives, OCT shall ensure that at all times:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>At least two (2) channels on the lowest service tier of cable television channels provided by the District&amp;#8217;s cable television system operators or open video system operators is allocated to the Mayor for use as a government channel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>At least two (2) channels on the lowest service tier of cable television channels provided by the District&amp;#8217;s cable television system operators or open video system operators is allocated to the Council for use as a government channel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>At least one (1) channel on the lowest service tier of cable television channels provided by the District&amp;#8217;s cable television system operators or open video system operators is allocated to the University of the District of Columbia (UDC)
        for use as an educational channel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>At least one (1) channel on the lowest service tier of cable television channels provided by the District&amp;#8217;s cable television system operators or open video system operators is allocated to the District of Columbia Public Schools (DCPS)
        for use as an educational channel; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>At least three (3) channels on the lowest service tier a of cable television channels provided by the District&amp;#8217;s cable television system operators or open video system operators are allocated to the Public Access Corporation (PAC) for
        use as public channels.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3301.3.</num>
    <text>The remaining channels after the minimum allocations as provided in subsection 3301.2 shall be allocated by OCT pursuant to these rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3301.4.</num>
    <text>The discretionary allocation provision in subsection 3301.3 and the application procedure in section 3302 shall not apply to additional channels requested by the Mayor or the Council for their use. Such additional channels shall be allocated by OCT
      upon request of the Mayor or the Council, subject to availability.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3301.5.</num>
    <text>Allocation of channels on the lowest service tier shall be subject to the approval of the Council, except that Council&amp;#8217;s approval shall not be required for allocations made to the Mayor or the Council for their use. Allocation of additional
      channels shall not be subject to the approval of the Council.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 7543 (September 5, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>