<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-3110</num>
  <heading>INTERRUPTION OF SERVICE (ยง 15-3110)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3110.1.</num>
    <text>A cable operator shall exercise its best efforts to limit a scheduled interruption of cable service to the shortest period of time, to the greatest extent possible.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3110.2.</num>
    <text>Except in emergencies or for interruptions of five (5) minutes or less, a cable operator shall interrupt system service after 7:00 a.m. and before 12:00 Midnight, on a weekend night, or a night preceding a legal holiday, only after gaining the approval
      of OCT and notifying subscribers. A cable operator shall notify OCT of the scheduled service interruption at least seventy-two (72) hours in advance, which period shall include at least one business day. A cable operator shall provide notice to
      subscribers of the interruption at least forty-eight (48) hours in advance, unless OCT authorizes a shorter period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3110.3.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection 3110.2, a cable operator may interrupt service after 12:00 Midnight and before 7:00 a.m. for greater than five (5) minutes and to conduct routine tests, maintenance, construction, repair, and other purposes with prior
      notification to OCT and affected subscribers. The cable operator shall provide notice at least forty-eight (48) hours in advance of a scheduled service interruption, unless OCT authorizes a shorter period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3110.4.</num>
    <text>A cable operator may provide notice to subscribers of a scheduled service outage through various means including electronic messages, advertisement spots on the system (for example, scrolling messages), or information on the cable operator&amp;#8217;s
      website.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3110.5.</num>
    <text>A cable operator shall maintain a written log of all service interruptions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 6797 (July 19, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>