<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-3199</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 15-3199)
    <text>When used in this chapter, the terms and phrases defined in this section shallave the meaning ascribed:</text>
    <text>Cable Operator &amp;#8211; any person or group (A) who provides cable service over aable system and directly or through one or more affiliates owns a significantnterest in such cable system, or (B) who otherwise controls or is responsibleor, through
      any arrangement, the management or operation of such a cableystem.</text>
    <text>Customer Service Representative &amp;#8211; a person employed or contracted by aable operator to assist, or provide service to, subscribers, whether bynswering telephone calls, managing repair or installation orders, answeringubscribers&amp;#8217;
      questions, receiving and processing payments, or performingther customer service-related tasks.</text>
    <text>OCT &amp;#8211; District of Columbia Government Office of Cable Television.</text>
    <text>Standard Installation &amp;#8211; any installation to a residence from the cableperator&amp;#8217;s existing network that does not exceed two hundred fifty (250)eet or as defined by an applicable franchise agreement.</text>
    <text>Subscriber &amp;#8211; a person who lawfully receives or requests to receive cableervice of any sort from a cable operator. The term shall have the same meanings the term &amp;#8220;customer&amp;#8221;.</text>
    <text>Unusual Circumstance &amp;#8211; a special occasion when the cable operatoroluntarily suspends its normal operations, such as a staff meeting. The termoes not include suspensions of operations caused by emergency circumstancesutside of the control
      of the cable operator, such as a natural disaster or anydentified force majeure.</text>
    <text>Website &amp;#8211; an Internet website dedicated to local subscribers of a Districtf Columbia cable operator. The website may be a part of a cableperator&amp;#8217;s larger website.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 6797 (July 19, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>