<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-4304</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 15-4304)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4304.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this rulemaking, the following terms and phrases shall have the following meaning:</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Commission&amp;#8221; means the Public Service Commission of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Electric Utility&amp;#8221; means the company that provides electric distribution service and is regulated by the Public Service Commission of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Liquid-immersed distribution transformer&amp;#8221; means a transformer that has an input voltage of 34,500 volts or less, an output voltage of 600 volts or less, uses oil or other liquid as a coolant, and is rated for operation at a frequency
      of 60 Hertz.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Minimally efficient distribution transformer&amp;#8221;, for reporting purposes of this chapter, shall mean:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>For transformers purchased before January, 2010, a transformer meeting the minimum efficiency specification established in Table 4-1 of NEMA Standards Publication TP 1-2002, which is incorporated by reference; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For transformers purchased on or after January 1, 2010, a transformer meeting the minimum efficiency standard established in 10 CFR Part 431, as amended, which is incorporated by reference.</text>
    </level>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Transformer&amp;#8221; means a device consisting of two or more coils of insulated wire that is designed to transfer alternating current by electromagnetic induction from one coil to another to change the original voltage or current value.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 11319 (October 31, 2008), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 9740-9743 (September 12, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>