<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-403</num>
  <heading>STATEMENT OF PRACTICABILITY (ยง 15-403)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>403.1.</num>
    <text>The utility company shall prepare and submit to the Public Service Commission a Statement of Practicability for Individual Metering for any master-metered apartment house for which termination of service is sought and for which at least sixty percent
      (60%) of the tenants have indicated an interest in the individual metering option on their Preliminary Election Sheets.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>403.2.</num>
    <text>The Statement of Practicability shall contain the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The address of the apartment house;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name of the owner;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The number of units;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Whether the entire apartment house can be individually metered;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Whether it is feasible to individually meter less than the entire apartment house;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The total cost of individual metering for the apartment house, the proposed cost to each tenant of individual metering, and the basis for the determination of both of these costs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>If individual metering is not possible, whether the apartment house can be sub-metered and, if so, how (e.g. by floor, by groups of units, etc.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The total cost of sub-metering and the proposed cost to each tenant; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Any special considerations pertaining to the apartment house and its service which may have a bearing on the utility&amp;#8217;s decision on practicability.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 3329, 3334 (July 24, 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>