<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-4201</num>
  <heading>FUEL MIX AND EMISSIONS DISCLOSURE REQUIREMENTS (§ 15-4201)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4201.1.</num>
    <text>Each active District of Columbia Electricity Supplier and the Electric Company shall report every six (6) months the fuel mix of electricity sold and the emissions produced in accordance with D.C. Official Code §§ 34-1504(c)(2)(A)(i) and 34-1517(b).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4201.2.</num>
    <text>Each active Electricity Supplier and the Electric Company must submit a semi-annual Fuel Mix and Emissions Report (&amp;#8220;Fuel Mix Report&amp;#8221;) to the Commission on June 1 and December 1. The June 1 report shall provide fuel mix and emissions
      information for the prior calendar year. The December 1 report shall provide fuel mix and emission information for the period January through June of the current year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4201.3.</num>
    <text>Each Fuel Mix Report must contain the following information in accordance with D.C. Official Code §§ 34-1504(c)(2)(A)(i) and 34-1517(b):</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The percentage of electricity generated from the following energy sources:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Coal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Oil;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Natural gas;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Nuclear;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Solar;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Wind;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Biomass;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Captured methane gas from landfill gas or wastewater treatment plant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Water, including hydroelectric and ocean;</text>
    </level>
    <text>(10) Geothermal;</text>
    <text>(11) Municipal solid waste; and</text>
    <text>(12) Other.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The emissions in pounds per megawatt-hour of:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Carbon dioxide;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Nitrogen oxides; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Sulfur dioxide.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4201.4.</num>
    <text>In the Fuel Mix Report, the percentages for § 4201.3(a)(5) through (11) above should also be added together and designated as the &amp;#8220;Renewable Energy Resources Subtotal.&amp;#8221;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4201.5.</num>
    <text>For electricity sold by an Electricity Supplier or the Electric Company that is from a specific generation resource, including any renewable energy credits associated with generation in the reporting period, the Electricity Supplier or the Electric
      Company shall include the specific generation resource in its Fuel Mix Report.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4201.6.</num>
    <text>For electricity sold by an Electricity Supplier or the Electric Company that is not from specific generation resources, the Electricity Supplier or the Electric Company shall include the PJM Environmental Information Services, Inc. (&amp;#8220;PJM
      EIS&amp;#8221;) average residual fuel mix statistics, by generation resource, in its Fuel Mix Report. Pursuant to § 4201.2 for the Fuel Mix Reports to be submitted by December 1 covering the time period January through June of the current year,
      Electricity Suppliers and the Electric Company may use estimates, if the actual numbers are unavailable, when reporting residual fuel mix statistics.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4201.7.</num>
    <text>A Fuel Mix Report shall be in a format similar to the information provided by the PJM EIS.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4201.8.</num>
    <text>Each Electricity Supplier and the Electric Company shall provide a Fuel Mix Report to its customers in the District of Columbia within the June and December billing cycles each year in accordance with D.C. Official Code §§ 34-1504(c)(2)(B)-(C) and
      consistent with § 4201.3 of this Chapter. The Fuel Mix Report submitted to the Commission shall indicate that the information is also being disclosed to customers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4201.9.</num>
    <text>If an Electricity Supplier or the Electric Company fails to file a semi-annual Fuel Mix Report or to disclose the information to its customers as required by this Chapter and D.C. Official Code §§ 34-1504(c)(2)(B)-(C), that company may be subject
      to Commission action. In addition, pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 34-1508, failure to file a Fuel Mix Report or disclose information to customers may result in suspension or revocation of a license to supply electricity or imposition of a civil
      penalty up to $ 10,000 per violation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 9737 (September 12, 2008), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 7572 (July 11, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>