<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-4301</num>
  <heading>PURCHASE OF LIQUID-IMMERSED DISTRIBUTION TRANSFORMERS (ยง 15-4301)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4301.1.</num>
    <text>This regulation applies to the electric utility that provides electric distribution service to the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4301.2.</num>
    <text>After January 1, 2009, and subject to reasonable commercial availability, the electric utility shall purchase liquid-immersed distribution transformers using the life-cycle cost methodology specified in Section 2, Efficiency Evaluation for Electric
      Utilities of NEMA Standards Publication TP 1-2002.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4301.3.</num>
    <text>Evaluation of Distribution Transformer Models:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Within each capacity class or type of liquid-immersed distribution transformers, a reasonable number of commercially available models shall be evaluated and, except as provided in paragraph (b), the model in each such class or type with the lowest
        total owning costs as determined by the life-cycle cost methodology shall be selected for the purchase.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If a utility is soliciting bids to supply multiple capacity classes or types of liquid-immersed distribution transformers under a single contract, models offered by a supplier in more than one capacity class or type may be combined for purposes
        of life-cycle cost evaluation, provided that the aggregation of models offered by a single supplier in such combined classes or types with the lowest total owning cost as determined by the life-cycle cost methodology conducted prior to contract
        award shall be selected for purchase.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>For purposes of this evaluation, all values for load losses and no-load losses shall be determined through the methods specified in the &amp;#8220;Uniform Test Method for Measuring the Energy Consumption of Distribution Transformers,&amp;#8221;
        Appendix A to Subpart K of 10 CFR, Part 431, as amended, which is incorporated by reference.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>For purposes of this evaluation, estimated values of energy and capacity shall be based upon the most current year available at the time of any bid solicitation. Nothing in this regulation shall require a utility to purchase any liquid-immersed
        distribution transformer that fails to meet federal energy efficiency standards specified in 10 CFR Part 431, as amended, which is incorporated by reference.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4301.4.</num>
    <text>After January 1, 2010, and subject to reasonable commercial availability, the electric utility shall purchase liquid-immersed distribution transformers that meet or exceed the energy efficiency standards specified in the Department of Energy&amp;#8217;s
      (&amp;#8220;DOE&amp;#8221;) final rules in Part 431 of Title 10 of the Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 11319 (October 31, 2008), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 9740-9743 (September 12, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>