<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-4110</num>
  <heading>MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS (§ 15-4110)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4110.1.</num>
    <text>The Electric Company may at any time request Commission approval to make changes in its tariffs. However, to the extent that those tariff changes would require conforming changes to either the RFP, the WFRSA generally, or any WFRSA that may be in
      effect from time to time:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>No such tariff changes may alter the rights and obligations of any wholesale supplier with respect to any WFRSA for which an RFP has already been issued, unless the supplier consents to have its rights or obligations changed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Electric Company shall serve notice of the tariff changes and copies of the proposed conforming changes to the RFP and/or WFRSA on all parties; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any such tariff changes must be consistent with the regulations, orders or other obligations to which the Electric Company is subject.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4110.2.</num>
    <text>If, after conducting the bid procedures in accordance with the RFP, the Electric Company still has SOS load that has not been awarded to a supplier, then:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Electric Company shall initially supply the unserved load by purchasing energy and all other necessary services through the PJM-administered markets, including but not limited to the PJM energy, capacity, and ancillary services markets, and
        any other service required by PJM to serve such unserved load, and shall include all the costs of such purchases in the retail rates charged for the service for which the purchases are made.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Within five (5) business days of it being determined by the Electric Company that the load is unserved, the Electric Company shall convene a meeting of all parties to the proceeding and Commission staff to discuss alternative ways to fill the unserved
        load, including but not limited to a rebid or a bilateral contract. The meeting process will conclude within ten (10) business days of the load being determined to be unserved, and within twenty (20) calendar days of it being determined that the
        load is unserved, the Electric Company shall file with the Commission, and serve upon the all parties to the proceeding, any proposal it has for serving the load in lieu of the procedure set forth in Section 4110.2(a); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Commission will resolve the Electric Company’s filing on an expedited basis. Any alternative means that the Commission approves will expressly provide that the Electric Company’s costs for filling the load will be recovered in retail rates in
        the same manner as all other charges pursuant to Section 4103.1. Until the Commission approves an alternate means of filling the load, Section 4110.2(a) will apply.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4110.3.</num>
    <text>If any load is left unserved after a wholesale supplier defaults:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Electric Company shall initially supply the defaulted load by purchasing energy and all other necessary services through the PJM-administered markets, including but not limited to the PJM energy, capacity, and ancillary services markets, and
        any other service required by PJM to serve such defaulted load, and shall include all the costs of such purchases, net of any offsetting recovery from the defaulting wholesale supplier, in the retail rates charged for the service for which the
        purchases are made; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>As soon as practicable after it is determined by the Electric Company that the load is unserved, the electric company shall file with the Commission a plan to fill the remaining term of the defaulted WFRSA. Such a plan shall be submitted to the
        Commission within ten (10) business days after a supplier default. Until the Commission approves a plan to fill the remaining term of the defaulted WFRSA, Section 4110.3(a) will apply.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4110.4.</num>
    <text>Access to confidential information relating to the Electric Company’s procurement of SOS power supply will be governed by the OPC Confidentiality Agreement, the Consultant’s Confidentiality Agreement contained in the Bidder RFP, and the Confidentiality
      Agreement contained in the RFP and the confidentiality provisions of the WFRSA (collectively the “Confidentiality Agreements”).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4110.5</num>
    <text>4110.5 Ninety (90) days following the Commission’s approval of the selection of winning bidders for the final tranche, the Commission will disclose upon request (a) the total number of bidders, and (b) the names of the winning bidders.</text>
    <text>Source: Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5404, 5420 (July 3, 2010).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>