<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-4402</num>
  <heading>SUBMETERING (§ 15-4402)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4402.1.</num>
    <text>When submeters are installed by an owner to measure the electricity or natural gas used by its tenants, all charges for electricity or natural gas used, except the allowed service charges permitted by sections 4405 (Periodic Tests and Checks) and
      4407 (Billing), shall be calculated from the readings of such submeters.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4402.2.</num>
    <text>Submeters in service shall be tested periodically by the owner pursuant to Section 4405 (Periodic Tests and Checks). If the test results reveal that the submeter is found to be no more than two percent (2%) fast or slow, no adjustment will be made
      to the tenant’s bill. If the submeter is found to be more than two percent (2%) fast or slow because of incorrect calibration, the owner will rebill the tenant for the correct amount as calculated for a period equal to one-half (1/2) of the time
      elapsed since the last previous test, but in no case for a period in excess of twelve (12) months or since occupancy by the existing tenant, whichever is less. The percentage registration of an electric submeter will be calculated by the “weighted
      average” of light load and full load which is calculated by giving a value of one to the light load and a value of four to the full load.</text>
    <text>The accuracy of a natural gas submeter will be measured at the check rate of flow, as provided in subsection 4401.10 (Section 4401, General Requirements).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4402.3.</num>
    <text>Whenever it is found that unmetered electricity or natural gas is being used as a result of tampering, the tenant shall pay to the owner an amount estimated by the owner to be sufficient to cover the electricity or natural gas used but not recorded
      by the meter and not previously paid for by the tenant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4402.4.</num>
    <text>Whenever it is found that, for any reason other than calibration or tampering, the submetering apparatus has not registered the true amount of electricity or natural gas which has been used by the tenant, the electricity or natural gas used during
      the entire period of incorrect registration will be estimated by the owner based upon all known pertinent facts, and the amount of electricity or natural gas so estimated will be used in calculating the corrected bill. The owner shall rebill the
      tenant for the adjusted amount for a period equal to one-half (1/2) of the time elapsed since the last previous test for submetering apparatus, but in no case for a period in excess of twelve (12) months or since occupancy by the existing tenant,
      whichever is less. The owner shall calculate the estimated bill in accordance with subsection 4407.10 (Section 4407, Billing).</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 9521, 9525 (November 11, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>