<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-4405</num>
  <heading>PERIODIC TESTS AND CHECKS (§ 15-4405)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4405.1.</num>
    <text>Each owner shall have a documented testing program, the primary purpose of which is to maintain an acceptable degree of accuracy during the service life of the equipment. All submetering equipment shall be tested in accordance with the provisions
      of the latest edition of the standards provided in subsections 4401.9 and 4401.10 (Section 4401, General Requirements). All energy allocation equipment shall be tested in accordance with the manufacturer’s suggested testing procedures and practices
      for such equipment. Tests shall be conducted no more than once in a twenty-four (24) month period, in accordance with D.C Official Code § 34-1553(c) (2010 Repl.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4405.2.</num>
    <text>All submeters shall be adjusted as close as possible to the condition of one hundred percent (100%) registration. No submeter shall be placed in service until its percentage registration has been established. The establishment of the percentage registration
      may be accomplished through the engagement of a certified lab or by a certificate provided by the manufacturer that is applicable only to the initial installation of the submeter. No electric submeter that exceeds the test calibration limits for
      watt-hour meters as set forth by the latest edition of ANSI C12 shall be placed in service or left in service. No natural gas submeter that exceeds the test calibration limits for meters as set forth by the latest edition of standards provided in
      subsection 4401.10 (Section 4401, General Requirements) shall be placed in service or left in service. In instances where an in service submeter is not properly calibrated, the owner shall calculate the corrected bill in accordance with subsection
      4402.2 (Section 4402, Submetering).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4405.3.</num>
    <text>A submeter shall be adjusted by a certified lab, if it is determined that the test calibration exceeds the limits set forth in subsection 4405.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4405.4.</num>
    <text>Energy allocation equipment shall be adjusted to the manufacturer’s specifications before being placed in service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4405.5.</num>
    <text>Any submetering or energy allocation equipment removed from service or replaced by other equipment for any purpose whatsoever shall be properly tested and adjusted before being placed in service again.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4405.6.</num>
    <text>The owner shall keep and maintain the following records for a period of no less than three (3) years:</text>
    <text>A record of all submetering or energy allocation equipment, identifying the equipment number and location (the tenant’s address where installed or if in reserve);</text>
    <text>The record of each test conducted shall show the identifying number of the equipment, the standard number and other necessary devices used, the date and type of test conducted, name and contact information for the individual conducting the test, the
      percentage registration at each load tested for submetering equipment, the accuracy level of the parameter measured by the energy allocation equipment, and sufficient data to permit verification of the test results; and</text>
    <text>A record of all the portable standards and reference standards used to test submetering and energy allocation equipment. Test equipment shall at all times be accompanied by a certified calibration card signed by the proper authority, with the date
      of the most recent certification and adjustment. Records of certifications and calibrations of all standards shall be kept on file in the office of the owner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4405.7.</num>
    <text>The aforementioned records, in subsection 4405.6, for each nonresidential rental unit shall be made available, upon request, to the tenant of that unit during reasonable business hours at the building manager’s office or, if there is no building manager
      available, at the nonresidential rental unit of the tenant at the convenience of the owner and tenant. The owner of the building may impose and collect a reasonable charge for copying documents, reflecting the actual costs of materials and labor
      for copying, prior to providing copies of the records to the tenant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4405.8.</num>
    <text>All records referenced in subsection 4405.6 shall be made available to the Commission upon request.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 9521, 9527 (November 11, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>