<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-4104</num>
  <heading>COMPETITIVE WHOLESALE BIDDING AND CONTRACTING PROCESS (§ 15-4104)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4104.1.</num>
    <text>The Electric Company shall solicit offers for Wholesale Full-Requirements Service via the RFP approved by the Commission. The Electric Company shall remain the NITS provider and shall be the designated PJM Load Serving Entity (“LSE”) for all SOS.
      The Electric Company, as the PJM LSE, shall provide the rights to nomination and make available to the wholesale suppliers all Firm Transmission Rights/Auction Revenue Rights (“FTR/ARRs”) to which it has rights pursuant to the PJM procedures applicable
      to FTR and ARRs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4104.2.</num>
    <text>The Electric Company shall solicit seasonally differentiated and, if applicable, time-of-use differentiated prices. In the case of multi-year-term contracts, prices shall, in addition, be annually specified. The solicitation shall be conducted through
      as many as four bidding rounds, as specified in the RFP.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4104.3.</num>
    <text>The total load associated with each SOS Customer Group shall be divided into bid blocks of approximately 50 MW to promote diversity of supply and reliable supply contract performance. Each bid block shall represent a percentage of the total SOS load
      that each supplier will be obligated to supply for the term of the contract regardless of changes in the magnitude of the total load for that SOS Customer Group. The size of the total load may vary from the 50 MW guideline for a particular group
      if the total load associated with a specific SOS Customer Group indicates that such variation is warranted. The Electric Company may alter the target size of the bid blocks by requesting permission to do so at the same time as it informs the Commission
      of its procurement plan, but only if it has reason to believe that the change would lead to more competitive offers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4104.4.</num>
    <text>SOS service years shall continue annually beginning on June 1 of each year and ending on May 31 of the following year, consistent with PJM planning periods, until modified by Commission Order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4104.5.</num>
    <text>Potential wholesale suppliers must demonstrate their qualifications to provide Wholesale Full Requirements Service by providing proof that they are qualified to participate in the PJM Markets and have all the necessary FERC authorizations to enter
      into wholesale energy contracts. Furthermore, the RFP and WFRSA shall specify the financial credit requirements that potential or actual wholesale SOS suppliers must demonstrate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4104.6.</num>
    <text>The Electric Company’s RFP will include specific forms of bid request, evaluation plan, and the WFRSA. The evaluation plan contained in the RFP will specify that all bids to serve the load associated with a specific SOS Customer Group and for a specific
      contract length will be compared on a discounted price basis to select the lowest cost winning bids.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4104.7.</num>
    <text>Upon completion of the bid evaluation process, the Electric Company will notify the winning bidders and execute a WFRSA with each winning bidder.</text>
    <text>Such contract execution will be contingent, however, on Commission approval of the bid awards, contracts and credit support provisions therein. The contract(s) will be deemed approved by the Commission unless the Commission orders otherwise within
      two (2) business days following their submission.</text>
    <text>Winning bidders will receive the actual prices in their offers for each year of the term of their supply contract. Winning bidders will not be permitted to revise prices or any other terms and conditions of the WFRSA, except as provided for in the
      WFRSA.</text>
    <text>Source: Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5404, 5410 (July 3, 2009).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>