<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-611</num>
  <heading>COMPLAINTS REGARDING EXISTING PAY TELEPHONES (ยง 15-611)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>611.1.</num>
    <text>Pay telephones associated with illegal activity or found to be a public nuisance may be subject to termination or alteration of service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>611.2.</num>
    <text>Any interested person may file a complaint concerning the operation of a pay telephone. A complaint alleging that an existing pay telephone(s) is in violation of any of the Rules under this Chapter must be submitted to the Commission in writing stating
      the basis for the complaint and the location or address of the existing pay telephone(s).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>611.3.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of a complaint regarding an existing pay telephone, the Commission shall make every reasonable effort to conduct an inspection of the pay telephone at issue within three business (3) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>611.4.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall notify, by certified mail, any PSP not in compliance with these Rules and direct the PSP to bring the pay telephone into compliance within thirty (30) days. A PSP shall be accorded forty-five (45) days from the time that it is
      notified to bring its pay telephone into compliance, provided the PSP can represent in good faith and in writing that the cause of the non-compliance is an administrative or technical matter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>611.5.</num>
    <text>The PSP shall notify the Commission in writing as to what actions have been taken to bring the pay telephone into compliance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>611.6.</num>
    <text>If a PSP fails to bring the pay telephone(s) into compliance within thirty (30) days, the Commission shall order the suspension of service to that instrument and may, in its discretion, order the termination of service to the PSP&amp;#8217;s other
      pay telephones until such time as the PSP complies with the Commission&amp;#8217;s regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 1151 (February 9, 2001); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 1316 (February 8, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>