<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-601</num>
  <heading>PAY TELEPHONE PROVIDER CERTIFICATION (ยง 15-601)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>601.1.</num>
    <text>A Pay Telephone Service Provider (&amp;#8220;PSP&amp;#8221;) seeking to provide pay telephone services within the District of Columbia (&amp;#8220;District&amp;#8221;) shall be certified by the Public Service Commission of the District of Columbia.
      This certification shall be renewed by previously approved PSPs every two years on March 31 in the same manner as the initial certification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.2.</num>
    <text>A Pay Telephone Certification Application (&amp;#8220;Certification Application&amp;#8221;) may be obtained from the Commission&amp;#8217;s Office of Consumer Services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.3.</num>
    <text>The Completed Certification Application shall contain:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Applicant&amp;#8217;s D.C. Business Tax Registration Number issued by the D.C. Office of Tax and Revenue;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A copy of the Applicant&amp;#8217;s license to do business in the District of Columbia issued by the D.C. Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The name, address, telephone number, fax number, and email address of a District of Columbia Registered Agent if the PSP does not have its principal place of business in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.4.</num>
    <text>The Certification Application shall be executed by an officer of a corporation, a partner of a partnership, a designated agent of the owner, or by a sole proprietor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.5.</num>
    <text>The completed Certification Application shall be accompanied by a non-refundable check or money order in the amount of $ 100.00, payable to the D.C. Treasurer. The completed Certification Renewal Application Form shall be accompanied by a non-refundable
      check or money order in the amount of $ 50.00, payable to the D.C. Treasurer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.6.</num>
    <text>All filings to the Commission concerning pay telephones shall be by hand delivery, certified mail or first class mail to the Commission&amp;#8217;s Office of Consumer Services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.7.</num>
    <text>Upon review of a completed Certification Application, the Commission shall certify the PSP and issue the PSP a certification number.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.8.</num>
    <text>A PSP certification may not be sold, assigned, or otherwise transferred.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.9.</num>
    <text>The Certification Application shall be available for public inspection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 1151 (February 9, 2001); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 1316 (February 8, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>