<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-122</num>
  <heading>REMEDIES AND PENALTIES (ยง 16-122)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>122.1.</num>
    <text>Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of this regulation pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction
      of this regulation shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Infractions Act of 1985.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>122.2.</num>
    <text>Any person who violates any provision of this chapter shall be subject to a penalty or a fine not exceeding three hundred dollars ($ 300) or imprisonment for not more than ten (10) days for each violation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>122.3.</num>
    <text>The remedies and penalties set forth in this chapter shall not be deemed to be mutually exclusive. The Department is authorized to pursue such remedies and penalties jointly and concurrently.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>122.4.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this chapter shall prevent any person from exercising any right or seeking any remedy to which he might otherwise be entitled, or from filing any complaint with any other agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>122.5.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this chapter shall be deemed to deprive any aggrieved party of such judicial review of orders of the Council or of any other agency or authority of the District of Columbia as may be available.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>122.6.</num>
    <text>If any section, subsection, sentence, clause, phrase or portion of this chapter is for any reason held invalid or unconstitutional by any court of competent jurisdiction, such section, subsection, sentence, clause, phrase, or portion shall be deemed
      a separate, distinct, and independent provision and such holding shall not affect the validity of the remaining provisions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>