<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-1202</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION FOR LICENSE (ยง 16-1202)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1202.1.</num>
    <text>Any person desiring to obtain a proprietary school license or to renew a license, shall file an application with the Department upon forms provided by the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1202.2.</num>
    <text>Each application for a proprietary school license, or for a renewal of a proprietary school license, shall be accompanied by a fee to be determined by the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1202.3.</num>
    <text>Each licensed proprietary school or applicant for license shall upon request of the Department, make its records and files available to the Department at reasonable times for the purpose of discharging its responsibilities under this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1202.4.</num>
    <text>The application shall include, but not be limited to, the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Title or name of the school, and location of its principal place of business;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The names of the owner or owners, officers, members of the board of directors, managing employees within the District, and any other person or business entity having a twenty-five (25%) or more ownership interest in the school;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The place or places where instruction will be given, as well as all offices and facilities located in the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The maximum student enrollment to be accommodated;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A current financial statement of the school prepared by a certified public accountant within thirty (30) days of the application and verified by the owner under oath;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The form and contents of the student enrollment agreement and contract (if not the same as enrollment agreement), which shall include the school&amp;#8217;s tuition and refund policy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A schedule of all tuition, fees, and other charges, and a statement of the school&amp;#8217;s tuition refund policies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>A pamphlet listing all the courses offered and the educational objective of the course or plan;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>A list of the names of all agents authorized to represent the school in soliciting prospective students, which shall be revised as necessary; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Copies of all advertising used by proprietary schools during the preceding six months including transcripts of radio and television commercials.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>