<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-1406</num>
  <heading>CONDUCT OF DOCUMENTARY ARBITRATION HEARINGS (ยง 16-1406)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1406.1.</num>
    <text>If the complainant elects a documentary arbitration procedure, the Board shall gather and disseminate the documentary information and evidence in accordance with the procedures under this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1406.2.</num>
    <text>The Board shall notify the complainant by certified mail that he or she shall submit a sworn or affirmed Statement as to the facts of the dispute and any evidence which he or she wishes the panel to consider. The complainant shall forward the sworn
      or affirmed statement documentation to the Board within fifteen (15) days from the date of his or her receipt of the certified notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1406.3.</num>
    <text>The Board shall notify the respondent of the dispute by certified mail. Included with the notice shall be a copy of the complainant&amp;#8217;s request for arbitration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1406.4.</num>
    <text>The respondent shall submit a sworn or affirmed statement as to the facts of the dispute and any evidence the respondent wishes the panel to consider to the Board within fifteen (15) days from the date of the respondent&amp;#8217;s receipt of the
      certified notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1406.5.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of both the complainant&amp;#8217;s and respondent&amp;#8217;s sworn or affirmed statements and documentary evidence, the Board, shall by certified mail, forward copies of the complainant&amp;#8217;s submissions to the respondent and
      forward copies of the respondent&amp;#8217;s submissions to the complainant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1406.6.</num>
    <text>Each party shall have the opportunity to respond to the opposing party&amp;#8217;s submissions. Each response shall be submitted in writing to the Board within ten (10) days from the date of the responding party&amp;#8217;s receipt of the documents.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1406.7.</num>
    <text>At the documentary hearing, the Board shall take the following actions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Review each document and statements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Consult with an appointed technical expert, as necessary;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Seek further information or documents from either or each party; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Schedule inspections, if necessary.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1406.8.</num>
    <text>Any evidence and statements received by the Board shall be considered part of the record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 2958, 2964 (May 16, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>