<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-1010</num>
  <heading>SEIZURE OR DETENTION OF PROPERTY BY POLICE OFFICERS (ยง 16-1010)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1010.1.</num>
    <text>Any member of the Metropolitan Police Department may take possession of any article of secondhand personal property in the possession of a dealer which he or she knows to be missing, or knows or has probable cause to believe to be stolen.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1010.2.</num>
    <text>Upon taking possession of the article, the member shall furnish the dealer with a receipt which shall include the date, name of the member taking the article, the member&amp;#8217;s rank, and a description of the article taken.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1010.3.</num>
    <text>Any article taken by a member from a dealer shall, as soon as possible, be delivered to the Property Clerk of the Metropolitan Police Department where it shall remain until such time as ownership or the right of possession, or both, have been determined
      according to law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1010.4.</num>
    <text>The Property Clerk of the Metropolitan Police Department shall notify the dealer in writing of any disposition of the property. The notice shall include the date of disposition and the name of the person receiving the property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1010.5.</num>
    <text>In lieu of taking possession of secondhand personal property pursuant to this section, a member of the Metropolitan Police Department may place a temporary detainer on the property for a period not to exceed sixty (60) calendar days from the date
      that the written notice of the detainer is issued to the dealer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1010.6.</num>
    <text>During the period of detention, the property shall remain in the custody of the dealer and the dealer shall be prohibited from selling, disposing of in any manner, or changing the identity of the property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1010.7.</num>
    <text>During the period of detention, the dealer shall keep the detained property separate and distinct from all other property in the dealer&amp;#8217;s place of business.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>