<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-1414</num>
  <heading>DECISIONS OF THE ARBITRATION PANEL (ยง 16-1414)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1414.1.</num>
    <text>Each decision of an arbitration panel shall be in writing and in the name of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1414.2.</num>
    <text>Each decision shall be rendered no later than sixty (60) days from the date the Board mailed the notice of acceptance. The period between the rejection and replacement of any panel shall not be counted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1414.3.</num>
    <text>The testimony and exhibits, together with all other papers and requests filed, and matters not presented in evidence buy with which official notice has been taken shall constitute the exclusive record for the decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1414.4.</num>
    <text>Each decision shall contain the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The panel&amp;#8217;s finding of act and reason for its decision;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The specific terms of the award, if applicable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The date or time limit and place for performance, if applicable; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A notice stating that any party may appeal to the D.C. Superior Court within twenty (20) days.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1414.5.</num>
    <text>The Board, upon verification of proper service, may issue a default decision in favor of the complainant upon failure of the respondent to appear in person at an oral arbitration or upon failure of the respondent to submit a written statement when
      a documentary hearing has been granted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1414.6.</num>
    <text>The Board, upon verification of proper service, may dismiss the complainant&amp;#8217;s claim upon failure of the complainant to appear in person at an oral arbitration proceeding or upon failure of the complainant to submit a written statement when
      a documentary hearing has been granted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1414.7.</num>
    <text>The Board shall send, by certified mail, a copy of its decision to each party.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 2958, 2966 (May 16, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>