<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-3402</num>
  <heading>SECURITY AND FIRE ALARM SYSTEMS INFRACTIONS (§ 16-3402)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3402.1.</num>
    <text>Reserved</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3402.2.</num>
    <text>Reserved</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3402.3.</num>
    <text>Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 3 infraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 5(a) of the Security and Fire Alarm Systems Regulation Act of 1980, effective Sept. 26, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-107; D.C. Official Code § 7- 2804(a))(engaging in the business of an alarm dealer within the District of Columbia without an alarm dealer&amp;#8217;s
        license);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 6(a) of the Security and Fire Alarm Systems Regulation Act of 1980 (D.C. Official Code § 7-2805(a)) (acting as an alarm system agent within the District of Columbia without an alarm agent&amp;#8217;s license); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Section 9(a) of the Security and Fire Alarm Systems Regulation Act of 1980 (D.C. Official Code § 7-2808(c)) (installing or maintaining an alarm system which does not have some safeguard which allows reasonable delay to halt or recall an accidental
        alarm activation before the alarm is communicated to the Metropolitan Police Department or the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3402.4.</num>
    <text>Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a class 4 infraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 4 of the Security and Fire Alarm Systems Regulation Act of 1980 (D.C Official Code § 7-2803) (using any unapproved signaling device to transmit, or cause to be transmitted, a prerecorded message to report any fire, burglary, holdup or other
        emergency directly to the Metropolitan Police Department or the District of Columbia Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 6(e) of the Security and Fire Alarm Systems Regulation Act of 1980 (D.C. Official Code § 7-2805(e)) (failing to display upon request a valid license identification card while installing, inspecting, maintaining, servicing or repairing an
        alarm system);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Section 7(a) of the Security and Fire Alarm Systems Regulation Act of 1980 (D.C. Official Code § 7-2806(a)) (failure of an alarm dealer to maintain and secure records);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Section 7(b) of the Security and Fire Alarm Systems Regulation Act of 1980 (D.C. Official Code § 7-2806(b)) (failure to maintain alarm agent user records as required by law);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Section 7(c) of the Security and Fire Alarm Systems Regulation Act of 1980 (D.C. Official Code § 7-2806(c)) (failure to post sign indicating alarm dealer);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Section 7(d) of the Security and Fire Alarm Systems Regulation Act of 1980 (D.C. Official Code § 7-2806(d)) (failure to adequately train or instruct employees);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Section 8(d) of the Security and Fire Alarm Systems Regulation Act of 1980 1980 (D.C. Official Code § 7-2807(d)) (failure of user to maintain posted name of alarm agent or dealer);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Section 8(a) of the Security and Fire Alarm Systems Regulation Act of 1980 (D.C. Official Code § 7-2807(a)) (causing or permitting a false alarm);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Section 8(c) of the Security and Fire Alarm Systems Regulation Act of 1980 (D.C. Official Code § 7-2807(c)) (failure to maintain an alarm system in good working order or failing to promptly repair defects);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Section 8(d) of the Security and Fire Alarm Systems Regulation Act of 1980 (D.C Official Code § 7-2807(d)) (failure of user to have person properly respond to scene when requested); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Section 9 of the Security and Fire Alarm Systems Regulation Act of 1980 (D.C. Official Code § 7-2808(a)) (installing or maintaining a system by any person which creates an improper sound).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 4959 (May 27, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>