<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-3615</num>
  <heading>PHARMACY LICENSURE AND POSTING INFRACTIONS (§ 16-3615)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3615.1</num>
    <text>3615.1 Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 1nfraction:</text>
    <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.03(d) (2005 Repl.)and 22 DCMR B § 1900.1operating, maintaining, opening, or establishing a pharmacy within the Districtf Columbia without a license or registration issued by the Mayor);</text>
    <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.03(f) (2005 Repl.)(using or having upon anstablishment or institution or any part of an establishment or institution, orisplaying within it, or affixing or using in connection with it, a sign bearinghe word or words “pharmacy,”
      “apothecary,” “drugstore,”druggist,” or any word or words of similar or like import which tends tondicate that the practice of pharmacy is being conducted in the establishmentr institution);</text>
    <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.06 (2005 Repl.), D.C. Official Code §-1210.06(b)(4) (2007 Repl.), and 17 DCMR § 6509.3 (unregistered pharmacyntern on duty);</text>
    <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.08 (2005 Repl.)(using a pharmacy license for aocation other than the one specified on the license; transferring a pharmacyicense, using a pharmacy license under a name other than the name under whichhe license was issued,
      or failure to promptly surrender a pharmacy license tohe Mayor as required);</text>
    <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.08(b) (2005 Repl.)(failure to renew a pharmacyicense);</text>
    <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.09(a)(2005 Repl.) and 22 DCMR B § 1901.1and §901.2 (operating a pharmacy without a pharmacist on duty or with an unlicensedharmacist on duty);</text>
    <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.10(a)(1) (2005 Repl.)(failure to notify the Mayorf a conviction of a felony or violation of a law or regulation of the Districtf Columbia or the United States relating to drugs by a person named in thepplication for pharmacy
      licensure);</text>
    <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.10(a)(2) (2005 Repl.) (furnishing false orisleading information to the Mayor or failing to furnish information requestedy the Mayor);</text>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.17 (2005 Repl.)(peddling drugs);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1902.1 and 1902.12 (operating a pharmacy outside of thelassification for which the license was issued or failing to adhere to theestrictions placed on the license);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1902.16 (failure to immediately return a pharmacy license tohe Director as required);</text>
    </level>
    <text>22 DCMR B § 1903.3 (shipping, mailing, or delivering in any manner prescriptionrugs or medical devices into the District of Columbia directly or indirectlyithout being registered as a non-resident pharmacy by the Department);</text>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1903.16(e)(1) (failure of a non-resident pharmacy to maintainertification for internet pharmacies acceptable to the Department for eachebsite and domain registration);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1903.16(e)(2) (failure of a non-resident pharmacy to maintainegistration in good standing in the District of Columbia as a foreignorporation); or</text>
    </level>
    <text>22 DCMR B § 1907.3 (operating a pharmacy in either a temporary or trailer-typeacility without a special or limited use license approved by the Director).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3615.2</num>
    <text>3615.2 Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 2nfraction:</text>
    <text>22 DCMR B § 1902.8 (failure to notify the Director within thirty (30) daysfter a change in the pharmacist-in-charge, Director of Pharmacy, or Responsibleuclear Pharmacist);</text>
    <text>22 DCMR B § 1903.8(h) (failure of a non-resident pharmacy to provide allebsite addresses and domain registrations to the Department);</text>
    <text>22 DCMR B §1903.10 (failure of a non-resident pharmacy to report a change inhe name or address of the resident agent in writing to the</text>
    <text>Director within thirty (30) days after the change);</text>
    <text>22 DCMR B § 1903.11 (failure of a non-resident pharmacy to report a change inhe pharmacist-in-charge or corporate officers within thirty (30) days after thehange);</text>
    <text>22 DCMR B § 1903.12 (failure of a non-resident pharmacy to notify theepartment within ten (10) days after a change in proprietorship or ownership,harmacy name, or location or failure to apply for a new registration);</text>
    <text>22 DCMR B § 1903.13 (failure of a non-resident pharmacy to notify theepartment within ten (10) days after closing);</text>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1903.16(a) (failure of a non-resident pharmacy to maintainicensure, registration, or a permit in good standing in the state in which theon-resident pharmacy is located);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1905.4 (failure to notify the Director at least sixty (60)ays prior to the change of proprietorship of a pharmacy or to apply for a newicense);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1906.1 (failure to notify the Director in writing of thelosing of a pharmacy not later than fifteen (15) days prior to the anticipatedate of closing or failure to include all required information in the notice);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1906.2 (failure to conspicuously post a sign notifying theublic of the closing date of the pharmacy at least fifteen (15) days prior tohe closing, failure to include all required information in the notice, orailure to comply with all
        posting requirements for the location of the notice);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1906.3 (failure to comply with all District and federalequirements for the transfer of files and records or failure to remove alligns and symbols referencing or indicating the presence of a pharmacy on theremises); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1906.4 (failure to submit to the Director all requiredicenses, registration, and the required written statement within fifteen (15)ays after the closing of the pharmacy).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3615.3</num>
    <text>3615.3 Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 3nfraction:</text>
    <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.09(a) (2005 Repl.)(failure of pharmacist on dutyo post his or her license in a conspicuous place while on duty);</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.09(a) (2005 Repl.)(failure to conspicuouslyisplay on the outside of the pharmacy the hours that the pharmacy is open forusiness);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 48-801.03 (2009 Repl.)(failure to post the currentelling prices for the one hundred (100) most commonly used prescription drugsnd related data);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 48-803.03(a) (2009 Repl.)(failure to prominentlyisplay a sign regarding drug substitution as required by D.C. Official Code 48-803.03(a)(2009 Repl.)); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1901.3 (failure to post conspicuously in the vicinity of theharmacy practice area: the pharmacy license, federal and District controlledubstances registrations, licenses of pharmacists on duty, certificate ofccupancy, and certificates
        of registration of pharmacy interns).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 5019 (May 27, 2005); as amended byotice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 7425 (August 19, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>