<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-3115</num>
  <heading>INSTALLMENT AGREEMENTS AND PAYMENT (ยง 16-3115)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3115.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall be eligible to apply for an installment agreement except as provided in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3115.2.</num>
    <text>A respondent who has been served a decision in which monetary sanctions of fifty dollars ($50) or more have been imposed may, within fifteen (15) days after the date of service, request permission to make payments pursuant to an installment agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3115.3.</num>
    <text>A respondent who has been served an NOI or second NOI, and who admits to infractions and penalties of fifty dollars ($50) or more may, within fifteen (15) days after the date of service, request permission to make payments pursuant to an installment
      agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3115.4.</num>
    <text>Installment applications shall be submitted on a form prescribed by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3115.5.</num>
    <text>Failure to submit a completed installment application along with all required documentation in a timely manner shall bar the respondent from receiving an installment agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3115.6.</num>
    <text>An installment agreement shall inform the respondent of the respondent&amp;#8217;s obligations and shall contain the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The duration of the agreement, which shall be six (6) months or less;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The due date for each installment payment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The terms and conditions of the agreement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>That collection proceedings shall be initiated to collect the amount owed for respondent&amp;#8217;s failure to comply with the terms and conditions of the installment agreement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>That the acceptable forms of payment are as follows:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Cash, which is not acceptable by mail; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A personal check, company check, certified check, cashier&amp;#8217;s check, postal money order, or bank money order payable to the order of the District of Columbia Treasurer; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>That the respondent&amp;#8217;s license or permit may be suspended for failure to make timely payments.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 5718, 5730 (September 4, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>