<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-3302</num>
  <heading>CORPORATION DIVISION INFRACTIONS (§ 16-3302)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3302.1</num>
    <text>3302.1 Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 1nfraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Submitting a document pursuant to the District of Columbia Official Codeitle 29 (Business Organizations) Enactment Act of 2010, effective July 11, 2011D.C. Law 18-378; D.C. Official Code §§ 29-101.01, et seq.) (the Act) and theocument contains a
        false statement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Operating in the District:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>As a domestic business corporation or professional corporation and withoutrticles of incorporation filed under D.C. Official Code § 29-302.02 (2011epl.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>As a domestic nonprofit corporation and without articles of incorporationiled under D.C. Official Code § 29-402.02 (2011 Repl.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>As a domestic limited liability partnership and without a statement ofualification filed under D.C. Official Code § 29-610.01 (2011 Repl.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>As a domestic limited partnership and without a certificate of limitedartnership filed under D.C. Official Code § 29-702.01 (2011 Repl.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>As a domestic limited liability company and without a certificate ofrganization filed under D.C. Official Code § 29-802.01 (2011 Repl.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>As a domestic general cooperative association and without articles ofncorporation filed under D.C. Official Code § 29-906 (2011 Repl.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>As a domestic limited cooperative association and without articles ofrganization filed under D.C. Official Code § 29-1003.02 (2011 Repl.); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>As a domestic statutory trust and without a certificate of trust filed under.C. Official Code § 29-1202.01 (2011 Repl.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Operating in the District as a foreign filing business organization entity:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Without having obtained a certificate of registration under D.C. Official Code 29-105.02 (2011 Repl.); or</text>
    <text>After its certificate of registration has been terminated under D.C. Officialode § 29-105.11 (2011 Repl.); and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Operating in the District under the jurisdiction of the Act, but after theusiness organization has been dissolved, whether voluntarily, judicially, ordministratively; provided, that this subsection shall not apply if theissolution has been revoked
        or the business organization has been reinstated inccordance with the Act.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3302.2</num>
    <text>3302.2 Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 3nfraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Failure to appoint and maintain a registered agent under D.C. Official Code 29-104.02 (2011 Repl.):</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>As a domestic filing entity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>As a domestic limited liability partnership that does not maintain a placef business in the District; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>As a qualified foreign entity; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Failure to register a trade name with the Department of Consumer andegulatory Affairs under D.C. Official Code § 47-2855.02 (2005 Repl.):</text>
    </level>
    <text>As a general partnership;</text>
    <text>As a foreign or domestic limited partnership;</text>
    <text>As a foreign or domestic limited liability company; or</text>
    <text>As a foreign or domestic corporation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 4908 (May 27, 2005); as amended byinal Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8162 (July 6, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>