<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-300</num>
  <heading>DEALERS AND SELLERS (ยง 16-300)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>300.1.</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise required by the context and except as provided otherwise in this section, the words &amp;#8220;dealer&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;seller&amp;#8221; mean any person other than a salesman who does the following for compensation:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Buys, sells, exchanges, or offers or attempts to buy, sell, or exchange an interest in a motor vehicle, whether on consignment or otherwise; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Negotiates or attempts to negotiate a purchase, sale or exchange of an interest in a motor vehicle; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Is engaged, wholly or in part, in the business of selling motor vehicles, whether or not the motor vehicles are owned by that person.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>300.2.</num>
    <text>The words &amp;#8220;dealer&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;seller&amp;#8221; shall not include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Public officers, their deputies, assistants, or employees, while performing their official duties;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Persons disposing of motor vehicles acquired for their own use and actually so used, when the same shall have been acquired and used in good faith and not for the purpose of avoiding the provisions of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Persons dealing solely in the sale and distribution of fire-fighting equipment, construction equipment, ambulances, or funeral vehicles, including motor vehicles adapted for those purposes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Manufacturers or representatives of manufacturers of motor vehicles on behalf of those manufacturers exclusively to licensed motor vehicle dealers; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Persons engaged in the business of buying motor vehicles from licensed dealers for sale or disposition outside of the District.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>300.3.</num>
    <text>The following persons may engage in the activities set forth in paragraphs (a) and (b) of ยง 300.1 without procuring a dealer&amp;#8217;s or a salesman&amp;#8217;s license:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Any person appointed by any court or acting under judgment or order of any court;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An auctioneer licensed by the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A person selling a motor vehicle to enforce a garage keeper&amp;#8217;s lien; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The employees of persons listed in ยง 300.3(a)-(c) when engaged in the specific performance of the duties of that employment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>