<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-3645</num>
  <heading>AQUATIC ANIMAL PROTECTION AND FISHING INFRACTIONS (§ 16-3645)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3645.1.</num>
    <text>Reserved</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3645.2.</num>
    <text>Violation of the following provision shall be a Class 2 infraction:</text>
    <text>19 DCMR § 1503.1(a) (introducing a species of fish or other aquatic organism not indigenous to the District of Columbia into the waters of the District of Columbia).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3645.3.</num>
    <text>Violation of the following provision shall be a Class 3 infraction:</text>
    <text>19 DCMR § 1503.1(e) (capturing, harassing, harming or failing to return to the waters immediately any organism listed as a threatened or endangered species).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3645.4.</num>
    <text>Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 4 infraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>19 DCMR § 1502.1 (taking of a fish or any other aquatic organism for sale or profit);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>19 DCMR § 1503.1(b) (possession of a fish which is under the minimum legal size);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>19 DCMR § 1503.1(c) (possessing more of a particular species of fish than is allowed by law);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>19 DCMR § 1503.1(d) (possessing fish with prescribed weight, from which the heads and tails have been removed);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>19 DCMR § 1503.1(f) (use of explosives, chemicals, firearms or electricity to take or injure fish or aquatic organisms);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>19 DCMR § 1503.1(h) (taking fish illegally);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>19 DCMR § 1503.1(i) (taking, catching or possessing striped bass or hybrid striped bass); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>19 DCMR § 1506.1 (angling for striped bass or hybrid striped bass).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3645.5.</num>
    <text>Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 5 infraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>19 DCMR § 1501.1 (fishing without a license);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>19 DCMR § 1501.3 (failure to display license upon request);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>19 DCMR § 1501.4 (collecting fish for scientific purposes without a permit);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>19 DCMR § 1501.5 (fishing without a valid license);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>19 DCMR §§ 1501.2 through 1502.7 (fishing with unauthorized equipment or methods); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>19 DCMR § 1503.1(g) (taking, catching or possessing a sturgeon).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 5057 (May 27, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>