<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-310</num>
  <heading>GROUNDS FOR DENIAL, SUSPENSION, OR REVOCATION OF LICENSES (§ 16-310)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>310.1.</num>
    <text>The license of each dealer, salesperson, automobile repossessor, and sales finance company shall be subject to denial, suspension, or revocation for any cause set forth in any other section of this chapter which is applicable to any such license or
      for any cause set forth in paragraph 46 of § 7 of An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and three, and for other purposes,
      approved July 1, 1902, 32 Stat. 628, as amended, (D.C. Code § 47-2844), including without limitation, any of the following causes:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Material misstatement in application for license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Willful failure or refusal to comply with any provision of statute or regulation relating to the sale, repossession, or financing of motor vehicles;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Defrauding any purchaser or prospective purchaser;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Willful misrepresentation or concealment through any subterfuge or device of any matter or the nature of any matter required by this chapter to be stated or furnished to the purchaser;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Willful employment of any fraudulent or misleading device, method, or practice in connection with the sale, repossession, or financing of the sale of a motor vehicle;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Willful use of advertising with regard to the sale, repossession, or financing of motor vehicles which is misleading or deceptive by reason of any false statement contained in that advertising, or which by reason of incompleteness may mislead or
        deceive; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Willful or fraudulent circumvention of any provision of statute or regulation relating to the sale, repossession, or financing of motor vehicles.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>310.2.</num>
    <text>In addition to the causes set forth in § 310.1, each dealer&amp;#8217;s license shall be subject to denial, suspension, or revocation for any of the following reasons:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Employing, engaging, appointing, allowing, or permitting any person to act as a salesperson or automobile repossessor for or on behalf of a dealer, with a reasonable opportunity to know that such person is not duly licensed as a salesperson or automobile
        repossessor for that dealer, or that the salesperson&amp;#8217;s or automobile repossessor&amp;#8217;s license of that person has been suspended or revoked;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Continuing a relationship in the business of selling motor vehicles with any person, with a reasonable opportunity to know that within the preceding three (3) years, he or she has finally been determined to have committed any act or omitted any
        duty which is cause for denying that person a license as a dealer, or which is cause for suspending or revoking any dealer&amp;#8217;s license issued to that person in his or her own name.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>310.3.</num>
    <text>In addition to the causes set forth in § 310.1, a salesperson&amp;#8217;s or automobile repossessor&amp;#8217;s license shall be subject to denial, suspension, or revocation for acting as a salesperson or automobile repossessor for or on behalf of
      any person with a reasonable opportunity to know that such person is not duly licensed as a dealer or that his or her dealer&amp;#8217;s license is suspended or revoked.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>