<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-3604</num>
  <heading>TISSUE BANK INFRACTIONS (§ 16-3604)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3604.1.</num>
    <text>Violation of the following provision shall be a Class 1 infraction: 22 DCMR § 301.1 (operating a tissue bank without a license).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3604.2.</num>
    <text>Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 2 infraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 300.3 (failure to manage and operate a tissue bank in accordance with good medical and public health practice);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 302.1 (failure to have a physician as director and operator of the bank);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 302.2 (failure to maintain a roster of authorized persons and to establish policies and procedures for operation of the bank);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 302.4 (failure of a hospital licensee to designate a physician as director and operator of the bank);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 303 (failure to comply with requirements concerning tissue acquisition, tissue withdrawal, and recordkeeping);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 304 (failure to comply with physical and sanitary requirements);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 305.2 (failure to cooperate in an inspection); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 306.1 (transporting tissue without the required record).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3604.3.</num>
    <text>Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 3 infraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 301.4 (failure to sign and certify application for license);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR §302.3 (failure to provide policies and procedures for inspection upon request); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 302.6 (failure to notify of change in operator).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3604.4.</num>
    <text>Violation of the following provision shall be a Class 4 infraction:22 DCMR § 301.10 (failure to frame and post license).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 4998 (May 27, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>