<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-401</num>
  <heading>INSPECTIONS AUTHORIZED (ยง 16-401)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>401.1.</num>
    <text>The Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs (DCRA) and other authorized government officials shall have authority to inspect towing businesses and towing service storage lots to determine compliance with these regulations. All violations discovered
      during inspections shall be reported to the Director, who may fine, suspend, or revoke the licenses of towing businesses, tow trucks, or towing service storage lots in accordance with this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.2.</num>
    <text>Before licensing a towing business, a tow truck, or a towing service storage lot, and at any time while a license or endorsement is in effect, a towing-related business shall permit the Director and other authorized government officials or their agents
      to inspect towing equipment, tow trucks, towing service storage lots, and any logs or documents related to towing services initiated within the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.3.</num>
    <text>To ensure compliance with these regulations, towing service storage lots shall be subject to periodic and random unannounced inspections by officials of DCRA, and officials of other government agencies authorized to inspect towing-related businesses
      and vehicles in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.4.</num>
    <text>No person shall interfere with an inspection authorized under this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.5.</num>
    <text>Copies of all documents, including any Notices of Infraction, computerized data, electronic records, and log book entries regarding the towing or impounding of a vehicle by a towing business or towing service storage lot shall be maintained at the
      primary location of the towing business indicated on the application submitted in accordance with ยง 402, for a period of not less than three (3) years. An owner, tow truck operator, or other employee of the towing business or towing services storage
      lot shall surrender or arrange the surrender of such records upon lawful demand by the Director, or his/her designated agent, or other authorized government official, within one (1) hour of the time of such demand.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.6.</num>
    <text>After demand has been made for records pertaining to any particular transaction, no record may be created and submitted as evidence or explanation of any towing service that had already been provided, except as may be required by an authorized government
      official during legal proceedings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 522 (January 21, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>