<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-404</num>
  <heading>REQUIRED TOW TRUCK EQUIPMENT AND MARKINGS (ยง 16-404)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>404.1.</num>
    <text>A towing business shall have available for its exclusive use a minimum of one (1) fully equipped and licensed tow truck.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>404.2.</num>
    <text>The trade name, primary location of business and primary phone number of the towing business shall appear on both doors of the cab of the tow truck in contrasting paint or vinyl lettering not less than 3&amp;#8243; in height.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>404.3.</num>
    <text>The minimum and maximum private towing and storage fees charged by the towing height. business shall appear on both sides of the tow truck in contrasting paint or vinyl lettering not less than 2&amp;#8243; in height.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>404.4.</num>
    <text>The unique alphanumeric identifier issued by DCRA to each tow truck shall appear on both sides of the tow truck in contrasting paint or vinyl lettering not less than 1&amp;#8243; in height.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>404.5.</num>
    <text>Each tow truck shall be equipped with a two-way communication system capable of transmitting and receiving messages between the towing business&amp;#8217;s office and the tow truck anywhere in the District of Columbia. The towing business shall have
      all permits and licenses required by District of Columbia and Federal law to operate the communications system.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>404.6.</num>
    <text>Each flat-bed tow truck shall have four (4) safety tie-down devices, chains, or straps in any combination. Chains used for light-duty tows (i.e., vehicles with a gross vehicle weight less than 4,000 pounds) shall be &amp;#8220;grade 7&amp;#8243; high-test
      chains, a minimum of 5/16&amp;#8243; in diameter. Straps shall be 2&amp;#8243; webbing with an 8,000 pound-per-linear-inch rating. Chains and straps shall be equipped with a &amp;#8220;transportation cluster.&amp;#8221; Straps shall have a ratchet
      device.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>404.7.</num>
    <text>If a tow truck is engaged in recovery, it shall have at least one (1) recovery chain of a minimum of &amp;#8220;grade 8&amp;#8243; alloy, which is a minimum of 5/16&amp;#8243; in diameter. In addition, it shall have two (2) four-ton (manufacturer-stamped)
      snatch blocks with one 4&amp;#8243; pulley equipped with locking devices.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>404.8.</num>
    <text>Each crane tow truck shall have at least a retracted boom, rated at four-tons, with one four-ton winch equipped with a minimum of 75 feet of 3/8&amp;#8243; wire rope. The cable must be able to support a load equal to or greater than the capacity of
      the winch. The boom must be able to support a load equal to or greater than the capacity of the winch or winches. Industry standards require a swage and thimble to be used when the wire rope is terminated with a fixed hook. A clip may only be used
      for an emergency repair. Each crane tow truck shall have dollies with securing devices.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>404.9.</num>
    <text>Each wheel lift tow truck shall have a minimum capacity of 3500 pounds. This standard applies whether wheel lift is on a stand-alone towing vehicle or is in combination with a crane tow truck or flat bed tow truck. In addition, each wheel lift tow
      truck shall have straps which have 2&amp;#8243; webbing with an 8,000 pound-per-linear-inch rating. Chains and straps shall be equipped with a &amp;#8220;transportation cluster.&amp;#8221; Straps shall have a ratchet device.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>404.10.</num>
    <text>All tow trucks shall have the following equipment, in good working order:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>One (1) all-purpose 5-pound fire extinguisher (rated 5ABC or better);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>One (1) set of wheel blocks;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A minimum of two (2) gallons of commercial absorbent to be used as a quick cover up for minor oil/gasoline spills;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>An air compressor and/or portable air tank equipped with hose and tire chuck for tire inflation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A minimum of two (2) red flags not less than 12&amp;#8243; x 12&amp;#8243; in size;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Two (2) portable red reflectors and two (2) red flares;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A set of tools which includes a set of screwdrivers, a wrecking bar, a</text>
    </level>
    <text>working flashlight, a set of lug wrenches, a jack, jumper cables, and a first-aid kit; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>At least one (1) of each of the following: broom, shovel, waste container, and axe.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>404.11.</num>
    <text>It shall be unlawful for a tow truck operator to tow a vehicle without properly using equipment that meets the manufacturer&amp;#8217;s minimum specifications for the towing of a specified vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 522 (January 21, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>