<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-400</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 16-400)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>400.1.</num>
    <text>[RESERVED]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>400.2.</num>
    <text>Except as provided herein, the provisions of this chapter shall apply to every person and entity that provides, or offers to provide, towing services within the District of Columbia, and shall apply to every person and entity that provides, or offers
      to provide, storage facilities for towed vehicles.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>400.3.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this chapter shall not apply to the towing of vehicles by the government agency that owns or controls them.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>400.4.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this chapter shall not apply to the towing of vehicles by any tow truck owned or operated by an entity or agency of the federal government or the District of Columbia Government.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>400.5.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this chapter shall not apply to the towing of vehicles by tow trucks owned by the person or entity that owns the towed vehicles, where the tow trucks are used only to tow the tow truck owner’s own vehicles and tow services are not
      offered to the public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>400.6.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this chapter shall not apply to: vehicles towed into or through the District of Columbia if the tow originates in another jurisdiction and the tow truck is licensed in that other jurisdiction, or to tow trucks registered in another
      jurisdiction responding to a call from the owner or operator for the removal of a motor vehicle from the District into another jurisdiction, provided that the tow truck is not equipped with a radio receiver capable of being tuned to the Metropolitan
      Police Radio wave lengths or frequencies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>400.7.</num>
    <text>Nothing contained in this chapter shall preclude any entity of the Government of the District of Columbia from establishing policies and procedures governing the towing of vehicles by or for that entity, provided that such additional policies and
      procedures are consistent with the provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>400.8.</num>
    <text>Upon demand by the owner or operator of a towed vehicle, a towing business shall provide the name, address, and current telephone number of the towing business’s insurance carrier, and the account number of the insurance policy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 522 (January 21, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>