<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-602</num>
  <heading>REPAIR DEALER LICENSE (§ 16-602)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>602.1.</num>
    <text>Each consumer goods repair dealer who provides repair services in the District in the motor vehicles repair category, under § 611, and each consumer goods repair dealer who provides services in the electronics equipment repair category pursuant to
      § 612, shall obtain a license from the Department pursuant to the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.2.</num>
    <text>At such time as consumer goods repair dealer licensure becomes mandatory in repair industry categoriesother than the motor vehicle and electronics categories, each consumer goods repair dealer shall be required to secure a separate license for each
      repair industry category subject to this chapter and in which the dealer provides repair services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.3.</num>
    <text>If a dealer confines repair services to one (1) or more specialties within a category, that dealer shall be required to secure a license only for each specialty in which the dealer provides repair services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.4.</num>
    <text>If a consumer goods repair dealer operates more than one (1) place of business offering repair services subject to this chapter, the dealer shall obtain a separate consumer goods repair dealer license for each separate place of business.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.5.</num>
    <text>Each applicant for a consumer goods repair dealer license shall demonstrate to the Department that the applicant conducts or intends to conduct repair services in the District, and that the applicant has supplied the Department with any other information
      required by § 604 or the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.6.</num>
    <text>Each applicant for a consumer goods repair dealer license who employs five (5) or fewer repairmen shall file with the Department a corporate surety bond in the amount of two thousand dollars ($ 2,000).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.7.</num>
    <text>Each applicant dealer who employs more than five (5) repairmen shall file a corporate surety bond in the amount of five thousand dollars ($ 5,000).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.8.</num>
    <text>The corporate surety bond shall serve as protection for any person aggrieved by violation of this chapter, in accordance with the provisions of D.C. Code § 47-2844 (1981 Ed.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>