<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-603</num>
  <heading>SUPERVISORY INSPECTOR LICENSE (ยง 16-603)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>603.1.</num>
    <text>Each motor vehicle and electronics equipment repair dealer shall be licensed as a supervisory inspector or shall be required to employ, under ยง 631, a supervisory inspector who shall be licensed pursuant to the requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.2.</num>
    <text>The Department shall establish a program for competency testing and registration of motor vehicles and electronics equipment supervisory inspectors.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.4.</num>
    <text>Any individual who has successfully passed the appropriate competency test and has otherwise complied with the licensing requirements for supervisory inspectors shall be designated by the Department as a &amp;#8220;Registered Automotive Supervisory
      Inspector&amp;#8221; or a &amp;#8220;Registered Electronics Supervisory Inspector,&amp;#8221; as the case may be, in the appropriate repair industry category or in a designated repair specialty within that category.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.5.</num>
    <text>Failure to obtain a license as required by this section and by ยง 602 may be raised as an affirmative defense to any suit brought by a consumer goods repair dealer or supervisory inspector seeking to collect payment for services performed by the dealer
      or inspector in that person&amp;#8217;s area of licensure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.6.</num>
    <text>Each applicant for a supervisory inspector license shall demonstrate to the Department, in a manner to be prescribed by the Department, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That the applicant is at least eighteen (18) years of age;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The applicant is physically fit to perform the duties of a supervisory inspector;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The applicant has successfully passed the competency examination administered or certified by the Department under this chapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The applicant is of good moral character.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.7.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall be presumed to be of good moral character unless he or she has been convicted of a crime which the Department finds has a substantial relationship to the functions and responsibilities to be performed by a supervisory inspector,
      and that the applicant has not demonstrated good moral character subsequent to the conviction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>