<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-611</num>
  <heading>REPAIR OF MOTOR VEHICLES (ยง 16-611)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>611.1.</num>
    <text>The repair industry category designated as &amp;#8220;motor vehicles&amp;#8221; shall include any passenger vehicle fully or partially powered by an internal combustion engine or an electric motor, and intended primarily as a means of transportation,
      and shall include trailers which are intended primarily for attachment to passenger vehicles.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>611.2.</num>
    <text>The Department shall establish and publish appropriate technical definitions, practices and procedural requirements consistent with this chapter and designed to assure public safety in the field of automotive repair.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>611.3.</num>
    <text>The Department shall identify motor vehicle repair services to be included within the scope of this chapter, including but not limited to repairing or changing tires; lubrication; installing light bulbs, batteries, windshield wiper blades, and other
      minor accessories; cleaning, adjusting, and replacing spark plugs; replacing fan belts, oil, and air filters; and other minor services which require mechanical expertise to be performed properly and have given rise to a high incidence of fraud or
      deceptive practices or involve a part of the motor vehicle essential to its safe operation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>611.4.</num>
    <text>The Department shall establish repair industry specialties within the category of motor vehicles repair and identify the specific types of motor vehicles repair services to be included in each specialty.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>611.5.</num>
    <text>The Department shall establish definitions of the following automotive repair terms and services, along with other terms and services that the Department may deem appropriate:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Motor: Minimum overhaul, engine overhaul, and tuneup;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Brake System: Brake adjustment and replacement, replace brake drum, turn brake drum, renew drum brake linings, rebuild wheel cylinder, rebuild master cylinder;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Visibility: Replace sealed beam, aim headlights, replace speedometer cable, replace windshield wiper motor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Steering and Suspension: Replace ball joint, replace shock absorber, replace wheel bearing, balance wheel, front end alignment, recondition power steering gear, replace power steering house;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Exhaust System: Replace tailpipe, replace muffler, replace exhaust pipe;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Ignition System: Replace cable set, replace or clean spark plugs (set), tune-up, replace points and condenser, retiming; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Fuel System: Replace carburetor, replace fuel pump, replace fuel filter, replace air cleaner.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>