<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-652</num>
  <heading>OUTDOOR REPAIR AND STORAGE OF MOTOR VEHICLES (§ 16-652)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>652.1.</num>
    <text>No repair services by a consumer goods repair dealer involving motor vehicles may be performed outside of a permanent garage or other permanent building, located on premises for which the dealer has a license to perform repair services on motor vehicles,
      except that the dealer may perform outdoors:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Within the boundaries of the dealer’s licensed premises, minor motor vehicle repair services limited to replacing batteries, changing tires, changing light bulbs or air filters, adding washer fluid or motor oil, and other comparably minor services,
        but excluding oil changes or any other services involving the removal of motor vehicle fluids; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>On disabled motor vehicles, emergency road services limited to jump-starting engines, replacing batteries, changing tires, and other comparably minor emergency services.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>652.2.</num>
    <text>The phrase “outdoor storage of motor vehicles” in Title 16, Section 314, excludes parking, at the licensed premises of a consumer goods repair dealer licensed to perform repair services on motor vehicles, of the following types of motor vehicles:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Customers’ motor vehicles kept on the premises for the purpose of having repair services performed on the vehicles by the dealer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Motor vehicles used by customers, employees, visitors, and other persons, to travel to and from the premises;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Operational motor vehicles that are owned by or leased to the dealer and that are kept and regularly used by the dealer for the purpose of transporting passengers, vehicles, supplies, or equipment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>652.3.</num>
    <text>To assist the Director in monitoring compliance with this section and with Title 16, Section 314, a consumer goods repair dealer shall maintain in a secure location on the dealer’s premises, for each motor vehicle kept on the premises that belongs
      to a customer, a record showing the customer’s name, address, and telephone number, the date the vehicle was received by the dealer, and the type or types of repair services that have been, are being, or are to be performed on the vehicle by the
      dealer, and shall make such record available for immediate inspection by the Director at any time during regular business hours.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 3096 (April 24, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>