<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-705</num>
  <heading>SUSPENSION OF REGISTRATION (ยง 16-705)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>705.1.</num>
    <text>If at least three (3) complaints of a registrant&amp;#8217;s failure to abide by the provisions of this chapter have been made to the Director during any twenty-four (24) month period by at least three (3) separate customers, the Director may give
      notice to the registrant of the Director&amp;#8217;s intent to hold a hearing to determine whether the registrant&amp;#8217;s registration under this chapter should be suspended.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.2.</num>
    <text>If a registrant has been convicted of a violation of this chapter or of any other criminal offense involving fraudulent conduct in connection with the transportation of household goods, the Director may give notice to the registrant of the Director&amp;#8217;s
      intent to hold a hearing to determine whether the registrant&amp;#8217;s registration under this chapter should be suspended.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.3.</num>
    <text>The notice to be given by the Director shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The time [which shall not be sooner than thirty (30) days from the date of the notice] and place for the hearing; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The basis upon which the Director proposes to suspend the registrant&amp;#8217;s registration.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.4.</num>
    <text>If the hearing is to be held upon the basis of customers&amp;#8217; complaints, the notice shall be accompanied by copies of those complaints.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.5.</num>
    <text>The notice shall be served upon the registrant personally or by either of the following methods:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>By leaving a copy of the notice at the last business address (or home address, if there is no business address) of which the Director has been given notice by the registrant with a person eighteen (18) years of age or older who works or resides
        there; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>By mailing a copy of the notice by certified mail, return receipt requested, to the business address (or home address if there is no business address) of which the Director has been given notice by the registrant.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.6.</num>
    <text>The Director shall conduct the hearing in accordance with the provisions of ยง 10 of the D.C. Administrative Procedure Act (D.C. Official Code ยง 2-1510 (2001 Ed.)).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.7.</num>
    <text>If on the basis of the evidence the Director is satisfied that the registrant has intentionally and regularly been conducting the business in violation of this chapter, the Director may issue an order suspending that registrant&amp;#8217;s registration
      for such time and under such circumstances as the Director deems proper.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.8.</num>
    <text>The order of suspension may extend to a permanent suspension of the registration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>