<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-804</num>
  <heading>APPOINTMENT OF THE MAYOR AS ATTORNEY-IN-FACT (ยง 16-804)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>804.1.</num>
    <text>In the application for any license under this chapter, the applicant shall appoint the Mayor as the applicant&amp;#8217;s true and lawful attorney upon whom may be served any judicial and other processes or legal notices directed to the licensee in
      any action or proceeding against the licensee growing out of the operation under the license applied for, and to a signification of the applicant&amp;#8217;s agreement that any such process or notice which is so served shall be of the same legal
      force and validity as if served upon the licensee personally in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>804.2.</num>
    <text>No process or notice may be served under the provisions of this section upon any individual residing in the District, or upon any domestic corporation organized under the District of Columbia Business Corporation Act, or upon any foreign corporation
      having a registered agent in the District under the provisions of that Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>804.3.</num>
    <text>The provisions of ยง 804.1 shall not be operative unless and until at least one (1) bona fide attempt has been made to serve the process or notice in a manner otherwise provided by law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>804.4.</num>
    <text>Service of process or notice in accordance with the provisions of this section shall be made by leaving with the Director not less than one (1) copy of the process or notice for each defendant to be served, together with a fee of two dollars ($ 2.00)
      for each defendant, except that no fee will be charged any District office or agency for the service of any process or notice under the authority of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>804.5.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of the process or notice, accompanied by the required fee and an affidavit stating there has been compliance with ยง 804.3, the Director shall forward the process or notice by certified mail to each defendant so served, at the address
      of the defendant as shown on the license issued to the defendant under the authority of this chapter or on the licensee&amp;#8217;s application for a license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>