<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-906</num>
  <heading>PAWNTICKETS (ยง 16-906)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>906.1.</num>
    <text>At the time of receiving a pledge the licensee shall deliver to the pledgor a pawnticket, in accordance with D.C. Official Code ยง 47-2884.12.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>906.2.</num>
    <text>The pawnticket shall be printed in a form approved by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>906.3.</num>
    <text>Each pawnticket shall be serially numbered by the printer, shall contain two (2) parts, one of which shall be retained by the licensee, at all times, and one of which shall be given to the pledgor at the time of the original pledge.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>906.4.</num>
    <text>Both the pledgor&amp;#8217;s ticket and the part kept by the licensee shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the pledgor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A description of the pledge;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The date of the transaction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The amount and duration of the loan; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The rate of interest charged.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>906.5.</num>
    <text>If a pledgor desires an additional loan or an extension of a loan on any pledge in the possession of the licensee, the licensee shall require the surrender of the outstanding pawnticket.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>906.6.</num>
    <text>Upon surrender of the original pawnticket under ยง 906.5, the licensee shall issue a new pawnticket in the amount of the loan, including any additional loan, and shall follow the procedure prescribed for the issuance of the original pawnticket.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>906.7.</num>
    <text>Whenever a new pawnticket is issued upon the making of an additional loan or an extension of a loan on a pledge in the possession of the licensee, the licensee shall enter a notation on the surrendered ticket and at the appropriate place in the pawn
      record ledger of the number of the newly-issued pawnticket.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>906.8.</num>
    <text>When a pledgor surrenders his portion of the pawnticket to the licensee, either on the redemption of a pledge, or upon the making of an additional loan or an extension of a loan on a pledge in the possession of the licensee, the licensee shall retain
      and file the pledgor&amp;#8217;s portion of the surrendered ticket in numerical order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>906.9.</num>
    <text>The licensee&amp;#8217;s portion of the pawnticket shall at all times be kept and filed in alphabetical order according to the pledgor&amp;#8217;s name.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>