<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-1606</num>
  <heading>RENEWAL OF LICENSES (ยง 17-1606)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1606.1.</num>
    <text>License renewal applications for an employment agency, employment counseling service, employer-paid personnel service, or job listing service shall be submitted to the Director at least thirty (30) days before the expiration date of the current license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1606.2.</num>
    <text>Renewal applications shall be granted if the following conditions are met:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>There are no outstanding violations of the Act or this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>All fines or collateral with respect to violations of the Act or this chapter have been paid;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The renewal application and any required bond is approved;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The applicant is in compliance with the Act, this chapter, and all other applicable laws, rules, and regulations of the District; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The license renewal fee is paid.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1606.3.</num>
    <text>Any employment agency, employment counseling service, employer-paid personnel service, or job listing service which fails to obtain a renewal of its license prior to expiration of the license shall be required to apply for a new license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1606.4.</num>
    <text>Prior to issuance of a license under ยง1600.3 an employer agency, employment counseling service, employer-paid personnel service or job listing service shall pay any outstanding fines or collateral, if any, stemming from operating without a license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 3165, 3168 (May 15, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>