<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-1511</num>
  <heading>EXAMINATIONS (ยง 17-1511)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1511.1.</num>
    <text>Each applicant for licensure by examination must pass the applicable written examination to be eligible for licensure by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1511.2.</num>
    <text>The following engineering examinations prepared and furnished by the National Council of Examiners for Engineering and Surveying meet the requirements of the District of Columbia for licensure as an engineer:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Examination in the fundamentals of engineering, known as the Fundamentals of Engineering (FE) examination, of eight (8) hours duration;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Examination in the principles and practice of engineering, known as the Principles and Practice of Engineering (PE) examination in the appropriate engineering discipline, of eight (8) hours duration.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1511.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant for licensure as a Professional Engineer or as an Engineer Intern shall be eligible for the appropriate examination as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An applicant for licensure as a Professional Engineer will be permitted to sit for the PE examination upon satisfactorily fulfilling all application requirements.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>No applicant may sit for the eight (8) hour FE examination or the eight (8) hour PE examination until the Board has established that the applicant is eligible for the examination.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An applicant for licensure as an Engineer Intern becomes eligible to sit for the FE examination during the senior year of enrollment in an engineering program leading to a baccalaureate degree in engineering which program has been approved by the
        Board. The enrollment of the applicant must be verified by the school being attended.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Professional Engineers are examined by discipline and shall select the discipline for examination on the application. Engineering specialties are listed in section 1512 of this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1511.4.</num>
    <text>The following examinations prepared and furnished by the National Council of Examiners for Engineering and Surveying, meet the requirements of the District of Columbia for licensure as a Professional Land Surveyor:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Examination in the fundamentals of land surveying, known as the Fundamentals of Land Surveying (FLS) examination, of eight (8) hours duration, and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Examination in the principles and practice of land surveying, known as the Principles and Practice of Land Surveying (PLS) examination, of eight (8) hours duration of which four (4) hours is on District of Columbia laws and procedures for the practice
        of land surveying.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1511.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant for licensure as a Professional Land Surveyor shall be eligible for the appropriate examination as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An applicant for licensure as a Professional Land Surveyor will not be permitted to sit for the PLS examination until the FLS examination has been passed.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An applicant may be permitted to sit for the eight (8) hour FLS examination or the eight (8) hour PLS examination after the Board has established that the applicant is eligible for the examination.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1511.6.</num>
    <text>Examinations are offered on dates and times set by the National Council of Examiners for Engineering and Surveying and at locations designated by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1511.7.</num>
    <text>Examinations will be given in English.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1511.8.</num>
    <text>The Board will not distribute copies of questions used on prior examinations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1511.9.</num>
    <text>The Board may publish specifications for all written examinations, which may be obtained from the Board upon request by persons who have been approved by the Board to take the national and/or District examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1511.10.</num>
    <text>Instructions provided prior to each examination will declare an examination open or closed book. When an applicant sits for an open-book examination, any books, bound materials of any sort, and Board-approved calculators or computers that are self-powered
      and non-printing may be used. Examinees shall not loan or exchange materials with any other person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1511.11.</num>
    <text>If an applicant fails to attend an examination for which he or she has been scheduled, the examination fee will be forfeited. In the case of illness, death in the family, or other unavoidable causes for absence the fee will be applied to the next
      test administration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1511.12.</num>
    <text>Failure of an applicant to attend an examination for which he or she has been scheduled to attend does not count as a failure of the examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1511.13.</num>
    <text>An applicant who fails to pass the first or second PE, PLS, FE, or FLS examination will be granted a request to sit for a third offering of the examination. In the event the applicant fails to pass a third examination and wishes to retake the examination,
      the Board may require the applicant to wait a prescribed period of time before taking the examination again and/or appear before the Board with evidence to show that he or she has acquired additional knowledge.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1511.14.</num>
    <text>An applicant for the PE or PLS examinations will be notified by the Board at least twenty-one (21) days before the examination date of approval to take the examination. The applicant must notify the Board if he/she is unable to sit for the examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1511.15.</num>
    <text>An initial applicant for the PE, FE, PLS, or FLS examinations must submit an application at least ninety (90) days before the examination date in order to sit for the examination. An applicant for re-examination must apply to take the examination
      at least sixty (60) days before the examination date in order to sit for the examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1511.16.</num>
    <text>Examination results, after review and approval of the passing score, will be supplied in writing to each examinee showing the applicant&amp;#8217;s score and the passing score. No results will be given in any other manner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 8783 (September 7, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>