<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-1616</num>
  <heading>FINDINGS, CONCLUSIONS, AND DECISION (§ 17-1616)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1616.1.</num>
    <text>Within thirty (30) days from the date the hearing is completed or the hearing record is closed, whichever is later, the hearing examiner shall submit proposed findings of fact and conclusions of law and a recommended decision to the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1616.2.</num>
    <text>The hearing examiner shall serve upon all parties a copy of the proposed findings of fact and conclusions of law and recommended decision at the same time that they are submitted to the Director. The proposed findings of fact and conclusions of law
      and recommended decision shall be served in accordance with §§1610.2 and 1610.3 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1616.3.</num>
    <text>The parties shall simultaneously be served with a notice advising that written exceptions to the proposed findings of fact and conclusions of law and recommended decision may be filed within fifteen (15) days from the date of receipt.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1616.4.</num>
    <text>The Director may permit or require the parties to present oral argument prior to rendering a final decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1616.5.</num>
    <text>The Director shall make a final decision within fifteen (15) business days of the filing of the exceptions or, when no exceptions are filed, within fifteen (15) business days of the expiration of the period within which exceptions may be filed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1616.6.</num>
    <text>If the Director, after reviewing the record, disagrees with any of the proposed findings of fact or conclusions of law or the recommended decision, the Director may make new findings of fact and conclusions of law and render a final decision accordingly,
      or may remand the case to the hearing examiner for further proceedings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1616.7.</num>
    <text>A final decision of the Director shall be served on the parties in accordance with §§1610.2 and 1610.3, and shall notify the aggrieved party of a right to judicial review, if any.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 3165, 3174 (May 15, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>