<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-1729</num>
  <heading>THE HEARING EXAMINER (§ 17-1729)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1729.1.</num>
    <text>The Director shall appoint an Administrative Law Judge, attorney examiner, or Hearing Examiner to conduct a hearing pursuant to § 103(c) of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985, effective October 5, 1985
      (D.C. Law 6-42; D.C. Official Code § 2-1801.03).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1729.2.</num>
    <text>The Hearing Examiner conducting a hearing has all of the powers and duties enumerated in § 1725 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1729.3.</num>
    <text>The Hearing Examiner, upon being appointed by the Director, shall be responsible for all matters pertaining to the hearing, including but not limited to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Establishing a hearing file;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Setting a date, time, and place for the hearing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Conducting the hearing in a fair and impartial manner;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Making proposed findings of fact and conclusions of law; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Forwarding the proposed findings of fact and conclusions of law to the Director for final decision.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1729.4.</num>
    <text>After hearing the evidence, a Hearing Examiner shall, within forty-five (45) days of the hearing, submit a recommended decision to the Director. At the same time, the Hearing Examiner shall serve the respondent with a copy of the decision and send
      a copy of the decision to the Corporation Counsel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1729.5.</num>
    <text>A decision of a Hearing Examiner adverse to a respondent shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Findings of fact;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Conclusions of law based on the findings of fact and application of the laws; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A recommended order.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1729.6.</num>
    <text>The Director may accept or reject the recommended decision of a Hearing Examiner in whole or in part.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1729.7.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § 1729.8, the Director, within thirty (30) days of the recommended decision of the Hearing Examiner, shall render a decision and notify the respondent and the Corporation Counsel of the action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1729.8.</num>
    <text>If the decision of a Hearing Examiner is adverse to the respondent, the Hearing Examiner, before issuing a final decision, shall serve the respondent with a copy of a proposed decision and give the respondent an opportunity to file exceptions, and
      written argument in support thereof, with the Director within ten (10) days of the date of service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1729.9.</num>
    <text>The Hearing Examiner shall consider any exceptions and argument filed by a respondent pursuant to § 1729.8 in issuing a final decision. If the respondent does not file exceptions within the required period, the proposed decision of the Hearing Examiner
      shall become the final decision of the Hearing Examiner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking at 50 DCR 9549 (November 14, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>