<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-1618</num>
  <heading>MOTIONS (ยง 17-1618)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1618.1.</num>
    <text>Except by leave of the hearing examiner during a hearing, an application for an order or other relief shall be made by written motion. A motion shall state with particularity the grounds on which it is based and shall clearly set forth the order or
      relief sought. If a motion is to be supported by memoranda, affidavits, or other papers, they shall be attached and served with them motion.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1618.2.</num>
    <text>A copy of each motion, opposition, reply, or other pleading filed shall be served on each party separately represented, and a certificate of service shall appear at the end of the pleading.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1618.3.</num>
    <text>Any party may file a response or opposition to a motion within seven (7) days after service of the motion but the Director or hearing examiner may shorten or extend this time. The response or opposition shall not include a motion for other affirmative
      relief against the moving party.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1618.4.</num>
    <text>A reply to a response or opposition may be filed within three (3) days after service of the response or opposition, but a reply shall not re-argue propositions, presented in the motion nor present matters which are not strictly in reply to the response
      or opposition. No further pleadings may be filed except by leave of the Director or the hearing examiner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1618.5.</num>
    <text>A motion or other pleading shall be submitted on business size eight and one-half inches by eleven inches (8 1/2&amp;#8243; x 11&amp;#8243;) paper. It shall contain the name and number of the case. All typing shall be double-spaced, except for footnotes
      and quotations, which may be single-spaced and indented. A motion or other pleadings shall be signed by the party filing it, or by the party&amp;#8217;s attorney.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1618.6.</num>
    <text>When service under ยง1618.2 is by mail, service shall be deemed complete upon deposit in the United States Mail with postage prepaid.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 3165, 3176 (May 15, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>