<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-109</num>
  <heading>FINDINGS AND DECISIONS (§ 17-109)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>109.1.</num>
    <text>The members of the board or commission who conduct the hearing shall render their decision, in writing, as soon as practicable, but not later than ninety (90) days after the date the hearing is completed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>109.2.</num>
    <text>The decision of the board or commission shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Findings of fact made by the board or commission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Application by the board or commission of the Act and this title to the facts as found by the board or commission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The decision of the board or commission based upon its findings of fact and application of the laws and regulations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A statement informing the person concerned of the right to have the decision reviewed by the D.C. Court of Appeals, and the time within which judicial review must be sought.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>109.3.</num>
    <text>Within five (5) days after the decision is rendered, the board or commission shall serve upon the person concerned, or that person&amp;#8217;s attorney of record, a copy of the written decision either personally or by certified mail.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>109.4.</num>
    <text>If the decision is sent by certified mail, it shall be deemed to have been served on the date contained on the return receipt, or on the date of the refusal of the person concerned to receive notice, or on the date of the unsuccessful attempt of the
      postal service to make delivery.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Sections 50.1, 50.2, and 50.3 of Regulation No. 72.3, approved January 28, 1972, 5DD DCRR §§50.1, 50.2, and 50.3, 18 DCR 436 (February 22, 1972).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>