<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-1608</num>
  <heading>CEASE AND DESIST ORDERS (§ 17-1608)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1608.1.</num>
    <text>The Director may issue cease and desist orders pursuant to § 13 of the Act, D.C. Code § 36-1012 (1981), for violation of the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1608.2.</num>
    <text>A written request for a hearing may be mailed, but shall not be considered timely filed unless received by the Director within fifteen (15) days of receipt of the cease and desist order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1608.3.</num>
    <text>If a timely request for a hearing is not filed, the order of the Director to cease and desist shall be final.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1608.4.</num>
    <text>If, after a hearing, the Director determines that no violation of the Act has taken place, the Director shall rescind the order to cease and desist.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1608.5.</num>
    <text>When the Director, after investigation, believes that any provision of the Act has been violated, but that the general public has not suffered and will not suffer immediate and irreparable loss and injury, the Director shall notify the alleged violator
      in writing of the alleged violation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1608.6.</num>
    <text>In the written notice with §1608.5, the Director shall inform the alleged violator of the provisions of §13(b) of the Act, D.C. Code §36-1012(b) (1981), relating to the alleged violator&amp;#8217;s right to respond to the notice and to the possible
      consequences of failure to respond.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1608.7.</num>
    <text>Within fifteen (15) days of receipt of this notification, the alleged violator may show cause to the Director in writing why the Director should not issue a cease and desist order. A written show cause response may be mailed, but shall not be considered
      timely filed unless it is received by the Director within the fifteen (15) day time limit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1608.8.</num>
    <text>If the alleged violator fails to respond to the Director&amp;#8217;s notice of violation within the time period set forth in §1608.6, the Director may issue a cease and desist order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1608.9.</num>
    <text>If the alleged violator&amp;#8217;s show cause response satisfies the Director that there is no basis for a cease and desist order, the Director shall terminate all proceedings against the alleged violator.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1608.10.</num>
    <text>If the alleged violator&amp;#8217;s show cause response does not satisfy the Director that there is no basis for a cease and desist order, the Director may schedule a hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1608.11.</num>
    <text>The Director shall notify the alleged violator in writing by certified mail of the date, time, and location of the hearing at least five (5) days in advance of the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1608.12.</num>
    <text>If the Director determines, after the hearing, that the alleged violator has violated any provision of the Act, the Director shall issue a cease and desist order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1608.13.</num>
    <text>If the Director determines, after the hearing, that the alleged violator has not violated any provision of the Act, the Director shall terminate all proceedings against the alleged violator.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1608.14.</num>
    <text>If the alleged violator fails to comply with a cease and desist order, the Director shall refer the matter to the Office of the Corporation Counsel of the District of Columbia for appropriate action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 3165, 3169 (May 15, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>