<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-1509</num>
  <heading>EXPERIENCE REQUIREMENTS (ยง 17-1509)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1509.1.</num>
    <text>A person applying for licensure as a Professional Engineer shall prove to the satisfaction of the Board that he or she has obtained four (4) or more years of experience indicating that he or she may be competent to practice engineering. In evaluating
      an applicant&amp;#8217;s experience, the Board shall consider the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Experience must be progressive on engineering projects to indicate that it is of increasing quality and requiring greater responsibility.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Only work of an engineering nature, which follows graduation from a Board approved curriculum, is creditable.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Experience shall not have been obtained in violation of the Act.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Experience gained in the armed services, to be creditable, must be of a character equivalent to that which would have been gained in the civilian sector doing similar work. The Board expects that the applicant, while in the armed services, served
        in an engineering or engineering-related group.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Experience should be gained under the supervision of a licensed professional engineer or, if the experience was gained without supervision, an explanation should be provided showing why the experience should be considered acceptable.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>For sales experience to be creditable, it must be demonstrated that engineering principles were required and used in gaining the experience.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Teaching experience, to be creditable, must be in engineering or engineering-related courses at an advanced level in a college or university offering an engineering curriculum of four (4) years or more that is approved by the Board.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Experience gained in engineering research and design projects by members of an engineering faculty where the Board approves the curriculum is creditable.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Successful completion of graduate study leading to the master&amp;#8217;s degree in engineering that has followed a baccalaureate degree in engineering may be used for credit for one (1) year&amp;#8217;s experience. If the Ph.D. in engineering is
        completed under the same conditions, two (2) years&amp;#8217; total experience may be credited. The two (2) years&amp;#8217; credit includes the one (1) year for the master&amp;#8217;s degree. If the Ph.D. is obtained without the master&amp;#8217;s
        degree, the credit for experience may be two (2) years.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Experience may not be anticipated. The experience must have been gained by the time of the application.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Experience in construction, to be creditable, must demonstrate the application of engineering principles.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Experience should include demonstration of knowledge of engineering mathematics, physical and applied science, properties of materials, and the fundamental principles of engineering design.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Experience should include demonstration of the application of engineering principles to the practical solution of engineering problems.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1509.2.</num>
    <text>A person applying for licensure as a Professional Land Surveyor shall prove to the satisfaction of the Board that he or she has obtained experience indicating that he or she may be competent to practice land surveying. In evaluating an applicant&amp;#8217;s
      experience, the Board shall consider the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Experience on land surveying projects shall be progressive to indicate that it is of increasing quality and requiring greater responsibility on the part of the applicant.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Experience shall not be obtained in violation of the Act.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Experience gained in the armed services, to be creditable, must be of a character equivalent to that which would have been gained in the civilian sector doing similar work. The Board expects that the applicant, while in the armed services, served
        in a land surveying group.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Experience should be gained under the supervision of a licensed Professional Land Surveyor or if the experience was gained without supervision, an explanation should be provided showing why the experience should be considered acceptable.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Teaching experience, to be creditable, must be at an advanced level in a land surveying curriculum approved by the Board.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A substantial portion of the experience must be spent in charge of work related to property conveyance and/or boundary line determination.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The applicant must demonstrate adequate experience in the technical field aspects of the profession.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 8783 (September 7, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>