<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-100</num>
  <heading>ADMINISTRATION AND ENFORCEMENT (§ 17-100)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>100.1.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this chapter shall apply to the following licensing and examining boards and commissions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Electrical Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Plumbing Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Board of Registration for Professional Engineers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Refrigeration and Air Conditioning Board; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Steam and Other Operating Engineers Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>100.2.</num>
    <text>A board or commission may do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Refuse to issue or renew a license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Revoke, suspend, or cancel any license; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Censure the holder of a license for any reason for which such action is permitted under the laws or regulations of the District governing the practice of the businesses and professions regulated by that board or commission.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>100.3.</num>
    <text>A board or commission may, upon its own motion, and shall upon the sworn complaint in writing of any person setting forth charges which, if proved, would constitute grounds for disciplinary action, request the Director to investigate the actions of
      any person who is an applicant for or holder of any license provided for in the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>100.4.</num>
    <text>Alternative Adjudication as a Civil Infraction</text>
    <text>In the alternative, adjudication of any infraction of the regulations to which the Administrative Rules for Occupational and Professional Licensing Boards are applicable may be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory
      Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of the regulations applicable to the Administrative Rules for Occupational and Professional Licensing
      Boards pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Section 4 of the District of Columbia Public Accountancy Act of 1977 D.C. Law 2-59 24 DCR 5975 (January 20, 1978), established a new 5-member Board of Accountancy replacing that board created under the District of Columbia Certified Public Accountancy
        Act of 1966, 80 Stat. 785, D.C. Code 1973, §2-911.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Section 5(a) of the District of Columbia Boxing and Wrestling Commission Act, D.C. Law 1-20, 22 DCR 649 (July 25, 1975), created a three-member Boxing and Wresting Commission replacing the Boxing Commission created in An Act to regulate boxing contests
        and exhibitions in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved December 20, 1944, 58 Stat. 823, ch. 812, D.C. Code 1973, § 2-1210.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Sections 4(a) and 34 of the District of Columbia Real Estate Licensure Act of 1982, D.C. Law 4-209, 30 DCR 390 (January 28, 1983), effective March 10, 1983, established a seven-member real estate commission and repealed An Act to define, regulate
        and license real estate, brokers, business chance brokers, and real estate salesman; to create a Real Estate Commission in the District of Columbia; to protect the public against fraud in real estate transactions; and for other purposes, approved
        August 25, 1937 (50 Stat. 787, D.C. Code 1967, §§ 45-1901 et seq.).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Sections 4(a) and 22 of the District of Columbia Funeral Services Regulatory Act of 1984, D.C. Law 5-84, 31 DCR 1815 (April 20, 1984), effective May 22, 1984, created a five-member board and abolished the earlier board established under paragraph
        44A(d)(2) of § 7 of An Act making appropriation to provide for expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for fiscal year ending June 30, 1903, and for other purposes, approved August 1, 1947 (61 Stat. 711; D.C. Code § 47-2873).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Sections 6 and 20 of the Veterinary Practice Act of 1982, D.C. Law 4-171, 29 DCR 5297 (December 3, 1982), effective March 9, 1983, established a Board Veterinary Examiners and repealed An Act to regulate the practice of veterinary medicine in the
        District of Columbia, approved April 20, 1908 (35 Stat. 64, D.C. Code § 32-101 (1981)).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Sections 201, 203, 204, 207, 208, 209, and 210 of the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, D.C. Law 6-99, 33 DCR 729 (February 7, 1986), effective March 25, 1986, created the Board of Dentistry, Board of Medicine, Board
        of Nursing, Board of Optometry, Board of Pharmacy, Board of Physical Therapy, Board of Podiatry, respectively; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Sections 1104(a), (b), (c), (d), (e), (f), and (g) of that Act repealed An Act for the regulation of the practice of dentistry in the District of Columbia, and for the protection of the people from empiricism in relation thereto, approved June 6,
        1982 (27 Stat. 42; D.C. Code § 2-1201 et seq.); Title I of An Act to define the term of &amp;#8220;registered nurse&amp;#8221; and to provide for the registration of nurses in the District of Columbia, approved February 9, 1907 (34 Stat. 887,
        D.C. Code §§ 2-1701.1 to 2-1701.10); An Act To regulate the practice of podiatry in the District of Columbia, approved May 23, 1918 (40 Stat. 560, D.C. Code §2-2201 et seq.); An Act To regulate the practice of optometry in the District of Columbia,
        approved May 28, 1924 (43 Stat. 177, D.C. Code §2-1801 et seq.); the Healing Arts Practice Act, District of Columbia, 1928, approved February 27, 1929 (45 Stat. 1326; D.C. Code §§2-1301 to 2-1343); the District of Columbia Practical Nurses&amp;#8217;
        Licensing Act, approved September 6, 1960 (74 Stat. 802, D.C. Code §§2-1702.1 to 2-1702.19); and the Physical Therapists practice Act, approved September 22, 1961 (89 Stat. 1955, D.C. Code §§2-1703.1 to 2-1703.21).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>The statutory authority to regulate the eight boards appears at the end of this chapter. Paragraphs §§402(12), (54), (57), (60), (61), (62), (64), and (65) of Reorganization Plan No. 3, D.C. Code 1973, Vol. 1 at 152 vested that regulatory authority
        in the District of Columbia Council.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Sections 1.2 and 1.3 of Regulation No. 72-3, approved January 28, 1972, 5DD DCRR, §§1.2 and 1.3, 18 DCR 436 (February 22, 1972); as amended by Regulation No. 72-30, 19 DCR 480 (January 8, 1973); as amended by Final Rulemaking at 39 DCR 660 (January
        22, 1993).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL NOTE Regulation 72-3, as amended, lists twenty-one boards and commissions: namely, Board of Accountancy, Board of Examiners and Registrars of Architects, Board of Barber Examiners, Boxing Commission, Board of Cosmetology, Board of Dental
        Examiners, Electrical Board, Commission on Licensure to Practice the Healing Art, Nurses&amp;#8217; Examining Board, Board of Optometry, Board of Pharmacy, Physical Therapists Examining Board, Plumbing Board, Board of Podiatry Examiners, Practical
        Nurses Examining Board, Board of Registration for Professional Engineers, Real Estate Commission, Refrigeration and Air Conditioning Board, Steam and Other Operating Engineers Board, Board of Funeral Directors and Embalmers, and Board of Examiners
        in Veterinary Medicine. The following statutes enacted by the Council of the District of Columbia either superceded or repealed earlier provisions of law relative to the regulation of thirteen of those boards or commissions:</heading>
      <text></text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>