<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-1514</num>
  <heading>INACTIVE LICENSURE STATUS (ยง 17-1514)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1514.1.</num>
    <text>A licensee may apply for inactive status by submitting a completed inactive status application and paying the appropriate inactive status fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1514.2.</num>
    <text>A person who is on inactive status shall not be required to pay the biennial renewal fee and shall not practice, offer to practice, or attempt to practice as a Professional Engineer or Professional Land Surveyor in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1514.3.</num>
    <text>A person may remain on inactive status for up to five (5) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1514.4.</num>
    <text>A person on inactive status may reactivate his or her license at any time within five (5) years by notifying the Board and by paying appropriate fees and by meeting all requirements of the Board for license renewal including the demonstration of continuing
      professional competency as a condition of reinstatement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1514.5.</num>
    <text>If a person seeking to return to active status has been on inactive status for five (5) years or more, that person shall be considered a new applicant and shall be required to meet all current requirements for licensure, unless the Board in its discretion
      determines that the failure to renew within the five (5) year inactive period was due to reasonable cause or excusable neglect.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1514.6.</num>
    <text>In the event an inactive licensee does not maintain a current license in any jurisdiction for the five (5) years prior to requesting reinstatement, that person will be required to take the Principles and Practice of Engineering (PE) examination or
      the Principles and Practice of Land Surveying (PLS) and the District of Columbia specific examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 8783 (September 7, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>