<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-1503</num>
  <heading>APPLICATIONS (ยง 17-1503)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1503.1.</num>
    <text>A person applying for licensure as a Professional Engineer or Professional Land Surveyor shall present his/her qualifications to the Board on forms provided by the Board.</text>
    <text>Professional Engineers are licensed by discipline and applicants shall select the discipline in which he or she seeks licensure from the choices available on the application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1503.2.</num>
    <text>A person who believes that he or she has the necessary qualifications for licensure according to the laws of the District of Columbia as a Professional Engineer or a Professional Land Surveyor, except for that of experience, may submit an application
      for licensure as an Engineer Intern or a Land Surveyor Intern.</text>
    <text>Engineer Interns are licensed by discipline and applicants shall select the discipline in which he or she seeks licensure from the choices available on the application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1503.3.</num>
    <text>A person who is within one (1) semester of completing a baccalaureate degree in engineering at an educational institution approved by the Board may submit an application to the Board for licensure as an Engineer Intern and, at the Board&amp;#8217;s
      discretion, may be permitted to take the fundamentals examination prior to graduation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1503.4.</num>
    <text>A person applying for licensure by examination shall not register for the examination unless approved by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1503.5.</num>
    <text>All applications shall be completed as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>All applications for licensure shall be made on the forms provided by the Board, but when the space provided on a Board form is inadequate, supplementary sheets provided by the Board (or if not provided by the Board, sheets of white printer or photocopy
        paper 8.5 x 11 inches) are to be used;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>In order to allow sufficient time for processing and for scheduling examinations, all applications that require examinations shall be filed with the Board at least ninety (90) days before the date set for the appropriate examinations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Withholding information, providing statements that are untrue, or misrepresenting facts may be cause for denial of an application, or if discovered after a license has been issued by the Board, suspension, reprimand, or revocation of the license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>An applicant shall supply correct addresses for all references. In the event that a reference fails to respond to a Board inquiry, the Board may delay processing an application until either the reference replies to the Board or the applicant provides
        another reference that replies to the Board; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>In relating experience, the applicant must account for all employment or work experience for the period of time that has elapsed since the beginning of the experience record. If the applicant is not employed, or is employed in other kinds of work,
        this should be indicated in the experience record.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1503.6.</num>
    <text>Applications for licensure by reciprocity or endorsement pursuant to D.C. Official Code ยง 47-2853.12(b), properly executed and submitted with verification by the National Council of Examiners for Engineering and Surveying (NCEES), shall be accepted
      in lieu of the same information that is required to appear on the application form provided by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 8783 (September 7, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>