<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2819</num>
  <heading>DISCIPLINARY ACTIONS (§ 17-2819)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2819.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may revoke or suspend, or refuse to renew or restore, the license of a veterinarian, or deny an applicant a license, for violation of section 10 of the Act, D.C. Code §2-2729 (1987 Supp.), after providing notice and an opportunity for a
      hearing pursuant to chapter 33 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2819.2.</num>
    <text>If the Board determines that there are sufficient grounds to take one of the actions specified in §2819.1, the Board, may, in place of taking such action, take one or more of the following lesser actions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Reprimand the veterinarian;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Place the veterinarian on probation for a specified period;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Impose limitations on the license of the veterinarian; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Require a course of remediation approved by the Board, which may include:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Therapy or treatment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Retraining; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Reexamination, in the discretion of and in the manner prescribed by the Board, after the completion of the course of remediation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2819.3.</num>
    <text>If the Board places a veterinarian on probation, imposes limitations on the license of a veterinarian, or requires a course of remediation pursuant to §§2819.2(b), (c), or (d), the Board may provide that the Board may suspend or revoke the veterinarian&amp;#8217;s
      license, if the veterinarian fails to satisfy the conditions of probation, to observe the limitations imposed on the license, or complete the course of remediation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2819.4.</num>
    <text>The Chairperson of the Board may sign an order, decision, or other document of the Board on behalf of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2819.5.</num>
    <text>A violation of the Act, this chapter, or chapter 33 of this title shall constitute unprofessional conduct within the meaning of § 10(a)(13) of the Act, D.C. Code §2-2729(a)(13) (1987 Supp.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 2226, 2238 (March 25, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>