<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-204</num>
  <heading>EXEMPTIONS FROM LICENSING REQUIREMENTS (§ 17-204)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>204.1.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this chapter shall not apply to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Any public utility as defined in D.C. Code §43-203 (1981), which is under the jurisdiction of the Public Service Commission of the District of Columbia, when that utility is engaged in the performance of work for which the utility holds a franchise
        to engage in rendering a public utility service;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Persons actually engaged in the performance of work under contract with the Federal government;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Persons performing electrical work in connection with the operation of signals or the transmission of intelligence by telegraph or telephone companies in rendering their duly authorized service, or persons installing, manufacturing, or repairing
        equipment designed for use as an integral part of the communication system owned and operated by a telegraph or telephone company; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Persons installing exposed electrical wiring in suitable laboratories for experimental purposes only.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>204.2.</num>
    <text>No license shall be required of an individual to perform electrical work in his or her residence, if that residence is owned and occupied by him or her, and a permit for any electrical work to be done is obtained as required in the D.C. Electrical
      Code.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>204.3.</num>
    <text>A business license or bond will not be required of a person, firm, or corporation to perform work in buildings or on premises under his, her, or its ownership or occupancy, if that person, firm, or corporation regularly employs a licensed master electrician,
      master electrician specialist, or a licensed maintenance and repair electrician.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>204.4.</num>
    <text>No occupational license as an electrician shall be required of a person engaged in any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Repair or replacement of sockets, receptacles, or snap switches;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>General maintenance to repair portable electrical equipment or lighting fixtures; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Other minor repairs at existing outlets on the premises in which he or she is regularly employed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>204.5.</num>
    <text>An individual who is employed only by the District of Columbia government, and whose name appears on the regular employment roll of the District, may be issued a special license without fee for a trade or occupation; Provided, that the following conditions
      shall apply:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The person shall not engage in work authorized by that license other than for the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The limitation set forth in paragraph (a) shall be stated on the face of the license.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>5J DCRR §§401, 403, 405, 503, and 507.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>