<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2707</num>
  <heading>REAL ESTATE GUARANTY AND EDUCATION FUND USE FOR PROGRAMS (ยง 17-2707)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2707.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may use the Fund to pay that proportion of the cost of a program that is equal to the percentage of the program directly related to establishing or maintaining an educational program to improve the competency of licensees or applicants for
      licensure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2707.2.</num>
    <text>The Board may authorize the Fund to be used for expenditures for conferences, workshops and educational programs, for real estate license officials as provided in ยง 2707.4 of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2707.3.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this subsection, a &amp;#8220;real estate license official&amp;#8221; means an employee of the District of Columbia whose duties involve the enforcement of real estate license laws, including but not limited to Board members, legal
      counsel, and other employees as designated by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2707.4.</num>
    <text>The Board may use the Fund to pay the entire permissible cost of participation for a real estate license official to attend a conference, workshop, or educational program if the Board determines the following;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That the conference, workshop, or educational program is qualified pursuant to ยง 2707.5; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That the real- estate license official&amp;#8217;s duties relate in whole or in part to the enforcement of real estate license laws.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2707.5.</num>
    <text>In deciding whether a conference, workshop, or educational program is qualified, the Board shall consider the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The educational objective of the proposed program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The length of the proposed program, the schedule of instruction, location, and anticipated number of participants;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A list of instructors and their credentials; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any other information about the conference, workshop, or program as the Board may require.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 6998 (July 29, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>