<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2906</num>
  <heading>RENEWAL OF LICENSE (ยง 17-2906)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2906.1.</num>
    <text>The Director shall mail a renewal notice to a licensee by first class mail to the licensee&amp;#8217;s address on file with the Director at least forty-five (45) days prior to the expiration of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2906.2.</num>
    <text>The failure of a licensee to receive the renewal notice required by this section does not relieve the licensee of the responsibility of renewing the license in a timely manner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2906.3.</num>
    <text>If the Director does not receive the applicatiion for renewal of a license prior to its expiration, the license shall lapse, but may be reinstated within thirty (30) days of its expiration upon receipt of a completed renewal application and the payment
      of an additional late fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2606.4.</num>
    <text>Reinstatement of a license that has been expired for over thirty (30) days shall be at the discretion of the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2606.5.</num>
    <text>The Director may conduct an on-site inspection, announced or unannounced, of a facility to determine compliance with the Act and this chapter for the purposes of determining whether the facility meets the requirements for renewal of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2906.6.</num>
    <text>The Director shall send a written report of the findings of the inspection to the licensee no later than fifteen (15) days after the conclusion of the inspection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2906.7.</num>
    <text>The Director shall not renew the license of a facility found to have deficiencies which pose a serious threat to the health, safety, or welfare of the animals under the care of the facility or the public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2906.8.</num>
    <text>The Director may require an applicant for renewal to submit a written, signed, and dated plan of correction to abate the deficiencies cited no later than ten (10) days following the receipt of the written report of the findings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2906.9.</num>
    <text>The Director shall renew the license of a facility with no deficiencies or with minor deficiencies that in the opinion of the Director can be corrected within (30) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 6630, 6632 (September 2, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>