<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2304</num>
  <heading>PRELICENSURE EXPERIENCE REQUIREMENTS (ยง 17-2304)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2304.1.</num>
    <text>There is no experience requirement for the Appraisal Trainee classification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.2.</num>
    <text>Applicants for the Licensed Real Property Appraiser shall have two thousand (2000) hours of appraisal experience obtained in no fewer than twelve (12) months.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.3.</num>
    <text>Applicants for the Certified Residential Real Property Appraiser classification shall have two thousand five hundred hours (2500) of appraisal experience obtained during no fewer than twenty-four (24) months of appraisal work.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.4.</num>
    <text>Applicants for the Certified General Real Property Appraiser classification shall have three thousand (3000) hours of appraisal experience obtained during no fewer than thirty (30) months of appraisal work.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.5.</num>
    <text>The Board may treat an applicant&amp;#8217;s hours of appraisal experience as cumulative when applied by the applicant toward achieving the necessary hours of appraisal experience for each classification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.6.</num>
    <text>For the Certified General Real Property Appraiser classification, fifty percent (50%) or one thousand five hundred (1,500) hours of the required three thousand (3,000) hours experience shall be in appraising non-residential real property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.7.</num>
    <text>Experience shall be supported by adequate written appraisal reports or file memoranda that shall be made available to the Board upon request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.8.</num>
    <text>The property address for each appraisal assignment shall be identified in the experience log.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.9.</num>
    <text>An hour of experience means verifiable time spent actively engaging in tasks that are in accordance with acceptable appraisal practice. Qualifying tasks may include activities such as data gathering, property inspection, analysis, report writing,
      or any other activity approved by the Appraisal Qualifications Board. Minimum standards for reports are those standards that are prescribed in Standard 2 of the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice in the edition in effect at the
      time of the reports&amp;#8217; preparation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.10.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in this section, acceptable appraisal practice for experience credit includes appraisal, review appraisals, real estate appraisal consulting, and mass appraisal activities that comply with USPAP and conforms to USPAP Standards 1,
      2, 3, 4, 5, or 6, where the appraiser demonstrates proficiency in appraisal principles, methodology, procedures, and reporting conclusions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.11.</num>
    <text>Appraisal experience shall be verifiable and shall be reported to the Board on a form provided by the Board. A completed form shall include the following information;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Type of property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Date of value;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Address of appraised property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Description of work performed by the trainee/applicant and the scope of the review and supervision by the supervising appraiser;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Number of actual work hours by the trainee/applicant on the assignment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The signature and state certification number of the supervising appraiser if applicable.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.12.</num>
    <text>The following experience credit shall be given for work performed in accordance with the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>75% credit for review appraisals performed under Standard 3 of the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>100% credit for a whole real estate or real property appraisal if the appraiser did 100% of the appraisal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>10% credit under Standard 2.5 of the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice for desk reviews where the review appraiser signs the appraisal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>100% credit for residential form appraisals and commercial form appraisals; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>100% credit for narrative appraisals.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.13.</num>
    <text>Separate appraisal logs shall be maintained for each supervising appraiser if applicable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.14.</num>
    <text>There is no maximum time limit during which experience may be obtained.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2304.15.</num>
    <text>Effective January 1, 2008, work experience must be USPAP compliant and have been earned on or after January 30, 1989.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 8480 (December 10, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 5846 (July 21, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 9991 (September 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>