<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2543</num>
  <heading>PARTNERSHIP AND CORPORATE PRACTICE[COLON] OWNERSHIP AND TRANSFER OF SHARES IN AROFESSIONAL CORPORATION (§ 17-2543)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2543.1.</num>
    <text>The shares of an accountancy corporation shall only be held by the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Corporation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An individual who either:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Holds a certified public accountant’s license pursuant to this chapter and D.C. Official Code § 47-2853.01 et seq. (2001);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Qualifies to hold shares in the corporation pursuant to D.C. Official Code §§ 29-408 (2001) and 47-2853.44 (2001); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An individual who is the personal representative or the estate of a deceased or legally incompetent shareholder.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2543.2.</num>
    <text>If there are two (2) or more shareholders in an accountancy corporation and one (1) of the shareholders dies or becomes a disqualified person as defined in D.C. Official Code § 29-415 (2001), that person’s shares shall be sold and surrendered in accordance
      with D.C. Official Code § 29-416 (2001).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2543.3.</num>
    <text>The restrictions listed in §§ 2543.1 and 2543.2 shall be set forth in the corporation’s by-laws or articles of incorporation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2543.4.</num>
    <text>The share certificates of an accountancy corporation shall contain the following legend: “The ownership and transfer of these shares and the rights and obligations of shareholders are subject to the limitations of the District of Columbia Professional
      Corporation Act.”</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2543.5.</num>
    <text>Each license holder shall notify the Board of Accountancy within thirty (30) days of the occurrence of any change relating to the requirements of §§ 2542 or 2543; including any changes in officers, shareholders, partners, and resident managers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4401 (April 30, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>