<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2201</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION FOR LICENSE (ยง 17-2201)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2201.1.</num>
    <text>Each application for a coal dealer&amp;#8217;s license shall be made on a form prescribed by the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2201.2.</num>
    <text>Each application shall contain the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of applicant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name under which business is conducted;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The form of ownership (individual, partnership, or corporation);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The address of the principal place of business;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>If a partnership, the names and addresses of all partners;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>If a corporation, the names and addresses of officers and directors, the date of incorporation, the jurisdiction of incorporation, and the amount of capital stock;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The number of trucks owned or operated for use of the coal business;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The date of commencement of business under name indicated;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The number of tons of coal sold during the preceding calendar year;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Whether the owner or any partner, officer, or director has any financial interest in any other concern selling coal in the District of Columbia. If so, the name of the concern(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>The location of yards or other storage space used by the business; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Any other information that may be required by the Mayor.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2201.3.</num>
    <text>Each application shall be sworn to before an officer authorized to administer oaths.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order 298,901/1, issued March 7, 1939, 5X DCRR ยง 1.1a.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>