<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2524</num>
  <heading>HEARING PROCEDURES (ยง 17-2524)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2524.1.</num>
    <text>If the person concerned mails a request for a hearing as required in ยง 2520, the Board shall, within twenty (20) days following receipt of a request, notify the person concerned of the time and place of the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2524.2.</num>
    <text>The Board shall hold the hearing not more than ninety (90) days nor less than thirty (30) days following the date of service of the notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2524.3.</num>
    <text>Each hearing before the Board shall be open to the public and all transcripts, filings, and other records associated with the hearing shall be available for public inspection unless sealed by operation of law or by an order issued by the hearing examiner
      or a court of competent jurisdiction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2524.4.</num>
    <text>At each hearing, at least a majority of the members of the Board shall be present to hear the evidence and render a decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2524.5.</num>
    <text>A person entitled to a hearing shall have the following rights:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>To be represented by counsel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>To present all relevant evidence by witnesses and books, papers, and other documents;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>To examine all opposing witnesses on any matter relevant to the issues; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>To have subpoenas issued to compel the attendance of witnesses and the production of relevant books, papers, and documents upon making written request to the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4401 (April 30, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>