<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2920</num>
  <heading>OPERATION OF RADIOLOGY EQUIPMENT (ยง 17-2920)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2920.1.</num>
    <text>A veterinarian using radiology equipment shall require operators to use lead aprons and gloves that are adequate to safeguard operators in accordance with federal and District law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2920.2.</num>
    <text>No person under eighteen (18) years of age shall be permitted to be present in the radiology area during the operation of radiology equipment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2920.3.</num>
    <text>The operator of radiology equipment shall stand well away from the useful beam and the animal during radiographic exposure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2920.4.</num>
    <text>No individual, other than the operator, may be in the X-ray room while exposures are being made unless such individual&amp;#8217;s presence is required.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2920.5.</num>
    <text>A veterinarian shall ensure that all X-ray equipment under his or her control is operated only by individuals competent to use the equipment safely.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2920.6.</num>
    <text>The veterinarian shall provide safety rules to each individual operating X-ray equipment under the veterinarian&amp;#8217;s control, including any restrictions of the operating technique required for the safe operation of the particular X-ray apparatus,
      and require that the operator demonstrate familiarity with these rules prior to using the equipment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2920.7.</num>
    <text>The rules cited under ยง2920.6 shall require all persons operating radiology equipment wear X-ray badges and that these badges be evaluated at least monthly by a qualified radiology laboratory. Records shall be maintained on the premises as to the
      individual badge exposure of all persons monitored.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2920.8.</num>
    <text>When an animal shall be held in position during radiography, mechanical supporting or restraining devices shall be used. If the animal must be held by a person, the person shall be protected by appropriate shielding devices and positioned so that
      no part of his or her body will be struck by the useful beam.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2920.9.</num>
    <text>Field radiograph procedures shall conform to the following specifications:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Protective lead aprons an gloves shall be used;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Employees shall be monitored for exposure; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Equipment shall be maintained in good operating condition.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2920.10.</num>
    <text>Radiographs shall be properly identified, filed for reference, and maintained for three (3) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2920.11.</num>
    <text>Radiology equipment and its use shall be in compliance with chapters 20 to 22 of Title 22 DCMR (Public Health and Medicine) and any other applicable District or federal laws or rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 6630, 6644 (September 2, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>