<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2203</num>
  <heading>COAL TRUCK LICENSE (§ 17-2203)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2203.1.</num>
    <text>Each coal truck license shall contain the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of owner of vehicle;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The coal truck license plate number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The date of issuance and the date of expiration;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The motor vehicle registration number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The year and place of registration;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The make, weight, and motor number of the vehicle;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The serial number of the body of the vehicle, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The coal capacity of the vehicle in cubic feet (ft.3);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The number of permanent compartments in the vehicle and the capacity of each compartment in cubic feet (ft.3); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>The number of sideboards on the vehicle, if any.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2203.2.</num>
    <text>The license shall be in the possession of the operator of the truck or other vehicle when in use, and the driver shall exhibit the license on demand.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2203.3.</num>
    <text>Each application for a coal truck license shall be made under oath on a form prescribed by the Mayor, and shall contain the information required under §2203.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2203.4.</num>
    <text>In the case of any truck or other vehicle that is the subject of a conditional sales agreement, chattel mortgage, or any other document or agreement by virtue of which title remains in the seller pending the payment of the purchase price, the vendee
      or mortgagor shall be deemed the owner of the vehicle so long as the vehicle remains in his or her possession or control.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2203.5.</num>
    <text>Each coal truck or other vehicle for which application for a license is made shall be inspected by an Inspector of Weights, Measures, and Markets, who shall certify on the application as to the correctness of the information contained in the application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order 298,901/1, issued March 7, 1939, 5X DCRR §§ 1.3d, 1.3e, 1.3f, and 1.3g.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>