<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2700</num>
  <heading>CHANGE OF LICENSEE STATUS (ยง 17-2700)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2700.1.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of a properly filed written request on a form approved by the Board and payment of the appropriate fees, the Board may approve the change of status of a real estate broker licensee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.2.</num>
    <text>An individual licensed as a real estate broker may request to change the status of the license to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That of a member, partner, trustee or officer of a firm, partnership, association, business trust or corporation; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That of an associate real estate broker with a firm, partnership, association, business trust, or corporation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.3.</num>
    <text>A change of status shall be effective for any unexpired portion of the licensure term.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.4.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of a licensee&amp;#8217;s completed change of status request, the Board shall issue a new license to the licensee reflecting the change of status but that contains the same expiration date as the original license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.5.</num>
    <text>The Board shall change the status of a real estate broker to an associate broker only if the real estate broker meets the definition of an associate broker established by D.C. Official Code ยง 47-2853.182(d).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.6.</num>
    <text>A firm, partnership, association, business trust, and corporate licensee shall notify the Board, by certified mail, of any change in the status of affiliation with real estate brokers and real estate salespersons.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.7.</num>
    <text>Licenses issued by the Board are not transferable to another person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 6998 (July 29, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>