<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-202</num>
  <heading>EXAMINING BOARD PROCEDURES (§ 17-202)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>202.1.</num>
    <text>An examining board may examine an applicant on the full scope of the license applied for, or the examination may be limited to one (1) or more specific subjects or branches of the occupation for which an application is made.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.2.</num>
    <text>Applicants presenting qualifications in special fields of the electrical trade shall be examined in those fields only. The license issued shall specify any limitations on the face of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.3.</num>
    <text>The board shall report its findings, with any limitations to be specified in the granting of a license, to the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.4.</num>
    <text>Action by the examining board is contingent on the presence of all members. For each member of the board, the Director shall appoint an alternate who shall satisfy the required standards of eligibility. A majority of the board members is sufficient
      to support a decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.5.</num>
    <text>The examination for an occupational license under this chapter shall include questions, diagrams, and other materials that are sufficient to thoroughly demonstrate to the examining board that the applicant has the experience and knowledge of regulations
      and construction methods considered necessary to engage in the class of occupation for which the applicant has filed a license application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.6.</num>
    <text>An applicant who successfully passes a required examination shall be recommended to the Director by the examining board for a license to engage in that business or occupation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.7.</num>
    <text>An applicant who fails to qualify for a license or who fails to report for an examination within twelve (12) months after filing a license application shall forfeit any fees paid in connection with the application unless subject to a refund as provided
      in §221. A new application shall be filed in accordance with this chapter before further consideration can be given to the applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>5J DCRR §§603, 604, 605, 611, 612, 613.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>