<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2501</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION FOR LICENSURE AND EXAMINATION (§ 17-2501)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2501.1.</num>
    <text>Each applicant for a Certified Public Accountant’s license in the District of Columbia by examination, reciprocity, or for an endorsement of a Certified Public Accountant license, shall duly file with the Board an application on a form prescribed
      and provided by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2501.2.</num>
    <text>An application for licensure is not considered filed until the Board receives all supporting documents, the application fee, and, if applicable, the examination fee. Supporting documents may include proof of identity as specified on the application
      form, certification of experience, official transcripts, and proof that the applicant has completed the education requirement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2501.3.</num>
    <text>Each applicant shall attest to the truthfulness of the application before a notary public, who shall affix his or her seal to the application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2501.4.</num>
    <text>Applications to take the Certified Public Accountant Examination shall be made on a form provided by the Board and filed with the Board by the due date specified by the Board in the application form. Applicants filing after the due date may be directed
      by the Board to take the computer-based Uniform CPA Examination during the next available examination window.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2501.5.</num>
    <text>If applicable, the Board or its designee will forward notification of the applicant’s eligibility for the computer-based examination to the National Association of State Boards of Accountancy (NASBA) for inclusion in the National Candidate Database.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2501.6.</num>
    <text>Eligible candidates shall be notified of the time and place of a computer-based examination or shall independently contact the Board or a test center operator identified by the Board to schedule the time and place for the computer-based examination
      at an approved test site. Scheduling reexaminations shall be made in accordance with the rules established by NASBA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2501.7.</num>
    <text>An applicant, upon receiving notification that he or she is eligible to take the CPA examination, shall be classified as a candidate for the purposes of these regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2501.8.</num>
    <text>A candidate who fails to appear for a scheduled Testing Event of the computer-based examination shall forfeit all fees charged for both the application and the examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4401 (April 30, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>