<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2717</num>
  <heading>SUSPENSION OF LICENSE THROUGH AFFILIATION (ยง 17-2717)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2717.1.</num>
    <text>When a real estate broker&amp;#8217;s license is suspended or revoked, all real estate salespersons employed by that real estate broker shall mail their licenses to the Board within fifteen (15) days of the revocation or suspension.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2717.2.</num>
    <text>When a real estate salesperson either is discharged by a real estate broker or terminates his or her employment under a real estate broker both the real estate salesperson and the real estate broker shall notify the Board within fifteen (15) days.
      Within fifteen (15) days of the discharge or termination, the real estate broker shall notify the real estate salesperson that his or her license has been mailed to the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2717.3.</num>
    <text>A real estate salesperson shall not perform any of the acts permitted within the scope of a real estate salesperson license until becoming reemployed with a real estate broker and a license has been reissued by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2717.4.</num>
    <text>In the event of a revocation or suspension of a real estate broker license issued to a firm, franchise, partnership, association, or corporation, the license issued to the principal real estate broker, or any member of a partnership or director or
      officer of an association or corporation, shall be summarily revoked or suspended by the Board unless:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>In a partnership, the connection with the member whose license has been suspended or revoked is severed within the time prescribed and that partner&amp;#8217;s activities with the partnership are terminated; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>In an association or corporation, the director whose license has been suspended or revoked is discharged and has no further participation in association or corporate activities.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 6998 (July 29, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>