<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2309</num>
  <heading>LICENSE RENEWAL (§ 17-2309)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2309.1</num>
    <text>2309.1 At least sixty (60) days prior to the expiration of a license, the Boardhall send a renewal application by first class mail to the holder of a licenset the licensee’s address on record with the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2309.2</num>
    <text>2309.2 A holder of a license shall meet all of the requirements for licenseenewal prior to the issuance of the renewal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2309.3</num>
    <text>2309.3 A holder of a license shall provide the Board a street address for theicensee’s residence, not a post office box, and shall notify the Board inriting of any change to the home or business address within thirty (30) days ofhe change.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2309.4</num>
    <text>2309.4 The failure of a holder of a license to receive the notice required by 2309.1 of this section does not relieve the holder of the responsibility ofenewing the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2309.5</num>
    <text>2309.5 A holder of a license who fails to renew before the expiration date mayenew the license within sixty (60) days after expiration upon paying theequired late fee and submitting proof of having completed the requiredontinuing education prior to
      the expiration date of the license. Upon renewal,he holder shall be deemed to have possessed a valid license during the periodetween the expiration of the license and its renewal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2309.6</num>
    <text>2309.6 If a licensee fails to renew his or her license within sixty (60) daysfter its expiration, the license shall be deemed to have lapsed on the date ofxpiration and the holder shall be required to apply for reinstatement of thexpired license pursuant
      to D.C. Official Code § 47-2853.15 (2005 Repl.) and §308 of chapter 33 (GENERAL RULES: FUNERAL DIRECTORS, VETERINARIANS, INTERIORESIGNERS AND REAL ESTATE APPRAISERS) of this title and pay the requiredeinstatement fee. A licensee may not apply for
      reinstatement if the license haseen expired for five (5) years or more.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2309.7</num>
    <text>2309.7 The Board shall deny a renewal application if the applicant has notompleted the continuing education requirements prior to the expiration date ofhe license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2309.8</num>
    <text>2309.8 Denial of an application for renewal for failure to complete theontinuing education requirements shall require the applicant to complete theontinuing education requirements prior to submitting an application foreinstatement pursuant to § 2310.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 8480 (December 10, 1993); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 5846 (July 21, 2006); as amendedy Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 9991 (September 26, 2008); as amended byotice of Final Rulemaking
        published at 58 DCR 10590, 10596 (December 16, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>