<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2103</num>
  <heading>ELIGIBILITY REQUIREMENTS &amp;#8211; HEALTH (ยง 17-2103)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2103.1.</num>
    <text>Each applicant for certification shall be required to submit a physician&amp;#8217;s certificate stating, to the best of the physician&amp;#8217;s knowledge after examining the applicant, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The applicant is not presently addicted to drugs or alcohol;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The applicant is not suffering from any debilitating mental defect or disorder; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The applicant is not suffering from serious heart disease, severe epilepsy, or other physical defect which might cause substantial loss of control in situations of severe stress.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2103.2.</num>
    <text>When testing for epilepsy or other physical defects which might involve substantial costs to determine, the doctor may rely upon the sworn statement of the applicant, under oath. The doctor must give his or her affirmation to the same effect.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2103.3.</num>
    <text>In cases where certification is requested concurrent with or as a condition of employment with a security agency or an employer, the security agency or employer shall certify the health of the applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2103.4.</num>
    <text>Each applicant shall be required to pass a drug screening administered by the security agency or employer upon initial application and upon application for certification renewal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2103.5</num>
    <text>2103.5</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Security officers shall be subject to reasonable suspicion drug and alcohol testing by the security agency or employer.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this section, the term &amp;#8220;reasonable suspicion&amp;#8221; means the officer is impaired while on duty.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2103.6.</num>
    <text>Security agencies or employers shall immediately notify the Mayor of any unexplained positive tests.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2103.7</num>
    <text>2103.7</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The certification of a security officer who fails a reasonable suspicion drug or alcohol test shall be summarily revoked.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this section, the term &amp;#8220;fails&amp;#8221; means:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The officer&amp;#8217;s blood contained more than .03%, by weight, of alcohol, or the officer&amp;#8217;s urine contained more than .04%, by weight, of alcohol, or that at the time of the test more than .14 micrograms of alcohol were contained in
        1 milliliter of his or her breath, consisting of substantially alveolar air; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The drug test detected the presence of a controlled substance in the officer&amp;#8217;s blood or urine.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>ยง3.6 of the Regulation Establishing Standards for Certification and Employment for Security Officers, Reg. No. 74.31, approved December 1, 1974, 21 DCR 1203 (December 13, 1974); as amended by D.C. ACT 16-465 published at 53 DCR 6726 (August 18,
        2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>