<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2520</num>
  <heading>DENIAL, SUSPENSION, AND REVOCATION OF LICENSES (§ 17-2520)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2520.1.</num>
    <text>Each applicant for examination, and each applicant for or holder of a license, shall be given notice and an opportunity for a hearing by the Board before the Board takes any action that would have one (1) or more of the following effects:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Denial of permission to take an examination for a license for which an applicant has correctly filed and whose application has been accepted as meeting the qualifications for examination;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Denial of a license after an examination for any cause other than failure to pass the examination;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Denial of a license by endorsement to an applicant who meets the qualifications set forth in the Acts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Denial of a license to an applicant who meets the qualifications set forth in these regulations and the Acts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Suspension of a license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Revocation of a license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Reprimand of a licensee; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Refusal to issue a renewal by annual registration for any cause other than failure to pay the prescribed renewal fee or the operation of any other District law that prohibits the Department from issuing a renewal license for reasons unrelated to
        a deficiency in the application or the applicant’s professional conduct.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2520.2.</num>
    <text>When the Board contemplates taking any action of the type specified in § 2520.1(a), (b), or (c), it shall give the applicant a written notice at least fifteen (15) days before the hearing. The notice shall contain the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That the applicant has failed to satisfy the Board as to his or her qualification to sit for examination or to be approved for licensure, as the case may be;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The reasons that the applicant has failed to satisfy the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>That the applicant may obtain a hearing before the Board by making a request for a hearing in the following manner:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Write a letter to the Board that contains a request for a hearing; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Mail the letter by certified mail or deliver the letter in person within twenty (20) days after service of the notice.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>That the applicant may be represented at the hearing by counsel.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2520.3.</num>
    <text>When the Board contemplates taking any action of the type specified in §§ 2520.1(d), (e), (f), (g), or (h), it shall give the person concerned a written notice at least fifteen (15) days before the hearing. The notice shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That the Board has sufficient evidence which, if not rebutted or explained, justifies the Board in taking the proposed action; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That the Board will take the proposed action unless the person concerned requests a hearing before the Board by making a request for a hearing in the following manner:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Write a letter to the Board that contains a request for a hearing; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Mail the letter by certified mail or deliver the letter in person within twenty (20) days after service of the notice.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>That the applicant may be represented at the hearing by counsel.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4401 (April 30, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>