<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-2418</num>
  <heading>FINDINGS AND DECISIONS (§ 17-2418)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2418.1.</num>
    <text>The members of the Board who conduct the hearing shall render their decision, in writing, as soon as practicable, but not later than ninety (90) days after the date of the hearing is completed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2418.2.</num>
    <text>The decision of the Board shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Findings of fact made by the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Application by the Board of the provisions of statutes and this chapter to the facts as found by the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The decision of the Board based upon findings of fact and the application of the law; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A statement informing the person concerned of his or her right to have the Board&amp;#8217;s decision reviewed by the District of Columbia Court of Appeals, and the time within which that judicial review must be sought.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2418.3.</num>
    <text>Within five (5) days after the decision is rendered, the Board shall serve a copy of the written decision upon the person concerned, or his or her attorney of record, either personally or by certified mail.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2418.4.</num>
    <text>If the decision is sent by certified mail, it shall be deemed to have been served on the date contained on the return receipt, or refusal of the person concerned to receive notice or the date of the unsuccessful attempt of the postal service to make
      delivery.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§§ 24.1, 24.2, and 24.3 of Regulation No. 73-13, approved May 24, 1973, 19 DCR 1147, 1152 (June 11, 1973), 25 DCRR §§ 24.1, 24.2, and 24.3.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>