<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-313</num>
  <heading>TERMINATION, SUSPENSION, AND REVOCATION OF LICENSES (§ 17-313)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>313.1.</num>
    <text>A business license issued under this chapter shall terminate if the licensee fails to file and maintain an approved bond as required under this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>313.2.</num>
    <text>Any license issued under this chapter shall be revoked if the surety on the bond becomes unsatisfactory to the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>313.3.</num>
    <text>The Board may revoke any license issued under this chapter when it is shown to its satisfaction that the licensee, in his or her license application or application for renewal, knowingly made a false statement or misrepresentation deemed material
      to the issuance or renewal of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>313.4.</num>
    <text>A contractor&amp;#8217;s or occupational license issued under this chapter may be suspended or revoked by the Board for a violation of this chapter or other District of Columbia law or regulation applicable to the licensed activity; Provided, that
      the Board has held a hearing on the question of the violation after at least ten (10) days notice to the licensee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>313.5.</num>
    <text>On information that any person licensed under this chapter has been convicted of an offense involving moral turpitude, the Board may, within its discretion, deny, revoke, or suspend the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>313.6.</num>
    <text>Upon the application of any person whose license has been denied, revoked, or suspended and upon showing a good cause, the Board may issue or reinstate the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order No. 55.2029, §§9(a)-(d), and 4(h), 5U DCRR, §§1.9(a)-(d) and 1.4(h).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>