<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3106</num>
  <heading>RENEWAL OF LICENSE (§ 17-3106)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3106.1</num>
    <text>3106.1 The Director may send a renewal notice to a licensee by first class mailo the licensee’s address on file with the Director at least forty-five (45)ays prior to the expiration of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3106.2</num>
    <text>3106.2 The failure of a licensee to receive the notice does not relieve theicensee of the responsibility of renewing the licensee in a timely manner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3106.3</num>
    <text>3106.3 A licensee who fails to file an application for renewal prior to thexpiration date of the license may file a late application within thirty (30)ays of the expiration of the license upon payment of the required renewal andate fees, but shall
      not operate the funeral services establishment until theicense renewal is issued.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3106.4</num>
    <text>3106.4 A license that is not renewed within thirty (30) days of its expirationapses.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3106.5</num>
    <text>3106.5 A license to operate a funeral services establishment granted to thestate of a deceased funeral director may not be renewed beyond three (3) yearsfter the death of the funeral director. If the normal term of the license aspecified by section
      3105 would extend beyond the expiration of this period, theerm of the license shall be shortened and the prescribed fee prorated so thathe three (3) limitation is not exceeded.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3106.6</num>
    <text>3106.6 The Director may conduct announced or unannounced onsite inspection of auneral services establishment to determine compliance with the act and thishapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3106.7</num>
    <text>3106.7 The Director shall send a written report of the findings of thenspection to the licensee not later than fifteen (15) days after the conclusionf the inspection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3106.8</num>
    <text>3106.8 The Director shall not renew the license of a funeral servicesstablishment with deficiencies which pose a serious threat to the publicealth, safety, or welfare.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3106.9</num>
    <text>3106.9 The Director may require an applicant for renewal to submit a written,igned, and dated plan of correction to abate the deficiencies cited no laterhan then (10) days following the receipt of the written report of the findings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3106.10</num>
    <text>3106.10 The Director may renew the license of a funeral services establishmentith minor deficiencies that, in the opinion of the Director, can be correctedithin thirty (30) days.</text>
    <text>Source: Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 7853, 7857 (October 23, 1992).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>