<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3209</num>
  <heading>SCOPE OF PRACTICE (ยง 17-3209)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3209.1.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term &amp;#8220;practice of interior design&amp;#8221; means providing or offering to provide consultations, preliminary studies, drawings, specifications, or any related service for the design analysis, programming,
      space planning, or aesthetic planning of the interior of buildings, using specialized knowledge of interior construction, building systems and components, building codes, fire and safety codes, equipment, materials, and furnishings, in a manner
      that will protect and enhance the health, safety, and welfare of the public whether one or all of these services are performed either in person or as the directing head of an organization. The practice of interior design does not include the practice
      of architecture, as defined in D.C. Official Code ยง 47-2853.61.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3209.2.</num>
    <text>This chapter shall not require a license for, or restrict or prohibit an individual from engaging in, any activity or service described in ยง 3209.1 of this chapter, if the individual is a licensed architect engaged in the practice of architecture
      pursuant to the laws of the District of Columbia. An individual licensed as an architect may not utilize the title &amp;#8220;Interior Designer&amp;#8221; unless the individual is also a licensed interior designer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3209.3.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the issuance of a building permit by the Department under the authority of the District of Columbia Construction Codes shall not constitute a license to engage in an activity or service enumerated in ยง 3209.1 of this
      chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 5441 (May 9, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>