<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3318</num>
  <heading>SERVICE (ยง 17-3318)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3318.1.</num>
    <text>A notice, pleading, order, or decision required by this chapter to be served on a respondent shall be served on the respondent or representative designated by the respondent or by law to receive service of papers. If a respondent has appeared through
      counsel, service shall be made upon the counsel of record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3318.2.</num>
    <text>Service on a respondent shall be directed to the last known address of the respondent on file with the Director and shall be completed by one of the following;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>By certified mail, return receipt requested;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>By personal delivery;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>By delivery to the address of respondent, or respondent&amp;#8217;s counsel or agent, on file with the Department, by leaving it at that address with a person of suitable discretion at least sixteen (16) years of age who is employed or resides at
        that address; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>In conformity with an order of a board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3318.3.</num>
    <text>Service on the board, the Director, or the Corporation Counsel shall be directed to the appropriate office and shall be completed by one of the following methods:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>By certified mail, return receipt requested; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>By personal delivery.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3318.4.</num>
    <text>Proof of service, stating the name and address of the person on whom service is made and the manner and date of service, shall be shown by one of the following methods:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If service was effected by certified mail, the return receipt indicating that the document was accepted, refused, or returned unclaimed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If service was effected by personal delivery, the certificate of the server indicating that the document was accepted or refused; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If service was effected pursuant to an order of the board, in the manner provided in that order.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3318.5.</num>
    <text>The date and time of service shall be established as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If service is effected by certified mail, it shall be deemed to have been served on the date and at the time shown on the return receipt that the document was accepted, refused, or returned unclaimed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If service was effected by personal delivery, it shall be deemed to have been served on the date and at the time on the certificate of service indicating that the document was accepted or refused; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If service was effected pursuant to an order of a board, it shall be deemed to have been served on a date and at a time as provided in that order.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3488, 3502 (May 13, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>