<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3207</num>
  <heading>LICENSE RENEWAL (ยง 17-3207)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3207.1.</num>
    <text>A licensed interior designer shall not file an application for renewal if the Board has suspended the applicant&amp;#8217;s license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3207.2.</num>
    <text>At least sixty (60) days prior to the expiration of a license, the Board shall send a renewal application by first class mail to the holder of a license at the licensee&amp;#8217;s known address on record with the board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3207.3.</num>
    <text>A holder of a license shall meet all of the requirements for license renewal prior to the issuance of the renewal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3207.4.</num>
    <text>A holder of a license shall provide the Board a street address for the licensee&amp;#8217;s residence, not a post office box, and shall notify the Board in writing of any change of home or business address within thirty (30) days of the change.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3207.5.</num>
    <text>The failure of a holder of a license to receive the notice required by ยง 3207.2 of this chapter does not relieve the holder of the responsibility of renewing the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3207.6.</num>
    <text>An applicant for renewal of an interior designer&amp;#8217;s license shall submit the renewal application in a timely manner to the Board and shall complete the continuing education requirements before the expiration date of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3207.7.</num>
    <text>Unless an extension of time has been granted pursuant to ยง 3210 of this chapter, the Board shall deny an application for renewal if the applicant has not completed the continuing education requirements prior to the expiration date of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3207.8.</num>
    <text>A holder of a license who fails to renew before the expiration date may renew the license within sixty (60) days after expiration by completing all renewal requirements and paying an additional late renewal fee. Upon renewal, the holder shall be deemed
      to have possessed a valid license during the period between the expiration of the license and its renewal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3207.9.</num>
    <text>If an applicant for renewal of a license fails to submit proof of completion of continuing education requirements or pay the late renewal fee within sixty (60) days after the expiration of the applicant&amp;#8217;s license, the license shall be considered
      to have lapsed on the date of expiration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3207.10.</num>
    <text>Denial of an application for renewal for failure to complete the continuing education requirements shall require the applicant to complete the continuing education requirements prior to submitting an application for reinstatement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 5441 (May 9, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>