<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3300</num>
  <heading>APPLICABILITY (§ 17-3300)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3300.1.</num>
    <text>This chapter shall apply to applicants for and holders of a license to practice a profession or occupation regulated by the following boards:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Board of Funeral Directors for the District of Columbia, established by § 4 of the District of Columbia Funeral Services Regulatory Act of 1984 (D.C. Law 5-84, D.C. Official Code § 3-401 et seq. (2001));</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Board of Veterinary Examiners for the District of Columbia, established by § 6 of the Veterinary Practice Act of 1982 (D.C. Law 4-171, D.C. Official Code § 3-505 (2001));</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Board of Real Estate Appraisers, established by § 2(c) of the Non-Health Related Occupations and Professions Licensure Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Law 16-130, D.C. Official Code § 47-2853.06(g) (2001));</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Barber and Cosmetology Board established by the Second Omnibus Regulatory Reform Amendment Act of 1998, effective April 20, 1999 (D.C. Law 12-261; D.C. Official Code § 47-2853.06 (c) (2001));</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The Board of Professional Engineering established by the Second Omnibus Regulatory Reform Amendment Act of 1998, effective April 20, 1999 (D.C. Law 12-261; D.C. Official Code § 47-2853.06 (c) (2001)); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The Board of Architecture and Interior Designers, established by the Second Omnibus Regulatory Reform Amendment Act of 1998, effective April 20, 1999 (D.C. Law 12-261; D.C. Official Code § 47-2853.06(a) (2001)).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3300.2.</num>
    <text>This chapter shall be supplemented by the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, D.C. Code §§ 1-1501 to 1-1511 (1987 Repl. Vol.), the Acts listed in § 3300.1, and rules promulgated pursuant to those Acts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3300.3.</num>
    <text>Other chapters of this title applying to individual boards promulgated pursuant to an Act listed in § 3300.1 shall prevail over this chapter in the event of a direct and irreconcilable conflict with this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is § 4(1) of the D.C. Funeral Services Regulatory Act of 1984, D.C. Law 5-84, D.C. Code § 2-2803(i) (1987 Supp.), and Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 87-186; § 6(1) of the Veterinary Practice Act of
        1982, D.C. Law 4-171, D.C. Code § 2-2725(m) (1987 Supp.), and Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 86-117; and § 5(3) of the D.C. Interior Designer Licensure Act of 1986, D.C. Law 6-172, D.C. Code § 2.3404(3) (1987 Supp.) and Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 87-277.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3488 (May 13, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 7699(September 12, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 5846(July 21, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published
        at 54 DCR 8783 (September 7, 2007); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 5454(May 9, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>