<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3323</num>
  <heading>CONDUCT OF HEARINGS (ยง 17-3323)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3323.1.</num>
    <text>All hearings before a board shall be open to the public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3323.2.</num>
    <text>At a hearing before a board, at least a majority of the members of a board shall be required to be present to hear the evidence and render a decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3323.3.</num>
    <text>A respondent entitled to a hearing has the following rights:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>To be represented by an attorney in accordance with ยง 3319;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>To present all relevant evidence by means of witnesses and books, papers, and other means;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>To examine all opposing witnesses on any matter relevant to the issues; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>To have subpoenas issued to compel the attendance of witnesses and the production of relevant books, papers, and other evidence, upon making a written request to a board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3323.4.</num>
    <text>A board may, grant or deny a motion for a continuance, and shall deny a motion for a continuance unless the motion:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>In the opinion of a board, set forth good cause for a continuance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Is filed at least two (2) business days before the date on which the hearing is to be held, except for extraordinary and unforeseen reasons such as the sudden illness of a party or a party&amp;#8217;s counsel.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Conflicting engagements of counsel, absence of counsel, or the employment of new counsel may be considered to constitute good cause for a continuance of a hearing only if set forth in a motion filed promptly after notice of the hearing has been given.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3323.6.</num>
    <text>After a hearing, and within time limits established by a board, the parties may submit proposed findings of fact, conclusions of law, and order, and may also submit memoranda of law on issues of law arising during the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3488, 3506 (May 13, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>