<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3301</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION FOR A LICENSE (ยง 17-3301)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3301.1.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a license under an Act listed in ยง 3300.1 shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Submit a completed application on the prescribed form to the board regulating the occupation or profession;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Have the application sworn to before a notary public;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Submit with the application two (2) recent passport-type photographs of the applicant&amp;#8217;s face measuring two inches by two inches (2&amp;#8243; x 2&amp;#8243;);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Pay the required application fee; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Arrange for the submission directly to a board of all required supporting credentials, documents, and materials, including transcripts, references, and test scores.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3301.2.</num>
    <text>A board may not presume qualifications that are not shown on an application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3301.3.</num>
    <text>A board may refuse to act on an application and may require the applicant to submit a new application if the application contains incomplete or evasive information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3301.4.</num>
    <text>If a board determines that an application is not in compliance with ยง 3301.1, the Director shall return the application unless the board determines that the deficiency is minor. If the application is returned, the Director may, in the Director&amp;#8217;s
      discretion, return the application fee to the applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3301.5.</num>
    <text>If a board determines that an application is not in compliance with ยง 3301.1, but that the deficiency is minor, the Director shall send a notice of the deficiency to the applicant. Upon receipt of the notice, the applicant shall correct the deficiency
      within thirty (30) days or other period specified in the notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3301.6.</num>
    <text>If the applicant fails to correct the deficiency within the required period, the application shall lapse and the applicant is required to submit a new application and pay the required fees to be considered for a license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3488, 3489 (May 13, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>