<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3726</num>
  <heading>MASSAGES AND SPA TREATMENTS (ยง 17-3726)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3726.1.</num>
    <text>Except as permitted by ยง3726.1 of this chapter, no barber or cosmetologist (including specialty cosmetology licensees) shall massage any part of a patron&amp;#8217;s body other than the scalp, face, neck, hands, or feet, nor shall any barber or cosmetologist
      perform any spa treatment services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3726.2.</num>
    <text>Cosmetologists and estheticians may massage the skin of a patron&amp;#8217;s body, outside of the locations listed in ยง3726.1, if the massage is directly related to and necessary to performing esthetic skin treatments and does not rise to the level
      of what would ordinarily be considered therapeutic or sports massage under the D.C. Official Code.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3726.3.</num>
    <text>Performing or advertising activities requiring licensure that are outside of the scope of licensure under this chapter is prohibited unless the licensee obtains a license for such activity from the appropriate regulatory agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3726.4.</num>
    <text>No salon or shop shall advertise itself as a spa unless it provides a minimum of one water based treatment that uses water of known composition, is staffed by appropriately trained therapists, has a minimum standard of furnishings, and possesses the
      proper licenses required to offer such facilities. Approved water based treatments use a hydrotherapy unit designed for recreational or therapeutic use, which is not drained, cleaned, or refilled after each use. It may include, but is not limited
      to, units designed for hydro-jet circulation, hot water, cold water, mineral bath, air induction bubbles, or any combination thereof. Common terminology for a spa includes, but is not limited to, therapeutic pool, hydrotherapy pool, whirlpool, hot
      spa, and hot tub.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 7699 (September 12, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>