<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3002</num>
  <heading>LICENSURE AS A FUNERAL DIRECTOR BY EXAMINATION (§ 17-3002)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3002.1.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a license under this section shall furnish proof to the Board that the applicant meets the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Is a graduate of a high school, by arranging for a certified transcript to be sent directly to the Director from the applicant&amp;#8217;s high school;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Is a graduate of an accredited school or college of mortuary science whose course of instruction is not less than twelve (12) months in duration or is composed of not less than eight hundred and forty (840) hours of study, or has successfully completed
        a two (2) year course of study leading to an associate degree in mortuary science, by arranging for a complete, certified transcript to be sent directly to the Director from the applicant&amp;#8217;s school or college of mortuary science; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Has had the following practical experience:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If a graduate of a school or college of mortuary science, at least two (2) years of practical experience as an apprentice funeral director; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If possessing an associate degree in mortuary science, experience of having actually performed the following at a satisfactory level:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Embalmed at least twenty-five (25) human remains; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Conducted or directed at least twenty-five (25) funerals; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Has achieved a passing grade on all three (3) parts of the examination specified in §3002.4.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3002.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a license who meets the requirements of §3002.1(c)(2) shall submit with the appplication a signed statement from each funeral director under whose immediate supervision the apprentice funeral director&amp;#8217;s duties were performed
      which shall contain the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The number of human remains embalmed by the applicant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The number of funerals conducted or directed during the period of apprenticeship served under the supervision of the funeral director;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A professional evaluation of the applicant&amp;#8217;s performance.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3002.3.</num>
    <text>The practical experience required by §3002.1(c) shall include full-time supervised training in all aspects of the business and practice of funeral directing, including the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The care, disposal, and preservation, by embalming or otherwise, of human remains;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The sale of funeral goods and services; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Business management.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3002.4.</num>
    <text>The examination required by §3002.1(d) shall consist of the following three (3) parts:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The national examination approved by the Conference of Funeral Service Examining Boards;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An oral examination developed by the Board; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A practical demonstration developed by the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3002.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall demonstrate receipt of a passing score (as determined by the Conference of Funeral Service Examining Boards) on the national examination part of the examination by arranging with the National Testing Service to forward a copy of
      the applicant&amp;#8217;s results directly to the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3002.6.</num>
    <text>The oral examination part of the examination shall include specific questions on District and federal laws and regulations concerning the practice of funeral directing, including, but not limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Anatomical Board, human tissue banks, and anatomical gifts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Vital statistics and containers for cremated human remains;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Trafficking in dead bodies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Cemeteries and crematories;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Licensing of funeral directors, apprentice funeral directors, and funeral services establishments; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Penalty provisions.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3002.7.</num>
    <text>The practical demonstration part of the examination may include specific oral questions on manual procedures, anatomical considerations and pathological conditions which are relevant to the proper care, preparation and preservation of human remains.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3002.8.</num>
    <text>The Board shall conduct the oral examination and practical demonstration parts of the examination at least two (2) times a year at a date, time, and location determined by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3002.9.</num>
    <text>An applicant who fails to pass a part of the examination, in order to be eligible for a license, shall file a new application with the Director and pay the required fee. An applicant shall not submit a new application within six (6) months of the
      date of the examination part failed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 2904 (April 22, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>