<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3302</num>
  <heading>EXAMINATION (§ 17-3302)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3302.1.</num>
    <text>An applicant desiring to take a national examination shall submit an application in compliance with § 3301.1 to a board regulating the occupation or profession at least ninety (90) days prior to the date of that examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3302.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant who has previously taken that examination shall submit such an application at least sixty (60) days prior to the date of that examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3302.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant may not take the national examination unless the materials required by § 3301.1(e) are received by a board at least forty-five (45) days prior to the date of that examination. The board may, in its discretion, permit an applicant to take
      an examination on a provisional basis although transcripts or other materials have not been received within this period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3302.4.</num>
    <text>A board may, in its discretion, reduce the required periods in §§ 3302.1 and 3302.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3302.5.</num>
    <text>The Director shall notify each applicant of the date, time, and place of the examination and of any examination procedures at least ten (10) business days prior to the date of the examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3302.6.</num>
    <text>The Director shall arrange for suitable space for an examination, designate persons to proctor the examination, and provide for adequate security to ensure the integrity of the examination process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3302.7.</num>
    <text>The Director shall notify each applicant whether the applicant passed the examination as soon as practicable after the Director receives the examination results unless the applicant is notified directly by a testing service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3302.8.</num>
    <text>An applicant who fails an examination may not challenge the results of the examination before a board or the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3302.9.</num>
    <text>If a testing service informs a board in writing that it erroneously determined that an applicant failed an examination and certifies that the applicant passed the examination, the board shall grant a license to the applicant if the applicant has met
      all other qualifications for a license and has paid all required fees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3302.10.</num>
    <text>If an applicant does not take an examination, the Director shall not refund the application fee or credit it to another examination unless a board determines that the applicant was unable to take the examination for good cause. For purposes of this
      subsection, &amp;#8220;good cause&amp;#8221; includes the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Illness or injury; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Death or serious illness of or injury to a member of the applicant&amp;#8217;s immediate family.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3302.11.</num>
    <text>A board, in making a determination under § 3302.10, may require a doctor&amp;#8217;s certificate or other satisfactory evidence of illness or injury.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3988, 3490 (May 13, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>