<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3099</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 17-3099)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3099.1.</num>
    <text>As used in this chapter, the following words and phrases have the meaning ascribed:</text>
    <text>Act &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia Funeral Services Regulatory Act of 1984, D.C. Law 5-84, D.C. Code §§ 2-2801 to 2-2819 (1987 Supp.).</text>
    <text>Board &amp;#8211; Board of Funeral Directors for the District of Columbia, established by the Act.</text>
    <text>Funeral goods &amp;#8211; personal property typically sold or provided in connection with the practice of funeral directing, including caskets, cremation or transportation containers, vaults, grave liners, funeral clothing or accessories, monuments
      and grave markers.</text>
    <text>Funeral services &amp;#8211; services rendered in connection with the practice of funeral directing.</text>
    <text>Funeral services establishment &amp;#8211; a location at which the practice of funeral directing is performed, or when the context requires, the persons or entity which owns the funeral business at that location.</text>
    <text>Next of kin &amp;#8211; the relative and priority of relatives as set forth in § 3012.2.</text>
    <text>Practice of funeral directing &amp;#8211; the care, preservation, disposal, or preparation of human remains for funeral services, burial, cremation, or transportation, including the provision of these services pursuant to a preneed contract.</text>
    <text>Preneed contact &amp;#8211; an agreement under which consideration is to be paid prior to the death of the beneficiary for funeral goods or services to be provided after the beneficiary&amp;#8217;s death.</text>
    <text>Purchaser &amp;#8211; a person responsible for paying consideration for funeral goods and services pursuant to a preneed contract.</text>
    <text>Service fee &amp;#8211; the amount charged for accounting, record keeping and other administrative costs relating to a preneed contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3099.2.</num>
    <text>The definition in § 3399 of chapter 33 of this title are incorporated by reference and apply to this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 2904, 2919 (April 22, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>