<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3704</num>
  <heading>BARBER AND COSMETOLOGY APPRENTICESHIPS (ยง 17-3704)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3704.1.</num>
    <text>Experience gained through a barber and cosmetology apprenticeship completed in barbershops or cosmetology salons shall satisfy the training and experience requirement for purposes of ยง3703.1 if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The apprentice completes classroom training as shown in ยง3704.5 and completes a minimum of two thousand (2000) hours of apprenticeship work experience;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The apprenticeship work experience component is at least twenty (20) hours per week and work experience is not less than one (1) year but lasts no longer than two (2) years from the date of registration;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Working as a &amp;#8220;shampooer&amp;#8221;, by whatever name known, shall not be credited towards the work experience component of the apprenticeship;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The apprenticeship classroom training curriculum has been approved by the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The apprentice is at least eighteen (18) years of age;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The apprenticeship program complies with the requirements of The Office of Apprenticeship Information and Training as set forth in 7 DCMR Chapter 11 (Apprenticeship); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Any information provided to the Office of Apprenticeship Information and Training by the apprentice and instructor must be provided to the Board of Barber and Cosmetology.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3704.2.</num>
    <text>A barber or cosmetology apprenticeship may fulfill only the training and experience requirement of these regulations. Upon completion of the apprenticeship, the apprentice shall sit for examination within six months or lose credit for all training
      and experience gained in the apprenticeship.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3704.3.</num>
    <text>An individual shall be registered by the Board before the individual may serve as an apprentice in a beauty salon or barbershop in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3704.4.</num>
    <text>While registration as an apprentice is in effect, the registration authorizes the individual to learn to practice barbering or cosmetology:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>In a cosmetology salon that holds a salon owner&amp;#8217;s license or a barbershop that holds a barbershop owner&amp;#8217;s license; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Under the supervision of;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If learning the practice of cosmetology, a licensed cosmetology instructor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If learning the practice of barbering, a licensed barber instructor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A licensed instructor may train one apprentice at a time, but the minimum numerical ratio required shall be one (1) apprentice to every three (3) operators employed.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Instructors that rent space pursuant to ยง3720 are not permitted to have apprentices and do not count towards instructor requirements of this section.3704.5 All classroom theory training must be completed before beginning the work experience part
        of the apprenticeship. The classroom training must occur in a Board approved school or continuing education course and shall consist of the following:</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3704.5.</num>
    <text>All classroom theory training must be completed before beginning the work experience part of the apprenticeship. The classroom training must occur in a Board approved school or continuing education course and shall consist of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>500 classroom theory hours for Barbers consisting of the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <text>Shampooing</text>
    <text>15</text>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <text>Scalp Treatments</text>
    <text>10</text>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <text>Chemical Straightening</text>
    <text>150</text>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <text>Personal Hygiene</text>
    <text>50</text>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <text>Ethics, Salesmanship</text>
    <text>25</text>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <text>Courtesy, Conduct, D.C. Law</text>
    <text>50</text>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <text>Anatomy, Physiology, Bacteriology, Pathology, Chemistry, Electricity</text>
    <text>150</text>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <text>Sanitation</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>