<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3122</num>
  <heading>COMPLAINTS; INVESTIGATIONS (§ 17-3122)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3122.1</num>
    <text>3122.1 The Director, on the Director’s initiative or on receipt of a complaint, shall investigate a funeral services establishment if the facts alleged would constitute grounds for disciplinary action under this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3122.2</num>
    <text>3122.2 A person may file a complaint in writing against a funeral services establishment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3122.3</num>
    <text>3122.3 The Director may request a funeral services establishment under investigation to respond in writing to any allegations. If the Director requests such a response, the Director shall inform the funeral services establishment:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That the funeral services establishment is not required to respond to the request;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That a copy of any response may be sent to the complainant, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>That the failure to respond will not be held against the funeral services establishment in any subsequent action based on the investigation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>That any response may be used against the funeral services establishment in a subsequent action.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3122.4.</num>
    <text>The Director may send a copy of the funeral services establishment response, if any, to the complainant and request a written reply within a time period determined by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3122.5</num>
    <text>3122.5 After considering the facts of a particular case, the complaint, if any, and any response, the Director shall take one of the following actions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Initiate an investigation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Issue a notice of intended disciplinary action pursuant to section 3125;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Notify the licensee or applicant that particular deficiencies are required to be corrected within the period stated in the notice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Refer the case to the Office of the Corporation Counsel for prosecution pursuant to section 19 of the act, D.C. Code, section 2-2818; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Dismiss the case</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3122.6</num>
    <text>3122.6 If the Director undertakes an investigation, the Director shall, within sixty (60) days of the completion of the investigation, take one of the actions listed in section 3122.5(b)-(e).</text>
    <text>Source: Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 7853, 7864 (October 23, 1992).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>