<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3731</num>
  <heading>APPROVED CONTINUING EDUCATION PROGRAMS (§ 17-3731)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3731.1</num>
    <text>3731.1 The Board, in its discretion, may approve continuing education programshat contribute to the growth in professional competence of a barber,osmetologist, or specialty cosmetologist, and that meet the other requirementsf this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3731.2</num>
    <text>3731.2 Unless the school or organization offering the program or course isxempt from the accreditation requirements of the Educational Licensureommission, the school or organization shall obtain certification or licensurerom the Educational Licensure
      Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3731.3</num>
    <text>3731.3 Schools or organizations accredited by the Educational Licensureommission that offer continuing education programs or courses shall beonsidered certified for the purposes of this section.</text>
    <text>The Board may approve the following types of continuing education programs, ifhe programs meet the requirements of § 3731.7:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A seminar or workshop;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An educational program given at a conference, institute, academy, or tradehow;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An undergraduate or graduate course given at a college or university,ncluding community or junior colleges; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A distance learning course that has been approved by the Board pursuant to 3731.8.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3731.5</num>
    <text>3731.5 A sponsor of a continuing education program shall submit a completedpplication to the Board at least ninety (90) days prior to the date of theresentation of each program for which the sponsor seeks approval.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3731.6</num>
    <text>3731.6 A sponsor of a continuing education program shall have the burden oferifying whether the Board, pursuant to this section, has approved a programrior to advertising the program as approved by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3731.7</num>
    <text>3731.7 In order to be approved by the Board for continuing education credit, arogram shall meet the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The program shall contribute to the professional competence ofarticipants;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The program shall be directly related to increasing the participants’nowledge and skills in the practice of barbering, cosmetology, or specialtyosmetology;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The stated program objectives shall specify the level of knowledge thearticipant should have attained, or the level of competency the participanthould be able to demonstrate, upon completing the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The program shall be developed by persons qualified in the subject matternd in instructional design;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The program shall be instructed by an individual approved by the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The program content shall be current in its subject matter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>All providers shall have a system of written evaluation by students inhich the program and the instructor are evaluated at the end of each offering.he evaluation form shall accompany the application. Providers shall keep theompleted evaluation forms
        on each program and instructor for four (4) yearsrom the end of the offering; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The sponsor shall agree to allow the Board to conduct an audit of theritten student evaluations at any time within four (4) years of the time that aiven program was offered.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3731.8</num>
    <text>3731.8 Distance learning courses may be approved as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Distance learning courses may be certified by the Board if they provide theoard with appropriate documentation that National Association of Barber Boardsf America (NABBA), National Coalition of Estheticians, Manufacturers/istributors &amp;#038;
        Associations (NCEA), or National-Interstate Council of Stateoards of Cosmetology, Inc. (NIC) certification is in effect, that the distanceearning course meets the content requirements of § 3731.7, and that the courseeets the following additional
        requirements of the Board:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Distance learning courses shall not include pre-licensing educationourses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Distance learning courses shall only include elective continuing educationourses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Distance learning courses shall be a mastery-based format defined asollows:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Having at least one (1) objective;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Having a method for measuring student progress;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Having delivery formats that are interactive, which may include computerased instruction via CD-ROM or the Internet; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Having a delivery format that does not deliver course material in aassive, text only format consisting primarily of questions similar to thoseound on the licensing examination;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Distance learning courses shall be equivalent to in-class continuousnstruction and attendance formats;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Approval under this section shall be revoked immediately in writing shouldertification by NABBA, NCEA, or NIC be discontinued for any reason;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The distance-learning provider shall inform the Board immediately ifertification by NABBA, NCEA, or NIC is discontinued for any reason; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A student shall complete the distance learning course within three (3)onths of the date of enrollment in the course.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3731.9</num>
    <text>3731.9 The Board may approve programs with a minimum of one (1) instructionalour.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3731.10</num>
    <text>3731.10 Any significant changes in program content or program instructor shalle submitted to the Board in writing at least thirty (30) days prior to thehange for Board approval.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3731.11</num>
    <text>3731.11 Approval of a program or course by the Board shall continue until thend of the two (2) year licensing period during which approval is given.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3731.12</num>
    <text>3731.12 A program sponsor shall issue a certificate of successful completion to licensee who completes the program. A program sponsor shall not issue aertificate to a licensee who fails to complete the entire program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3731.13</num>
    <text>3731.13 Within ten (10) days after the completion of the continuing educationrogram, the program sponsor shall forward to the Board a list of allarticipants, which shall include each participant’s license number, name, andddress.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3731.14</num>
    <text>3731.14 A program sponsor shall retain records of the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The outline of the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The program date(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The program location(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The instructor(s); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The number of instructional hours.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3731.15</num>
    <text>3731.15 A program sponsor shall retain a copy of the information required by §731.12 and 3731.13 for a period of at least five (5) years of the time that aiven program was offered.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3731.16</num>
    <text>3731.16 A sponsor of a program that has been approved by the Board for one (1)icense period shall reapply for approval at least ninety (90) days prior to theeginning of the next license renewal period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3731.17</num>
    <text>3731.17 A sponsor of a continuing education program that has been approved byhe Board may apply for renewal of that program by submitting a renewalpplication and, in alternate renewal cycles, providing an updated syllabusutlining the course content.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3731.18</num>
    <text>3731.18 Sponsors or schools offering continuing education programs shall notifyhe Board in writing within thirty (30) days, if certification by NABBA, NCEA,r NIC ceases.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 8353, 8355 (September0, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>