<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3310</num>
  <heading>FALSE OR MISLEADING COMMUNICATIONS AND ADVERTISING (ยง 17-3310)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3310.1.</num>
    <text>A practitioner shall not make or cause to be made a false or misleading communication about the practitioner&amp;#8217;s occupation or profession, or services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3310.2.</num>
    <text>A practitioner shall not falsely represent that the practitioner is certified by, a member of, or otherwise endorsed by, a professional society, association, or other organization.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3310.3.</num>
    <text>A practitioner shall not communicate that the practitioner specializes in a particular field of the practitioner&amp;#8217;s occupation or profession unless the practitioner is in fact a specialist in the particular field or possesses a certificate
      required by the occupation or profession to be a specialist in the field.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3310.4.</num>
    <text>Subject to this section, a practitioner may advertise services through media such as a telephone directory, legal director, newspaper or other periodical, radio or television, or written communication not involving personal contact.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3310.5.</num>
    <text>As used in this section, a communication is &amp;#8220;false&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;misleading&amp;#8221; if it:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Contains a material misrepresentation or omits to make a representation necessary to make the statement considered as a whole not misleading; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Contains an assertion about the practitioner or the practitioner&amp;#8217;s occupation or profession, or services, which cannot be substantiated.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3488, 3496 (May 13, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>