<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3311</num>
  <heading>REFERRAL FOR PROSECUTION OF PERSONS COMMITTING CERTAIN OFFENSES (§ 17-3311)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3311.1.</num>
    <text>A District employee or member of a board shall inform the Director and a board if the employee or board member has good cause to believe that a person has committed one of the following offenses in connection with an application for a license or in
      any proceeding before a board:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Wilfully making a false statement of a material fact under oath at a hearing or other proceeding which the person does not believe is true and in fact is not true in violation of D.C. Code § 22-2511 (1987 Supp.) (perjury);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Wilfully procuring another to commit perjury in violation of D.C. Code § 22-2512 (1987 Supp.) (subornation of perjury);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Wilfully making a false statement of a material fact on an application or other official document that was sworn to before a notary public in violation of D.C. Code § 22-2513 (1987 Supp.) (false swearing); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Wilfully making a false statement in writing of a material fact which statement could reasonably be expected to be relied upon as true in violation of D.C. Code § 22-2514 (1987 Supp.) (false statements).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3311.2.</num>
    <text>If a board or the Director determines that there is good cause to believe that a person committed one of the offenses listed in § 3311.1, the board or Director may refer the matter to the appropriate official for prosecution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3311.3.</num>
    <text>All application forms for a license under this title shall contain a notice stating in substance the following:</text>
    <text>The making of a false statement on this application or on documents required by this application is punishable by criminal penalties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3488, 3496 (May 13, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>