<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3716</num>
  <heading>BARBERSHOPS AND COSMETOLOGY SALONS (ยง 17-3716)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3716.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall operate a salon or shop anywhere in the District without first having obtained the appropriate Business licenses, registrations, and/or certificates.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3716.2.</num>
    <text>No Public Health: Public Accommodations endorsement to operate a salon or shop in the District shall be issued until the Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs has done the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Determined that the applicant has complied with all applicable laws and regulations enforced by the Department;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Verified that the proper barber, cosmetology, or specialty cosmetology professional license required by this chapter has been issued; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Determined that the applicant has paid the applicable fees as established by the Director and has been issued the appropriate Certificate of Occupancy.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3716.3.</num>
    <text>Each salon or shop owner shall apply for and obtain from the Board a salon or shop license that shall be issued without examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3716.4.</num>
    <text>Any owner who intends to manage a salon or shop shall obtain both a salon license and a manager&amp;#8217;s license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3716.5.</num>
    <text>A license shall be obtained for each place of business and the appropriate fee shall be paid for each license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3716.6.</num>
    <text>Each salon or shop owner shall frame the salon or shop license under clear glass or plastic and shall post the license in the salon or shop in plain view of the public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3716.7.</num>
    <text>Each salon or shop shall have one licensed manager on duty at all times during operating hours. In emergencies, where a manager cannot be present, the owner may designate a licensed operator as a temporary manager for up to 48 hours. The owner must
      notify the Board in writing immediately if a licensed operator has been designated as a temporary manager. If the owner cannot have a licensed manager on duty after 48-hours the owner shall petition the Board for an extension. The petition for extension
      shall be submitted in writing via facsimile and regular mail or personal delivery. Extensions are granted at the Board&amp;#8217;s discretion and may be revoked by the Board at any time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 7699 (September 12, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>