<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4715</num>
  <heading>REGISTRATION OF COLLABORATING PHYSICIANS AND ACUPUNCTURISTS (ยง 17-4715)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4715.1.</num>
    <text>An acupuncturist and a physician shall register their collaboration with the Board on the prescribed form.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4715.2.</num>
    <text>An acupuncturist shall file a separate registration form for each physician with whom an acupuncturist collaborates.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4715.3.</num>
    <text>The acupuncturist and collaborating physician shall provide the following information on the registration form:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and telephone number of the collaborating physician and the licensed acupuncturist;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An acknowledgement by the physician that the physician understands and accepts the physician&amp;#8217;s duties to the acupuncture patient and the acupuncturist as set forth in this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An acknowledgement by the acupuncturist that the acupuncturist understands and accepts the acupuncturist&amp;#8217;s duties to the patient and collaborating physician as set forth in this chapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The signatures of the physician and acupuncturists.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4715.4.</num>
    <text>An acupuncturist shall not begin treating a patient until a registration form has been filed with the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4715.5.</num>
    <text>A collaborating physician and the acupuncturist shall give the Board written notice of the termination of an agreement to collaborate within fifteen (15) days following the termination of the agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 7159, 7166 (October 13, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>