<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-400</num>
  <heading>REQUIREMENTS FOR LICENSED OPERATORS (§ 17-400)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>400.1.</num>
    <text>The operation and maintenance of the following equipment shall be exempt from the requirement of having licensed operating engineers:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Vehicles operated under the regulations of the D.C. Public Service Commission or the U.S. Interstate Commerce Commission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Machinery on boats or vessels operated under the regulations of the United States Coast Guard;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Automotive vehicles used solely for traction purposes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Packaged, self-contained air conditioning units;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Automatically operated air conditioning systems with non-toxic and non-inflammable refrigerant and not over a total of one hundred twenty-five (125) compressor horsepower, where no one refrigerant circuit is in excess of seventy-five (75) horsepower;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Automatically operated air conditioning systems using the heat absorption cycle with a non-toxic and non-inflammable refrigerant and not over a total of one hundred twenty-five (125) tons of refrigeration, where no one refrigerant circuit is in
        excess of seventy-five (75) tons, except where a boiler of a type and capacity that requires a licensed engineer is used;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Cold storage and refrigeration systems using non-toxic and non-inflammable refrigerant not in excess of seventy-five (75) compressor horsepower;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Cold storage and refrigeration systems using the heat absorption cycle with a non-toxic and non-inflammable refrigerant not in excess of forty (40) tons;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Cold storage and refrigeration systems using toxic or inflammable refrigerant not in excess of five (5) compressor horsepower;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Cold storage and refrigeration systems using the heat absorption cycle with a toxic or inflammable refrigerant not in excess of three (3) tons;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Automatically operated pumping stations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Hot water heating boilers where the total boiler horsepower is not in excess of seventy-five (75) horsepower [sixteen thousand eight hundred square feet (16,800 ft.2) of water radiation at one hundred fifty degrees Fahrenheit (150° F.)];</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Air compressors having a capacity of less than one hundred ten cubic feet per minute (110 ft.3/min.) at one hundred pounds per square inch (100 lbs./in.2) pressure;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>Motor or engine driven electric generator sets used for welding or lighting not in excess of fifty kilovolt amperes (50 KVA); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>Low pressure steam boilers having gravity or trap returns.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>400.2.</num>
    <text>The operation and maintenance of the following equipment shall be by or under the daily supervision of a steam or other operating engineer who is duly licensed in the proper class by the Board of Examiners for Steam and Other Operating Engineers in
      the District of Columbia:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Boilers and boiler auxiliaries;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Steam engines;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Refrigeration equipment with non-toxic and non-inflammable refrigerant driven by electric motors in excess of twenty-five (25) horsepower;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Refrigeration systems using the heat absorption cycle with non-toxic and non-inflammable refrigerant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Refrigeration systems of five (5) or more compressor horsepower using a toxic or inflammable refrigerant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Refrigeration systems of three (3) or more tons using the heat absorption cycle with a toxic or inflammable refrigerant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Internal combustion engines in excess of twenty-five (25) horsepower; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Air compressors driven by electric motors or internal combustion engines.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is An Act to regulate steam-engineering in the District of Columbia, approved February 28, 1887, 24 Stat. 427, ch. 272. Sec. 2.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§§1.1 and 1.2 of Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order No. 301, 945, 5M DCRR §§1.1 and 1.2.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>