<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4614</num>
  <heading>CONTINUING EDUCATION REQUIREMENTS FOR PRACTICING PHYSICIANS (ยง 17-4614)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4614.1.</num>
    <text>Subject to ยง 4614.2, this section shall apply to actively practicing applicants for the renewal or reinstatement of a license for a term expiring December 31, 2006, and for subsequent terms.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4614.2.</num>
    <text>Physicians actively practicing medicine in the District of Columbia shall submit proof of having completed fifty (50) American Medical Association Physician Recognition Award (AMA/PRA) Category I hours of Board of Medicine approved continuing education
      credit during the two-year period preceding the date the license expires.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4614.3.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, a physician is actively practicing medicine if each calendar year the physician meets the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Maintains a practice of one thousand (1,000) patient-visits per year;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Is employed full-time in medical teaching, research, or administration; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Is employed part-time in medical teaching, research, or administration and maintains a practice of five-hundred (500) patient-visits per year.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4614.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant under this section shall prove completion of required continuing education credits by submitting with the application the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name of the program, its location, and a description of the subject matter covered;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The dates on which the applicant attended the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The hours of credit claimed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Verification of completion of the credits by signature or stamp of the sponsor.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4614.5.</num>
    <text>This section shall not apply to applicants for an initial license by national examination, reciprocity, or endorsement, nor shall it apply to applicants for the first renewal of a license granted by examination. Neither shall the requirement for continuing
      education apply to physicians specifically exempted due to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Hardship;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Disability;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Serious illness;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Service in the United States Congress;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Military service or other circumstances as the Board deems appropriate if supported by adequate documentation acceptable to the Board; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Postgraduate training pursuant to ยง 4611.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4614.6.</num>
    <text>Physicians seeking such an exemption shall submit a written request with appropriate documentation including a description of circumstances sufficient to justify such an exemption.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4614.7.</num>
    <text>A request for an exemption shall be submitted to the Board in a sufficient time period prior to the expiration of the license to receive a determination from the Board as to whether an exemption shall be granted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4614.8.</num>
    <text>A physician suspended for disciplinary reasons shall not be exempt from from the requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 4796 (June 16, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>