<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4810</num>
  <heading>PRACTICE OF CHIROPRACTIC ASSISTANTS (ยง 17-4810)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4810.1.</num>
    <text>A chiropractic assistant may perform the following under the supervision of a licensed doctor of chiropractic:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Case histories, if properly trained by the supervising chiropractor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Diagnostic testing, but must have specialized training by a program or institution listed in section 4807.1;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Therapeutic ancillary procedures, but must have specialized training by a program or institution listed in section 4807.1, and in addition, have specific written instructions from the supervising licensed chiropractor with ancillary privileges;
        and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The taking of x-rays, but must have specialized training by a program or institution listed in section 4807.1, and in addition, have specific written instructions from the supervising licensed chiropractor.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4810.2.</num>
    <text>A chiropractic assistant may not perform the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Any tasks requiring manipulative or adjustment techniques;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The rendering of diagnostic results or interpretations; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Giving treatment advice without direct written orders from the Doctor of Chiropractic.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4810.3.</num>
    <text>A licensed doctor of chiropractic shall be fully responsible for all of the actions performed by the chiropractic assistant during the time of the supervision and is subject to disciplinary action for any violation of the Act or this chapter by the
      person supervised.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 558 (January 27, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 7945 (July 25, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>