<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4402</num>
  <heading>EDUCATIONAL AND EXPERIENCE REQUIREMENTS (§ 17-4402)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4402.1.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § 4403, an applicant for a license shall furnish proof satisfactory to the Board that the applicant holds a baccalaureate or higher degree, with a major in human nutrition, foods and nutrition, dietetics, or food systems management,
      from an institution that was approved by an accrediting body recognized by the Council on Postsecondary Accreditation or the Secretary of the United States Department of Education at the time the applicant graduated, in accordance with § 702(a)
      of the Act, D.C. Code § 2-3307.1(a) (1988 Repl. Vol.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4402.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall have completed an American Dietetic Association approved, planned, continuous, preprofessional experience component in dietetic practice of not less than nine hundred (900) hours under the supervision of a registered dietitian or
      a licensed dietitian.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4402.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant who provides evidence of current registration as a registered dietitian with the Commission on Dietetic Registration of the American Dietetic Association (CDRADA) shall be deemed to have met the education and experience requirements of
      this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4402.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant, including a registered dietitian deemed to be qualified under § 4402.3, shall submit a certified transcript of the applicant&amp;#8217;s educational record(s) and an official certificate of graduation to the Board with the completed
      application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3008 (April 29, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 2747, 2749 (May 4, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>