<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4404</num>
  <heading>NATIONAL EXAMINATION (§ 17-4404)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4404.1.</num>
    <text>To qualify for a license by examination, an applicant shall receive a passing score on the certification examination sponsored by the CDRADA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4404.2.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § 4404.3, an applicant shall submit the applicant&amp;#8217;s examination results, which have been certified or validated by CDRADA, to the Board with the completed examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4404.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant who provides written verification of current registration as a registered dietitian from CDRADA shall be deemed to have met the requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4404.4.</num>
    <text>The Board shall waive the examination requirements of the Act and this section for any applicant who presents evidence satisfactory to the Board of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That the applicant meets the educational requirements of the Act and this chapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That the applicant was employed in the practice of dietetics on a substantially full-time basis for at least three (3) of the five (5) years immediately preceding March 25, 1986.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4404.5.</num>
    <text>The application for the waiver shall be received by the Board prior to March 25, 1988.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4404.6.</num>
    <text>An applicant under this section shall demonstrate the experience qualifications under §§ 4404.4 and 4404.5 by submitting the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Evidence documenting that at least four thousand five hundred (4,500) hours of substantially full-time practice were completed over at least three (3) of the five (5) years immediately preceding March 25, 1986;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Locations and time periods;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Hours of supervised practice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Nature of practice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Performance rating or letter of reference from a supervisor; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The supervisor&amp;#8217;s name and position.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4404.7.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, the term &amp;#8220;substantially full-time&amp;#8221; means at least thirty (30) hours per week.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3008, 3010 (April 29, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 2747, 2749 (May 4, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>