<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4604</num>
  <heading>APPLICANTS EDUCATED IN THE FIFTH PATHWAY PROGRAM (§ 17-4604)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4604.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant a license to practice medicine to an applicant in the Fifth Pathway Program who completed a foreign medical educational program not accredited by one of the accrediting bodies listed in § 4602.3(b) if the applicant does as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Meets all requirements of this chapter except for §§ 4602.1(b), 4602.3, and 4603; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Board that the applicant&amp;#8217;s education and training are substantially equivalent to the requirements of this chapter and the Act in ensuring that the applicant has the proper training, experience,
        and qualifications to practice medicine by submitting the documentation required by this section.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4604.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant under this section shall furnish proof satisfactory to the Board that the applicant meets the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Was a resident of the United States during the period of enrollment in the foreign medical school;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Has successfully completed the didactic curriculum of a foreign medical school listed in a directory of medical schools published by the World Health Organization;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Has attained a passing grade on the Foreign Medical Graduate Examination in the Medical Sciences (FMGEMS);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Has completed one (1) year of individually supervised clinical training under the direction of a medical school accredited by the LCME at a level satisfactory to the Board; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Possesses a valid Fifth Pathway Program certificate.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4604.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant under this section shall arrange for a transcript of the applicant&amp;#8217;s medical education record to be sent directly from the educational institution to the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4604.4.</num>
    <text>If a document required by this chapter is in a language other than English, an applicant shall arrange for its translation into English by a translation service acceptable to the Board and shall submit a notarized translation signed by the translator
      attesting to its accuracy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 5999, 6003 (August 5, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>