<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4912</num>
  <heading>PRESCRIBING DRUGS AND DISPENSING DRUGS (§ 17-4912)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4912.1.</num>
    <text>All physician assistants may perform those duties and responsibilities, including the ordering, prescribing, dispensing, and administration of drugs and medical devices that are delegated by their supervising physician(s). Each prescription must bear
      the name of the supervising physician and physician assistant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4912.2.</num>
    <text>All written prescriptions issued by a physician assistant shall be written on a prescription pad that bears the printed names of the physician assistant and the supervising physician. The physician assistant must include the federal Drug Enforcement
      Agency (DEA) registration number on prescriptions for controlled medications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4912.3.</num>
    <text>Electronic prescription orders must comply with the provisions of Title 22 DCMR, § 1304.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4912.4.</num>
    <text>Physician assistants may request, receive, and sign for professional samples and may dispense professional samples to patients as delegated by a supervising physician and as otherwise consistent with §§ 4912.1 and 4912.6.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4912.5.</num>
    <text>As delegated to do so by a supervising physician, physician assistants may order, prescribe, and dispense legend drugs and controlled substances enumerated in schedules II through V in D.C. Official Code § 48-902.01 et seq. Physician assistants authorized
      to prescribe and/or dispense controlled substances must register with the DEA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4912.6.</num>
    <text>Professional samples of drugs dispensed pursuant to § 4912.4 shall be labeled to show the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and strength of the drug;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The lot and control number; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The expiration date of the drug.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4912.7.</num>
    <text>All drugs dispensed by a physician assistant, except professional samples, shall be labeled to show the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the providing institution;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name of the supervising physician and physician assistant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The name of the patient;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The date dispensed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The name and strength of the drug;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Directions for use;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Cautionary statements, if appropriate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The lot and control number; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The expiration date of the drug.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4912.8.</num>
    <text>A physician assistant who administers, dispenses, or prescribes a prescription drug shall enter a progress note in the patient&amp;#8217;s chart on the date of the transaction and shall include the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Each prescription that a physician assistant orders; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name, strength, and quantity of each drug that a physician assistant dispenses or administers.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 8263, 8271 (December 8, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 8489, 8490 (August 31, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>