<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4914</num>
  <heading>SUPERVISION (ยง 17-4914)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4914.1.</num>
    <text>A physician assistant and a temporary licensed physician assistant shall be under the supervision of a physician at all times during which the physician assistant is working in his or her official capacity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4914.2.</num>
    <text>In an inpatient setting, supervision of a physician assistant shall include, but not be limited to, continuing or intermittent physical presence of the supervising physician with constant availability through electronic communications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4914.3.</num>
    <text>In an outpatient setting, supervision of a physician assistant shall include, but not be limited to, constant availability through electronic communications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4914.4.</num>
    <text>It is the obligation of each team of physician(s) and physician assistant(s) to ensure that the physician assistant&amp;#8217;s scope of practice is identified; that delegation of medical tasks is appropriate to the physician assistant&amp;#8217;s
      level of competence; that the relationship of, and access to, the supervising physician(s) is defined; and that a process for evaluation of the physician assistant&amp;#8217;s performance is established. If the physician assistant is authorized
      to practice in a licensed health care facility or other practice setting, that entity is also responsible for assuring the above through its credentialing and privileging or equivalent process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4914.5.</num>
    <text>More than one physician may enter into a delegation agreement with a physician assistant. For each delegation agreement, the physician assistant and the physician whose name is listed first on the delegation agreement shall each be responsible for
      determining the terms and boundaries of the agreement, for updating the delegation agreement, and for overall quality assurance oversight as set forth in ยง 4914.4. Each physician who signs the delegation agreement is responsible for supervising
      the care of patients whose care the physician has delegated to the physician assistant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4914.6.</num>
    <text>If a physician (due to a planned or unplanned absence) is unable personally to supervise the physician assistant consistent with the delegation agreement and this section, responsibility shall be delegated by the supervising physician to another supervising
      physician whose signature appears on the delegation agreement. If the supervising physician is unable to delegate supervisory responsibility to another supervising physician, the physician assistant may request another supervising physician on the
      delegation agreement to assume the responsibility of supervising. The supervising physician must consent to assume the responsibilities of the absent supervising physician.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4914.7.</num>
    <text>A supervising physician must be a physician licensed in the District and must have accepted responsibility for supervision of the physician assistant by having signed the delegation agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4914.8.</num>
    <text>The names of supervising physician(s) shall be included in the delegation agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4914.9.</num>
    <text>Each physician assistant and one of the supervising physicians listed on the delegation agreement must complete a practice advisory review on a quarterly basis and document the review on a form kept on file in a personnel file at the location in which
      the physician assistant practices.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4914.10.</num>
    <text>A physician shall not supervise more than four (4) physician assistants at one time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 8263, 8272 (December 8, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 8492 (August 31, 2007); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 4201 (March 22, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>