<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4108</num>
  <heading>SETTLEMENT CONFERENCES (ยง 17-4108)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4108.1.</num>
    <text>A board, in its discretion, may request a respondent against whom an action is proposed to attend a settlement conference.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4108.2.</num>
    <text>A board shall serve a request to attend a settlement conference in accordance with ยง4105. The request shall state as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That, if the respondent desires to participate in a settlement conference, the respondent is required to notify the board within ten (10) days or such other reasonable period specified in the notice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That the respondent is entitled to be represented by an attorney;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>That the respondent is not required to attend the settlement conference; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>That the respondent&amp;#8217;s failure to agree to attend a settlement conference will not be held against the respondent at a hearing based on the complaint.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4108.3.</num>
    <text>If a respondent agrees to attend a settlement conference, the board shall notify the respondent, the Director, and the Corporation Counsel, of the date, time, and place of the settlement conference.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4108.4.</num>
    <text>A board may designate a member of the Board, its counsel, or an employee of the Department to participate in a settlement conference on behalf of the board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4108.5.</num>
    <text>The parties at a settlement conference may enter into a negotiated settlement or consent decree that is binding on all parties; Provided, that the settlement or consent decree is approved by the board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4108.6.</num>
    <text>If the board accepts part, but not all, of the proposed negotiated settlement or consent decree, it may request the respondent to attend another settlement conference.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4108.7.</num>
    <text>A respondent who agrees to a negotiated settlement or consent decree that is approved by the board shall waive all of the respondent&amp;#8217;s rights of appeal or reconsideration under this subtitle or the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 5872, 5880 (September 11, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>