<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4304</num>
  <heading>LICENSURE BY EXAMINATION (§ 17-4304)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4304.1.</num>
    <text>To qualify for a license by examination, an applicant shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Meet the education requirements set forth under § 4302.1 or § 4303 of this chapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Receive a passing score on the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The National Board of Dental Hygiene Examination;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Northeast Regional Board (NERB) examination; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The District of Columbia Dental Law Examination.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4304.2.</num>
    <text>To apply for a license by examination, an applicant shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Submit a completed application to the Board on the required forms and include:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s social security number on the application; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Two (2) recent passport-type photographs of the applicant&amp;#8217;s face measuring two inches by two inches (2&amp;#8243; x 2&amp;#8243;) which clearly expose the area from the top of the forehead to the bottom of the chin.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Submit an official certificate of graduation in a sealed envelope from the educational institution(s) to the Board, which shall verify that the applicant meets the educational requirements set forth under § 4302.1 or 4303.1 of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Submit the applicant&amp;#8217;s examination results, which have been certified or validated by the NERB and the National Board of Dental Hygiene Examination;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Pass the District of Columbia Dental Law Examination; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Pay all required fees.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4304.3.</num>
    <text>The passing scores on the examinations shall be those established by the National Board of Dental Hygiene Examination and NERB on each test that forms a part of the examinations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4304.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant who has successfully completed the NERB examination ten (10) or more years prior to the date of receipt by the Board of the application for licensure shall be required to retake the NERB examination, unless the applicant is applying for
      licensure by endorsement pursuant to § 4309 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 797, 789 (January 27, 1980); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 2727, 2748 (May 4, 1990); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 9539 9540 (October 5, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>