<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-409</num>
  <heading>RENEWAL OF EXPIRED LICENSES (ยง 17-409)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>409.1.</num>
    <text>Reexamination and a fee of three dollars ($3) shall be required for the renewal of licenses that have been allowed to lapse.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.2.</num>
    <text>Any person licensed under the authority of this chapter who has failed to renew his or her license prior to its expiration shall be permitted to renew the license without being required to take an examination in connection with the renewal, subject
      to the following conditions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That the license was not revoked during the period for which it was issued, and was in full force and effect on the date of expiration; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That application for renewal has been made in writing within thirty (30) days after the date the license expired.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.3.</num>
    <text>Nothing contained in this section shall be construed as authorizing or permitting the holder of a license which has expired and has not been renewed to continue to operate as if he or she were still holding a valid license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.4.</num>
    <text>Nothing contained in this section shall be construed as waiving any person from engaging in an activity for which a license is required without having first been issued a valid license to engage in that activity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.5.</num>
    <text>If a license expires while the licensee is in service in the U.S. Armed Forces, the license may be renewed without further examination upon presentation of his or her license to the Chairperson of the Board of Examiners within six (6) months after
      discharge with proof that the licensee was serving in the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Coast Guard at the date of the expiration of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>409.6.</num>
    <text>The usual renewal fee of three dollars ($3) shall be paid, and the new expiration date shall be one (1) year from the date of approval by the Chairman of the Board of Examiners. All licenses issued under this section shall expire September 30 of each
      year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>ยง6.1 of Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order No. 301, 945, 5M DCRR ยง6.1.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>