<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4399</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 17-4399)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4399.1.</num>
    <text>As used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Applicant &amp;#8211; a person applying for a license to practice dental hygiene under this chapter.</text>
    <text>Board &amp;#8211; the Board of Dentistry, established by ยง 201 of the Act, D.C. Code ยง 2-3302.1 (1988 Repl. Vol.)</text>
    <text>Dentist &amp;#8211; a person licensed to practice dentistry under the Act.</text>
    <text>Dental hygienist &amp;#8211; a person licensed to practice dental hygiene under the Act.</text>
    <text>Direct supervision &amp;#8211; supervision by a dentist who is in the dental office or treatment facility, personally diagnoses the condition to be treated, personally authorizes the procedures, remains in the dental office or treatment facility while
      the procedures are being performed by the dental hygienist, and evaluates the performance of the dental hygienist before dismissal of the patient.</text>
    <text>General supervision &amp;#8211; supervision based on instructions given by a licensed dentist either in person or by a communications device, but not requiring the physical presence of the dentist on the premises at the time actions are performed.</text>
    <text>NERB &amp;#8211; North East Regional Board of Dental Examiners, Inc.</text>
    <text>NERB Examination &amp;#8211; the examination in dental hygiene offered by the North East Regional Board of Dental Examiners, Inc., or its successor.</text>
    <text>Regional Board &amp;#8211; the examination in dental hygiene offered by the North East Regional Board of Dental Examiners, Inc. or an equivalent national or regional clinical testing agency recognized by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4399.2.</num>
    <text>The definitions in ยง 4099 of chapter 40 of this title are incorporated by reference and are made applicable to this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 787, 795 (January 27, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 9548 (October 5, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>