<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4303</num>
  <heading>APPLICANTS EDUCATED IN FOREIGN COUNTRIES (ยง 17-4303)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4303.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant a license to practice dental hygiene to an applicant who completed an educational program in a foreign country, other than the Dominion of Canada, which program is not recognized by the ADA, if the applicant:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Meets all requirements of this chapter except for ยง 4302.1; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Board that the applicant&amp;#8217;s education and training are substantially equivalent to the requirements of this subtitle and the Act and that the applicant is qualified to practice dental hygiene.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4303.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant under this section, in lieu of meeting the requirements of ยง 4302.1, shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Submit to the Board an official transcript and a copy of the degree or diploma indicating that the applicant has completed a professional program in the field of dental hygiene in any country other than the United States or its territories, or the
        Dominion of Canada; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Submit to the Board proof that the applicant has successfully completed the National Board of Dental Hygiene Examination.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4303.3.</num>
    <text>The Board may interview an applicant under this section to determine whether the applicant&amp;#8217;s education or training meets the requirements of the Act and this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4303.4.</num>
    <text>If a document required by this chapter is in a language other than English, an applicant shall arrange for its translation into English by a translation service acceptable to the Board and shall submit a translation signed by the translator attesting
      to its accuracy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 787, 788 (January 27, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 9539 (October 5, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>