<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4916</num>
  <heading>SUPERVISING PHYSICIAN (ยง 17-4916)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4916.1.</num>
    <text>A physician wishing to supervise a physician assistant must</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be licensed in the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be free from any restriction on his or her ability to supervise a physician assistant that has been imposed by Board disciplinary action; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Maintain a written delegation agreement with the physician assistant. The agreement must state that the physician will exercise supervision over the physician assistant in accordance with any rule adopted by the Board and will retain professional
        and legal responsibility for the care rendered by the physician assistant. The agreement must be signed by the physician and the physician assistant and updated at the time of physician assistant licensure renewal or as needed. The agreement must
        be filed pursuant to ยง 4915.2 with the Board and a copy must be kept on file at the practice site.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4916.2.</num>
    <text>A physician assistant may perform health care tasks as long as the supervising physician is available by electronic communications or has designated a substitute supervising physician. A supervising physician has ultimate responsibility for the medical
      care and treatment given to a patient by a physician assistant to whom the supervising physician has delegated authority to perform health care tasks.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4916.3.</num>
    <text>A licensed physician assistant may, if permissible under the bylaws, rules and regulations of the practice setting, write medical orders, including those for controlled substances, for patients under the care of the physician responsible for his/her
      supervision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4916.4.</num>
    <text>Repealed</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 8263, 8279 (December 8, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 8494 (August 31, 2007); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 4201 (March 22, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>