<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4915</num>
  <heading>DELEGATION AGREEMENT (ยง 17-4915)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4915.1.</num>
    <text>Prior to the physician assistant beginning practice, he or she shall have a written delegation agreement using the form provided by the Board. The delegation agreement shall describe the physician assistant&amp;#8217;s role in the practice and the
      settings in which the supervising physician(s) delegate(s) to the physician assistant the authority to see patients.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4915.2.</num>
    <text>The delegation agreement form must be signed by the supervising physician(s) and physician assistant and be filed by the physician assistant with the Board and kept on file at the primary practice site.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4915.3.</num>
    <text>In the event that there are changes to the delegation agreement, a new agreement form must be signed by the physician and physician assistant and be filed by the physician assistant with the Board and kept on file at the primary practice site.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4915.4.</num>
    <text>If there are changes to the supervising physician(s), the physician assistant must file with the Board a form provided by the Board for additions and deletions to the list of supervising physicians within ten (10) days of the effective date of the
      change.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4915.5.</num>
    <text>If there is a change in the employment status of the physician assistant, or the delegation agreement is otherwise terminated, a termination form provided by the Board must be filed by the first supervising physician listed on the delegation agreement
      with the Board within ten (10) days of the change of employment status of the physician assistant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4915.6.</num>
    <text>A delegation agreement expires automatically upon termination of the employment of a physician assistant. However, termination of employment of a physician assistant does not cause a physician assistant&amp;#8217;s license to expire.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4915.7.</num>
    <text>Whenever it is determined that a physician or physician assistant is practicing in a manner inconsistent with the delegation agreement, the Board may demand modification of the agreement and take disciplinary action as appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4915.8.</num>
    <text>The Board shall maintain the following records regarding physician assistants, which records shall be available for public inspection:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A registry of physician assistants;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A registry of supervising physicians; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A copy of each delegation agreement.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 8263, 8275 (December 8, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 8493 (August 31, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>