<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4699</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 17-4699)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4699.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Applicant &amp;#8211; a person applying for a license to practice medicine under this chapter.</text>
    <text>Board &amp;#8211; the Board of Medicine, established by ยง 203(a) of the Act, D.C. Code ยง 2-3302.3 (1987 Supp.).</text>
    <text>Category I &amp;#8211; structured activities receiving an American Medical Association Physicians Recognition Award (AMA/PRA) that are designated by an organization approved by the Accreditation Council for Continuing Medical Education (ACCME) or
      the American Osteopathic Association (AOA).</text>
    <text>Chronic pain &amp;#8211; a pain state that is persistent.</text>
    <text>Licensed physician &amp;#8211; a physician licensed under the Act.</text>
    <text>Pain &amp;#8211; an unpleasant sensory and emotional experience associated with actual or potential tissue damage or described in terms of such damage.</text>
    <text>Physician &amp;#8211; a person holding a degree in medicine or osteopathy.</text>
    <text>Postgraduate physician &amp;#8211; a person who holds a degree in medicine or osteopathy who is enrolled in a postgraduate clinical training program prior to licensure in any jurisdiction in the United States.</text>
    <text>Substance abuse &amp;#8211; the use of any substance for non-therapeutic purposes or use of medication for purposes other than those for which it is prescribed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4699.2.</num>
    <text>The definitions in ยง 4099 of chapter 40 of this title are incorporated by reference into and are applicable to this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 5999, 6012 (August 5, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 837 (February 10, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 4796, 4798 (June 16, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>