<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4204</num>
  <heading>LICENSURE BY EXAMINATION (§ 17-4204)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4204.1</num>
    <text>4204.1 To qualify for a license by examination, an applicant shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Meet the education requirements set forth under § 4202 of this chapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Receive a passing score on the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Part I and Part II of the examination of the Joint Commission on National Dental Examinations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Northeast Regional Board (NERB) or the American Board of Dental Examiners (ADEX) Examination, which shall include a passing score on the Periodontal Examination; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The District of Columbia Dental Law Examination.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4204.2.</num>
    <text>To apply for a license by examination, an applicant shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Submit a completed application to the Board on the required forms and include:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s social security number on the application; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Two (2) recent passport-type photographs of the applicant&amp;#8217;s face measuring two inches by two inches (2&amp;#8243; x 2&amp;#8243;) which clearly expose the area from the top of the forehead to the bottom of the chin.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Submit an official certificate of graduation in a sealed envelope from the educational institution(s) to the Board, which shall verify that the applicant meets the educational requirements set forth under § 4202 of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Submit the applicant’s examination results, which have been certified or validated by the NERB or the ADEX, whichever is applicable, and the Joint Commission of National Dental Examiners;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Pass the District of Columbia Dental Law Examination; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Pay all required fees.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4204.3.</num>
    <text>The passing scores on the examination shall be those established by the Joint Commission on National Dental Examinations and NERB or ADEX on each test that forms a part of the examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4204.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant who has successfully completed the NERB or the ADEX examination ten (10) or more years prior to the date of receipt by the Board of the application for licensure shall be required to retake the NERB or ADEX examination, unless the applicant
      is applying for licensure by endorsement pursuant to § 4209 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 927, 929 (February 12, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 2747 (May 4, 1990); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 10681 (December 9, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 59 DCR 8527 (July 20, 2012); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 16841 (December 13, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>