<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4714</num>
  <heading>DUTIES OF COLLABORATING PHYSICIAN TO ACUPUNCTURIST (ยง 17-4714)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4714.1.</num>
    <text>A collaborating physician shall give written authorization to the acupuncturist to initiate treatment. The authorization shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A summary of the findings of the physician&amp;#8217;s examination of the patient; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Restrictions, if any, to be placed on the course of acupuncture treatment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4714.2.</num>
    <text>A collaborating physician shall be available to the acupuncturist on a daily basis for consultation by a communication device regarding the patient&amp;#8217;s condition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4714.3.</num>
    <text>A collaborating physician shall designate a physician to be available for consultation in the temporary absence of the collaborating physician and shall notify the acupuncturist of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The telephone number; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The office address of the back-up physician.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4714.4.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this subsection, a collaborating physician shall be considered absent if the collaborating physician:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Travels beyond a thirty (30) mile radius of the District; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Is unable to practice medicine because of illness, injury, attention to personal needs, or other conflict with the requirements of the practice.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4714.5.</num>
    <text>A collaborating physician shall provide written notice to the acupuncturist of the collaborating physician&amp;#8217;s intent to terminate the collaboration prior to terminating the collaboration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 7159, 7165 (October 13, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>