<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4217</num>
  <heading>UNAUTHORIZED PRACTICE (ยง 17-4217)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4217.1.</num>
    <text>A dentist shall not engage in any treatment, therapy, or testing in the District of Columbia that is not:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Within the scope of the practice of dentistry pursuant to D.C. Official Code ยง 3-1201.02(5)(2001);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Commonly used in dental practice in the United States; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Currently taught in United States dental schools or dental residency programs accredited by the American Dental Association Commission on Dental Accreditation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4217.2.</num>
    <text>A dentist shall not perform any extraoral aesthetic or cosmetic procedures in the District of Columbia including but not limited to laser hair removal, skin resurfacing, skin refirming, skin tightening, skin rejuvenation, or injection of substances
      into the body for the purpose of wrinkle-removal, unless he or she:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Holds an active District of Columbia dental license in good standing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Has successfully completed an oral and maxillofacial surgery residency program accredited by the American Dental Association Commission on Dental Accreditation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Only performs aesthetic or cosmetic procedures above the clavicle or within the head and neck region of the body; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Only performs those procedures which are appropriate to his or her training and experience.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4217.3.</num>
    <text>A dentist shall not employ, contract with, supervise, or otherwise aid or assist another individual in the performance of extraoral aesthetic or cosmetic procedures in the District of Columbia including but not limited to laser hair removal, skin
      resurfacing, dermabrasion, skin refirming, skin tightening, skin rejuvenation, or injection of substances into the body for the purpose of wrinkle-removal unless the individual actually performing the procedures meets the requirements set forth
      in ยง 4217.2 of this chapter or is otherwise licensed and authorized under the Act to perform such procedures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4217.4.</num>
    <text>A dentist shall not employ, contract with, supervise, or otherwise aid or assist another individual in the performance of general spa services and procedures in the District of Columbia including but not limited to massage therapy, facials, tooth
      bleaching, cosmetic tattooing, manicures, or pedicures, unless the individually actually performing the procedures is duly licensed or otherwise authorized under applicable District of Columbia law to perform the procedures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 301 (January 9, 2009); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 6989 (August 28, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>