<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4603</num>
  <heading>APPLICANTS EDUCATED IN FOREIGN COUNTRIES (§ 17-4603)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4603.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant a license to practice medicine to an applicant educated in a foreign country who does as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Meets all requirements of this chapter except for §§ 4602 and 4604; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Board that the applicant&amp;#8217;s education and training are substantially equivalent to the requirements of this chapter and the Act in ensuring that the applicant has the proper training, experience,
        and qualifications to practice medicine by submitting the documentation required by this section.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4603.2.</num>
    <text>Repealed</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4603.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant under this section shall furnish proof satisfactory to the Board that the applicant has successfully completed all educational and training requirements to practice medicine in the foreign country in which the medical education was undertaken.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4603.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant under this section shall possess a valid standard certificate from the Educational Commission for Foreign Medical Graduates (ECFMG).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4603.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant under this section shall complete three (3) years of postgraduate clinical training in a program that meets the requirements of § 4602.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4603.6.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall arrange for a certified transcript of the applicant&amp;#8217;s medical education record to be sent directly from the educational institution to the Board or its designees, except as provided by § 4603.8.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4603.7.</num>
    <text>The Board may waive the transcript requirement of § 4603.6 on a showing of extraordinary hardship if the applicant is able to establish by substitute documentation that the applicant possesses the requisite education and degrees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4603.8.</num>
    <text>If a document required by this chapter is in a language other than English, an applicant shall arrange for its translation into English by a translation service acceptable to the Board and shall submit a notarized translation signed by the translator
      attesting to its accuracy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 5999, 6002 (August 5, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 6834 (July 22, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>