<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4014</num>
  <heading>LICENSE OR CERTIFICATE BY RECIPROCITY (ยง 17-4014)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4014.1.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a license or certificate by reciprocity shall furnish proof satisfactory to the board regulating the health occupation of either of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That the applicant is licensed or certified and in good standing as a member of the health occupation for which the applicant seeks a license or certificate in a jurisdiction on the list developed by the board pursuant to ยง4014.3, by submitting
        from the jurisdiction a certificate of licensure or certification in good standing; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Proof of the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>That the applicant is licensed or certified and in good standing as a member of the health occupation for which the applicant seeks a license or certificate in a jurisdiction of the United States with requirements which are substantially equivalent
        to the requirements of the Act, by submitting from the jurisdiction a certificate of licensure or certification in good standing; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>That the jurisdiction in which the applicant is licensed or certified admits members of the health occupation for which the applicant seeks a license or certificate who are licensed or certified by the District in a like manner as the District admits
        members of that health occupation who are licensed or certified in that jurisdiction, by arranging for the jurisdiction to provide to the Board a certificate or other written statement, signed by appropriate officials.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4014.2.</num>
    <text>A board, in its discretion, may deny an application for a license by reciprocity of a person against whom disciplinary action has been taken, or who has been convicted of a crime bearing on the applicant&amp;#8217;s fitness to practice, in another
      jurisdiction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4014.3.</num>
    <text>A board may develop a list of jurisdictions whose requirements for licensure or certification are substantially equivalent to the requirements of the Act and which admit members of the health occupation regulated by the board who are licensed or certified
      in the District in a like manner as the District admits members of that health occupation who are licensed or certified in those jurisdictions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4014.4.</num>
    <text>A board may interview an applicant under this section to determine whether the applicant&amp;#8217;s education, training, or character meets the requirements of the Act and this subtitle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4014.5.</num>
    <text>A board, in its discretion, may grant a provisional license or certification not to exceed ninety (90) days to an applicant who has met the requirements of this subtitle except for the receipt by the board of required certification or other proof
      or licensure or certification in the other jurisdiction; Provided, that the board determines to its satisfaction, by telephone inquiry or other means, that the applicant has a license or certificate in good standing from the jurisdiction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4014.6.</num>
    <text>The Director shall issue a provisional license granted by a board pursuant to ยง4014.5.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 2240 (March 25, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>