<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5402</num>
  <heading>EDUCATIONAL REQUIREMENTS (§ 17-5402)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5402.1.</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, an applicant for a license shall furnish proof satisfactory to the Board in accordance with § 504(n) of the Act, D.C. Official Code § 3-1205.04(n) of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That the applicant has successfully completed a nursing education program leading to licensure as a registered nurse which was approved by the Board or by a nursing board in the United States or U.S. territory with standards determined by the Board
        to be substantially equivalent to the standards in the District; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That the applicant has successfully completed a basic nursing education program in Canada leading to licensure as a registered nurse which was approved by a Canadian Provincial nursing board with standards determined by the Board to be substantially
        equivalent to the standards in the District. The applicant shall:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Furnish proof satisfactory to the Board in accordance with § 504(n) of the Act, D.C. Official Code § 3-1205.04(n), that the applicant&amp;#8217;s education and training are substantially equivalent to the requirements of this chapter and the Act;
        and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If a document required by this chapter is in a language other than English, an applicant shall arrange for its translation into English by a translation service acceptable to the Board and shall submit the translation signed by the translator attesting
        to its accuracy.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 622 (January 20, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 2747, 2751 (May 4, 1990); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 8613 (September 3, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>