<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5708</num>
  <heading>SCOPE OF PRACTICE (ยง 17-5708)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5708.1.</num>
    <text>In addition to the general functions specified in ยง 5700, a nurse-anesthetist may perform all of the functions listed below, to include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Determining the health status of the patient as it relates to the relative risks associated with the anesthetic management of the patient;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Based on history, physical assessment, and supplemental laboratory results, determining appropriate type of anesthesia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Ordering pre-anesthetic medication;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Performing procedures commonly used to render the patient insensible to pain during the performance of surgical, obstetrical, therapeutic, or diagnostic clinical procedures. This shall include ordering and administering:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>General and regional anesthesia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Inhalation agents and techniques;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Intravenous agents and techniques; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Techniques of hypnosis;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Order or perform monitoring procedures indicated as pertinent to the anesthetic health care management of the patient;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Support life functions during anesthesia health care, including inductions and intubation procedures, the use of appropriate mechanical supportive devices, and the management of fluid, electrolyte, and blood component balances;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Recognize and take appropriate corrective action for abnormal patient responses to anesthesia, adjunctive medication, or other forms of therapy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Recognize and treat cardiac arrhythmia while the patient is under anesthetic care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Management of the patient while in the post-anesthesia recovery phase, including post-anesthesia evaluation of the patient, ordering the administration of fluids and drugs, discharging of the patient;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Place peripheral and central venous and arterial lines for blood sampling and monitoring as appropriate; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Such other functions and services the Board deems appropriate upon review and analysis of professional and association literature which articulates scopes and standards for nurse-anesthetist practice.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 3491, 3493 (May 12, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 11751 (December 27, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>