<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5205</num>
  <heading>NATIONAL EXAMINATION (ยง 17-5205)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5205.1.</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, an applicant shall receive a passing score on the required level of the examination sponsored by the Naturopathic Physicians Licensing Examination (NPLEX) basic science examination and clinical science
      examination sections administered by the North American Board of Naturopathic Examiners (NABNE), or other examination approved by the Board of Medicine.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5205.2.</num>
    <text>A passing score on the Part I series of the Basic Science Examination shall be a minimum converted score of seventy-five (75) on each of the five (5) parts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5205.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant who does not achieve a score of at least sixty (60) on each of failed parts shall be required to retake the entire Part I series.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5205.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall take and pass Part II of the Core Clinical Science Examination within ten (10) years of taking Part I of the Basic Science Examination. Failure to take and pass Part II within the ten (10) year period shall result in the applicant
      retaking Part I again.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5205.5.</num>
    <text>A passing score on Part II of the Core Clinical Science Examination shall consist of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Achieving a minimum converted score of at least seventy-five (75) on all eight (8) Part II Core Clinical Science Examinations; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Under the Compensatory Model for Part II Core Clinical Science Series:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Achieving a converted score on the Physical and Clinical Examination of at least seventy-five (75);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Achieving an average converted score on the eight (8) Part II Core Clinical Science Examinations of at least seventy-five (75) with Clinical Add-On Examination scores not being included in the average; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Achieving a converted score for every Part II Core Clinical Science Examination of at least seventy (70).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5205.6.</num>
    <text>Part II Add-On Examinations for Homeopathy, Minor Surgery and Acupuncture shall not be required.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by final rulemaking published at 53 DCR 4799 (June 16, 2006); as amended by final rulemaking published at 54 DCR 6427 (June 29, 2007); as amended by final rulemaking published at 54 DCR 7486 (August 3, 2007 ).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>