<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5411</num>
  <heading>SUPERVISED PRACTICE OF STUDENTS (ยง 17-5411)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5411.1.</num>
    <text>A student may practice registered nursing only in accordance with the Act and this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5411.2.</num>
    <text>A student who is fulfilling educational requirements under ยง 103(c) of the Act, D.C. Official Code ยง 3-1201.03(c), may be authorized to engage in the supervised practice of registered nursing without a District of Columbia license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5411.3.</num>
    <text>Only a registered nurse licensed under the Act, who is an appointed faculty member of the accredited school, college, or university, or a preceptor meeting the qualifications set forth in chapter 56 of this title, shall be authorized to supervise
      the practice of registered nursing by a student.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5411.4.</num>
    <text>A student who practices pursuant to this section shall only practice at a hospital, long-term care facility, a health facility operated by the District or federal government, a health education center, or other health care facility considered appropriate
      by the school, college, or university.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5411.5.</num>
    <text>All supervised practice of a student shall take place under general or immediate supervision of a registered nurse.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5411.6.</num>
    <text>A person who has been denied a license, disciplined, convicted of an offense that bears directly upon his or her fitness to be licensed, or who has such an action pending in the District of Columbia or another jurisdiction shall not practice pursuant
      to this section unless first authorized by the Board in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5411.7.</num>
    <text>A student practicing under this section shall not assume administrative or technical responsibility for the operation of a nursing program, unit, service, or institution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5411.8.</num>
    <text>A student shall identify himself or herself as such before engaging in the supervised practice of registered nursing. A student shall wear a picture identification badge with lettering clearly visible to the client bearing the name of the student
      and the position title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5411.9.</num>
    <text>A student shall not receive compensation of any nature, directly or indirectly, from a client or client&amp;#8217;s family member.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5411.10.</num>
    <text>The appointed supervising faculty member shall be fully responsible for the practice by a student during the period of supervision and may be subject to disciplinary action for violations of the Act or this chapter by the student.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5411.11.</num>
    <text>The Board may deny an application for licensure by, or take other disciplinary action against, a student who is found to have violated the Act or this chapter. The Board may, in addition to any other disciplinary actions permitted by the Act, revoke,
      suspend, or restrict the privilege of the student to practice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 622, 629 (January 20, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 8613 (September 3, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>