<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5102</num>
  <heading>RENEWAL OF LICENSE (ยง 17-5102)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5102.1.</num>
    <text>The holder of a license to practice as an anesthesiologist assistant shall renew his or her license by submitting a completed application on the forms required by the Advisory Committee on Anesthesiologist Assistants and paying the required fees prior
      to the expiration of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.2.</num>
    <text>The Board&amp;#8217;s staff shall mail out applications for renewal at least sixty (60) days prior to the date the license expires.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.3.</num>
    <text>The license holder shall have the burden of notifying the Board if a renewal notice is not received.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.4.</num>
    <text>A license holder shall notify the Board in writing of a change of home or business address within thirty (30) days after the change.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.5.</num>
    <text>A license holder applying for renewal of a license to practice as an anesthesiology assistant shall submit evidence of current national certification or recertification as an Anesthesiologist Assistant &amp;#8211; Certified (AA-C), as applicable,
      by the National Commission for Certification of Anesthesiologist Assistants, or its successor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.6.</num>
    <text>A license holder applying for renewal of a license who fails to submit proof of having completed the requirement as set forth in ยง5102.5 by the date the license expires may renew the license within sixty (60) days after the expiration by submitting
      the required documents and paying the required late fees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.7.</num>
    <text>Upon submitting the required documents and paying the required late fees, the license holder shall be deemed to have possessed a valid license during the period between the expiration of the license and the submission of the required documents and
      fees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.8.</num>
    <text>If a license holder applying for renewal of a license fails to submit proof of completion of the requirements set forth in ยง5102.5 or pay the late fee within sixty (60) days after the expiration of the license holder&amp;#8217;s license, the license
      shall be considered to have lapsed on the date of expiration and the license holder shall thereafter be required to apply for reinstatement of an expired license and meet all requirements and fees for reinstatement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.9.</num>
    <text>The Board may, in its discretion, grant an extension of the sixty (60) day period to renew the license after expiration, if the license holder&amp;#8217;s failure to submit proof of the requirements or pay the late fee was for good cause. As used
      in this section, &amp;#8220;good cause&amp;#8221; includes the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Serious and protracted illness of the license holder;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The death or serious and protracted illness of a member of the license holder&amp;#8217;s immediate family; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Active military deployment pursuant to 17 DCMR ยง 4015.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 91 (January 6, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>