<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5605</num>
  <heading>CONDITIONAL ACCREDITATION (ยง 17-5605)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5605.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may place a nursing program that has failed to meet or maintain the requirements and standards of this chapter on conditional accreditation status.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5605.2.</num>
    <text>Conditional accreditation status denotes that certain conditions must be met within a designated time period for the program to be granted or restored to full accreditation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5605.3.</num>
    <text>The Board may determine the length of time to be allotted, not to exceed two (2) years, for the correction of the deficiencies identified by the Board and to bring the program into compliance with the requirements and standards of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5605.4.</num>
    <text>When the Board determines that a program is substantially out of compliance with the requirements and standards of this chapter, the Board may, in its discretion, prohibit a program that has conditional accreditation status from admitting new students
      until the program has been restored to full accreditation status. The program shall be given notice and an opportunity for a hearing prior to the Board implementing a prohibition against the admittance of new students.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5605.5.</num>
    <text>Under conditional accreditation status, the program may continue to operate while correcting the identified deficiencies and working toward meeting the conditions for full accreditation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5605.6.</num>
    <text>Students who graduate from conditionally accredited programs shall be eligible to take the NCLEX in the District, and upon passing the examination, become licensed in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5605.7.</num>
    <text>If the program fails to meet the specified conditions within the designated time period, the Board may withdraw accreditation and the program shall be removed from the Board&amp;#8217;s list of accredited programs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5605.8.</num>
    <text>The Board shall maintain a list of the programs that are accredited by the Board. The list shall be maintained current on the Department&amp;#8217;s Internet website. The list shall also be compiled and published annually and available to the public
      upon request. The Board may charge a fee for distribution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 7190 (July 23, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 2116 (March 9, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>