<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5403</num>
  <heading>EDUCATIONAL REQUIREMENTS FOR APPLICANTS EDUCATED IN FOREIGN COUNTRIES (ยง7-5403)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5403.1.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a license who completed an educational program in a foreign country, which program was not approved in accordance with ยง 5402.1, shall furnish proof satisfactory to the Board in accordance with ยง 504(n) of the Act, D.C. Official Code
      ยง 3-1205.04(n) of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That the applicant&amp;#8217;s education and training are substantially equivalent to the requirements of this chapter and the Act;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That the applicant successfully completed the Commission on Graduates of Foreign Nursing Schools (CGFNS) examination by submitting a certificate from CGFNS; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>That the applicant has spoken and written competency in English by documenting one of the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Graduation from a nursing program where English was the only language of instruction through the applicant&amp;#8217;s inclusive dates of attendance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Successful completion of the Test of Spoken English (TSE) examination with a passing score of fifty (50);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Successful completion of the International English Language Testing System (IELTS) examination with a passing score of six and one half (6.5) overall with a spoken band score of seven (7.0); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Provide proof that the applicant has completed a total of twelve (12) months of full-time employment in the United States during the two (2) years immediately preceding the date of application.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5403.2.</num>
    <text>If a document required by this chapter is in a language other than English, an applicant shall arrange for its translation into English by a translation service acceptable to the Board and shall submit the translation signed by the translator attesting
      to its accuracy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 622, 623 (January 24, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 8613 (September 3, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>