<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5705</num>
  <heading>NATIONAL EXAMINATION (ยง 17-5705)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5705.1.</num>
    <text>In addition to the requirements in ยง 5701 and ยง 5704, to qualify for a certificate to practice as a certified registered nurse-anesthetist in the District of Columbia, an applicant shall receive a passing score on the national certification examination
      by the Council on Certification of Nurse Anesthetists or any other nationally recognized certifying body accepted by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5705.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall submit proof of having obtained a passing score on the examination by arranging to have official written verification of the certification, or a certified, notarized copy of the examination results, sent directly to the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5705.3.</num>
    <text>A national certification program acceptable to the Board shall provide:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A scope of practice statement that reflects the standards of specialized and advanced nursing practice in the area of certification;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An approval process for the formal programs of study in the area of certification which shall:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be based on measurable objectives that relate directly to the scope of practice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Include theoretical and clinical content directed to the objectives; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Be equivalent to at least one academic year preceptorship which is part of the formal program and shall be included as part of the academic year. Current practice in the area of certification will not be accepted as a substitute for the formal program
        of study.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An examination in the area of certification shall:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Measure the theoretical and clinical content denoted in the scope of practice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Be developed in accordance with generally accepted standards of validity and reliability; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Be open only to registered nurses who have successfully completed the program of study referred to in paragraph (b) of this subsection.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A certification maintenance program.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5705.4.</num>
    <text>The passing score on the certification examination shall be the passing score established by the certifying body administering the examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5705.5.</num>
    <text>The Board shall issue and update a list of nationally recognized certifying bodies accepted by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5705.6.</num>
    <text>Failure to maintain recertification as a certified registered nurse-anesthetist shall result in the loss of status as a licensed nurse-anesthetist.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 3491, 3492 (May 12, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 2747, 2751 (May 4, 1990); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 11751 (December 27, 2002); as amended by Final Rulemaking published
        at 51 DCR 7228 (July 23, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>