<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5602</num>
  <heading>DENIAL OF INITIAL ACCREDITATION (ยง 17-5602)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5602.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may deny initial accreditation for any of the following reasons when it determines that a program will be unable to meet the standards of this chapter:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Board has determined that a program has not met, maintained or will be unable to meet or maintain the requirements and standards of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Failure to hire a nurse administrator who meets the qualifications of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Failure to hire faculty who meet the qualifications of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Noncompliance with the school&amp;#8217;s stated philosophy, program design, objectives or outcomes, or policies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Failure to implement the approved curriculum;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Failure to maintain the required NCLEX pass rate for first-time test takers, if applicable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Failure to submit records and reports to the Board in a timely manner;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Noncompliance with any of the regulations in this chapter; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Other activities or situations, as determined by the Board, that indicate a program is not meeting the legal requirements and standards of this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5602.2.</num>
    <text>The Board shall promptly issue a denial letter to the nursing school notifying it of the Board&amp;#8217;s decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5602.3.</num>
    <text>If initial accreditation is denied, the nursing school may request a hearing before the Board within twenty (20) days from receipt of the denial letter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 7190 (July 23, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 2116 (March 9, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>