<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5003</num>
  <heading>PRACTICE BY REGISTERED NATUROPATHS (§ 17-5003)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5003.1.</num>
    <text>A person registered to practice naturopathy may use the title &amp;#8220;Doctor of Naturopathy&amp;#8221;.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5003.2.</num>
    <text>As required by Section 901 (c) of the Act, all naturopaths who are not licensed to practice medicine under the Act shall provide to all clients or patients a written notice which shall read as follows:</text>
    <text>This notice is provided to you pursuant to D.C. law. I am a registered Doctor of Naturopathy, but I am not a licensed medical doctor and therefore do not practice &amp;#8220;the application of scientific principles to prevent, diagnose and treat physical
      and mental diseases, disorders, and conditions and to safeguard the life and health of any woman and infant through pregnancy and parturition.&amp;#8221;</text>
    <text>An identical notice, in printing of a size to be easily readable, shall be posted in a prominent place in each office or location of practice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5003.3.</num>
    <text>A person registered to practice naturopathy or naturopathic healing under this chapter may counsel individuals and treat human conditions through the use of &amp;#8220;naturally occurring substances&amp;#8221;, forces and agencies as defined herein.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5003.4.</num>
    <text>It shall be unlawful for a naturopath practicing in the District of Columbia to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Falsely lead any person to believe he or she practices medicine as defined in the Act.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Use x-rays, perform surgical procedures, inject any substance into another person by needle, or perform any invasive procedure on another person;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Deliver infants;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Prescribe for or provide to another person any drug, substance or device regulated by the laws of the District or Federal governments or available by prescription only; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>File birth or death certificates or sign claims or authorization for payment of workers’ compensation benefits, Medicare or Medicaid benefits, or benefits provided for health care through other publicly assisted programs.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 6129 (August 14, 1992).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>