<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5516</num>
  <heading>STANDARDS OF CONDUCT (ยง 17-5516)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5516.1.</num>
    <text>A practical nurse shall adhere to the standards set forth in the &amp;#8220;Code of Ethics for Nurses&amp;#8221; as published by the American Nurses Association, as they may be amended or republished from time to time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5516.2.</num>
    <text>A practical nurse shall respect the client&amp;#8217;s right to privacy by protecting confidential information unless obligated or allowed by law to disclose the information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5516.3.</num>
    <text>A practical nurse shall not accept or perform professional responsibilities that the nurse is not competent to perform.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5516.4.</num>
    <text>A practical nurse shall not, after accepting an assignment or responsibility for a client&amp;#8217;s care, and without giving adequate notice to the supervisor so that arrangements can be made for continuation of nursing care by others:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Unilaterally sever the established nurse-client relationship;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Leave a client for a length of time, or in a manner, that exposes the client unnecessarily to risk of harm; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Leave a nursing assignment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5516.5.</num>
    <text>A practical nurse shall know, recognize, and maintain professional boundaries of the nurse-client relationship.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5516.6.</num>
    <text>A practical nurse shall provide nursing services, without discrimination, regardless of the age, disability, economic status, gender, national origin, race, religion, or health problems of the client served.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 701 (January 26, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>