<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5604</num>
  <heading>FULL ACCREDITATION OF ADVANCED PRACTICE NURSING EDUCATION PROGRAMS (ยง 17-5604)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5604.1.</num>
    <text>Following graduation of its first class, a program shall submit to the Board a self-evaluation report of compliance with the provisions of this chapter. The Board may recommend a survey visit for consideration of full accreditation of a program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5604.2.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant full accreditation to a program after the graduation of its first class if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The program has submitted proof to the Board of current accreditation by a national accrediting body approved by the Board; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The program has demonstrated continued ability to meet the standards and requirements of this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5604.3.</num>
    <text>Before granting full accreditation of a program, the Board shall review the application materials and survey reports for granting accreditation of advanced practice nursing education programs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5604.4.</num>
    <text>The Board may recommend deadlines for submission of materials and survey materials.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5604.5.</num>
    <text>In order to maintain full accreditation status, a program with full accreditation status shall maintain:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>All the standards and requirements of this chapter, as they may be amended or republished from time to time; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Accreditation with NLNAC, CCNE, or other accrediting bodies approved by the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5604.6.</num>
    <text>Each program&amp;#8217;s coordinator shall submit a written annual report to the Board on forms provided by the Board, and pay the required review fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5604.7.</num>
    <text>The Board may designate persons to perform announced or unannounced on-site visits to a nursing school.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5604.8.</num>
    <text>Nursing programs that are currently accredited by the Board as of the effective date of these regulations, shall have twelve (1 2) months from the effective date to come into compliance with these regulations.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Board may, at its discretion, grant an extension of the twelve (1 2) month period.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An extension shall not be granted in cases where the Board determines that a program has not made reasonable efforts to comply with the regulations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 7190 (July 23, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 2116 (March 9, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>