<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5210</num>
  <heading>LAWFUL PRACTICE (ยง 17-5210)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5210.1.</num>
    <text>An individual licensed to practice naturopathic medicine under the Act may use the titles &amp;#8220;Doctor of Naturopathic Medicine,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Naturopathic Physician,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Licensed Naturopath,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Naturopathic
      Doctor,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Doctor of Naturopathy,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Naturopath,&amp;#8221; or the initials &amp;#8220;ND.&amp;#8221;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5210.2.</num>
    <text>An individual licensed to practice naturopathic medicine may:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Administer or provide for preventive and therapeutic purposes natural medicines by their appropriate route of administration the following:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Natural remedies;</text>
    <text>Topical medicine;</text>
    <text>Counseling;</text>
    <text>Hypnotherapy;</text>
    <text>Dietary therapy;</text>
    <text>Naturopathic physical medicine;</text>
    <text>Therapeutic devices; and</text>
    <text>Barrier devices for contraception.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Order, perform, review and interpret the results of diagnostic procedures commonly used by physicians in general practice, including:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Physical and orificial examinations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Electrocardiograms;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Diagnostic imaging techniques;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Phlebotomy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Clinical laboratory test and examinations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Physiological function tests.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5210.3.</num>
    <text>An individual licensed to practice naturopathic medicine under this Act shall not:</text>
    <text>Prescribe, dispense, or administer any controlled substances, except those natural medicine authorized by this Act;</text>
    <text>Perform surgical procedures, except for minor office procedures, as defined by rule;</text>
    <text>Use for therapeutic purposes, any device regulated by the United States Food and Drug Administration (FDA) that has not been approved by the FDA;</text>
    <text>Participate in naturopathic childbirth, unless the naturopathic physician:</text>
    <text>Passes a specialty examination in obstetrics or natural childbirth approved by the Advisory Committee on Naturopathic Medicine, the Board of Medicine, or the Mayor, such as the American College of Nurse Midwives Written Examination or an equivalent
      national examination;</text>
    <text>Has a minimum of 100 hours of course work, internship, or preceptorship in obstetrics of natural childbirth approved by the Advisory Committee on Naturopathic Medicine;</text>
    <text>Files with the Department of Health and maintains a written collaboration agreement with a licensed obstetrician who is qualified to perform obstetrical surgery; and</text>
    <text>Has assisted in a minimum of fifty (50) supervised births, including prenatal and postnatal care, under the direct supervision of a licensed naturopathic, medical, or osteopathic physician with training in obstetrics or natural childbirth, at least
      twenty-five (25) of which document the naturopathic physician as the primary birth attendant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5210.4</num>
    <text>5210.4 The Board, in consultation with the Advisory Committee on Naturopathic Medicine, may issue and update annually a formulary listing of natural remedies authorized to be used in the practice of naturopathic medicine.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 4799 (June 16, 2006); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 1469 (February 18, 2011); as corrected by Errata Notice published at 58 DCR 2406 (March 18, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>