<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5409</num>
  <heading>RENEWAL OF A LICENSE (ยง 17-5409)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5409.1.</num>
    <text>A licensee shall renew his or her license by submitting a completed application on the forms required by the Board and paying the required fees prior to the expiration of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5409.2.</num>
    <text>The Board&amp;#8217;s staff shall mail out applications for renewal at least sixty (60) days prior to the date the license expires.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5409.3.</num>
    <text>A licensee shall have the burden of notifying the Board if a renewal notice is not received.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5409.4.</num>
    <text>A licensee shall notify the Board in writing of a change of home or business address within thirty (30) days after the change.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5409.5.</num>
    <text>A licensee applying for renewal shall submit proof as set forth in ยง 5410 of completion of twenty-four (24) contact hours of continuing education in the licensee&amp;#8217;s current area of practice commencing with the renewal period of 2006. Only
      continuing education hours obtained in the two (2) years immediately preceding the application date will be accepted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5409.6.</num>
    <text>A licensee applying for renewal of a license who fails to submit proof of having completed the continuing education requirements by the date the license expires may renew the license within sixty (60) days after the expiration by submitting proof
      pursuant to ยง 5410 and by paying the required late fees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5409.7.</num>
    <text>Upon submitting proof and paying the required late fees, the licensee shall be deemed to have possessed a valid license during the period between the expiration of the license and the submission of the required documents and fees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5409.8.</num>
    <text>If a licensee applying for renewal of a license fails to submit proof of completion of the continuing education requirements, or pay the late fee within sixty (60) days after the expiration of the applicant&amp;#8217;s license, the license shall be
      considered to have lapsed on the date of expiration and the health care professional shall thereafter be required to apply for reinstatement of an expired license and meet all requirements and fees for reinstatement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5409.9.</num>
    <text>The Board may, in its discretion, grant an extension of the sixty (60) day period to renew the license after expiration, if the licensee&amp;#8217;s failure to submit proof of completion of the continuing education requirements or pay the late fee
      was for good cause. As used in this section &amp;#8220;good cause&amp;#8221; includes the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Serious and protracted illness of the licensee; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The death or serious and protracted illness of a member of the licensee&amp;#8217;s immediate family.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5409.10.</num>
    <text>The Board may, in its discretion, waive continuing education requirements for a licensee who submits proof of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Serving as a speaker at an approved continuing education program. The presentation shall have been completed during the period for which credit is claimed; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Being the author or editor of a published periodical, if the periodical has been published or accepted for publication during the period for which credit is claimed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5409.11.</num>
    <text>If a licensee has previously received credit in connection with a particular presentation, the Board shall not grant credit for a subsequent presentation unless the presentation involved either a different subject or substantial additional research
      concerning the same subject.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 8613 (September 3, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>