<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5716</num>
  <heading>SUPERVISED PRACTICE OF APPLICANTS FOR CERTIFICATION BY ENDORSEMENT (ยง 17-5716)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5716.1.</num>
    <text>An applicant may practice nurse-anesthesia only in accordance with the Act and this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5716.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant for certification by endorsement shall be authorized to engage in the supervised practice of nurse anesthesia in the District of Columbia without a District of Columbia certificate if the applicant:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Is currently certified by the Council on Certification of Nurse Anesthesia or a certifying body approved by the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Is currently licensed, in good standing, under the laws of a state or territory of the United States; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Has an initial application pending for certification by endorsement to practice nurse-anesthesia in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5716.3.</num>
    <text>A person who has been denied a certificate, denied a license, disciplined, convicted of an offense that bears directly upon his or her fitness to be licensed, or who has such an action pending in the District of Columbia or another jurisdiction shall
      not practice pursuant to this section unless first authorized by the Board in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5716.4.</num>
    <text>Within five (5) business days after the application for certification by endorsement has been received by the Board&amp;#8217;s staff, the Board&amp;#8217;s staff shall issue a practice letter to the applicant to document that his or her application
      is pending and that he or she is eligible to practice under the Act and this chapter. The practice letter is not renewable and shall expire:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Ninety (90) days from the date of issuance; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Upon receipt of written notice from the Board that the application for certification has been denied, whichever date is the earliest.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5716.5.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of the practice letter, the applicant shall inform employers of the date of expiration of the letter and shall immediately cease the practice of nurse anesthesia on that date or upon receipt of the written notice as set forth in ยง 5716.4.
      The graduate thereafter may practice in any other area for which the graduate is qualified and licensed in the District, until receipt of a certificate to practice nurse anesthesia in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5716.6.</num>
    <text>Only a registered nurse anesthetist certified under the Act, who is a supervisor, shall be authorized to supervise the practice of nurse-anesthesia by an applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5716.7.</num>
    <text>A supervisor shall not supervise more than two (2) applicants at one time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5716.8.</num>
    <text>All supervised practice of an applicant shall take place under general or immediate supervision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5716.9.</num>
    <text>An applicant who practices pursuant to this section shall only practice at a hospital, long-term care facility, a health facility operated by the District or federal government, or other health care facility considered appropriate by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5716.10.</num>
    <text>An applicant practicing under this section shall not assume administrative or technical responsibility for the operation of a nurse-anesthesiology program, unit, service, or institution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5716.11.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall not receive compensation of any nature, directly or indirectly, from a client or client&amp;#8217;s family member, except for a salary based on hours worked under supervision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5716.12.</num>
    <text>The supervisor shall be fully responsible for the practice by an applicant during the period of supervision and may be subject to disciplinary action for violations of the Act or this chapter by the applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5716.13.</num>
    <text>The Board may deny an application for a certificate by, or take other disciplinary action against, an applicant who is found to have violated the Act or this chapter. The Board may, in addition to any other disciplinary actions permitted by the Act,
      revoke, suspend, or restrict the privilege of the applicant to practice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 7228 (July 23, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>