<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5199</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 17-5199)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5199.1.</num>
    <text>As used in this chapter the following terms have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Anesthesiologist Assistant &amp;#8211; a person licensed to practice as an anesthesiologist assistant under the Act</text>
    <text>Anesthesiologist &amp;#8211; a physician who has completed a residency in anesthesiology approved by the American Board of Anesthesiology or the American Osteopathic Board of Anesthesiology and who is currently licensed to practice medicine in the
      District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Assist &amp;#8211; to carry out procedures as requested by the supervising anesthesiologist, provided that the requested procedures are within the anesthesiologist assistant&amp;#8217;s training and scope of practice, is medically directed, and defined
      by the supervising anesthesiologist in conformance with acceptable standards for anesthesia care and, approved by the hospital or ambulatory surgical facility medical staff.</text>
    <text>Board &amp;#8211; the Board of Medicine, established by § 203(a) of the Act, D.C. Code § 3-1202.03(a)(1) (2001).</text>
    <text>Committee &amp;#8211; the Advisory Committee on Anesthesiologist Assistants, established by § 203 (c-1) of the Act. D.C. Official Code § 3-1202.03(c-1) (2001). Immediately available 7 means the supervising anesthesiologist is:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Present in the building or facility in which anesthesia services are being provided by assistant; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Able to directly provide assistance to the anesthesiologist assistant in providing anesthesia services to the patient in accordance with the prevailing standards of</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Acceptable medical practice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The American Society of Anesthesiologists&amp;#8217; guidelines for best practice of anesthesia in a care team model; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any additional requirements established by the Board of Medicine through a formal rulemaking process.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Supervision &amp;#8211; directing and accepting responsibility for the anesthesia services rendered by an anesthesiologist assistant in a manner approved by the Board of Medicine.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5199.2.</num>
    <text>The definitions in § 4099 of chapter 40 of this title and the Act are incorporated by reference into and are applicable to this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 91 (January 6, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>