<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5206</num>
  <heading>CONTINUING EDUCATION REQUIREMENTS (§ 17-5206)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5206.1.</num>
    <text>Subject to § 5206.2, this section shall apply to applicants for the renewal, reactivation, or reinstatement of a license for a term expiring February 28, 2008.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5206.2.</num>
    <text>This section shall not apply to applicants for an initial license by examination, reciprocity, or endorsement, nor shall it apply to applicants for the first renewal of a license granted by examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5206.3.</num>
    <text>A continuing education credit shall be valid only if it is part of a program or activity approved by the Board in accordance with § 5207.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5206.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant for renewal of a license shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Have completed thirty (30) hours of approved continuing education credit during the two (2) year period preceding the date the license expires;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Attest to completion of the required continuing education credit on the renewal application form; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Be subject to a random audit.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5206.5.</num>
    <text>To qualify for a license a person in inactive status within the meaning of § 511 of the Act, D.C. Official Code § 3-1205.11 (2001) for five (5) years who submits an application to reactivate a license shall submit proof pursuant to § 5206.8 of having
      completed fifteen (15) hours of approved continuing education credit in the year immediately preceding the date of the application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5206.6.</num>
    <text>To qualify for a license, a person in inactive status within the meaning of § 511 of the Act, D.C. Official Code § 3-1205.11 (2001) for more than five (5) years who submits an application to reactivate a license shall submit proof pursuant to § 5206.8
      of having completed approved continuing education credit in the year immediately preceding the date of the application as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Thirty (30) hours of approved continuing education credit; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>One hundred sixty (160) hours within a sixty (60) day period of professional practice under the supervision of a naturopathic physician.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5206.7.</num>
    <text>To qualify for a license, an applicant for reinstatement of a license shall submit proof pursuant to § 5206.8 of having completed approved continuing education credit in the year immediately preceding the date of the application as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Thirty (30) hours of approved continuing education credit; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>One hundred sixty (160) hours within a sixty (60) day period of professional practice under the supervision of a naturopathic physician.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5206.8.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § 5206.10, an applicant under this section shall prove completion of required continuing education credits by submitting with the application the following information with respect to each program:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the sponsor of the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name of the program, its location, a description of the subject matter covered, and the names of the instructors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The dates on which the applicant attended the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The hours of credit claimed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Verification by the sponsor of completion, by signature or stamp.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5206.9.</num>
    <text>Beginning with the 2008 renewal period, the Board shall conduct a random audit of continuing education credits at the completion of each renewal period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5206.10.</num>
    <text>Applicants for renewal of a license shall only be required to prove completion of the required continuing education credit by submitting proof pursuant to § 5206.8 if requested to do so as part of the random audit, or if otherwise requested to do
      so by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by final rulemaking published at 53 DCR 4799 (June 16, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>