<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5406</num>
  <heading>LICENSURE BY RE-ENTRY PROGRAM (ยง 17-5406)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5406.1.</num>
    <text>A health professional who fails to apply for reinstatement of a District of Columbia registered nursing license within five (5) years after the license expires, and who is not currently licensed to practice registered nursing under the laws of a state
      or territory of the United States, may apply for licensure to practice registered nursing in the District of Columbia under licensure by re-entry program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5406.2.</num>
    <text>To apply for licensure by re-entry program, an applicant shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Submit a completed application to the Board on the required forms and include:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s social security number on the application; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Two (2) recent passport-type photographs of the applicant&amp;#8217;s face measuring two inches by two inches (2&amp;#8243; x 2&amp;#8243;) which clearly exposes the area from the top of the forehead to the bottom of the chin.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Submit proof of completion of a re-entry program approved by the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Submit any other required documents; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Pay all required fees.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5406.3.</num>
    <text>An application that remains incomplete for ninety (90) days or more from the date of submission shall be considered abandoned, and closed by the Board. The applicant shall thereafter be required to reapply, comply with the current requirements for
      licensure, and pay the required fees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 622, 625 (January 20, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 8613 (September 3, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>