<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-5610</num>
  <heading>ADVANCED PRACTICE NURSING EDUCATION PROGRAMS (ยง 17-5610)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5610.1.</num>
    <text>This section shall apply to advanced practice nursing education programs that prepare students for practice as nurse-anesthetists, nurse-midwives, nurse-practitioners, or clinical nurse specialists.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.2.</num>
    <text>An advanced practice nursing program shall operate within, or be affiliated with, an accredited college or university that is authorized to award graduate degrees or post-graduate degrees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.3.</num>
    <text>A college or university desiring initial accreditation of an advanced practice program shall submit a proposal to the Board as set forth. in ยง 560l.l(b) to establish an advanced practice nursing education program that prepares students for practice
      as nurse-anesthetists, nurse-midwives, nurse-practitioners, or clinical nurse specialists.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.4.</num>
    <text>To be eligible for accreditation, the advanced practice program shall be at the graduate or post-graduate level.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.5.</num>
    <text>There shall be a program coordinator who shall, with the participation of the faculty, be responsible for the planning, implementation, and evaluation of the advanced practice program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.6.</num>
    <text>The program coordinator shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be a registered nurse, licensed in good standing in the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Have a District of Columbia certificate to practice as an advanced practice nurse in a specialty appropriate to the type of program being administered;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Have a minimum of a master&amp;#8217;s degree in nursing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Have educational preparation or experience, in teaching and curriculum development or administration at the graduate level;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Have a minimum of two (2) years of clinical experience as an advanced practice nurse; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Have current knowledge of nursing practice at the advanced practice nurse level.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.7.</num>
    <text>The faculty shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be registered nurses licensed and in good standing in the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Have a minimum of a master&amp;#8217;s degree in nursing or certification; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Be qualified through academic preparation to teach the subject assigned and shall meet the standards for faculty appointment by the governing institution.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.8.</num>
    <text>Faculty responsible for clinical management courses or involved in clinical teaching and supervision shall in addition to the requirements of ยง 5610.7:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be licensed or certified in the state in which they practice, to practice as an advanced practice nurse in a specialty appropriate to the type of program being taught;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Have a minimum of two (2) years of clinical experience as an advanced practice nurse; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Maintain clinical practice within the advanced role and specialty.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.9.</num>
    <text>There shall be written personnel policies for nursing faculty and clinical instructors that are in keeping with accepted educational standards and which encourage continuing professional growth and development.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.10.</num>
    <text>The program of study shall be:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>At least the equivalent of one academic year, as determined by the governing institution;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A minimum of five hundred (500) supervised clinical hours, with a minimum of fifty (50) minutes constituting an hour;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Developed and implemented by the program coordinator and faculty through an organizing framework which reflects the philosophy or mission statement of the advanced nursing education program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Sequentially and logically organized to facilitate student attainment of the knowledge, skills, attitudes, and abilities necessary to achieve the program objectives or outcomes for graduates at that level; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Based on sound educational principles.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.11.</num>
    <text>The curriculum content shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Didactic and clinical learning experiences necessary to meet the program goals and outcomes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Concepts and principles critical to advanced practice nursing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Professional and legal implications of the nurse in the advanced practice role;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Knowledge and skills relevant to practice in the area of specialty;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Theoretical and clinical role preparation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Clinical major courses in the specialty area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A practicum, preceptorship, or internship to integrate essential content and the clinical major courses; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Separate, advanced level academic courses in:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Pharmacotherapeutics;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Assessment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Pathophysiology or psychopathology; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Diagnosis and management of problems within the specialty area.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.12.</num>
    <text>For clinical nurse specialist programs, the program shall also meet the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Qualify the graduate for a master&amp;#8217;s degree in nursing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Have a curriculum that contains a minimum of nine (9) semester credit hours, or the equivalent, in a specific clinical major; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Have clinical major courses that include didactic content and offer clinical experiences in a specific clinical specialty or practice area.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.13.</num>
    <text>The faculty shall develop and implement a written plan for evaluation of the total program and shall provide for student participation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.14.</num>
    <text>The data from the evaluation plan shall be utilized for continuous program improvement and shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Evaluation time intervals;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Student evaluation of their classroom and clinical experiences and recommendations for improvement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Measurements of graduate satisfaction regarding the adequacy of the nursing program to prepare them for the scope of their practice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Evaluation of the graduates by their employers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Faculty and student evaluation of the program&amp;#8217;s clinical placements and agencies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Evaluation of the students and faculty by the clinical facilities utilized for clinical placements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Trending graduation rates;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Evaluation of the methods and tools used to measure the students&amp;#8217; cognitive, affective, and psychomotor achievement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Evaluation of the program objectives or outcomes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Evidence that the program is meeting its objectives or outcomes as well as the changing needs of nursing and its community;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Recommendations and a planned course of action for program improvement and the correction of identified deficiencies; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Evidence that prior recommendations and evaluation findings have been acted upon.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.15.</num>
    <text>Students shall be provided didactic instruction in correlation with the related clinical learning experiences.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.16.</num>
    <text>A clinical instructor shall not supervise more than six (6) students while in the clinical setting and the actual number of students assigned per instructor shall be based on the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The acuity of the patients needs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The objectives of the learning experience;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The class level of the students;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The physical placement of the students;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The instructor&amp;#8217;s teaching methods; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The requirements established by the clinical agency.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.17.</num>
    <text>The faculty shall be responsible and accountable for managing clinical learning experiences of students.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.18.</num>
    <text>Supervised clinical practice must include the opportunity to provide pharmacological and non-pharmacological management of diseases and problems considered within the scope of practice of the advanced practice nurse&amp;#8217;s specialty and role.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.19.</num>
    <text>The faculty shall develop written objectives for each clinical course to be used as a guide for the selection of clinical agencies and student placements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.20.</num>
    <text>The students shall be assigned only to facilities that provide students with opportunities to achieve the goals of the program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.21.</num>
    <text>The program shall ensure that its student practice sites contracts with clinical agencies are maintained current and specify the expectations and responsibilities of the parties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.22.</num>
    <text>The program shall develop and implement evaluation methods and tools to be used for measuring students&amp;#8217; cognitive, affective, and psychomotor achievement to assure satisfactory progression.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.23.</num>
    <text>Clinical preceptors may be used to enhance clinical learning experiences after a student has received clinical and didactic instruction in the specific area or course.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.24.</num>
    <text>When clinical preceptors are used, the following conditions shall be met:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The criteria for selecting a preceptor shall be in writing and shall include the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The method of selecting clinical preceptors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The plans for orientation of clinical preceptors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The clinical objectives or outcomes of the preceptorship; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A system for monitoring and evaluating the student&amp;#8217;s learning &amp;#8216; experiences.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The designated faculty member shall retain responsibility for the student&amp;#8217;s learning experiences and meet periodically with the clinical preceptor and the student to monitor and evaluate the student&amp;#8217;s learning experiences.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.25.</num>
    <text>The designated faculty member shall be readily available, either directly or by a communication device, when students are in the clinical area.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5610.26.</num>
    <text>The clinical preceptor shall have the following minimum qualifications:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Current licensure, in good standing, in the state in which they are providing the preceptorship, at or above the level for which the student is preparing, which shall include physicians;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be licensed or certified in the state in which they practice, to practice in a specialty appropriate to the type of program being taught, or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Have a minimum of two (2) years of clinical experience;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Maintain clinical practice within the role and specialty; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Have a philosophy of health care congruent with that of the nursing program.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 7190 (July 23, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 2116 (March 9, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>