<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6999</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 17-6999)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6999.1.</num>
    <text>As used in this chapter, the following terms shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Applicant &amp;#8211; a person applying for a license to practice psychology under this chapter.</text>
    <text>Board &amp;#8211; the Board of Psychology, established by §211 of the Act, D.C. Code §2-3302.11 (1987 Supp.).</text>
    <text>Continuing education – an ongoing process consisting of formal learning activities that: (1) are relevant to psychological practice, education and science; (2) enable psychologists to keep pace with emerging issues and technologies; and (3) allow
      psychologists to maintain, develop and increase competencies to improve services to the public and enhance contributions to the profession.</text>
    <text>General supervision &amp;#8211; the supervision in which the supervisor is available to the supervisee either in person or by a communications device.</text>
    <text>Good cause &amp;#8211; serious illness of the applicant; the death or serious illness of a member of the applicant&amp;#8217;s immediate family; or other cause sufficient to the Board.</text>
    <text>Immediate supervision &amp;#8211; supervision in which the supervisor is physically with the supervisee and either discussing or observing the supervisee&amp;#8217;s practice.</text>
    <text>Psychologist &amp;#8211; a person licensed to practice psychology under the Act, unless the context requires otherwise.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6999.2.</num>
    <text>The definitions in §4099 of chapter 40 of this title are incorporated by reference into and are applicable to this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 2921, 2932 (April 22, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 6019, 6024 (July 31, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>