<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6107</num>
  <heading>RECERTIFICATION (ยง 17-6107)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6107.1.</num>
    <text>Recertification of a trained medication employee shall be required every two (2) years, and shall include verification of a Board-approved twelve (12) hours of in- service training in pharmacology or medication administration and the supervisory registered
      nurse&amp;#8217;s verification of the trained medication employee&amp;#8217;s continued adequacy of performance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6107.2.</num>
    <text>Recertification applications shall be submitted to the Board before the expiration of the current certification and shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be signed by the trained medication employee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Include the supervisory registered nurse&amp;#8217;s written verification of the trained medication employee&amp;#8217;s continued adequacy of performance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Include documentation verifying successful completion of twelve (12) hours of board approved in-service training; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Be accompanied by the required registration fee.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6107.3.</num>
    <text>The Board shall recertify an applicant upon receiving a complete recertification application, proof of the applicant&amp;#8217;s continued competence, and the appropriate registration fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 2581 (March 23, 2001); as amended by Emergency Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 3071 (April 18, 2003) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 6464 (August 8, 2003) [EXPIRED];
        as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 9242 (October 31, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>