<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6411</num>
  <heading>PRACTICE OF OPTOMETRY BY STUDENTS (ยง 17-6411)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6411.1.</num>
    <text>A student may perform actions which require a license as an optometrist only in accordance with the Act and this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6411.2.</num>
    <text>Only a student fulfilling the education requirements under ยง103(c) of the Act, D.C. Code ยง2-3301.3 (1987 Supp.) and ยง6402 shall be authorized to practice under this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6411.3.</num>
    <text>Only an optometrist or ophthmologist may supervise practice by students under this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6411.4.</num>
    <text>A student may practice only under the general or immediate supervision of an optometrist or ophthalmologist who is available in person on the premises, but who need not be physically present in the room at the time the student practices.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6411.5.</num>
    <text>For at least ten percent (10%) of supervised practice during any one (1) month period, a supervising optometrist or ophthalmologist shall be physically with the student and either discussing or observing the student&amp;#8217;s practice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6411.6.</num>
    <text>A supervising optometrist or ophthalmologist shall review a student&amp;#8217;s optometric examination findings before a patient leave the office.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6411.7.</num>
    <text>A student shall see patients on a randomly selected basis without bias toward a particular type of patient care, such as Medicare, Medicaid, or union contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6411.8.</num>
    <text>A student shall identify himself or herself as a student before performing actions of an optometrist.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6411.9.</num>
    <text>A supervising optometrist or opthalmologist shall sign all prescriptions for eyeglasses or contact lenses.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6411.10.</num>
    <text>A supervising optometrist or ophthalmologist is fully responsible for all supervised practice by a student during the period of supervision, and is subject to disciplinary action for any violation of the Act or this chapter by the student.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6411.11.</num>
    <text>A student shall not receive compensation of any nature, directly or indirectly, from a patient, except for a salary based on hours worked in the training program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6411.12.</num>
    <text>A student shall be subject to all of the applicable provisions of the Act and this subtitle. The Board may deny an application for a license by, or take other disciplinary action against, a student who is found to have violated the Act or this subtitle,
      in accordance with chapter 41 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6411.13.</num>
    <text>If the Board finds that a student has violated the Act or this subtitle, the Board may, in addition to any other disciplinary actions permited by the Act, revoke, suspend, or restrict the privilege of the student to practice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 4494, 4500 (June 17, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>