<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6706</num>
  <heading>CONTINUING EDUCATION REQUIREMENTS (§ 17-6706)
    <text>Subject to § 6706.2, this section shall apply to applicants for the renewal,</text>
    <text>reactivation, or reinstatement of a license for a term expiring on or afterJanuary 31, 2013, and for subsequent terms.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <num>6706.2</num>
    <text>6706.2 This section shall not apply to applicants for the first renewal of aicense.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6706.3</num>
    <text>6706.3 A continuing education credit shall be valid only if it is approved byhe Board in accordance with § 6707.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6706.4</num>
    <text>6706.4 To qualify for a license, an applicant for renewal of a license shall:</text>
    <text>Have completed four (4) continuing education units or forty (40) credit hours ofpproved continuing education credit during the two (2) year period immediatelyreceding the date the license expires, which shall include not more than two2) continuing
      education units or twenty (20) credit hours of approvedontinuing education credits earned through internet courses;</text>
    <text>Attest to completion of the required continuing education units or credits onhe renewal application form; and</text>
    <text>Be subject to a random audit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6706.5</num>
    <text>6706.5 A licensee who is selected to participate in the Board’s continuing</text>
    <text>education audit shall, within thirty (30) days after receiving notice of the</text>
    <text>selection, submit proof pursuant to § 6706.8 of having completed the required approved continuing education credits during the two (2)-year period immediately preceding the date the license expires.</text>
    <text>To qualify for a license, a person in inactive status, within the meaning of §11 of the Act (D.C. Official Code § 3-1205.11(2007 Repl.)) for five (5) yearsr less who submits an application to reactivate a license shall submit proofursuant to §  6706.7
      of having completed the following within the two (2)ear period preceding the date of the application for reactivation of thatpplicant’s license:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Four (4) continuing education units or forty (40) credit hours of approvedontinuing education credits; and</text>
    </level>
    <text>An additional two (2) continuing education units or twenty (20) credit</text>
    <text>hours of approved continuing education credit for each additional year thathe applicant was in inactive status beginning with the third year; provided,hat the maximum total number of units and credits required under paragraphs (a)nd (b) of this subsection
      shall not exceed ten (10) continuing education unitsr one hundred (100) hours.</text>
    <text>To qualify for a license, a person in inactive status, within the meaning of §11 of the Act (D.C. Official Code § 3-1205.11(2007 Repl.)) for more than five5) years who submits an application to reactivate a license shall submit proofursuant to § 6706.9
      of having completed the following within the two (2) yeareriod preceding the date of the application for reactivation of thatpplicant’s license:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Four (4) continuing education units or forty (40) credit hours of approvedontinuing education credits;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An additional two (2) continuing education units or twenty (20) credit</text>
    </level>
    <text>hours of approved continuing education credit for each additional year thathe applicant was in inactive status beginning with the third year provided,hat the maximum total number of units and credits required under paragraphs (a)nd (b) of this subsection
      shall not exceed ten (10) continuing education unitsr one hundred (100) hours; and</text>
    <text>Proof of achieving a rating of “Sufficiently Qualified” on the Federationf State Boards of Physical Therapy’s Practice Review Tool, or of successfulompletion of a Board-approved reentry course.</text>
    <text>To qualify for a license, an applicant for reinstatement of a license that has</text>
    <text>expired pursuant to § 512(b) of the Act (D.C. Official Code §-1205.12(b)(2007 Repl.)) shall submit proof pursuant to § 6706.9 of havingompleted:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Four (4) continuing education units or forty (40) credit hours of approved continuing education credits within the two (2) year periodreceding the date of the application for reinstatement; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An additional two (2) continuing education units or twenty (20) creditours of approved continuing education credit for each additional year thathe license was expired beginning with the third year; provided, that theaximum total number of units
        and credits required under paragraphs (a) andb) of this subsection shall not exceed ten (10) continuing education unitsr one hundred (100) hours.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Except as provided in § 6706.10, an applicant under this section shall proveompletion of the required continuing education credits by submitting with thepplication the following information with respect to each program for whichontinuing education
      credit is claimed, and shall maintain for a period of ateast five (5) years the following information with respect to each program:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the sponsor of the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name of the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The location of the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A description of the subject matter covered in the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The names of the program instructors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The dates on which the applicant attended the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The hours of credit claimed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Verification by the sponsor of completion, by signature or stamp.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Applicants for renewal of a license shall only be required to prove completionf the required continuing education credits by submitting proof pursuant to §706.9 if requested to do so as part of the random audit, or if otherwiseequested to do so by
      the Board.</text>
    <text>An applicant for renewal of a license who fails to submit proof of having</text>
    <text>completed the continuing education requirements by the date the license expiresay renew the license up to thirty (30) days after the expiration by submittinghis proof and paying the required additional late fee.</text>
    <text>Upon submission of proof and payment, the applicant shall be deemed to haveossessed a valid license during the period between the expiration of theicense and the submission of the proof and payment.</text>
    <text>If an applicant for renewal of a license fails to submit proof of completion ofontinuing education requirements or pay the late fee within thirty (30) daysfter the expiration of the applicant’s license, the license shall beonsidered to have lapsed
      on the date of expiration.</text>
    <text>The Board may, in its discretion, grant an extension of the thirty (30) dayeriod to renew after expiration if the applicant’s failure to submit proof ofompletion was for good cause. For the purposes of this section, good causencludes the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Serious and protracted illness of the applicant; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The death or serious and protracted illness of a member of thepplicant&amp;#8217;s immediate family.</text>
    </level>
    <text>If an applicant for renewal of a license fails to submit proof of havingompleted continuing education requirements by the date the license expires, thepplicant shall not practice until his or her license has been renewed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 945, 948 (February 12, 1988); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 6451 (June 25, 2004); as amendedy Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 2600 (March 14, 2008); as amended byotice of Final Rulemaking
        published at 58 DCR 5462 (July 1, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>