<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6203</num>
  <heading>APPLICANTS EDUCATED IN FOREIGN COUNTRIES (§ 17-6203)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6203.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant a license to practice nursing home administration to an applicant who completed an educational program in a foreign country, which program is not accredited in accordance with § 6202.1(a), if the applicant meets the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Meets all requirements of this chapter except for § 6202.1(a); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Board that the applicant&amp;#8217;s education and training are substantially equivalent to the requirements of this subtitle and the Act in ensuring that the applicant is qualified to practice nursing home
        administration, by submitting the documentation required by § 6203.2.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6203.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant under this section shall, in lieu of meeting the educational accreditation requirement of § 6202.1(a), submit one of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Proof satsifactory to the Board that the applicant has received the required degree from a foreign institution that was accredited, at the time the degree was conferred, by an accrediting body recognized by the national government of the country
        in which the institution is located; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A certification from a private education evaluation service approved by the Board that the applicant&amp;#8217;s foreign education is substantially equivalent to the education required by this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6203.3.</num>
    <text>If a document required by this chapter is in a language other than English, an applicant shall arrange for its translation into English by a translation service acceptable to the Board and shall submit a translation signed by the translator attesting
      to its accuracy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3774, 3779 (May 20, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>