<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6504</num>
  <heading>LICENSE BY EXAMINATION (§ 17-6504)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6504.1.</num>
    <text>To qualify for a license by examination, an applicant shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Meet the education requirements set forth under § 6502.1(a), or if the applicant was educated in a foreign country meet the requirements set forth under § 6503;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Meet the training requirements set forth under § 6502.1(b);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Receive a passing score on each test that forms a part of the NAPLEX, or its successor, which shall be the passing score as determined by the NABP;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Receive a passing score on each test that forms a part of the MPJE for the District of Columbia, or its successor, which shall be the passing score as determined by the NABP;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Be at least 18 years of age; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Have not been convicted of a crime involving moral turpitude or bearing directly on the fitness of the applicant to be licensed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6504.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant for licensure by examination, who has previously successfully completed the NAPLEX and/or MPJE examinations, but has not actively engaged in the practice of pharmacy in the United States or was not actively licensed as a pharmacist in
      the United States for more than five (5) years prior to the date of the application, in addition to the other requirements of this section, shall be required to do the following in order to qualify for licensure under this section:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Retake the NAPLEX and MPJE examinations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Register as a Pharmacy Intern and complete an additional pharmacy internship consisting of seven hundred and fifty (750) hours of independent pre-licensure professional practice under the supervision of a licensed pharmacist who uses the standards
        for pre-licensure professional practice described in § 6502 of this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6504.3.</num>
    <text>To apply for a license by examination, an applicant shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Submit a completed application to the Board on the required forms and include:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s social security number on the application. If the applicant does not have a social security number, the applicant shall:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Submit with the application a sworn affidavit, under penalty of perjury, stating that he or she does not have a social security number; and</text>
    </level>
    <text>(ii) Submit proof acceptable to the Board that he or she is legally authorized to be in the United States, such as a Certificate of Citizenship or Naturalization, Resident Alien Card, a valid foreign passport with a visa; or a work permit card from
      the Department of Homeland Security (I-766 or I-688B).</text>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Two (2) recent passport-type photographs of the applicant&amp;#8217;s face measuring two inches by two inches (2&amp;#8243; x 2&amp;#8243;), which clearly expose the area from the top of the forehead to the bottom of the chin; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>One (1) clear photocopy of a U.S. government-issued photo ID, such as a driver&amp;#8217;s license, as proof of identity.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Submit official transcripts mailed directly to the Board of Pharmacy from each educational institution in a sealed envelope, which shall verify that the applicant has successfully completed an educational program in the practice of pharmacy meeting
        the requirements set forth in § 6502.1(a) of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Applicants educated in foreign countries must submit a Foreign Pharmacy Graduate Examination Committee (FPGEC) Certification in lieu of an official transcript;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Submit proof acceptable to the Board that the applicant has successfully completed a pharmacy internship meeting the training requirements set forth in § 6502.1(b) of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Pay all required fees; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Successfully complete the NAPLEX and MPJE examinations after receiving Board approval to take the examinations and arrange to have the score results sent directly to the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6504.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant under this section shall successfully complete the NAPLEX and MPJE examinations within one (1) year from the date the Board approves the applicant to take the examinations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6504.5.</num>
    <text>If an applicant under this section fails to successfully complete the NAPLEX and MPJE examinations within one (1) year from the date of approval to take the exam, his or her application shall be considered abandoned and closed by the Board. The applicant
      shall thereafter be required to reapply, comply with the current requirements for licensure, and pay the required fees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6504.6.</num>
    <text>If an applicant under this section fails to successfully complete the NAPLEX and MPJE examinations within one (1) year from the date of approval to take the exam, then upon expiration of his or her supervised practice letter, the applicant shall immediately
      cease from practicing. Thereafter the applicant may perform only the duties of a pharmacy technician until the applicant receives a pharmacist license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6504.7.</num>
    <text>A supervised practice letter issued under this section is not renewable and shall expire one (1) year from the date of issuance.</text>
    <text>as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 8091 (May 4, 1994); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 4330 (April 18, 2008).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6243, 6246 (September 1, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 2747, 2753 (May 4, 1990);</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>