<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6604</num>
  <heading>APPLICANTS EDUCATED IN FOREIGN COUNTRIES (§ 17-6604)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6604.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant a license to practice professional counseling to an applicant who completed an educational program in a college or university in a foreign country which is not accredited in accordance with § 6602 if the applicant meets the following
      requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Meets all requirements of this chapter except for § 6602.1; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Board that the applicant&amp;#8217;s education and training are substantially equivalent to the requirements of this chapter and the Act in ensuring that the applicant is qualified to practice professional
        counseling by submitting the documentation required by § 6604.2 of this section.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6604.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant under this section shall, in lieu of meeting the requirements of § 6602.1, submit one of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Proof satisfactory to the Board that the applicant has received a master&amp;#8217;s degree or higher from a foreign institution which was accredited, at the time the degree was conferred, by an accrediting body recognized by the national government
        of the country in which the institution is located; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A certification from a private education evaluation service approved by the Board that the applicant&amp;#8217;s foreign education is substantially equivalent to the education provided in an accredited program.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6604.3.</num>
    <text>The Board may interview an applicant under this section to determine whether the applicant&amp;#8217;s education or training meets the requirements of the Act and this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6604.4.</num>
    <text>If a document required by this chapter is in a language other than English, an applicant shall arrange for its translation into English by a translation service acceptable to the Board and shall submit a translation signed by the translator attesting
      to its accuracy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 5238 (August 5, 1994).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>