<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6703</num>
  <heading>APPLICANTS EDUCATED IN FOREIGN COUNTRIES (ยง 17-6703)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6703.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant a license to practice physical therapy to an applicant who has been educated outside of the United States if the applicant meets the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Provides satisfactory proof that the applicant&amp;#8217;s education is substantially equivalent to the requirements of physical therapists educated in an accredited education program as determined by the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Passes the Board-approved English proficiency examination if the applicant&amp;#8217;s native language is not English; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Passes the examination approved by the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6703.2.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, &amp;#8220;substantially equivalent&amp;#8221; means that the applicant for licensure educated outside of the United States shall have:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Graduated from a physical therapy education program that prepares the applicant to engage without restriction in the practice of physical therapy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Provided written proof that the applicant&amp;#8217;s school of physical therapy education is recognized by its own ministry of education or equivalent governmental authority;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Undergone a credentials evaluation by a Board-approved evaluating body that has determined the candidate has met uniform criteria for educational requirements as further established by rule; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Passes the examination approved by the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6703.3.</num>
    <text>Deleted</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6703.4.</num>
    <text>The Board may interview an applicant under this section to determine whether the applicant&amp;#8217;s education or training meets the requirements of the Act and this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6703.5.</num>
    <text>If a document required by this chapter is in a language other than English, an applicant shall arrange for its translation into English by a translation service acceptable to the Board and shall submit a translation signed by the translator attesting
      to its accuracy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 945, 946 (February 12, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 6451 (June 25, 2004); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 5462 (July 1, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>