<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6211</num>
  <heading>PRACTICE OF NURSING HOME ADMINISTRATION BY STUDENTS AND GRADUATES (§ 17-6211)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6211.1.</num>
    <text>A student or graduate may practice nursing home administration only under the general or immediate supervision of a nursing home administrator in accordance with this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6211.2.</num>
    <text>Only the following persons shall be authorized to practice under this section:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Students whose practice fulfills educational requirements under § 103(c) of the Act (D.C. Official Code § 3-1201.03) (2001) and § 6202 of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Students whose practice is not in fulfillment of educational requirements; Provided, that the student shall arrange for submission of a letter from the student&amp;#8217;s educational institution to the Board which certifies that the student is
        actively completing an educational program pursuant to § 6202.1 and that the institution has no objection to the student&amp;#8217;s practice; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Graduates fulfilling experience requirement under § 504(f)(1)(B) of the Act (D.C. Official Code § 3-1205.04(f)(1)(B)) (2001) and § 6202 of this chapter, or during the pendency of the graduate&amp;#8217;s initial application for a license under this
        chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6211.3.</num>
    <text>A person who has been denied a license, has been disciplined, or who is the subject of a pending denial or disciplinary action, in the District of Columbia or another jurisdiction, may not practice pursuant to this section unless authorized by the
      Board in writing to do so.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6211.4.</num>
    <text>A supervisor shall, within two (2) weeks of supervising a student or graduate, inform the Board in writing of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The supervisor&amp;#8217;s name and address;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The student or graduate&amp;#8217;s name;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The expected period of supervision; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The nature and location of the practice of the student or graduate.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6211.5.</num>
    <text>A student or graduate shall, within two (2) weeks of practicing pursuant to this section, inform the Board in writing of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The supervisee&amp;#8217;s name and address;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The supervisor&amp;#8217;s name;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The expected period of supervision;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The nature and location of the practice of the student or graduate; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The jurisdictions in which the supervisee is licensed, if any.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6211.6.</num>
    <text>A student or graduate shall wear a badge which identifies himself or herself as a student or graduate to a resident before performing actions of a nursing home administrator.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6211.7.</num>
    <text>At least eight (8) hours of supervised practice during any one (1) month period shall be under immediate supervision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6211.8.</num>
    <text>A graduate may not practice under this section for more than eighteen (18) months unless such practice is during the pendency of an of an initial application by the student or graduate for a license under this chapter. However, the Board, in its discretion,
      may extend the eighteen (18) month limit for good cause shown.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6211.9.</num>
    <text>A student or graduate shall not receive compensation of any nature, directly or indirectly, from a resident, except a salary based on hours worked under supervision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6211.10.</num>
    <text>A supervisor shall be fully responsible for all supervised practice by a student or graduate during the period of supervision and is subject to disciplinary action pursuant to § 514 of the Act (D.C. Official Code § 3-1205.14) (2001) for any violation
      of the Act or this chapter by the student or graduate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6211.11.</num>
    <text>A student or graduate shall be subject to all of the applicable provisions of the Act and this subtitle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6211.12.</num>
    <text>The Board may deny authorization to practice pursuant to this section, deny a license, or take other disciplinary action against a student or graduate who is found to have violated the Act or this subtitle, in accordance with chapter 41 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3774, 3785 (May 20, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 10630 (November 19, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>