<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6312</num>
  <heading>RESPONSIBILITIES (§ 17-6312)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6312.1</num>
    <text>6312.1 An occupational therapist shall exercise sound judgment and providedequate care in the performance of duties in accordance with nationallyecognized standards of practice while treating patients or supervising thereatment of patients.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6312.2</num>
    <text>6312.2 An occupational therapist shall be responsible for managing all aspectsf the occupational therapy care of each patient. An occupational therapisthall provide the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The initial evaluation and treatment plan for each patient and allupporting documentation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Periodic reevaluation for each patient and all supporting documentation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The documented discharge of the patient, including the response to thentervention at the time of discharge.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6312.3</num>
    <text>6312.3 An occupational therapist shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Directly supervise all students training to be occupational therapists or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Countersign all documentation that the students draft.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6312.4</num>
    <text>6312.4 An occupational therapist or occupational therapy assistant supervising student shall be responsible for all of the students’ actions performedithin the scope of practice during the time of supervision and shall be subjecto disciplinary action
      for any violation of the Act or this chapter by theerson supervised.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 4551 (June 9, 2006); as amended byinal Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 2598 (March 14, 2008); as amended byotice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 3133, 3140 (April 20, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>