<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6799</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 17-6799)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6799.1.</num>
    <text>As used in this chapter, the following terms shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Applicant &amp;#8211; a person applying for a license to practice physical therapy under this chapter.</text>
    <text>Board &amp;#8211; the Board of Physical Therapy, established by § 209 of the Act (D.C. Official Code § 2-1202.09).</text>
    <text>Continuing education unit &amp;#8211; a unit of measurement representing ten (10) hours of continuing education credit.</text>
    <text>Direct supervision &amp;#8211; the supervision in which a physical therapist is personally</text>
    <text>present and immediately available within the treatment area to give aid, direction, and instruction when physical therapy procedures or activities are performed.</text>
    <text>Intramuscular manual therapy &amp;#8211; a technique used to treat myofascial pain that uses a dry needle, without medication, that is inserted into a trigger point with the goal of releasing or inactivating the trigger points and relieving pain.</text>
    <text>Physical therapist &amp;#8211; a person licensed to practice physical therapy under the Act.</text>
    <text>Physical therapy aide &amp;#8211; a person trained by a physical therapist to perform designated routine tasks related to the operation of a physical therapy service under the direct supervision of a physical therapist.</text>
    <text>Physical therapy assistant – a physical therapy assistant who is a person licensed to practice under the Act.</text>
    <text>Practice of physical therapy &amp;#8211; the independent evaluation of human disability, injury, or disease by means of noninvasive tests of neuromuscular functions and other standard procedures of physical therapy, and the treatment of human disability,
      injury, or disease by therapeutic procedures, rendered on the prescription of or referral by a licensed physician, osteopath, dentist, or podiatrist, or by a licensed registered nurse certified to practice as an advanced registered nurse as authorized
      pursuant to § 601 of the Act (D.C. Official Code § 3-1206.01), embracing the specific scientific application of physical measures to secure the functional rehabilitation of the human body. These measures include the use of therapeutic exercise,
      therapeutic massage, heat or cold, air, light, water, electricity, or sound for the purpose of correcting or alleviating any physical or mental disability, or preventing the development of any physical or mental disability, or the performance of
      noninvasive tests of neuromuscular functions as an aid to the detection or treatment of any human condition.</text>
    <text>Restricted license &amp;#8211; a license upon which the board has placed any restrictions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6799.2.</num>
    <text>The definitions in § 4099 of chapter 40 of this title are incorporated by reference into and are applicable to this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 945, 954 (February 12, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 1061, 1063 (February 3, 1989); and as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 6451 (June 25, 2004); as amended by Final
        Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 7949 (July 25, 2008); as corrected by Errata Notice published at 57 DCR 11093, 11095 (November 26, 2010); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 817, 819 (January 28, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>