<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-601</num>
  <heading>FILING FEES FOR ALL ENTITIES (ยง 17-601)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>601.1.</num>
    <text>The following fees shall be charged on all domestic and foreign filing entities:</text>
    <text>Withdrawal of filed record before effectiveness: the fee shall be equal to the filed record fee;</text>
    <text>Correcting filed record: the fee shall be equal to the filed record fee;</text>
    <text>Listing of commercial registered agent: one hundred fifty dollars ($150);</text>
    <text>Termination of listing of commercial registered agent: one hundred fifty dollars ($150);</text>
    <text>Change of name, address, type of entity, or jurisdiction of formation by commercial registered agent:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To change information for all entities represented by a commercial registered agent: ten dollars ($10) per entity; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To change information for single entities: the fee shall correspond to the statement of change fee reflected under the rest of the chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <text>Resignation of registered agent: no fee;</text>
    <text>Appointment or cancelation of registered agent by non-qualified foreign entity or non-filing domestic entity: one hundred fifty dollars ($150);</text>
    <text>Service of process, notice, or demand on entity: fifty dollars ($50);</text>
    <text>Statement of conversion: the fee shall be equal to the fee for registering a domestic filing entity;</text>
    <text>Amendment or abandonment of statement of conversion: the fee shall be equal to the fee for filing a statement of conversion;</text>
    <text>Statement of domestication: The fee shall be equal to the fee for registering a domestic filing entity;</text>
    <text>Amendment or abandonment of statement of domestication: the fee shall be equal to the fee for filing a statement of domestication;</text>
    <text>Long-form status certificate: The fee shall be double the status certificate fee for each respective entity type; and</text>
    <text>If a corporate filing fee is not specifically enumerated, then the fee shall be equal to the comparable service fee under this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Act of 2010, effective September 24, 2010 (D.C. Law 18-223), published at 57 DCR 6242, 6274 (July 23, 2010); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8165, 8166 (July 6, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>