<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6014</num>
  <heading>SUPERVISED PRACTICE OF STUDENTS (ยง 17-6014)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6014.1.</num>
    <text>A student may practice as a clinical nurse specialist only in accordance with the Act and this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6014.2.</num>
    <text>A student fulfilling education requirements for certification and practicing within the limitations set forth in ยง 103(c) of the Act, D.C. Official Code ยง 3-1201.03(c), shall be authorized to engage in the supervised practice as a clinical nurse specialist
      without a District of Columbia certificate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6014.3.</num>
    <text>A person who has been denied a certificate, denied a license, disciplined, convicted of an offense that bears directly upon his or her fitness to be licensed, or who has such an action pending in the District of Columbia or another jurisdiction shall
      not practice pursuant to this section unless first authorized by the Board in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6014.4.</num>
    <text>Only a clinical nurse specialist certified under the Act, who is an appointed faculty member of the accredited school or college, or a preceptor meeting the requirements set forth in chapter 56 of this Title, shall be authorized to supervise the practice
      of a clinical nurse specialist by a student.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6014.5.</num>
    <text>A student who practices pursuant to this section shall only practice at a hospital, long-term care facility, a health facility operated by the District or federal government, or other health care facility considered appropriate by the ANCC or other
      certifying body approved by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6014.6.</num>
    <text>All supervised practice of a student shall take place under general or immediate supervision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6014.7.</num>
    <text>A student under this section shall not assume administrative or technical responsibility for the operation of a clinical nurse specialist program, unit, service, or institution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6014.8.</num>
    <text>A student shall identify himself or herself as such before practicing as a nurse practitioner. A student shall wear a picture identification badge with lettering clearly visible to the client bearing the name of the student and the position title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6014.9.</num>
    <text>A student shall not receive compensation of any nature, directly or indirectly, from a client or client&amp;#8217;s family member.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6014.10.</num>
    <text>The supervisor or preceptor, as applicable, shall be fully responsible for the practice by a student during the period of supervision and may be subject to disciplinary action for violations of the Act or this chapter by the student.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6014.11.</num>
    <text>The Board may deny an application for a certificate by, or take other disciplinary action against, a student who is found to have violated the Act or this chapter. The Board may, in addition to any other disciplinary actions permitted by the Act,
      revoke, suspend, or restrict the privilege of the student to practice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 7228 (July 23, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>