<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6207</num>
  <heading>APPROVED CONTINUING EDUCATION PROGRAMS AND ACTIVITIES (ยง 17-6207)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6207.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may, in its discretion, approve continuing education programs and activities that contribute to the growth of an applicant in professional competence in the practice of nursing home administration and which meet the other requirements of
      this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6207.2.</num>
    <text>The Board may approve the following types of continuing education programs, if the program meets the requirements of ยง 6207.3:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An undergraduate or graduate course given at an accredited college or university;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A seminar or workshop; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An educational program given at a conference.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6207.3.</num>
    <text>To qualify for approval by the Board, a continuing education program shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be current in its subject matter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be developed and taught by qualified individuals; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Meet one of the following requirements:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be administered or approved by an organization, educational institution, or health care facility approved by the Board; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Be submitted by the program sponsors to the Board for review no less than thirty (30) days prior to the date of the presentation and be approved by the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6207.4.</num>
    <text>The Board may issue and update a list of approved continuing education programs, organizations, educational institutions, or health care facilities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6207.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall have the burden of verifying whether a program is approved by the Board pursuant to this section prior to attending the program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6207.6.</num>
    <text>The Board may approve the following continuing education activities by an applicant:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Serving as an instructor or speaker at an approved continuing education program; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Publishing a book or a chapter in a book or publishing a book review, article, or abstract in a professional journal or bulletin.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6207.7.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant continuing education credit to a person who serves as a preceptor for an A.I.T. program under ยง 6202.8.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3774, 3783 (May 20, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 10628 (November 19, 2004); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 9400, 9403 (November 4, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>