<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6711</num>
  <heading>PRACTICE OF PHYSICAL THERAPY BY STUDENTS OR GRADUATES (ยง 17-6711)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6711.1.</num>
    <text>This section shall apply to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Students enrolled in recognized schools or colleges as candidates for a degree in physical therapy; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Applicants for a license whose first application for a license in the District of Columbia is pending.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6711.2.</num>
    <text>A student or applicant may perform actions which require a license as a physical therapist only in accordance with the Act and this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6711.3.</num>
    <text>A first-time applicant for a physical therapy license may practice physical therapy under the direct supervision of a physical therapist licensed in the District of Columbia while the initial application is pending.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6711.4.</num>
    <text>A first-time applicant practicing physical therapy pursuant to ยง 6711.3 who fails the national examination or the District examination on the first attempt shall not thereafter continue to practice physical therapy until such time as a physical therapy
      license is duly issued to that individual.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6711.5.</num>
    <text>A student or applicant may practice physical therapy only under the direct supervision of a licensed physical therapist.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6711.6.</num>
    <text>A student or applicant shall identify himself or herself as a student or applicant at all times when performing actions of a physical therapist</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6711.7.</num>
    <text>A physical therapist supervising a student or an applicant shall be fully responsible for all of the actions performed by the student or applicant during the time of the supervision and is subject to disciplinary action for any violation of the Act
      or this chapter by the person supervised.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6711.8.</num>
    <text>A student may not be paid or receive compensation of any nature, directly or indirectly from a patient.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6711.9.</num>
    <text>A student or applicant shall be subject to all of the applicable provisions of the Act and this chapter. The Board may deny an application for a license by, or take other disciplinary action against a student or applicant who is found to have violated
      the Act or this chapter, in accordance with chapter 41 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6711.10.</num>
    <text>If the Board finds that a student or applicant has violated the Act or this chapter, the Board may, in addition to any other disciplinary actions permitted by the Act, revoke, suspend, or restrict the privilege of the student or applicant to practice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6711.11.</num>
    <text>Pursuant to ยง 6710.12, a physical therapist shall review and co-sign any documentation written by a physical therapy student or a first-time applicant for a physical therapy license practicing pursuant to ยง 6711.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 936, 951 (February 12, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 1061 (February 3, 1989); and as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 6451 (June 25, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>