<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6807</num>
  <heading>APPROVED CONTINUING EDUCATION PROGRAMS AND ACTIVITIES (ยง 17-6807)
    <text>The Board may, in its discretion, approve continuing education program and activities that contribute to the growth of a licensee in professional</text>
    <text>competence in the practice of podiatry which meet the other requirements of this section. In order to be approved by the Board, a</text>
    <text>continuing education program or activity shall contribute directly to the professional competence of the licensee.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <num>6807.2.</num>
    <text>The Board may approve the following types of continuing education programs, if the program meets the requirements of ยง 6807.3:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A seminar or workshop;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An educational program given at a conference; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>In-service training.</text>
    </level>
    <text>To qualify for approval by the Board, a continuing education program shall:</text>
    <text>Be current in its professional subject matter;</text>
    <text>Be developed and taught by qualified individuals; and</text>
    <text>Meet one (1) of the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be administered or pre-approved by the Council on</text>
    </level>
    <text>Podiatric Medical Education; or</text>
    <text>Be submitted by the program sponsor to the Board for</text>
    <text>approval no fewer than sixty (60) days before the date of</text>
    <text>presentation.</text>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
    <text>Pursuant to ยง 6807.3, a course agenda for a continuing education program shall be submitted by the licensee for approval by the Board no fewer than thirty (30) days before the date the course begins.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6807.5.</num>
    <text>The Board may issue an update to the list of approved continuing education programs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6807.6.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall have the burden of verifying whether a program is</text>
    <text>approved by the Board pursuant to this section prior to attending the program.</text>
    <text>In accordance with ยง 6807.1, no credit shall be given for business, practice management, or internet technology seminars or courses.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 955, 958 (February 12, 1988); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 8072 (August 17, 2007); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 8578, 8579 (October 7, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>