<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-606</num>
  <heading>LIMITED LIABILITY PARTNERSHIP FILING FEES (ยง 17-606)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>606.1.</num>
    <text>The following fees shall be charged for filings by limited liability partnerships:</text>
    <text>Statement of qualification: two hundred twenty dollars ($220);</text>
    <text>Certificate of good standing or status certificates: fifty dollars ($50);</text>
    <text>Certified copy of filing: fifty dollars ($50);</text>
    <text>Biennial report: three hundred dollars ($300);</text>
    <text>Late fee: an additional one hundred dollars ($100);</text>
    <text>Reservation or transfer of name: fifty dollars ($50);</text>
    <text>Registration or renewal of name: two hundred dollars ($200);</text>
    <text>Change of registered agent by entity: fifty dollars ($50);</text>
    <text>Change of name or address by noncommercial registered agent: fifty dollars ($50);</text>
    <text>Foreign registration statement: two hundred twenty dollars ($220);</text>
    <text>Amendment of foreign registration statement: two hundred twenty dollars ($220);</text>
    <text>Withdrawal of registration of registered foreign entity: two hundred twenty dollars ($220);</text>
    <text>Withdrawal on dissolution or conversion to non-filing entity other than limited liability partnership: two hundred twenty dollars ($220);</text>
    <text>Transfer of registration: two hundred twenty dollars ($220);</text>
    <text>Termination of registration reinstatement: three hundred dollars ($300);</text>
    <text>Reinstatement after administrative dissolution: three hundred dollars ($300);</text>
    <text>Statement of merger: two hundred twenty dollars ($220);</text>
    <text>Amendment or abandonment of statement of merger: two hundred twenty dollars ($220);</text>
    <text>Statement of interest exchange: two hundred twenty dollars ($220);</text>
    <text>Amendment or abandonment of statement of interest exchange: two hundred twenty dollars ($220);</text>
    <text>Statement of cancellation: two hundred twenty dollars ($220); and</text>
    <text>Statement of amendment: two hundred twenty dollars ($220).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Act of 2010, effective September 24, 2010 (D.C. Law 18-223), published at 57 DCR 6242, 6278 (July 23, 2010); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8165, 8174 (July 6, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>