<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6712</num>
  <heading>PHYSICAL THERAPY ASSISTANTS AND AIDES (ยง 17-6712)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6712.1</num>
    <text>6712.1 A physical therapy assistant or physical therapy aide may perform physical therapy functions only in accordance with this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6712.2</num>
    <text>6712.2 A physical therapy assistant may perform the following functions under the direct supervision of a physical therapist:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Use of therapeutic exercise, mechanical traction, therapeutic massage, compression, heat, cold, ultraviolet, water, and electricity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Measurement and adjustment of crutches, canes, walkers, and wheelchairs, and instruction in their use and care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Instruction, motivation, and assistance to patients and others in improving pulmonary function, learning, and functional activities such asre-ambulation, transfer, ambulation and daily living activities; and the usend care of orthoses, prostheses,
        and supportive devices;</text>
    </level>
    <text>Modification of treatment procedures as indicated by patient response and withinhe limits specified in the plan of care, and reported orally or in writing tohe physical therapist; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Participation in routine administrative procedures required for a physical therapy service.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6712.3</num>
    <text>6712.3 A physical therapy aide may perform the following functions under the direct supervision of a physical therapist:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Gait practice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Activities of daily living;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Transfer activities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Hot or cold packs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Paraffin bath;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Hydrotherapy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Whirlpool; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Therapeutic exercises.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6712.4</num>
    <text>6712.4 A physical therapy assistant or physical therapy aide may not performhe</text>
    <text>following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Interpret referrals;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Perform evaluation procedures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Initiate or adjust treatment programs; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Assume responsibility for planning patient care.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Pursuant to ยง 6710.12, a physical therapist shall review and co-sign any</text>
    <text>documentation written by a physical therapy assistant or physical therapy aide.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 936, 952 (February 12, 1988); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 1061, 1062 (February 3, 1989);nd as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 6451 (June 25, 2004); asmended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 55 DCR 7949 (July 25, 2008); asorrected by Errata Notice published at 57 DCR 11093, 11094 (November 26, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>