<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6399</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 17-6399)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6399.1.</num>
    <text>As used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Applicant &amp;#8211; a person applying for a license to practice as an occupational therapist, or to practice as an occupational therapy assistant, under this chapter, as the context requires.</text>
    <text>Board &amp;#8211; the Board of Occupational Therapy, established by ยง 206 of the Act, D.C. Official Code ยง 3-1202.06 (2001).</text>
    <text>Contact hour &amp;#8211; means fifty (50) minutes of continuing education credit.</text>
    <text>Direct supervision &amp;#8211; supervision in which an occupational therapist is personally present and immediately available within the treatment area to give aid, direction, and instruction when occupational therapy procedures or activities are
      performed.</text>
    <text>General supervision &amp;#8211; supervision in which the supervisor is available on the premises or by communication device at the time the supervisee is practicing, and can be on-site in the event of a clinical emergency within two (2) hours.</text>
    <text>Immediate supervision &amp;#8211; oversight of an individual through face-to-face observations and in physical proximity to the individual being supervised.</text>
    <text>Level I Fieldwork &amp;#8211; Enrichment of didactic coursework through direct observation and participation in selected aspects of the occupational therapy process to enable students to develop a basic comfort level with and understanding of the
      needs of clients.</text>
    <text>Level II Fieldwork &amp;#8211; Development of competent entry-level, general occupational therapists and occupational therapy assistants through exposure to in-depth experiences in delivering occupational therapy services to a variety of clients.</text>
    <text>Occupational therapist &amp;#8211; a person licensed to practice occupational therapy under the Act.</text>
    <text>Occupational therapy- (i) The therapeutic use of everyday life activities with individuals or groups, with or without compensation, for the purpose of participation in roles and situations in homes, schools, workplaces, communities, and other settings
      to promote health and welfare for those who have or are at risk for developing an illness, injury, disease, disorder, condition, impairment, disability, activity limitation, or participation restriction; (ii) Addressing the physical, cognitive,
      psycho-social, sensory, or other aspects of performance in a variety of contexts to support engagement in everyday life activities that affect health, well-being, and quality of life; (iii) The education and training of persons in the direct care
      of patients through the use of occupational therapy; and (iv) The education and training of persons in the field of occupational therapy.</text>
    <text>Occupational therapy aide &amp;#8211; a person who has received on-the-job training in occupational therapy and is employed in an occupational therapy setting under the immediate supervision of a licensed occupational therapist.</text>
    <text>Occupational therapy assistant &amp;#8211; a person licensed to practice as an occupational therapy assistant under the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6399.2.</num>
    <text>The definitions in ยง 4099 of Chapter 40 of this title are incorporated by reference and apply to this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 936, 944 (February 12, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 1059, 1060 (February 3, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 4551 (June 9, 2006); as amended by Notice of
        Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 3133, 3144 (April 20, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>