<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6310</num>
  <heading>REINSTATEMENT (ยง 17-6310)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6310.1.</num>
    <text>Reinstatement shall apply to persons with expired licenses.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6310.2</num>
    <text>6310.2 A person may not apply for reinstatement if his or her license has been expired for more than five (5) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6310.3</num>
    <text>6310.3 An applicant for reinstatement of a license to practice as an occupational therapist who holds an active license in any other jurisdiction shall submit proof of having completed twelve (12) contact hours in an approved continuing education
      program for each year that the applicant was not licensed, up to a maximum of sixty (60) hours. Twenty-four (24) hours must have been completed within two (2) years prior to the date the application is submitted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6310.4</num>
    <text>6310.4 An applicant for reinstatement of a license to practice as an occupational therapist who does not hold an active license in any jurisdiction shall submit proof pursuant to ยง 6307 of having completed the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Twelve (12) contact hours in clinical coursework in an approved continuing education program for each year that the applicant was not licensed up to a maximum of sixty (60) hours. Twenty-four (24) contact hours shall have been completed within two
        (2) years prior to the date the application is submitted; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>One hundred sixty (160) hours of supervised clinical training by a licensed occupational therapist within two (2) months prior to the date the application is submitted.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6310.5</num>
    <text>6310.5 An occupational therapy assistant applicant for reinstatement who holds a current license in any other jurisdiction shall submit proof of having completed six (6) contact hours in an approved continuing education program for each year that
      the applicant was not licensed up to a maximum of thirty (30) hours. Twelve (12) contact hours must have been completed within two (2) years prior to the date the application is submitted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6310.6</num>
    <text>6310.6 An applicant for reinstatement of a license to practice as an occupational therapy assistant who does not hold a current license in any other jurisdiction, shall submit proof pursuant to ยง 6307 of having completed the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Six (6) contact hours in an approved continuing education program for each year that the applicant was not licensed up to a maximum of thirty (30) hours. Twelve (12) contact hours must have been within two (2) years prior to the date the application
        is submitted; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>One hundred sixty (160) hours of supervised clinical training</text>
    </level>
    <text>within the two (2) months prior to the date the application is submitted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 4551 (June 9, 2006); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 3133, 3138 (April 20, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>