<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6403</num>
  <heading>APPLICANTS EDUCATED IN FOREIGN COUNTRIES (ยง 17-6403)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6403.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant a license to practice optometry to an applicant who completed an educational program in a educational institution in a foreign country which program is not accredited by the Council on Optometric Education of the American Optometric
      Association if the applicant meets the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Meets all requirements of this chapter except for ยง 6402.1; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Board that the applicant&amp;#8217;s education and training are substantially equivalent to the requirements of this subtitle and the Act in ensuring that the applicant is qualified to practice optometry by
        submitting the documentation required by ยง 6403.2.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6403.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant under this section shall, in lieu of meeting the requirements of ยง 6402.1, submit with the application a certification from a private education evaluation service approved by the Board that the applicant&amp;#8217;s foreign education
      is substantially equivalent to the education provided in an accredited program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6403.3.</num>
    <text>The Board may interview an applicant under this section to determine whether the applicant&amp;#8217;s education or training meets the requirements of the Act and this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6403.4.</num>
    <text>If a document required by this chapter is in a language other than English, an applicant shall arrange for its translation into English by a translation service acceptable to the Board and shall submit a translation signed by the translator attesting
      to its accuracy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 4494, 4495 (June 17, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>