<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6613</num>
  <heading>CONTINUING EDUCATION CREDITS (ยง 17-6613)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6613.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant continuing education credit for whole hours only, with a minimum of fifty (50) minutes constituting one (1) credit hour.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6613.2.</num>
    <text>The Board may, in its discretion, audit up to five percent (5%) of the renewal applications to ensure that the continuing education requirement has been met.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6613.3.</num>
    <text>For graduate courses that are taken for educational credit, each semester hour of credit shall constitute ten (10) hours of continuing education credit, and each quarter hour of credit shall constitute fifteen (15) hours of continuing education credit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6613.4.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant a maximum of five (5) continuing education credits per year to an applicant who attends in-service education programs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6613.5.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant a maximum of fifty percent (50%) of an applicant&amp;#8217;s continuing education requirement for completing continuing education activities under ยง 6611.6</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6613.6.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant credit for preparation and presentation time to an applicant who serves as a speaker at an approved program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6613.7.</num>
    <text>The maximum amount of credit that may be granted for preparation time is twice the amount of the associated presentation time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6613.8.</num>
    <text>If an applicant has previously received credit in connection with a particular presentation, the Board shall not grant credit for a subsequent presentation unless it involves either a different subject or substantial additional research concerning
      the same subject.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6613.9.</num>
    <text>The presentation shall have been completed during the period for which credit is claimed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6613.10.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant continuing education credit under ยง 6611.6(b) only if the applicant proves to the satisfaction of the Board that the work has been published or accepted for publication during the period for which credit is claimed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6613.11.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant continuing education credits for the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>New program development that shall count for a maximum of eight (8) hours. New program development includes a new course, seminar, or workshop. New courses shall be graduate or undergraduate level college or university courses.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Dissertation that shall count for a maximum of 18 hours. Dissertation credit may only be counted once.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Clinical supervision or consultation given or received outside of the place of employment shall count for a maximum of ten hours.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Leadership positions that shall count for a maximum of ten (10) hours.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6613.12.</num>
    <text>The following leadership positions are acceptable for continuing competency credit:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Officer of state or national counseling organization;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Editor and or reviewer of professional counseling journal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Member of a national ethics disciplinary review committee rendering licenses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Active member of a counseling committee producing a substantial written product; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Chair of a major counseling conference or convention;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Other leadership positions with justifiable professional learning experiences.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6613.13.</num>
    <text>Pursuant to ยง 6613.12, to receive credit for the leadership position, the position shall last for a minimum of one (1) year after the date of first licensure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6613.14.</num>
    <text>Practice-related programs shall count up to a maximum of eight (8) hours. The board may allow up to eight (8) contact hours of continuing competency as long as the licensee submits proof of attendance plus a written justification of how the activity
      assists him or her in his or her direct service to clients. Examples include: language courses, software training, medical topics, etc.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6613.15.</num>
    <text>Membership in a state counseling licensure or certification board shall count for a maximum of ten (10) hours of continuing education credit for each year of membership.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 6145 (May 30, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>