<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-7810</num>
  <heading>CONTINUING EDUCATION CREDITS (ยง 17-7810)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7810.1</num>
    <text>7810.1 For the purposes of this chapter, one (1) credit hour shall mean sixty60) minutes of learning time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7810.2</num>
    <text>7810.2 The Board may grant credit for Board-approved activities as specifiedelow:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Board shall grant credit for a course given at an accredited college orniversity, provided that:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Each three (3) hour academic course constitutes thirty (30) hours ofontinuing education; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For approved three (3) hour academic courses that are audited, two (2)ontinuing education credit hours shall be granted.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Board may grant a maximum of six (6) continuing education hours perenewal period to an applicant who attends a pre-approved in-service educationrogram.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7810.3</num>
    <text>7810.3 The Board may grant credit for serving as a presenter or speaker at aonference, seminar, workshop, or in-service training, or electronic oreb-based course subject to the following restrictions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Hours granted pursuant to this section shall not exceed six (6) per renewaleriod;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If an applicant has previously received credit in connection with aarticular presentation, the Board shall not grant credit for a subsequentresentation unless it involves either a different subject or substantialdditional research concerning the
        same subject;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The presentation shall have been completed during the period for whichredit is claimed and;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The maximum amount of credit which may be granted for preparation time iswice the amount of the associated presentation time or twice the amount ofontact hours awarded for participants.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7810.4</num>
    <text>7810.4 The Board may grant credit to an applicant for publication of anrticle in a professional journal or publication of a book or a chapter in aook or publication of a book review in a professional journal related toudiology or speech-language pathology,
      subject to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Board may grant an applicant who is an author or sole editor of aublished book eight (8) hours of continuing education credit per renewaleriod, if the book has been published or accepted for publication during theeriod for which credit is claimed
        and the applicant submits proof of this factn the application;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Board may grant an applicant who is the sole author or co-author of aeer-reviewed published original paper four (4) hours of continuing educationer renewal period; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Board may grant an applicant who is sole author of a published bookeview one (1) continuing education hour of credit per renewal period.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 4336, 4342 (May 20,011); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8530, 8534 (July 20,012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>