<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-712</num>
  <heading>COMMERCIAL REGISTERED AGENT FOR A FEE OR ON BEHALF OF MULTIPLE FILING ENTITIES§ 17-712)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>712.1.</num>
    <text>An individual or entity intending to serve as the commercial registered agent for a fee and for fifty (50) or more filing entities shall:</text>
    <text>File with the Superintendent a commercial registered agent listing statement; and</text>
    <text>Include the signature of the entity, individual, or other person authorized to sign on behalf of the commercial registered agent on the commercial registered agent listing statement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>712.2.</num>
    <text>An individual or entity serving as a commercial registered agent pursuant to § 711.1 shall file a commercial registered agent filing with the Superintendent within thirty (30) business days of serving a minimum of fifty (50) filing entities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>712.3.</num>
    <text>An individual or entity currently serving as a commercial registered agent for a fee and for fifty (50) or more filing entities shall:</text>
    <text>File with the Superintendent a commercial registered agent listing statement; and</text>
    <text>Include the signature of the entity, individual, or other person authorized to sign on behalf of the commercial registered agent on the commercial registered agent listing statement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>712.4.</num>
    <text>An individual or entity currently serving as a commercial registered agent pursuant to § 711.2 shall file a commercial registered agent filing with the Superintendent within thirty (30) business days that these regulations are adopted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>712.5</num>
    <text>712.5 Failure to comply with filing a commercial registered agent listing statement may lead to the removal by the Superintendent of the commercial registered agent from each entity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>712.6.</num>
    <text>An individual or entity serving as a commercial registered agent for a fee and for fifty (50) or less filing entities may:</text>
    <text>File with the Superintendent a commercial registered agent listing statement; and</text>
    <text>Include the signature of the entity, individual, or other person authorized to sign on behalf of the commercial registered agent on the commercial registered agent listing statement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 13139 (September 20, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>