<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-7007</num>
  <heading>LICENSE BY ENDORSEMENT (ยง 17-7007)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7007.1.</num>
    <text>An applicant is eligible for a license by endorsement if the applicant:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Obtained initial licensure in the United States by an examination equivalent to the level of licensure for which the applicant is applying; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Is currently licensed in good standing as a social worker under the laws of a state or territory of the United States pursuant to licensure requirements which, as determined by Board, were substantially equivalent at the time of licensure to the
        requirements of this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7007.2.</num>
    <text>To apply for a license by endorsement, an applicant shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Submit a completed application to the Board on the required forms and include:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s social security number on the application. If the applicant does not have a social security number, the applicant shall submit a sworn affidavit, under penalty of perjury, with the application stating that he or she does
        not have a social security number; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Two (2) recent passport-type photographs of the applicant&amp;#8217;s face measuring two inches by two inches (2&amp;#8243; x 2&amp;#8243;) which clearly expose the area from the top of the forehead to the bottom of the chin.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Submit a copy of his or her current license with the application;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Obtain licensure verification from the original state or territory of licensure that the license is current and in good standing. The licensure verification form must be sent directly to the Board, by the verifying Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Submit the applicant&amp;#8217;s certified or validated examination results, which shall confirm that the applicant has received a passing score on the required level of the national examination or on another examination determined by the Board
        to be equivalent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Meet any other requirements as set forth by the Board; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Pay all required fees.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7007.3.</num>
    <text>An application that remains incomplete for ninety (90) days or more from the date of submission shall be considered abandoned, and closed by the Board. The applicant shall thereafter be required to reapply, submit the required documents and completed
      forms, and pay the required fees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7007.4.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the Board from utilizing other authorized databases to verify an applicant&amp;#8217;s current licensure standing in other jurisdictions of the U.S. or to review disciplinary records.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 8281, 8283 (December 8, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 10686 (December 9, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>