<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-7009</num>
  <heading>APPROVED CONTINUING EDUCATION PROGRAMS AND ACTIVITIES (§ 17-7009)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7009.1.</num>
    <text>The Board shall approve only continuing education programs and activities that contribute to the growth of an applicant in professional competence in the practice of social work and which meet the other requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7009.2.</num>
    <text>The Board may approve the following types of continuing education programs, if the programs meet the requirements of § 7009.6:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An undergraduate or graduate course given at an accredited college or university;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A seminar or workshop; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An educational program given at a conference.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7009.3</num>
    <text>7009.3 The Board may approve the following independent home studies and distance learning continuing education activities:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Serving as an instructor or speaker at a conference, seminar, or workshop;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Publication of an article in a professional journal, publication of a book or a chapter in a book, or publication of a book review in a professional journal or bulletin;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Internet courses, video courses, telecourses, videoconferences, and teleconferences offered by accredited colleges or universities, or pre-approved by local or national professional social work organizations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Independent study programs directly related to social work approved by accredited college or university schools of social work, local or national professional social work organizations, the Association of Social Work Boards (ASWB), or the Board,
        and peer study groups sanctioned by local or national social work organizations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7009.4.</num>
    <text>No more than twelve (12) CEUs may be accepted in any renewal period, or for reinstatement or reactivation of a license, for approved independent home studies and distance learning continuing education activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7009.5</num>
    <text>7009.5 Independent study programs and distance learning continuing education activities, including internet courses, shall not be used to satisfy the continuing education ethics requirement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7009.6.</num>
    <text>To qualify for approval by the Board, a continuing education program shall meet the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be current in its subject matter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be developed and taught by individuals with demonstrated qualifications in the topic in consultation with a licensed social worker; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Meet one of the following requirements:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be administered or approved by:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>A recognized social work, mental health, or human services organization that is approved by the Board; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A college or university that is accredited by an accrediting body recognized by the Secretary of the United States Department of Education or the Council on Postsecondary Accreditation; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Be submitted by the program sponsors to the Board for review no less than three (3) months prior to the date of the presentation and be approved by the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7009.7.</num>
    <text>Requests for approval of continuing education programs received by the Board after the continuing education program has already occurred will not be approved or accepted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7009.8.</num>
    <text>The Board may issue and update a list of approved continuing education organizations and programs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7009.9.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall have the burden of verifying whether a program or activity is approved by the Board pursuant to this section prior to attending the program or engaging in the activity.</text>
    <text>The Board shall not grant continuing education credits for:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Work done in the course of an applicant’s normal occupation or incident to the performance of his or her regular professional duties, such as teaching, research, or course preparation in the case of a teacher or professor whether on a full-time
        or part-time basis;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Meetings and activities not related to the practice of social work which are required as part of an applicant’s professional activities such as job orientations, and agency required administrative trainings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Individual or group supervision; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Other activities, which are not of the type of activities approved by the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 5881 (July 25, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 10686 (December 9, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 4209, 4215 (May 4, 2012); as amended by Final Rulemaking published
        at 60 DCR 8489 (June 7, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>