<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-7908</num>
  <heading>CONTINUING EDUCATION CREDITS (ยง 17-7908)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7908.1</num>
    <text>7908.1 For the purposes of this chapter, one (1) credit hour shall mean sixty60) minutes of learning time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7908.2</num>
    <text>7908.2 The Board may grant credit for Board-approved activities as specifiedelow:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Board shall grant credit for a course given at an accredited college orniversity provided that:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Each three (3)-credit-hour academic course constitutes thirty (30) hours ofontinuing education; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For each approved three (3)-credit-hour academic course that is audited,wo (2) continuing education hours shall be granted.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Board may grant a maximum of six (6) continuing education hours perenewal period to an applicant who attends a pre-approved in-service educationrogram.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7908.3</num>
    <text>7908.3 The Board may grant credit for serving as a presenter or speaker at aonference, seminar, workshop, or in- service training, or electronic oreb-based course subject to the following restrictions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Hours granted pursuant to this section shall not exceed six (6) hours perenewal period;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If a licensee or a renewal, reinstatement, or reactivation applicant hasreviously received credit in connection with a particular presentation, theoard shall not grant credit for a subsequent presentation unless it involvesither a different subject
        or substantial additional research concerning theame subject;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The presentation was completed during the period for which credit islaimed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The maximum amount of credit which may be granted for preparation time iswice the amount of the associated presentation time or twice the amount ofontact hours awarded for participants.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7908.4</num>
    <text>7908.4 The Board may grant credit for publication of an article in arofessional journal or publication of a book or a chapter in a book orublication of a book review in a professional journal related to audiology orpeech-language pathology, subject
      to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Board may grant eight (8) hours of continuing education credit perenewal period to an author or sole editor of a published book, if the book wasublished or accepted for publication during the period for which credit islaimed and the applicant
        submits proof of this fact in the application;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Board may grant four (4) hours of continuing education per renewaleriod to the sole author or co-author of a peer-reviewed published originalaper; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Board may grant one (1) continuing education hour of credit per renewaleriod to the sole author of a published book review.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 7314 (September 4, 2009); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 148 (October 18, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>