<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-7707</num>
  <heading>CONTINUING EDUCATION REQUIREMENTS (ยง 17-7707)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7707.1.</num>
    <text>This section shall apply to applicants for the renewal, reactivation, and reinstatement of a license for the term expiring March 31, 2006 and for subsequent terms.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7707.2.</num>
    <text>This section shall not apply to applicants for an initial license by reciprocity or endorsement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7707.3.</num>
    <text>Continuing education credit shall be granted only for programs or activities approved by the Board in accordance with section 7708.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7707.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant for renewal, reactivation, or reinstatement of a license to practice marriage and family therapy, shall submit proof of having completed thirty (30) hours of approved continuing education during the two-year (2) period preceding the date
      the license expires or preceding the date of the application for reactivation or reinstatement. The thirty (30) hours of approved continuing education shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A minimum of fifteen (15) of the thirty (30) hours shall be completed in the physical presence of the approved sponsor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Six (6) hours of the thirty (30) hours shall be in ethics;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The remaining twenty-four (24) hours of continuing education may consist of current and emerging issues in marriage and family therapy such as the study of:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Non-traditional families;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Domestic violence;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>HIV;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Aging;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>End-of-life issues;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Addiction and psychopharmacology; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Trauma.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7707.5.</num>
    <text>To qualify for a license, a person in inactive status within the meaning of section 511 of the Act, (D.C. Official Code ยง 3-1205.11 (2001)), who submits an application to reactivate a license shall submit proof of having met the continuing education
      requirements for each licensing period that the license was in inactive status.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7707.6.</num>
    <text>To qualify for a license, an applicant for reinstatement of a license to practice marriage and family therapy pursuant to section 512 of the Act (D.C. Official Code ยง 3-1205.12 (2001)) shall submit proof of having completed fifteen (15) hours of credit
      in an approved continuing education program for each year after March 31, 2006 that the applicant was not licensed, up to a maximum of seventy-five (75) hours.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7707.7.</num>
    <text>An applicant for license renewal, reactivation, or reinstatement under this section shall prove completion of required continuing education credits by submitting with the application the following information with respect to each program:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the sponsor of the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name of the program, its location, a description of the subject matter covered, and the names of the instructors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The dates on which the applicant attended the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The hours of credit claimed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Verification by the sponsor of completion, by signature or stamp.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7707.8</num>
    <text>7707.8 The Board shall accept for continuing education credit any credits or courses sponsored by the following organizations:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The American Association for Marriage and Family Therapy (AAMFT);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The National Association of Social Workers (NASW);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The American Psychological Association (APA);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The National Board for Certified Counselors (NBCC); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Other state Marriage and Family Therapy boards.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7707.9.</num>
    <text>An applicant for renewal of a license who fails to submit proof of having completed continuing education requirements by the date the license expires may renew the license up to sixty (60) days after expiration by submitting the proof pursuant to
      section 7707.7 and by paying the required additional late fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7707.10.</num>
    <text>Upon submitting proof and paying the late fee, the applicant shall be deemed to have possessed a valid license during the period between the expiration of the license and the submission of the required documentation and payment of the late fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7707.11.</num>
    <text>If an applicant for renewal of a license fails to submit proof of completion of continuing education requirements or pay the late fee within sixty (60) days after the expiration of the applicant&amp;#8217;s license, the license shall be deemed to
      have lapsed on the date of expiration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7707.12.</num>
    <text>The Board may, in its discretion, grant an extension of the sixty (60) day period to renew after expiration if the applicant&amp;#8217;s failure to submit proof of completion was for good cause.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 7845 (September 29, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 8247 (August 24, 2007); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 9260 (October 28, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>