<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-7511</num>
  <heading>PRACTICE OF MASSAGE THERAPY BY STUDENTS OR APPLICANTS (ยง 17-7511)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7511.1.</num>
    <text>This section shall apply to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Students enrolled in schools or colleges recognized by the Board pursuant to ยง 7502.1 as candidates for a certificate or degree in massage therapy; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Applicants for a license whose first application for a license in the District of Columbia is pending.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7511.2.</num>
    <text>A student or applicant may perform actions which require a license as a massage therapist only in accordance with the Act and this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7511.3.</num>
    <text>Students and applicants shall adhere to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A student shall practice massage therapy only under the charge of a supervisor; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An applicant may practice massage therapy prior to licensure for 90 days under the charge of a supervisor.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7511.4.</num>
    <text>The practice of massage therapy by a student or applicant must be subject to the written consent and protocols of the supervisor or school.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7511.5.</num>
    <text>A student or applicant shall identify himself or herself as a student or applicant at all times when performing actions of a massage therapist.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7511.6.</num>
    <text>A massage therapist supervising a student or an applicant shall be fully responsible for massage therapy performed according to the written protocols of the school or supervisor by the student or applicant during the time of the supervision and is
      subject to disciplinary action for any violation of the Act or this chapter by the person supervised.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7511.7.</num>
    <text>A student may not be paid or receive compensation of any nature, directly or indirectly, from a client.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7511.8.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to bar a school from charging fees for its students&amp;#8217; massage therapy services to the public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7511.9.</num>
    <text>A student or applicant shall be subject to all of the applicable provisions of the Act and this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7511.10.</num>
    <text>In accordance with Chapter 41 of this title, the Board may deny an application for a license by, or take other disciplinary action against a student or applicant who is found to have violated the Act or this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7511.11.</num>
    <text>If the Board finds that a student or applicant has violated the Act or this chapter, the Board may, in addition to any other disciplinary actions permitted by the Act, revoke, suspend, or restrict the privilege of the student or applicant to practice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 7716 (October 30, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 8524 (September 16, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 8933 (September 14, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>