<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-8607</num>
  <heading>APPROVED CONTINUING EDUCATION PROGRAMS AND ACTIVITIES (§ 17-8607)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8607.1.</num>
    <text>Only continuing education programs and activities approved by the Board shall be counted toward meeting the required number of continuing education hours.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8607.2.</num>
    <text>The Board may, in its discretion, approve continuing education programs and activities that contribute to the growth of an applicant in professional competence in the practice of psychology and which meet the other requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8607.3.</num>
    <text>The Board may approve the following types of continuing education programs if the programs meet the requirement of § 8607.3:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A seminar or workshop;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An education program given at a conference;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>In-service training; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>An online or home study course; or</text>
    </level>
    <text>An undergraduate or graduate course given at an accredited college or university provided that the undergraduate course shall be acceptable only if the Board determines that the course is required or needed by the registrant as an introductory component
      of a professional development plan for the purpose of entering an area of psychology for which the registrant is currently not qualified to practice independently.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8607.4.</num>
    <text>To qualify for Board approval, a continuing education program shall:</text>
    <text>Be current in its subject matter;</text>
    <text>Be developed by qualified individuals of whom one shall be a psychologist;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Be taught or facilitated by at least one (1) qualified individual; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Meet one (1) of the following requirements:</text>
    </level>
    <text>The program shall be administered by an accredited college or university;</text>
    <text>The program shall be approved by a Board-recognized</text>
    <text>psychology organization or accredited health care facility; or</text>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The program is approved by the Board. In order to be approved by the Board, the program sponsor shall submit to the Board for review at least sixty (60) days prior to the start of the program the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The sponsor’s name and address;</text>
    </level>
    <text>The program’s name;</text>
    <text>The location;</text>
    <text>A description and specific goals;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>The target audience’s maximum size and professional level (Master’s or doctorate);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>The program’s tentative or actual schedule, including the allotted time for lunch, breaks and topic headings or subheadings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(G)</num>
      <text>An appropriately constructed evaluation form and continuing education completion verification document;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(H)</num>
      <text>The name and credentials of each instructor or speaker including relevant education, training, research, publications, work samples(s), honor or awards, special recognition; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(I)</num>
      <text>If applicable, the evaluation results of comparable</text>
    </level>
    <text>programs or activities previously conducted by the</text>
    <text>sponsor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8607.5.</num>
    <text>The Board shall maintain a list of approved continuing education programs on its website.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8607.6.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall have the burden of verifying whether a program is approved by the Board pursuant to this section prior to attending the program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8607.7</num>
    <text>8607.7 The Board may approve the following continuing education activities:</text>
    <text>Serving as an instructor or speaker at a conference, seminar, workshop, or in-service training;</text>
    <text>Being the author or coauthor of an article (including “critiques” and “responses”) or a book review in a professional journal or periodical, or author or coauthor of a book or book chapter;</text>
    <text>Serving as an editor (including “associate” and “junior” levels) for a professional journal, periodical, or book;</text>
    <text>Serving as an article reviewer for a professional journal or periodical; or</text>
    <text>Having developed an online or home study continuing education course.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 3246, 3250 (April 15, 2011); as corrected by Errata Notice published at 59 DCR 8356, 8357 (July 13, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>