<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-8611</num>
  <heading>SUPERVISION OF PSYCHOLOGY ASSOCIATES (§ 17-8611)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8611.1.</num>
    <text>A supervisor of a psychology associate shall supervise only in those areas</text>
    <text>within the supervisor’s competence based on the supervisor’s education,</text>
    <text>training, and experience. The supervisor shall delegate supervisory</text>
    <text>responsibility to another psychologist or psychiatrist to ensure that the</text>
    <text>psychology associate receives appropriate supervision in areas outside of</text>
    <text>the expertise of the original supervisor.</text>
    <text>Appropriate supervision is determined by the following:</text>
    <text>Education, training, and experience of the psychology associate;</text>
    <text>Nature and extent of the services to be performed by the psychology associate; and</text>
    <text>Setting in which the services are to be performed.</text>
    <text>A supervisor may supervise a maximum of five (5) psychology associates</text>
    <text>at any one (1) time.</text>
    <text>A supervisor shall ensure that a psychology associate is practicing within</text>
    <text>the scope of the psychology associate’s competencies as demonstrated by the psychology associate’s documented training and experience in a</text>
    <text>particular area of practice.</text>
    <text>A supervisor shall maintain appropriate documentation of the nature and</text>
    <text>extent of the supervision provided or delegated, including the dates, duration, and focus of the supervisory sessions. The supervisor shall provide a reason for any delegation of supervisory responsibility.</text>
    <text>Pursuant to § 8611.5 a supervisor shall provide documentation requested</text>
    <text>upon demand by an individual authorized by the board.</text>
    <text>A supervisor shall not engage in supervision of a psychology associate</text>
    <text>who is a friend or relative.</text>
    <text>A supervisor shall immediately report to the Board, by certified mail, the</text>
    <text>date of termination of the supervisory relationship with a psychology</text>
    <text>associate.</text>
    <text>A supervisor shall be responsible for all services provided by a</text>
    <text>psychology associate under the supervisor’s supervision.</text>
    <text>A psychology associate shall inform the supervisor of all complaints,</text>
    <text>formal or informal, about the services provided by the psychology associate.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 3246, 3255 (April 15, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>