<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-8108</num>
  <heading>SCOPE OF PRACTICE (ยง 17-8108)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8108.1</num>
    <text>8108.1 A supervising physician has ultimate responsibility for the medical care and treatment provided to a patient by a licensed polysomnographic technologist or registered polysomnographic technician or trainee to whom the supervising physician
      has delegated authority to perform health care tasks that require the provision of sleep-related services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8108.2.</num>
    <text>A licensed polysomnographic technologist shall practice:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Only under the general supervision of a licensed physician; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Only in a hospital sleep laboratory or a stand-alone sleep center.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8108.3.</num>
    <text>The scope of practice of a licensed polysomnographic technologist includes the following:</text>
    <text>Analyzing, monitoring, and recording physiologic data during sleep and wakefulness;</text>
    <text>Scoring and analyzing acquired physiologic data;</text>
    <text>Maintaining nasal and oral airways that do not extend in the trachea;</text>
    <text>The therapeutic and diagnostic use of oxygen;</text>
    <text>Monitoring and recording physiologic data during sleep, including sleep-related respiratory disturbances;</text>
    <text>Reading and analyzing test results obtained from home-based, self-administered diagnostic tests;</text>
    <text>Cardiopulmonary resuscitation;</text>
    <text>The use of positive airway pressure, including continuous positive airway pressure (CPAP), bi-level modalities, and multiple function modalities;</text>
    <text>Using data to assist a licensed physician in the diagnosis and treatment of sleep and wake disorders;</text>
    <text>Assisting with the diagnosis and treatment of individuals who suffer from sleep disorders as a result of developmental defects, the aging process, physical injury, disease, or actual or anticipated somatic dysfunction;</text>
    <text>Observing and monitoring physical signs and symptoms, general behavior, and general physical responses to polysomnographic evaluation and determining whether initiation, modification, or discontinuation of a treatment regimen is warranted;</text>
    <text>Assessing, diagnosing, and assisting in the treatment and research of disorders, syndromes, and dysfunctions that are sleep-related, manifest during sleep, or disrupt normal sleep and wake cycles and activities;</text>
    <text>Using evaluation techniques that include limited cardiopulmonary function assessments, the need and effectiveness of therapeutic modalities and procedures, and the assessment and evaluation of the need for extended care; and</text>
    <text>Transcribing and implementing written or verbal orders of a physician pertaining to the practice of polysomnography.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8108.4.</num>
    <text>A registered polysomnographic technician shall practice:</text>
    <text>Under the general supervision of a physician who is ultimately responsible for the quality of care provided, or the direct supervision of a licensed polysomnographic technologist; and</text>
    <text>Only in a hospital sleep laboratory or a stand-alone sleep center.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8108.5.</num>
    <text>The scope of practice of a registered polysomnographic technician is limited to the following:</text>
    <text>Analyzing, monitoring, and recording physiologic data during sleep and wakefulness;</text>
    <text>Maintaining nasal and oral airways that do not extend in the trachea;</text>
    <text>The therapeutic and diagnostic use of oxygen;</text>
    <text>Cardiopulmonary resuscitation;</text>
    <text>The use of positive airway pressure, including continuous positive airway pressure (CPAP), bi-level modalities, and multiple function modalities;</text>
    <text>Assisting licensed polysomnographic technologists and licensed physicians with reading and analyzing test results obtained from home-based, self-administered diagnostic tests;</text>
    <text>Recognizing wake and sleep stages; and</text>
    <text>Transcribing and implementing written or verbal orders of a physician pertaining to the practice of polysomnography, if consistent with the level of education and experience of the registered polysomnographic technician.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8108.6</num>
    <text>8108.6 A registered polysomnographic trainee shall practice:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Under the general supervision of a physician who is ultimately responsible for the quality of care provided, and the direct supervision of a licensed polysomnographic technologist; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Only in a hospital setting.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8108.7.</num>
    <text>The scope of practice of a registered polysomnographic trainee is limited to the</text>
    <text>following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Analyzing, monitoring, and recording physiologic data during sleep and wakefulness;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Maintaining nasal and oral airways that do not extend in the trachea;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The therapeutic and diagnostic use of oxygen;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Cardiopulmonary resuscitation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Implementing written orders of a physician pertaining to the practice of polysomnography, if consistent with the level of education and experience of the registered polysomnographic trainee.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 3758, 3766 (April 29, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>