<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-8399</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 17-8399)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8399.1.</num>
    <text>As used in this Chapter the following terms shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Act &amp;#8211; SafeRx Amendment Act of 2008, effective March 26, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-0131; 55 DCR 4462, published on April 25, 2008 (the Act), and Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 2008-XXX, dated May XX, 2008.</text>
    <text>Applicant- A person applying for a license to practice pharmaceutical detailing under this chapter.</text>
    <text>Board &amp;#8211; the Board of Pharmacy, established by § 208 of the Act, D.C. Official Code § 3-1202.08.</text>
    <text>Conference &amp;#8211; (1) A meeting, symposium, exposition, exhibit, convention, assembly, or like gathering, including meetings of a regional, national, or international professional association, society, or body, for the discussion of health-related
      issues consisting of multi-pharmaceutical company or labeler representation and targeting a regional, national, or international audience; or (2) a scientific or medical educational meeting or symposium that is accredited by a nationally recognized
      healthcare professional education accreditation body (e.g., the Accreditation Council for Continuing Medical Education, the Accreditation Council for Pharmacy Education, and the American Nurses Association).</text>
    <text>Department &amp;#8211; Department of Health</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; Director of the Department</text>
    <text>District of Columbia Family Medical Leave Act &amp;#8211; District of Columbia Family Medical Leave Act of 1990, effective October 3, 1990 (D.C. Law 8-181; D.C. Official Code § 32-501 et seq.)</text>
    <text>Family Medical Leave Act &amp;#8211; Family Medical Leave Act of 1993, approved February 5, 1993 (107 Stat. 7; 29 U.S.C. § 2601 et seq.)</text>
    <text>FDA &amp;#8211; the federal Food and Drug Administration</text>
    <text>HORA &amp;#8211; Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code § 3-1201.01 et seq.) Institution of Higher Education- as defined in § 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965, as amended, approved
      October 7, 1998 (112 Stat. 1581; 20 U.S.C. § 1001).</text>
    <text>Labeler &amp;#8211; An entity or person that receives pharmaceutical products from a manufacturer or wholesaler and repackages those pharmaceuticals for later retail sale and that has a labeler code from the federal Food and Drug Administration under
      21 C.F.R. § 207.20.</text>
    <text>Manufacturer &amp;#8211; a manufacturer of pharmaceutical products and includes subsidiary or affiliate of a manufacturer.</text>
    <text>Medication Advisory Committee &amp;#8211; any committee or panel that is responsible for making recommendations or decisions regarding a formulary to be used by a health program administered by the government of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Multi-pharmaceutical or labeler representation- at least three or more pharmaceutical companies or labelers which shall not be subsidiaries, or affiliations of the same company or parent company.</text>
    <text>Pharmaceutical Company &amp;#8211; any entity that is engaged in, either directly or indirectly, the production, preparation, propagation, compounding, manufacturing, conversion or processing of a drug or biologic product, including any person acting
      as its agent or representative.</text>
    <text>Pharmaceutical Detailer: a person licensed under the Act to engage in the practice of pharmaceutical detailing.</text>
    <text>Pharmaceutical Product &amp;#8211; a drug or biologic regulated by the federal Food and Drug Administration.</text>
    <text>Practice of Pharmaceutical detailing &amp;#8211; the practice by a representative of a pharmaceutical manufacturer or labeler of communicating in person with a licensed health professional, or an employee or representative of a licensed health</text>
    <text>Sales Call- any in person communication with a health care professional or his or her employees or representatives for the direct purpose of selling marketing, or promoting a pharmaceutical product, or providing information about a pharmaceutical
      product for the purpose of selling, marketing, or promoting such pharmaceutical product on behalf of a pharmaceutical manufacturer or labeler.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 9317 (August 29, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 2951 (April 17, 2009); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 5739, 5740 (July 2, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>