<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-8008</num>
  <heading>CONTINUING EDUCATION REQUIREMENTS (§ 17-8008)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8008.1.</num>
    <text>This section shall apply to applicants for the renewal, reactivation, or reinstatement of a license for a term expiring December 31, 2008, and for subsequent terms.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8008.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant for renewal of a license to practice as a surgical assistant shall submit proof pursuant to § 8008.6 of having completed during the two-year (2) period preceding the date the license expires approved continuing education units (CEUs)
      constituting fifty (50) hours of CEU credit as specified in § 8009.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8008.3.</num>
    <text>A continuing education credit may be granted only for a program or activity approved by the Board in accordance with § 8009.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8008.4.</num>
    <text>A surgical assistant who is required to obtain continuing education units pursuant to § 8008.2 may, in lieu of meeting the requirement of that section through the completion of CEUs approved by the Board pursuant to § 8009, furnish proof satisfactory
      to the Board that the surgical assistant holds a current valid certification from the American Board of Surgical Assistants or the National Surgical Assistant&amp;#8217;s Association and has completed fifty (50) hours of CEUs over a two-year (2)
      period as part of that certification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8008.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant for reactivation of an inactive license or reinstatement of a license to practice as a surgical assistant shall submit proof pursuant to § 8008.6 of having completed during the two-year (2) period immediately preceding the date of application
      approved CEUs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8008.6.</num>
    <text>An applicant under this section shall furnish proof of having completed required continuing education units by submitting with the application the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name of the program and its approval number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The dates on which the applicant attended the program or performed the activity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The hours of credit claimed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Verification by the applicant of completion.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 9549 (October 5, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>