<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-8099</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 17-8099)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8099.1.</num>
    <text>As used in this chapter the following terms have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Board &amp;#8211; the Board of Medicine, established by § 203(a) of the Act, D.C. Official Code § 3-1202.03(a) (1) (2001).</text>
    <text>Committee &amp;#8211; the Advisory Committee on Surgical Assistants, established by § 203 (c-3) of the Act. D.C. Official Code § 3-1202.03(c-3) (2001).</text>
    <text>Immediately available &amp;#8211; physically present in the surgical suite and capable of responding to the surgical assistant and the patient as medically appropriate.</text>
    <text>Practice by surgical assistants &amp;#8211; means the provision of aid by a person who is not a physician licensed to practice medicine, under the direct supervision of a surgeon licensed in the District, in exposure, hemostasis, closures, and other
      intraoperative technical functions that assist a physician in performing a safe operation with optimal results for the patient.</text>
    <text>Surgical assistant &amp;#8211; a person licensed to practice as a surgical assistant under the Act, or meeting the requirements for licensure in the District, regardless of whether he or she are licensed in fact, until March 6, 2009.</text>
    <text>Surgical suite &amp;#8211; includes the operating room as well as contiguous recovery rooms.</text>
    <text>Supervising surgeon &amp;#8211; a surgeon licensed by the Board who delegates to a licensed surgical assistant surgically assisting and oversees and accepts responsibility for the surgical assisting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8099.2.</num>
    <text>The definitions in § 4099 of chapter 40 of this title and the Act are incorporated by reference into and are applicable to this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 9549 (October 5, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>