<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-9004</num>
  <heading>SCOPE OF PRACTICE (ยง 17-9004)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>9004.1.</num>
    <text>Subject to the restrictions set forth in this section, a dentist may delegate to a registered dental assistant only those procedures which are:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Appropriate to the training and experience of the dental assistant and the practice of the supervising dentist;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Reversible; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>To be performed under the direct supervision of the dentist.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9004.2.</num>
    <text>Level I Dental Assistant may perform the following functions under direct supervision of a dentist:</text>
    <text>Placing retraction cord;</text>
    <text>Placing matrices;</text>
    <text>Applying a medicinal agent to a tooth for a prophylactic purpose;</text>
    <text>Placing periodontal dressings;</text>
    <text>Removing temporary restorations without the use of a rotary instrument;</text>
    <text>Removing sutures;</text>
    <text>Taking impression for study models or diagnostic casts;</text>
    <text>Rinsing and aspirating the oral cavity;</text>
    <text>Retracting the lips, cheek, tongue, and flaps;</text>
    <text>Placing or removing materials for the isolation of the dentition, provided that the material is not retained by the dentition;</text>
    <text>Applying topical anesthesia;</text>
    <text>Constructing athletic mouth guards in models;</text>
    <text>Performing intraoral photography;</text>
    <text>Curing by the use of halogen light;</text>
    <text>Checking for loose bands;</text>
    <text>Whitening; and</text>
    <text>Other functions as approved by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9004.3.</num>
    <text>Level II Dental Assistant may perform the following functions under direct supervision of a dentist:</text>
    <text>All functions permitted to Level I Dental Assistant, as enumerated in ยง 9004.2;</text>
    <text>Performing vitality tests;</text>
    <text>Taking alginate impressions for intraoral appliances;</text>
    <text>Applying topical fluoride;</text>
    <text>Applying desensitizing agents;</text>
    <text>Placing or removing a rubber dam;</text>
    <text>Etching;</text>
    <text>Fabricating indirect restorations in a dental office;</text>
    <text>Placing or removing a matrix band;</text>
    <text>Drying a root canal;</text>
    <text>Preparing and fitting stainless steel crowns;</text>
    <text>Preparing temporary crowns;</text>
    <text>Removing excess cement;</text>
    <text>Removing or placing a periodontal dressing (except placing the original periodontal dressing); and</text>
    <text>Constructing athletic mouth guards on models.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9004.4.</num>
    <text>Level I or II Dental Assistant working under the direct supervision of an orthodontist may also perform the following functions:</text>
    <text>Preparing and fitting orthodontic bands;</text>
    <text>Removing excess cement from around orthodontic bands;</text>
    <text>Placing and removing arch wires;</text>
    <text>Cementing orthodontic bands, placing bonded attachments, or removing cemented or bonded orthodontic bands and attachments;</text>
    <text>Placing elastics and ligatures; and</text>
    <text>Selecting headgear.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9004.5.</num>
    <text>A dentist shall not delegate to a dental assistant any of the following procedures:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Those procedures excluded by 17 DCMR ยง 4215.1;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A preliminary dental examination;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A complete prophylaxis, including the removal of any deposits, diseased crevicular tissue, accretion, or stain from the surface of a tooth or a restoration;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The intraoral polishing of a tooth or a restoration;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The charting of cavities during preliminary examination, prophylaxis, or polishing; however, a dentist may permit an assistant to record the charting of cavities as dictated by the dentist or dental hygienist during the course of a preliminary examination
        or dental procedure;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The instruction of individuals or groups of individuals in oral health care, unless it is in the dental office and done as instructed by the dentist;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The application of pit and fissure sealants;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Diagnostic screening to identify indications of oral abnormalities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Administration of local anesthesia with board identified criteria and certification;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Administration of nitrous oxide with Board identified criteria and certification;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Placement of temporary restorations; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Taking final impressions.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 5852, 5853 (July 15, 2011); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10055 (July 12, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>