<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-9309</num>
  <heading>REINSTATEMENT OF EXPIRED CERTIFICATION (ยง 17-9309)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>9309.1.</num>
    <text>If a home health aide fails to renew his or her certification, the Board shall reinstate the certification if the applicant:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Applies to the Board for reinstatement of the certification within five (5) years after the certification expires;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Provides evidence of having completed twelve (12) continuing education hours within the year prior to submission of an application; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Provides evidence of having worked for a minimum of one hundred (100) hours within the last twenty four (24) months as an HHA under the supervision of a licensed nurse or other licensed health professional.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9309.2.</num>
    <text>If an HHA fails to apply for reinstatement within five (5) years after the certification expires, the Board may reinstate the certification if the applicant provides proof of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Current certification in another jurisdiction approved by the Board; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Having practiced for a minimum of one hundred (100) hours within the last twenty-four (24) months under the supervision of a licensed nurse or other licensed health professional deemed appropriate by the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9309.3.</num>
    <text>If an HHA does not hold a certification in another jurisdiction and fails to apply for reinstatement within five (5) years after his or her certification expires, the applicant shall meet the requirements for certification pursuant to ยง 9304.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8359, 8366 (July 13, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>