<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-9003</num>
  <heading>EDUCATION REQUIREMENT (§ 17-9003)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>9003.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall be registered as a Level I Dental Assistant or Level II Dental Assistant unless he or she has graduated from high school or has a general equivalency diploma.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9003.2.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § 9003.3, an applicant for a registration as a Level II Dental Assistant shall provide satisfactory evidence to the Board of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That the applicant has successfully completed and graduated from an educational program for dental assistants approved by the Board or the American Dental Association’s (ADA) Commission on Dental Accreditation (CODA);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That the applicant possesses a current and valid certification as a Certified Dental Assistant from the Dental Assisting National Board (DANB); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>That the applicant has completed a dental assisting program approved by the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9003.3.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the requirements of § 9003.2, an applicant for a registration as a Level II Dental Assistant may be granted a registration if the applicant registers no later than September 17, 2012 and provides satisfactory evidence of the following:</text>
    <text>That the applicant has been performing the duties of a dental assistant on the effective date of this chapter; and</text>
    <text>That the applicant has demonstrated competency to perform the duties of a dental assistant to the satisfaction of the supervising dentist.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9003.4.</num>
    <text>As a prerequisite to registration, a dental assistant shall present proof to the Board that he or she has completed a course in dental radiography training that the Board deems satisfactory.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 5852, 5853 (July 15, 2011); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10055 (July 12, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>