<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-9327</num>
  <heading>HOME HEALTH AIDE TRAINING PROGRAM CURRICULUM (§ 17-9327)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>9327.1.</num>
    <text>Core training requirements include:</text>
    <text>Cardio-pulmonary resuscitation (CPR) – basic life support (BLS) for Healthcare Providers;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>First aid;</text>
    </level>
    <text>The role of nursing assistive personnel;</text>
    <text>Client rights and privacy;</text>
    <text>Legal and ethical duties, including recognition, prevention, and reporting of abuse or neglect;</text>
    <text>Care sensitive to culture, religion, national origin, gender identity, and sexual orientation;</text>
    <text>Interpersonal communication;</text>
    <text>Receiving delegation and working as a member of the health care team;</text>
    <text>Basic safety skills;</text>
    <text>Infection prevention, including standard precautions;</text>
    <text>Delegated nursing functions including:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Taking and documenting vital signs, intake and output, and other routine observations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Measuring and documenting the client’s height and weight; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Recognizing, reporting, and documenting abnormal changes in behavior or body functions;</text>
    </level>
    <text>Basic restorative skills, including safe transfer, ambulation, maintaining range of motion, and positioning;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Personal care skills, including but not limited to bathing, feeding, hydration, skin care, dressing, grooming, and toileting;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>Caring for the client’s environment;</text>
    </level>
    <text>Promoting the client’s independence;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(p)</num>
      <text>Measures for ensuring safety of clients at risk which include but are not limited to:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Cognitive impairment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Sensory deficits or impairments;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Communication limitations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Altered level of consciousness; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Agitation or combativeness;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(q)</num>
      <text>Working with agitated or combative clients, including techniques useful in the prevention of abuse;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(r)</num>
      <text>Prohibition on use of restraints;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(s)</num>
      <text>End of life care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(t)</num>
      <text>Supporting individuals with cognitive, intellectual or developmental disabilities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(u)</num>
      <text>Supporting individuals with behavioral problems;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(v)</num>
      <text>Basic emergency procedures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(w)</num>
      <text>Preventing fatigue and burn-out;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(x)</num>
      <text>Types of abusive behavior; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(y)</num>
      <text>Requirements of reporting incidents.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9327.2.</num>
    <text>Training requirements specific to the role of the HHA shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Tasks and responsibilities of an HHA;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Implementation of a plan of care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Legal and ethical considerations for an HHA;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Respect for client property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Personal and community safety for an HHA;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Delegated nursing functions:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Basic restorative skills, including transfers, ambulation, range of motion, and positioning, that are appropriate for the home setting;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Assisting with self-administration of medication;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Administering an enema;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Care of ostomy including skin and changing appliance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Administering oxygen therapy; and</text>
    </level>
    <text>Medication administration following medication aide certification;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The foundations for working with the home care client, the family, and significant others of the client and home care team members, including:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Family dynamics;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Communication with the client, the client’s family, and significant others in the home setting;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Dealing with barriers to communication in the home;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Communication with the home care team;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Maintaining relationships with the client, the client’s family, and significant others;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Understanding basic human needs; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Individual, family, and cultural differences;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Foundations for a safe client environment, including:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>General home safety;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Infection prevention in the home;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Fire safety in the home setting;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Emergencies in the home setting;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Home care considerations, including:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Food and nutrition, meal planning, and meal preparation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Housekeeping, laundering, and food shopping;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Maintenance of a clean, safe, and healthy environment; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Use and care of medical equipment in the home; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Simple procedures such as non-sterile dressings; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Understanding and working with various client populations in home care settings including:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Introduction to infant and child care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Mental and physical disabilities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Chronic illness and disease conditions;</text>
    </level>
    <text>Caring for the terminal client in the home;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The elderly client; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Proper use of assistive devices, such as lifts, prosthetic, and orthotic devices.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9327.3.</num>
    <text>The training program for an HHA using Board-approved model curriculum shall provide a minimum of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>One hundred twenty-five hours (125) of didactic and clinical training consisting of sixty-five (65) hours of classroom instruction, twenty (20) hours of laboratory, and forty (40) hours of clinical; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Thirty-two hour (32) of didactic and clinical training in a certified nursing assistant (CNA) bridge course consisting of sixteen (16) hours of classroom and laboratory, and sixteen (16) hours of clinical.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9327.4.</num>
    <text>Each training program’s curriculum shall prepare trainees to practice as required in § 9315 prior to any direct contact with a client.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9327.5.</num>
    <text>Each training program shall report to the Board for approval of any proposed change in its curriculum prior to the implementation of the change.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9327.6.</num>
    <text>Each training program shall have a sufficient number of qualified instructors to meet the purposes and objectives of the program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9327.7.</num>
    <text>The training program shall be coordinated by a registered nurse with:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A current, unencumbered license issued by the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>At least two (2) years of experience as a registered nurse; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Clinical experience in the practice setting that he or she is coordinating.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9327.8.</num>
    <text>The program coordinator’s responsibilities shall include, but not be limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Ensuring that the curriculum is coordinated and implemented in accordance with this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Establishing job descriptions stating the responsibilities of the instructors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Ensuring that each instructor meets the qualifications specified in this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Ensuring that each student is properly supervised during the student’s clinical experience; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Ensuring that each clinical preceptor evaluates the student’s performance and provides the evaluation results to the clinical instructor.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9327.9.</num>
    <text>The training programs for HHAs shall be performed by a licensed nurse who is:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Licensed as a registered nurse in the District of Columbia and has a minimum of two (2) years of current clinical experience in the clinical practice setting in which he or she teaches; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Licensed as a practical nurse in the District of Columbia and has a minimum of three (3) years of current clinical experience in the home or residential settings.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9327.10.</num>
    <text>A licensed, qualified health professional as listed in D.C. Official Code § 3-1201.02 (2012 Supp.) who has a minimum of two (2) years of experience may offer training to HHAs in non-nurse related content.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9327.11.</num>
    <text>The following conditions shall be met when clinical preceptors are used:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The criteria for selecting a clinical preceptor shall be in writing and shall include the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The method of selecting clinical preceptors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The plans for orientation of clinical preceptors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The clinical objectives or outcomes of the preceptorship; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A system for monitoring and evaluating the preceptor’s learning experiences.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9327.12.</num>
    <text>There shall be a written agreement between the preceptor and the training program specifying the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The clinical objectives or outcomes; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The system used for monitoring and evaluating the trainee’s learning experiences.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9327.13.</num>
    <text>The clinical instructor shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Retain responsibility for the trainee’s learning experiences and meet periodically with the clinical preceptor and the trainee to monitor and evaluate the trainee’s learning experiences; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be readily available, either directly or by a communication device, when preceptors are in the clinical area.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9327.14.</num>
    <text>The clinical preceptor shall have:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A minimum of two (2) years of experience as a licensed nurse or HHA;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Experience providing direct client care during the five (5) years immediately preceding the date of the written agreement between the preceptor and the training program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A philosophy of health care congruent with that of the HHA program; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Current knowledge of practice at the HHA level.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9327.15.</num>
    <text>Each clinical instructor and preceptor shall be licensed or certified in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9327.16.</num>
    <text>Clinical instruction shall be offered in the setting in which the HHA shall work.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9327.17.</num>
    <text>The ratio of clinical instructors to trainees in clinical areas involving direct care of clients shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be based upon the client acuity level, skill level of the trainee, and the clinical setting; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Not exceed one (1) instructor or preceptor to two (2) HHAs.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9327.18.</num>
    <text>Each clinical instructor and preceptor’s qualifications shall be documented in the official records of the program and shall be available for review by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9327.19.</num>
    <text>Each clinical instructor shall be responsible for:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Assisting in the development, implementation, and evaluation of the purpose, philosophy, and objective of the training program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Helping to implement and evaluate the curriculum;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Facilitating preceptor participation in the program and evaluating the progress and retention of preceptors in the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Giving guidance to preceptors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Evaluating preceptor achievement in the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Providing for preceptor and peer evaluation of his or her teaching effectiveness; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Participating in continuing nursing education programs to improve his or her competence in areas of responsibilities.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8359, 8376 (July 13, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>