<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-1027</num>
  <heading>STANDARDS OF CONDUCT FOR REPRESENTATIVES (§ 18-1027)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1027.1.</num>
    <text>No representative appearing at a hearing pursuant to § 1025 shall do any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Engage in behavior that disrupts the hearing.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Refuse to obey the instructions of a hearing examiner as to procedure.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Engage in actions or verbal conduct that show disrespect for the hearing examiner.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Encourage or induce a respondent or witness to make a statement or offer evidence, that the representative knows or reasonably should have known is false, fraudulent or misleading.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1027.2.</num>
    <text>No person who entered an appearance or was named in an affidavit required by § 1025.9 within the previous one (1) year period may offer any Department employee any gift, gratuity or thing of value.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1027.3.</num>
    <text>No non-attorney representative may represent to a current or prospective client that they are an attorney at law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1027.4.</num>
    <text>No person offering advice or representation with respect to an adjudication may solicit potential clients in a building, or on the sidewalks adjacent to such a building, in which the Department offers hearings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1027.5.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of § 1027.4, soliciting shall include offering any information to a respondent that identifies the person’s services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1027.6.</num>
    <text>No representative shall accept payment for their services inside a building occupied by the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1027.7.</num>
    <text>Any person who violates any provision of this section may be barred from representing a respondent for a period to be determined by the Chief Hearing Examiner, based upon the extent of the violation(s) and whether the person was previously barred.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1027.8.</num>
    <text>Prior to taking the action in § 1027.7, the Chief Hearing Examiner shall send a notice, by regular mail to the person’s business address or, if none can be determined, to the person’s home address.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1027.9.</num>
    <text>The notice in § 1027.8 shall state the grounds for the action, the proposed duration of the bar, and inform the person of his or her right to a hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1027.10.</num>
    <text>The hearing on the proposed bar shall be conducted by the Director or his or her designee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1027.11.</num>
    <text>Following the hearing, the Director or his or her designee shall issue an order, which shall be sent by regular mail to the address in § 1027.8.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1027.12.</num>
    <text>No decision or order of the Chief Hearing Examiner or the Director or his or her designee under this section may be appealed to the Traffic Adjudication Appeals Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 849 (February 10, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>