<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-1209</num>
  <heading>PARKING BICYCLES ON PUBLIC SPACE (§ 18-1209)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1209.1.</num>
    <text>A person may secure a bicycle to a stanchion for a period of not more than twelve (12) consecutive hours, by means of a lock or similar device, in accordance with the requirements of § 1209.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1209.2.</num>
    <text>A person may secure a bicycle to a stanchion by means of a lock or similar device as long as securing the bicycle does not obstruct or unduly impede traffic or pedestrian movement and as long as securing bicycles has not been forbidden by any notice
      posted by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1209.3.</num>
    <text>No person shall secure a bicycle to any of the following publicly-owned facilities:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Fire hydrants;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Police and fire call boxes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Electric traffic signal poles;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Stanchions or poles located within bus zones or stands;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Stanchions or poles located within twenty-five feet (25 ft.) of an intersection;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Trees under ten inches (10 in.) in diameter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1209.4.</num>
    <text>There shall be no fee charged for use of parking meter stanchions used in accordance with these regulations; Provided, that the parking space adjacent to the meter is not occupied by the bicycle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1209.5.</num>
    <text>The Director may remove any bicycle secured to a stanchion which is not in compliance with this section; Provided, that the bicycle is impounded in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1209.6.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in this chapter, no person shall park a bicycle:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Upon a highway other than the roadway against the curb; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Upon a sidewalk; except in a rack to support the bicycle, against a building, or at the curb in such a manner as to afford the least obstruction to pedestrian traffic.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1209.7.</num>
    <text>All provisions of this section shall be equally applicable to the parking or securing of motorized bicycles.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 72-13 effective June 30, 1972, 32 DCRR §§ 11.503(a) &amp;#8211; (d), Special Edition; as amended by § 2(z) of the District of Columbia Motorized Bicycle Act, D.C. Law 1-110, 23 DCR 4954 (January 21, 1977) and as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 53 DCR 6101 (July 28, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>