<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-109</num>
  <heading>DUPLICATE OR MODIFIED LICENSES AND SPECIAL IDENTIFICATION CARDS (ยง 18-109)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>109.1.</num>
    <text>If a learner&amp;#8217;s permit, a provisional permit, special identification card or driver&amp;#8217;s license issued under the provisions of this chapter is lost or destroyed, the person to whom the permit, license, or special identification card
      was issued may obtain a duplicate, or substitute, upon furnishing proof satisfactory to the Director that the permit, license, or special identification card has been lost or destroyed, and payment of the required fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>109.2.</num>
    <text>Unless the Department is notified of the non-receipt of a license within thirty (30) days of issuance of a temporary license, the required fee for a duplicate shall be paid.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>109.3.</num>
    <text>Whenever any person, after applying for a driver&amp;#8217;s license or special identification card, moves from the address set forth in the application, that person shall, within five (5) days thereafter, notify the Director in writing of both the
      old and new addresses.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>109.4.</num>
    <text>Whenever any person, after receiving a driver&amp;#8217;s license or special identification card, moves from the address set forth in the license or special identification card, that person shall, within five (5) days thereafter, notify the Director
      in writing of both the old and new addresses and of the number of the license or special identification card.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>109.5.</num>
    <text>Whenever the name of any person who has received a driver&amp;#8217;s license or special identification card is changed by marriage or otherwise, that person shall, within five (5) days thereafter, notify the Director in writing of his or her former
      and new names and of the number of the license or special identification card.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>109.6.</num>
    <text>No later than thirty (30) days after providing notice as required by ยง 109.4 or ยง 109.5, the person must appear at the Department with supporting documentation, surrender their old license or special identification card, and obtain a new license or
      special identification card.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 2065 (March 4, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 845 (February 10, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>