<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-1016</num>
  <heading>STYLE OF PLEADINGS AND PETITIONS (§ 18-1016)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1016.1.</num>
    <text>All pleadings, notices, orders and other papers filed under the provisions of this chapter shall be captioned &amp;#8220;Before the Department of Motor Vehicles of the District of Columbia.&amp;#8221;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1016.2.</num>
    <text>A document shall contain the Department Docket Number, if assigned.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1016.3.</num>
    <text>Each petition filed under this chapter shall be styled in the manner of pleadings as provided in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1016.4.</num>
    <text>Each document shall contain a title appropriate to the proceedings which describe generally the type of document it purports to be, such as one of the following;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>&amp;#8220;In the Matter of the Revocation (or Suspension) of (license, registration) of (person whose license or registration is revoked or suspended);&amp;#8221;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>&amp;#8220;In the Matter of the Adoption of a Rule Relating to ____;&amp;#8221;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>&amp;#8220;In the Matter of an Amendment (or Repeal) of Rule No. ____of the rules relating to ____;&amp;#8221;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>&amp;#8220;In the Matter of Applicability of Rule (or Order) No. ____of the rules relating to ____;&amp;#8221;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>&amp;#8220;In the Matter of an Application for a Certificate of Self-Insurance under D.C. Code § 40-494;&amp;#8221; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>&amp;#8220;Motion to ____.&amp;#8221;</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1016.5.</num>
    <text>Each petition shall meet the general requirements of documents under §§ 1010, 1011, and 1012.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1016.6.</num>
    <text>Upon filing, each petition shall be given a docket number and shall become a matter of public record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1016.7.</num>
    <text>Each petition shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A concise statement of the facts which tends to show the petitioner&amp;#8217;s interest;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Supporting data, facts, or evidence upon which petitioner relies as justification for the action prayed for; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A prayer for the order to which the petitioner believes he or she may be entitled.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 4399 (June 6, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 5988 (July 25, 2003)</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>