<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-1201</num>
  <heading>SAFE OPERATION OF BICYCLES, AND MOTORIZED BICYCLES (ยง 18-1201)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1201.1.</num>
    <text>Every person who propels a vehicle by human power or rides a bicycle on a highway shall have the same duties as any other vehicle operator under this title, except as otherwise expressly provided in this chapter, and except for those duties imposed
      by this title which, by their nature or wording, can have no reasonable application to a bicycle operator.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.2.</num>
    <text>A person shall operate a bicycle, sidewalk bicycle or personal mobility device in a safe and non-hazardous manner so as not to endanger himself or herself or any other person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.3.</num>
    <text>(a) A person operating a bicycle may overtake and pass another vehicle only under conditions which permit the movement to be made with safety.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A person operating a bicycle may overtake and pass other vehicles on the left or right side, staying in the same lane as the overtaken vehicle, or changing to a different lane, or riding off the roadway, as necessary to pass with safety.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If a lane is partially occupied by vehicles that are stopped, standing, or parked in that lane, a person operating a bicycle may ride in that or in the next adjacent lane used by vehicles proceedings in the same direction.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.4.</num>
    <text>No person shall operate or ride a bicycle other than upon or astride a regular seat attached to the bicycle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.5.</num>
    <text>No person shall operate or ride on a bicycle with more persons on it at any one time than the bicycle is equipped to carry.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.6.</num>
    <text>No person shall operate or ride a bicycle while carrying any package, bundle, or article which prevents the operator from keeping at least one hand on the handle bars.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.7.</num>
    <text>Persons riding upon a roadway shall not ride more than two abreast except on paths or part of roadways set aside for the exclusive use of bicycles. Persons riding two abreast shall not impede the normal and reasonable movement of traffic and, on a
      lane roadway, shall ride within a single lane.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.8.</num>
    <text>No person shall operate a bicycle at a speed in excess of any posted limit or at a speed which is greater than is reasonable and prudent under the conditions then existing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.9.</num>
    <text>There shall be no prohibition against any person riding a bicycle or personal mobility device upon a sidewalk within the District, so long as the rider does not create a hazard; provided, that no person shall ride a bicycle or operate a personal mobility
      device upon a sidewalk within the Central Business District except on those sidewalks expressly designated by Order of the Mayor, nor shall any person ride a bicycle upon a sidewalk in any area outside of the Central Business District if it is expressly
      prohibited by Order of the Mayor and appropriate signs to such effect are posted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.10.</num>
    <text>Any person riding a bicycle or personal mobility device upon a sidewalk shall yield the right-of-way to pedestrians, and shall travel at a speed no greater than the posted speed limit of the adjacent roadway; provided, that such speed is safe for
      the conditions then existing on the sidewalk.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.11.</num>
    <text>A person propelling a bicycle or operating a personal mobility device upon and along a sidewalk or while crossing a roadway in a crosswalk shall have all the rights and duties applicable to a pedestrian under the same circumstances, except that the
      bicyclist or personal mobility device operator must yield to pedestrians on the sidewalk or crosswalk.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.12.</num>
    <text>The operator of a bicycle or personal mobility device emerging from, or entering an alley, driveway, or building, shall upon approaching a sidewalk, or the sidewalk area extending across any alleyway, yield the right-of-way to all pedestrians approaching
      on said sidewalk, and upon entering the roadway shall yield the right-of-way to all vehicles approaching on said roadway, to the extent necessary to safely enter the flow of traffic.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.13.</num>
    <text>No bicyclist shall suddenly leave a sidewalk and ride into the path of a vehicle which is so close that it is impossible for the driver to yield.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.14.</num>
    <text>No person operating a bicycle shall sound any warning device at any intersection so as to interfere with the obedience to the instructions of official traffic control signals or to the directions of police traffic control officers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.15.</num>
    <text>No person shall operate a bicycle except in obedience to the instructions of official traffic control signals, signs, and other control devices applicable to vehicles, unless otherwise directed by a police officer or other person authorized to direct
      and control traffic.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.16.</num>
    <text>No person riding upon a bicycle shall attach himself or herself or the device upon which he or she is riding to any vehicle upon a highway, roadway, or in an alley.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.17.</num>
    <text>All provisions of this section shall be equally applicable to the operation and riding of motorized bicycles, except as specifically provided in this chapter; provided, that nothing in this chapter shall be construed as to limit the applicability
      of Chapters 1, 4, 5, 6, and 7 with respect to the licensing, registration, inspection, or equipment of motorized bicycles or motorcycles.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.18.</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise permitted for a motor vehicle, no person shall operate a motorized bicycle on any sidewalk or any off-street bikepath or bicycle route within the District. This prohibition shall apply even though the motorized bicycle is being
      operated solely by human power.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.19.</num>
    <text>A motorized bicycle may be operated on any part of a roadway designated for the use of bicycles.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 72-13 effective June 30, 1972, 32 DCRR ยง 11.201, 11.203, Special Edition; as amended by Regulation No. 74-5 effective April 21, 1974; by ยง 2(z) of the District of Columbia Motorized Bicycle Act, D.C. Law 1 110, 23 DCR 4954 (January
        21, 1977); by Final Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 4930 (November 7, 1980) incorporating text of Proposed Rulemaking at 27 DCR 4153 (September 19, 1990);as amended by D.C. Act published at 52 DCR 1446 (February 18, 2005); as amended by D.C. Act
        published at 53 DCR 10225 (December 29, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>