<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-1303</num>
  <heading>ISSUANCE OF COMMERCIAL DRIVERS LICENSE (§ 18-1303)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1303.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall be issued a commercial driver’s license unless that person meets the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Is a resident of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Meets the following conditions:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Possesses a commercial driver’s instruction license; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Has met the requirements of §§ 1315 and 1316 of this chapter, unless granted a waiver pursuant to § 1318;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Meets requirements provided in § 1327; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Surrenders his or her non-commercial or commercial driver’s license from any state.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1303.2.</num>
    <text>A commercial driver who establishes residency in the District of Columbia shall apply for a commercial driver’s license within thirty (30) days after establishing residency, and shall otherwise comply with the requirements of this Chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1303.3.</num>
    <text>A commercial driver who applies to operate a commercial motor vehicle in a different group or endorsement from the group or endorsement in which the applicant already has a commercial driver’s license shall fill out the application in § 1301 and pass
      all applicable tests specified in §§ 1315 and 1316 for the new vehicle group or different endorsements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1303.4.</num>
    <text>A commercial driver’s license or commercial driver’s instruction license shall not be issued to a person while the person is subject to a disqualification from driving a commercial vehicle or while the person’s driving privileges are suspended, revoked
      or cancelled in the District of Columbia or any state.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1303.5.</num>
    <text>A commercial driver’s license or commercial driver’s instruction license shall not be issued to a person who has a commercial driver’s license issued by any other state unless the person first surrenders the license to the Department of Motor Vehicles,
      who shall return the license to the issuing state(s) for cancellation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1303.6.</num>
    <text>No person shall be allowed to renew a commercial driver’s license or convert an out-of-state commercial driver’s license to a District of Columbia commercial driver’s license, if the commercial driver’s license has expired for more than sixty (60)
      days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 10913 (November 26, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>