<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-1403</num>
  <heading>ROUTING (ยง 18-1403)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1403.1.</num>
    <text>The following roadways have been posted for the interstate routing of hazardous materials through the District of Columbia by motor vehicles required to display markings or placards:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Interstate 295 from the D.C. &amp;#8211; Md. boundary at Oxon Run Creek, to the interchange with Interstate 695 in the vicinity of 11th and L Streets, S.E.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Interstate 695, from the interchange with Interstate 295, in the vicinity of 11th and L Streets, S.E., to the interchange with Interstate 395, in the vicinity of 2nd and E Streets, S.W.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Interstate 395 from the D.C. &amp;#8211; Va. boundary, to the interchange with Interstate 695 in the vicinity of 2nd and E Streets, S.W.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Anacostia Freeway from the Kevin Welch Memorial Bridge, to East Capitol Street; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Kenilworth Avenue, N.E., from East Capitol Street to the D.C. &amp;#8211; Maryland line.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1403.2.</num>
    <text>No motor vehicle, trailer, or other cargo-carrying body which is transporting hazardous materials, and is required to display markings or placards, shall enter the following tunnels or any access ramp to the tunnels:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Interstate &amp;#8211; 395 freeway tunnel from the south portal to the most northerly portal at K Street, N. W.; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Ninth Street Expressway tunnel from the north portal at Madison Drive to the south portal, which is south of Independence Avenue.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1403.3.</num>
    <text>Through hazardous materials traffic, while in the District of Columbia, is restricted to routes designated in ยง 1403.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8861 (November 3, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>