<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-1100</num>
  <heading>VIOLATONS OF LICENSE PROVISIONS (ยง 18-1100)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1100.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall do any act forbidden by or fail to perform any act required by the provisions of chapters 1 through 9 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.2.</num>
    <text>No person shall display, cause or permit to be displayed, or have in his or her possession any canceled, revoked, suspended, fictitious, or fraudulently altered driver&amp;#8217;s license or any card or other document which such person holds out or
      represents as being a valid motor vehicle license issued by the District or any federal, state, territorial, or foreign government (or any agency or political subdivision of any of the foregoing) unless the card or document has been issued as represented.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.3.</num>
    <text>No person shall lend his or her driver&amp;#8217;s license to any other person or knowingly permit the use of the license by another person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.4.</num>
    <text>No person shall display or represent as his or her own, any driver&amp;#8217;s license not issued to him or her.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.5.</num>
    <text>No person shall fail or refuse to surrender to the Department upon lawful demand any driver&amp;#8217;s license which has been suspended, revoked, or canceled.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.6.</num>
    <text>No person shall use a false or fictitious name in any application for an driver&amp;#8217;s license or knowingly make a false statement, knowingly conceal a material fact, or otherwise commit a fraud in any such application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.7.</num>
    <text>No person shall permit any unlawful use of an operator&amp;#8217;s license issued to him or her.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.8.</num>
    <text>No person shall give information knowing the same to be false or knowingly swear or affirm falsely to any matter or thing required by the terms of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.9.</num>
    <text>No person whose license to operate a motor vehicle is subject to any restriction or restrictions shall operate a motor vehicle in the District unless he or she, the motor vehicle, or both he or she and the motor vehicle, comply in every respect with
      the restriction(s).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.10.</num>
    <text>No person shall aid or assist, or attempt to aid or assist, another person to obtain a license by misrepresentation, making a false statement, knowingly concealing a material fact, or otherwise committing a fraud;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.11.</num>
    <text>No person shall aid or assist, offer to aid or assist, or solicit for a fee charged, directly or indirectly, any person to obtain a license in or around any building or premises in which licenses are issued, or to interfere in any manner with any
      person or persons engaged in issuing or applying for such licenses in or around any building or premises.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1100.12.</num>
    <text>No person shall authorize or knowingly permit a motor vehicle owned by him or her or under his or her control to be driven by any person who is not authorized under the provisions of this title, or who is not licensed for the type or class of vehicles
      to be driven or in violation of any of the provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>