<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-1002</num>
  <heading>ADOPTION OF ADMINISTRATIVE RULES AND REGULATIONS (ยง 18-1002)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1002.1.</num>
    <text>Whenever the Director proposes to adopt, amend, or repeal a rule or regulation, the adoption and promulgation of which has been delegated to the Director, any interested party or parties may submit data or views on the action proposed in the form
      of a written petition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.2.</num>
    <text>Any interested party or parties may petition in writing to the Director for the adoption, repeal, or amendment of any rule, the authority for which has been delegated to the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.3.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt, the Director may refer a petition to the Chief Examiner with a request for a written report on the advisability of any action to be taken upon the petition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.4.</num>
    <text>The Chief Examiner shall submit his or her report as soon thereafter as is possible with recommendations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.5.</num>
    <text>If the Director determines that the petition discloses sufficient reasons in support of the prayers therein to justify the institution of public rulemaking, an appropriate notice will be issued to all petitioners that a public hearing will be held
      on the matter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.6.</num>
    <text>If the Director determines that the petition does not show sufficient grounds to justify rulemaking procedures, petitioner will be so notified together with the grounds for denial.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.7.</num>
    <text>The Director may order a hearing to be held prior to the adoption, amendment or repeal of a rule in the manner prescribed in this chapter, insofar as said procedures are applicable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.8.</num>
    <text>The Examiner to whom the proceeding has been assigned shall submit to the Director a summary of the arguments of both sides and an initial decision which shall contain a statement of findings of fact and conclusions based thereon as well as the reasons
      thereof, and a proposed draft of any recommended rule or amendment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.9.</num>
    <text>The Director shall file any rule, amendment, or repeal thereof approved by him or her with the Office of Documents and Administrative Issuances.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1002.10.</num>
    <text>If any rule is adopted pursuant to proceedings initiated by petition of any interested party, a copy of the rule shall be delivered to the party.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>