<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-1110</num>
  <heading>PENALTIES FOR VIOLATIONS (ยง 18-1110)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1110.1.</num>
    <text>Any person violating any provision of any of the following sections or subsections shall, upon conviction, be punished by a fine of not more than</text>
    <text>one thousand dollars ($1,000.00), or by imprisonment for not more than thirty (30) days , or both:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Sections 1101, 1102, 1103, 1104, or 1105 of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>REPEALED</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Subsection 500.2 of chapter 5 (which requires motor vehicle dealers to be licensed);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Subsection 900.1 of chapter 9 (which requires driving instructors to be licensed);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>REPEALED; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Subsection 2403.4 of chapter 24 (which prohibits unauthorized use of an emergency parking permit).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1110.2.</num>
    <text>Any person who obtains or attempts to obtain or who aids, assists, or attempts to aid or assist another person to obtain a license by misrepresentation, or who permits his or her motor vehicle license to be used by any person other than the one to
      whom issued, or who changes the name of the licensee appearing on any such license, or who makes any other alteration on such license, or who uses the license of another, shall be punished by a fine of not more than three hundred dollars ($ 300)
      or imprisonment not to exceed ten (10) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1110.3.</num>
    <text>Any person whose license has been suspended or revoked, and who, after due notice of such suspension or revocation, shall refuse to deliver such suspended or revoked license or duplicate thereof or both to the Director within the time specified in
      such notice of suspension or revocation, shall be punished by a fine of not more than one hundred dollars ($ 100).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1110.4.</num>
    <text>Any person found guilty of violating any provision of ยง 736 of this title (which prohibits possession or use of radar detectors and jammers) shall, upon conviction of the violation, be subject to a fine of not more than three hundred dollars ($ 300).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1110.5.</num>
    <text>Any person violating any provision of ยง 1100 of this chapter or any other provision of this title for which a penalty is not specifically provided shall, upon determination of liability for the violation be subject to a civil fine or other sanction(s),
      pursuant to the provisions of the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1110.6.</num>
    <text>Any person found violating subsection 1200.8 of Chapter 12 (which prohibits tampering with a bicycle locked or placed in a rack, or otherwise secured), shall be punished by a fine of not more than three hundred dollars ($300.00) or imprisonment not
      to exceed ten (10) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 850 (February 10, 2006); as amended by 54 DCR 5764 (February 2,2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>