<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-1316</num>
  <heading>COMMERCIAL DRIVERS LICENSE SKILLS TEST (§ 18-1316)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1316.1.</num>
    <text>Any applicant for a commercial driver license shall pass each section of a commercial driver’s license skills test that meets the standards set forth in 49 CFR 383.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1316.2.</num>
    <text>The passing score for each of the sections of the test required by § 1316.1 is eighty percent (80%) or higher.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1316.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant may not take the commercial driver’s license skills test until at least thirty (30) days have elapsed from the issuance of a learner’s permit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1316.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant must wait the following periods after failing a commercial driver’s license skills test:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>At least sixty (60) days from the first unsuccessful attempt; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>At least ninety (90) days from any subsequent unsuccessful attempt.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1316.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant may take the commercial driver’s license skills test no more than four (4) times in a twelve (12) month period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1316.6.</num>
    <text>In addition to the penalty specified in subsection 103.9 of this title, if an applicant misses a CDL skills test appointment, the applicant will be assessed one failed test.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1316.7.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a commercial driver’s license who does not successfully complete the air-brake component of the driving-skill test in a vehicle or combination of vehicles equipped with air brakes, shall, if otherwise qualified, receive a commercial
      driver’s license that restricts the license holder from operating a commercial motor vehicle equipped with air brakes as provided in subsection 1313.3(b).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 10913 (November 26, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 5758 (June 17, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5764 (July 17, 2009); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking
        published 57 DCR 10912, 10915 (November 19, 2010); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 9016, 9017 (October 21, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>