<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-1212</num>
  <heading>VEHICLES USED FOR TRANSPORTING EXPLOSIVES (§ 18-1212)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1212.1.</num>
    <text>All permits for the transportation of explosives in amounts in excess of fifty (50) pounds shall be approved by the Chief of Police or his or her designated agent. The transportation shall be over a pre-arranged route prescribed by the Chief of Police
      or his or her designated agent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1212.2.</num>
    <text>Transportation of explosives shall be confined to areas outside of Zone 1 as defined by the traffic regulations of the District of Columbia, except for the purpose of delivery of the explosive within the zone.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1212.3.</num>
    <text>Every vehicle, when used for transporting explosives, shall be marked on both sides and rear with the word ‘EXPLOSIVES” in letters not less than four (4 in.) inches in height in a contrasting color. In place of the marking, the vehicle shall display
      a red flag at least twenty-four inches square (24 in.2) in such a manner that it will be readily visible from all directions with the word “EXPLOSIVES painted, stamped, or sewed thereon in white letters at least six inches (6 in.) in height.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1212.4.</num>
    <text>Every vehicle, when used for transporting explosives, shall be provided with a separate compartment solely for the explosives, and the explosives shall not be placed in any other portion of the vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1212.5.</num>
    <text>Every vehicle, when used for transporting explosives, shall be equipped with not less than two (2) fire extinguishers, suitable for use on oil fires, filled and ready for immediate use and located near the driver’s seat.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1212.6.</num>
    <text>The operator of a vehicle transporting explosives shall not leave the vehicle unattended, except while actually making deliveries.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1212.7.</num>
    <text>Vehicles transporting explosives shall not be taken into a garage, or other repair shop, for repairs or storage until all explosives have been removed from the vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1212.8.</num>
    <text>Explosives, when possible, shall be transported only during daylight hours.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1212.9.</num>
    <text>Vehicles transporting explosives shall not be driven within three hundred feet (300 ft.) of each other.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1212.10.</num>
    <text>Explosives shall not be transported in any vehicle which is coupled to and not a part of the towing vehicle, nor shall any other vehicle be towed by a vehicle transporting explosives.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1212.11.</num>
    <text>Blasting caps or detonators shall not be transported in the same vehicle with explosives.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1212.12.</num>
    <text>No metal, metal tools, oils, matches, firearms, electric storage batteries, inflammable substances, acids, oxidizing or corrosive compounds shall be transported in the body of any truck or vehicle transporting explosives.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 9, §§11(a)-(i) of the Police Regulations, May 1981.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>