<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-2428</num>
  <heading>COMMERCIAL PERMIT PARKING; ANNUAL PASS (§ 18-2428)
    <text>There is established a commercial permit parking (CPP) annual pass to provideommercial motor vehicle owners the option to purchase an annual parking passor a commercial motor vehicle to park in loading zones or at curbside parkingpaces instead of
      paying for parking at the meter in those zones.</text>
    <text>A commercial motor vehicle owner or company shall complete an application, to berovided by DDOT, including identifying information on each vehicle to beegistered for a CPP annual pass.</text>
    <text>DDOT shall provide a decal to a participating commercial motor vehicle owner toffix to each commercial motor vehicle in the owner’s fleet that isarticipating in the CPP annual pass program.</text>
    <text>The commercial parking permit decal shall display the following information:</text>
    <text>A serial number or other identifying mark; and</text>
    <text>The expiration date, which shall specify the last day that the permit for theommercial motor vehicle is effective.</text>
    <text>Except as provided in § 2428.6, a participating company shall affix a validarking decal provided by DDOT on each commercial motor vehicle in theompany’s fleet that is participating in the CPP program on the lower rightand corner of the passenger side
      window.</text>
    <text>A company that purchases seventy-five (75) permits may, subject to approval byDOT, use their company logo instead of the decal.</text>
    <text>The CPP annual pass shall allow for parking at designated loading zones duringimes specified in those zones; provided, that if no time is specified, theoading zone shall be in effect between 7:00 a.m. to 6:30 p.m., or in a meteredurbside zone during
      off-peak hours of 10:00 a.m. to 2:00 p.m. and when meternforcement is not in effect, as posted on the signs and meters in the parkingone; provided further, that such parking is otherwise consistent with therovisions of § 2402.</text>
    <text>Notwithstanding § 2404.5, a commercial motor vehicle may park outside a loadingone between the hours of 10:00 a.m. and 2:00 p.m. with a valid annual pass ift occupies no more than two (2) metered spaces or no more than forty feet (40t.) within a parking
      zone serviced by a multi-space meter.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 16844 (December 13, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>