<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-2217</num>
  <heading>CLOSED STREETS, PLAY STREETS, BUS STREETS, BUS RESTRICTED STREETS (§ 18-2217)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2217.1.</num>
    <text>Whenever authorized signs are erected indicating any street or part of the street is a play street, no person shall drive a vehicle upon any such street or portion of the street except drivers of vehicles with a destination on that street or whose
      residences are within the closed area, and then the driver shall exercise the greatest care in driving upon that street or portion of street.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2217.2.</num>
    <text>No person shall operate a vehicle on a street that has been closed to vehicular traffic except as specifically permitted by an official traffic control device.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2217.3.</num>
    <text>No person shall drive any vehicle across or over any public street at which there is any official barrier, sign, or authorized person indicating that the street is closed, except as otherwise provided.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2217.4.</num>
    <text>The speed limit for the streets designated by §§ 2217.1, 2217.2 and 2217.3 shall be fifteen (15) miles per hour.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2217.5.</num>
    <text>No vehicle except buses proceeding on a designated bus route, bicycles, personal mobility devices, and authorized emergency vehicles shall travel on those streets or portions of streets designated as bus streets or bus lanes except as provided in
      §§ 22 17.6, 2217.7, 4005 and 4006.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2217.6.</num>
    <text>Vehicles may use a single block portion of a bus street if destined for existing parking facilities within the limits of that single block portion of the bus street.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2217.7.</num>
    <text>Vehicles delivering or picking up goods within the limits of a single block portion of a bus street where direct access from adjacent streets or alleys is not provided may travel on that single block portion of the bus street.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2217.8.</num>
    <text>Whenever authorized signs are erected to restrict buses from any street or portion of street, no person shall operate a bus upon such street or portion of the street at anytime unless otherwise excepted as stated on official authorized sign.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 4322 (July 3, 1987); and amended by D.C. Act 16-553, 53 DCR 10225 (December 29, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>