<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-2413</num>
  <heading>ISSUANCE OF RESIDENTIAL PARKING PERMITS (ยง 18-2413)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2413.1.</num>
    <text>After the Director designates a block for residential permit parking, the Director may post signs on the block indicating the times, days of the week, locations, and the conditions under which parking over two (2) hours shall be by permit only.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2413.2.</num>
    <text>In cases where there are parking prohibitions in a block during part, but not all, of the period when residential permit parking regulations apply, the Director may post, at his or her discretion, residential permit parking signs on the blocks for
      the balance of the residential permit parking period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2413.3.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in ยง 2424, the Director shall issue a residential permit parking sticker upon application, and upon payment of the fee established pursuant to ยง 2415, only to the owner or the operator of a motor vehicle who resides on property
      abutting a street designated as a residential permit parking block.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2413.4.</num>
    <text>The Director may issue a residential permit parking sticker, upon application and payment of the fee established pursuant to ยง 2415, to a motor vehicle owner who resides on:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Property abutting a block designated as a residential permit parking street which is not eligible for residential permit parking because of existing parking restrictions, but which is surrounded by streets which have been designated as residential
        permit parking streets or have other restrictions which prohibit all day parking; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A private street which is not eligible for residential permit parking because of its roadway designation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2413.5.</num>
    <text>Residential permit parking stickers may be issued only for, and shall be valid only on, vehicles which are registered in the District, or which have valid reciprocity privileges in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2413.6.</num>
    <text>Buses, commercial vehicles, sightseeing vehicles and motor vehicles longer than twenty-two feet (22 ft.) shall not be issued residential permit parking stickers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2413.7.</num>
    <text>The Director may replace current residential permit parking stickers, without extension of their duration, when the sticker holder changes address from one (1) zone to a block designated for residential permit parking in a different zone, or where
      a residential permit parking sticker holder provides satisfactory evidence of the destruction of the original sticker.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2413.8.</num>
    <text>The residential parking permit shall expire on the same date that the vehicle registration expires.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2413.9.</num>
    <text>The Director shall with all deliberate speed, implement an eighteen (18) month residential parking pilot program within the boundaries of Historic Georgetown, including the area of Georgetown.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>D.C. ACT 13-459 published at 48 DCR 9435 (December 1, 2001); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 003972 (April 11, 2008); and as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 7793 (July 25, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>