<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-2701</num>
  <heading>ELIGIBILITY (§ 18-2701)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2701.1.</num>
    <text>A resident or non-resident person with a disability may apply to the Director to obtain the privileges granted under this section, if the individual meets the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Has permanently lost the use of one (1) or both legs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Is so severely disabled as to be unable to walk without the aid of a mechanical device. The term mechanical device for purposes of this section, includes wheelchairs, walkers, crutches, long leg braces, and may include canes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Suffers from any respiratory disease or ailment, as determined by the Director, after consideration of the extent that the Arterial PO2 is less than sixty (60 mm Hg), the Forced Vital Capacity (“FVC”) is less than fifty percent (50%) of the predicted
        value, the Forced Expiratory Volume in one (1) second (FEVI) is less than forty percent (40%) of the predicted value and the FEVI/FVC is less than forty percent (40%) of the actual value when measured in liters by a spirometer based on predicted
        normal values for the individual’s sex, age, and height as set forth in tables 2 through 7 on pages 89-94 of the “American Medical Association: Guides to the Evaluation of Permanent Impairment,” 2nd ed. Chicago, American Medical Association, 1984;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Is a person with a disability, as certified by a licensed physician and determined by the Director, that is permanent, and that substantially impairs the individual’s mobility; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Is a person with a disability, as certified by a licensed physician and determined by the Director, that is not permanent, but that substantially impairs the individual’s mobility for no less than five (5) weeks.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 6698 (August 21, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>