<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-2100</num>
  <heading>STANDARDS FOR PLACEMENT OF TRAFFIC CONTROL DEVICES, SIGNS, AND PAVEMENT MARKINGS§ 18-2100)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2100.1.</num>
    <text>The Director of the District Department of Transportation (Director) shall place and maintain such traffic control devices upon all streets and highways as the Director shall deem necessary to indicate and to carry out the provisions of this chapter
      or to regulate, warn, or guide traffic.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2100.2.</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia adopts the Federal Highway Administration&amp;#8217;s Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices (2003 ed., rev. 1 Nov. 2004) (MUTCD), and all subsequent editions thereof , as the official standard for traffic signs, traffic
      signals, pavement markings, and traffic control devices in the District of Columbia, with the following exceptions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The centerline pavement markings on Pennsylvania Avenue, N.W., between 3rd Street, N.W., and 15th Street, N.W., shall be white rather than yellow as required by Chapter 3B, Section 3B.01 of the MUTCD.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The countdown display on pedestrian crossing signals shall operate for the duration of the &amp;#8220;WALK&amp;#8221; interval for pre-timed traffic signals rather than operate only during the &amp;#8220;DON&amp;#8217;T WALK&amp;#8221; interval
        as required by Chapter 4E, Section 4E.07 of the MUTCD.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Lane control signs installed prior to January 1, 2008, shall be mounted along the side of the roadway rather than over the centerline of the controlled lane as required by Chapter 4J, Section 4J.03 of the MUTCD.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2100.3.</num>
    <text>Temporary traffic control measures, as published in the District of Columbia Work Zone Manual, shall conform to the standards set by Part 6 of the MUTCD. The Director may adopt additional temporary traffic control measures that are relevant to the
      unique traffic conditions of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2100.4.</num>
    <text>The most recent edition of the MUTCD and the District of Columbia Work Zone Manual may be reviewed at the offices of the District Department of Transportation, 2000 14th Street, N.W., 7th Floor, Washington, D.C. 20009. Copies may also be obtained,
      upon request, from the Director upon payment of a reasonable copying fee to be determined by the Director. The most recent edition of the MUTCD may also be found on the District Department of Transportation website: http://www.ddot.dc.gov.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 5277(May 2, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>