<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-2218</num>
  <heading>FUNERAL PROCESSIONS, PARADES, AND OTHER AUTHORIZED PROCESSIONS (§ 18-2218)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2218.1.</num>
    <text>Processions and parades, except funerals, shall not be allowed except by permit issued by the Chief of Police, which permit shall designate the time and route of such procession or parade, and no part of the procession or parade shall move except
      according to the terms of the permit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2218.2.</num>
    <text>No driver of a vehicle shall drive between the vehicles comprising a funeral or other authorized procession while they are in motion and when the vehicles are conspicuously designated as required by this chapter. The provision shall not apply at intersections
      where traffic is controlled by traffic control signals or police officers, except as provided in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2218.3.</num>
    <text>Each driver in a funeral or other procession shall drive as near to the right-hand edge of the roadway as practicable and shall follow the vehicle ahead as close as is practicable and safe.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2218.4.</num>
    <text>The leading vehicle in a funeral procession shall stop at any intersection where the traffic control device requires such a stop, but after the leading vehicle has entered the intersection, all vehicles in the funeral procession shall continue their
      passage; Provided, that this subsection shall not apply when there is a funeral escort officer preceding the funeral procession.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2218.5.</num>
    <text>A funeral composed of a procession of vehicles in order to be recognized as such, shall display on each vehicle two (2) illuminated headlights.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2218.6.</num>
    <text>A funeral procession accompanied by an escort officer shall have the right-of-way and have the right to proceed through an intersection where the traffic control device normally would require a stop.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2218.7.</num>
    <text>A funeral escort officer is designated to be a person wearing a name tag on a uniform distinguishable from the Metropolitan Police Department uniform, which identifies by name the person, company, partnership, or corporation by which the escort officer
      is employed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2218.8.</num>
    <text>A funeral escort officer shall be mounted on a motorcycle equipped with the following special equipment, as well as the standard equipment required by law:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A flashing signal light of a color approved by the Department of Public Works;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A two-way radio sufficient to allow communication with the home office of the person, company, partnership, or corporation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A designation of the name of the motor escort person, company, partnership, or corporation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2218.9.</num>
    <text>A funeral escort officer shall not wear sidearms and shall not have the power of arrest.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2218.10.</num>
    <text>The vehicles in a procession returning from a funeral shall not display headlights, except during the hours when lights are required to be displayed on all motor vehicles.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Commissioners’ Order 274,310/949 effective September 1, 1949, 17 DCRR §§ 104 &amp;#8211; 107 (October 19, 1970); as amended by Commissioners’ Order 68-795 effective December 28, 1968.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>