<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-2202</num>
  <heading>OVERTAKING AND PASSING (§ 18-2202)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2202.1.</num>
    <text>The rules set forth in this section shall govern the overtaking and passing of vehicles proceeding in the same direction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2202.2.</num>
    <text>The driver of a vehicle overtaking another vehicle proceeding in the same direction shall pass to the left of the vehicle at a safe distance and shall not again drive to the right side of the roadway until safely clear of the overtaken vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2202.3.</num>
    <text>No vehicle shall at any time be driven to the left side of the roadway under the following conditions; Provided, that these restrictions shall not apply to driving on a one-way roadway:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>When approaching the crest of a grade or upon a curve in the highway where the driver’s view is obstructed within such distance as to create a hazard if another vehicle approaches from the opposite direction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>When approaching within one hundred feet (100 ft.) of or while traversing any intersection or railroad grade crossing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>On the roadway of any bridge, viaduct, or tunnel; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>On the approach roadway within one hundred feet (100 ft.) of any bridge, viaduct, or tunnel.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2202.4.</num>
    <text>Except when overtaking and passing on the right is permitted, the driver of an overtaken vehicle shall give way to the right in favor of the overtaking vehicle on audible signal and shall not increase the speed of his or her vehicle until completely
      passed by the overtaking vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2202.5.</num>
    <text>The driver of a vehicle may overtake and pass upon the right of another vehicle only under the following conditions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>When the vehicle overtaken is making or about to make a left turn;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>On a street or highway with unobstructed pavement not occupied by parked vehicles and of sufficient width for two (2) or more lines of moving vehicles in each direction; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>On a one-way street or upon any roadway upon which traffic is restricted to one direction of movement; where the roadway is free from obstructions and of sufficient width for two (2) or more lines of moving vehicles.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2202.6.</num>
    <text>The driver of a vehicle may overtake and pass another vehicle on the right only under conditions permitting such movement in safety. In no event shall the passing movement be made by driving off the pavement or main-traveled portion of the roadway.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2202.7.</num>
    <text>No vehicle shall be driven to the left side of the center of the roadway while overtaking and passing another vehicle proceeding in the same direction unless the left side is clearly visible and is free of oncoming traffic for a sufficient distance
      ahead to permit the overtaking and passing to be completed without interfering with the safe operation of any vehicle approaching from the opposite direction or any vehicle overtaken.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2202.8.</num>
    <text>In every event, an overtaking vehicle must return to the right hand side of the roadway before coming within one hundred feet (100 ft.) of any vehicle approaching from the opposite direction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2202.9.</num>
    <text>On any street where official traffic control devices have been erected giving notice that bicycles are entitled to the use of the full right-hand lane then available for moving traffic, the driver of a motor vehicle shall not drive within that right
      hand lane while overtaking or passing a bicycle being driven in that lane, and after overtaking or passing, shall not drive into that right-hand lane until safely clear of the overtaken bicycle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2202.10.</num>
    <text>A person driving a motor vehicle shall exercise due care by leaving a safe distance, but in no case less than 3 feet, when overtaking and passing a bicycle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Commissioners’ Order 274, 310/949 effective September 1, 1949, 17 DCRR § 27, 28, 29 (October 19, 1970); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 24 DCR 8653 (April 7, 1978); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 1115 (February 6,
        2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>