<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-2511</num>
  <heading>SPECIFIED ROUTES (§ 18-2511)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2511.1.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term “I-695” means that highway that is between I-295 in the vicinity of 11th and L Streets, S.E. and I-395 in the vicinity of 2nd and E Street, S.W.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2511.2.</num>
    <text>A vehicle, in accordance with the provisions and exemptions provided for in § 2501.3, 2502.3, 2502.4, and 2502.6, may operate on the following streets, roads, and highways:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>I-295 from the District of Columbia &amp;#8211; Maryland line to the Interchange with I-695 in the vicinity of 11th and L Streets, S.E.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>I-695 from the interchange with I-295 in the vicinity of 11th and L Streets, S.E., to the interchange with I-395 in the vicinity of 2nd and E Streets, S.W.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>I-395 from the Virginia &amp;#8211; D.C. line to the interchange with I-695 in the vicinity of 2nd and E Streets, S.W.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Anacostia Freeway from the 11th Street Bridge (I-295) to East Capitol Street; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Kenilworth Avenue, N.E. from East Capitol Street to the D.C. &amp;#8211; Maryland line.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2511.3.</num>
    <text>No vehicle covered by the provisions of §§ 2501.3, 2502.3, 2502.4, and 2502.6 shall be operated on any other street, highway, or road, which is not listed in § 2511.2 unless the vehicle is operated in accordance with the conditions and requirements
      of a special permit issued by the Director pursuant to § 2508.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2511.4.</num>
    <text>Procedures for approval or denial of special permits issued under § 2511.3 shall be carried out in the following manner:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An analysis of the proposed access routes will be made by application of vehicle templates to plans of the routes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Approval of access for these vehicles on any individual route applies to all vehicles of the same type regardless of ownership;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Denial of access to terminals and services will be only on the basis of safety and engineering analysis of the access route;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A request for access will be automatically approved if the request is not acted upon by the Director within ninety (90) days of receipt of the application; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Denial of access for any one hundred two inch wide (102 in./w.) vehicles will be only on the basis of the characteristics of specific routes. in particular significant deficiencies in lane width.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 3716, 3718 (June 20, 1986); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at38 DCR 6646 (November 1, 1991).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>