<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-3011</num>
  <heading>HEARING PROCEDURES (§ 18-3011)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3011.1.</num>
    <text>Each hearing will be held before a hearing examiner or the Chief Hearing Examiner. No other person has the authority to adjudicate a traffic infraction or to dismiss a notice that has been returned to the Bureau.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.2.</num>
    <text>All hearings will be open to the public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.3.</num>
    <text>Hearings will be held at the Bureau of Traffic Adjudication, 65 K Street, N.E., Washington, D.C.; provided, that the Director, in his or her discretion, may establish other permanent or temporary hearing locations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.4.</num>
    <text>The hearing examiner shall ensure that the hearing is conducted in an orderly manner and shall have the authority to exclude any respondent or other person from the hearing on the grounds of substantial interference or obstruction of the orderly hearing
      process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.5.</num>
    <text>The Bureau may, with or without the consent of the respondent, consolidate for hearing or appeal any and all matters within its jurisdiction pending against a respondent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.6.</num>
    <text>The Rules of Civil Procedure and the Rules of Criminal Procedure for the Superior Court of the District of Columbia are not binding on the Bureau of Traffic Adjudication.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.7.</num>
    <text>Forms of pleadings, motion practice, and discovery procedures set forth in the rules cited in § 3011.6 do not apply to any proceedings conducted by the Bureau unless specifically authorized by this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.8.</num>
    <text>The provisions of chapter 10 of this title, “Procedures for Administrative Hearings and Other Actions,” shall apply to all administrative adjudications conducted by the Bureau of Traffic Adjudication, except as provided by this chapter in accordance
      with the Traffic Adjudication Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>