<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-3017</num>
  <heading>TRANSCRIPTS OF HEARINGS (ยง 18-3017)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3017.1.</num>
    <text>Transcripts of the hearing proceedings may be ordered through the Bureau, on a form prescribed for that purpose.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3017.2.</num>
    <text>Fees for transcripts shall be at a rate set by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3017.3.</num>
    <text>Transcripts may be ordered upon payment of a deposit of fifty dollars ($ 50). This fee shall be refunded to any appellant who is successful in an appeal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3017.4.</num>
    <text>No notice of appeal with transcript will be accepted for fling by the Appeals Board unless accompanied by the deposit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3017.5.</num>
    <text>When the cost of the transcript has been determined to be less than the amount of the transcript deposit, the sum by which the deposit exceeds the cost of the transcript shall be refunded to the appellant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3017.6.</num>
    <text>When the cost of the transcript is determined to exceed the amount of the transcript deposit, the appellant shall be notified of the balance due for preparing the transcript. The balance due shall be paid within ten (10) days from the date of the
      notification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3017.7.</num>
    <text>If the appellant fails to make any payment when due as required by this section or if any check or other instrument offered to make any payment due is dishonored the appeal shall be dismissed by the Appeals Board without consideration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3017.8.</num>
    <text>Notice of any action taken pursuant to ยง 3017.7 shall be sent to the appellant by ordinary mail.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 4403 (June 6, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 5988 (July 25, 2003); as amended by D.C. Act 15-295 published at 51 DCR 1340 (February 6, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>