<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-301</num>
  <heading>MANDATORY REVOCATIONS (§ 18-301)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>301.1.</num>
    <text>The Director shall forthwith revoke the license of any person upon receiving a record of such person’s conviction of any of the following offenses:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Operating or being in control of a motor vehicle while the person&amp;#8217;s alcohol concentration is 0.08 grams or more either per 100 milliliters of blood or per 210 liters of breath or is 0.10 grams or more per 100 milliliters of urine, or while
        under the influence of intoxicating liquor or any drug or any combination thereof; or while the ability to operate a vehicle is impaired by the consumption of intoxicating liquor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any homicide committed by means of a motor vehicle;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Leaving the scene of an accident in which the motor vehicle driven by him or her was involved and in which there is personal injury without giving assistance or making known his or her identity and address and the identity and address of the owner
        of the vehicle;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Reckless driving or operating a motor vehicle while the ability to operate a motor vehicle is impaired by the consumption of intoxicating liquor involving personal injury;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any felony in the commission of which a motor vehicle is used; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>If the person is under twenty-one (21) years of age, operating a motor vehicle while the person’s blood, breath, or urine contains any measurable amount of alcohol.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.2.</num>
    <text>The Director shall revoke, for one (1) year, the license of any person who refuses to submit to chemical testing upon receipt of an officer’s sworn report as required by § 5(a) of the District of Columbia Implied Consent Act, approved October 21,
      1972 (86 Stat. 1018, D.C. Official Code § 50-1905(a)).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.3.</num>
    <text>The Director shall revoke the license of a person upon receipt of evidence that the person was issued a final deportation or removal order by the federal government.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 72-13 effective June 30, 1972,32 DCRR § 2.304 Special Edition; as amended by § 10 of Anti-Drunk Driving Act of 1982, D.C. Law 4-145, 29 DCR 3138, 3147 (July 23, 1982); and by § 7 of the Alcoholic C Beverage Control Act and Rules Reform
        Amendment Act of 1994, D.C. Law 10-122, 41 DCR 1658, 1664 (April 1994); as amended by D.C. Act 12-517, 46 DCR 5 (January 1, 1999); and amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 846 (Feb 10, 2006); and amended by D.C. Act 16-488 at 53 DCR
        8675 (October 27, 2006); and amended by D.C. Act 16-636 at 54 DCR 903, 908 (February 2, 2007); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 5243, 5245 (June 18, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>