<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-3004</num>
  <heading>SERVICE OF THE NOTICE OF INFRACTION (§ 18-3004)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3004.1.</num>
    <text>Service of the appropriate copy of the Notice of Infraction as provided for in § 3003 may be made in person to the operator of a vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3004.2.</num>
    <text>Personal service shall be used for moving violations and parking violations, except as otherwise provided in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3004.3.</num>
    <text>In cases of parking violations:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Where the owner or operator is not present, the appropriate copy of the notice shall be served by affixing it to the vehicle in a conspicuous and secure manner.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Where the notice of infraction is issued by an automated parking enforcement system, the appropriate copy of the notice shall be mailed to the registered owner of the vehicle.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3004.4.</num>
    <text>Service of notice by affixation to the vehicle, or by mail for notices issued by an automated parking enforcement system, shall have the same force and effect as personal service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3004.5.</num>
    <text>The operator of a vehicle who is not the owner, but who uses or operates the vehicle with the permission of the owner, either express or implied, shall be deemed to be the agent of the owner to receive service of the notice in cases of parking violations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3004.6.</num>
    <text>The Bureau shall provide, upon request of the respondent, his or her attorney, or authorized agent, photocopies of tickets or, if issued from a hand-held electronic device or automated parking enforcement system, printouts of data contained on tickets
      issued to that respondent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3004.7.</num>
    <text>The Director shall prescribe procedures for application for photocopies or, if issued from a handheld electronic device, printouts of data contained on tickets. The fee shall be one dollar ($ 1) per copy. The Director or his or her designee may waive
      or reduce the fee for good cause.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3004.8.</num>
    <text>When a notice of infraction is issued for a violation of Section 4 of the International Registration Plan Agreement Act of 1996, effective September 5, 1977 (D.C. Law 12-14; D.C. Official Code 50-1507.03), the operator of the vehicle shall be deemed
      the agent of the owner or apportioned operator for the purposes of receiving service of the notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3004.9.</num>
    <text>In the case of a moving violation where a Notice of Infraction is not issued at the time of the incident, a subsequently issued Notice shall be served as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If the respondent is a District resident, the Notice shall be personally served; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the respondent is not a District resident, the Notice shall be served by mailing the appropriate copy of the Notice by certified mail, return receipt requested to the respondent’s address as available through the Washington Area Law Enforcement
        System, or similar interstate database containing license information from state issuing agencies, or the address displayed on the respondent’s driver’s license as presented at the time the incident was first investigated,</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3004.10.</num>
    <text>In accordance with §§ 3002.9 and 3003.3, the original of a Notice of Infraction served in accordance with § 3004.9 shall be submitted to the Department of Motor Vehicles within fifteen (15) calendar days after issuance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3004.11.</num>
    <text>A submitted Notice of Infraction shall indicate proof of service as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If served pursuant to § 3004.9(a) the Notice shall be signed by the respondent; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If served pursuant to § 3004.9(b); the Notice shall be accompanied by the original certified mail receipt bearing either the respondent’s signature or a notation of signature refusal from the U.S. Postal Service.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 5558 (July 7, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 5639 (September 23, 2005); as amended by D.C. Act 17-417 published at 55 DCR 7513 (July 11, 2008); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking
        published at 58 DCR 4563 (May 27, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>