<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-307</num>
  <heading>NOTICE OF SUSPENSION OR REVOCATION (§ 18-307)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>307.1.</num>
    <text>Whenever the Director, acting under this chapter, revokes the license of any person as a consequence of a conviction for a traffic offense for which mandatory revocation is required or pursuant to § 5 of the Clean Hands Act (D.C. Code § 47-2864),
      an order of revocation shall be prepared setting forth the proposed action and the grounds therefor in sufficient detail to permit the person to understand fully the nature of the order and the reasons for the order and shall include complete information
      on the manner in which that person may seek restoration of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>307.2.</num>
    <text>Whenever the Director or a hearing examiner, pursuant to §§ 303.3 and 303.5, orders the suspension or revocation of a license because of the accumulation of traffic points, the suspension or revocation order shall include a copy of the licensee’s
      driver’s record. The notice shall notify the person that the order will take effect within ten (10) days (fifteen (15) days if the person is a non-resident), unless that person files a written objection with the Director or hearing examiner based
      solely upon the accuracy of the driving record. The filing of an objection operates as a stay of the order until the Director or hearing examiner renders a written decision on the objection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>307.3.</num>
    <text>Whenever the Director acting under this chapter, proposes to revoke or suspend the license of any person for any reason which does not require a revocation, a notice of proposed suspension or revocation shall be prepared setting forth the proposed
      action and the grounds for the proposed action in sufficient detail to permit that person to understand fully the nature of the proposed action and the reasons for the proposed action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>307.4.</num>
    <text>The notice shall take effect within ten (10) days (fifteen (15) days if the person is a non-resident) unless that person files a written petition with the Director for a hearing in which the Director must prove sufficient grounds for the proposed
      action. The demand shall be filed in the manner prescribed in chapter 10. The filing of such a demand does not operate as a stay of such order when the order has been issued revoking or suspending a permit on account of mental or physical incapacity,
      for driving while the person&amp;#8217;s alcohol concentration is 0.08 grams or more either per 100 milliliters of blood or per 210 liters of breath or is 0.10 grams or more per 100 milliliters of urine, or while under the influence of intoxicating
      liquor or any drug or any combination thereof or while the ability to operate a vehicle is impaired by the consumption of intoxicating liquor; for manslaughter when an automobile is involved, or for operating a motor vehicle equipped with a smoke
      screen. Each notice issued pursuant to this section shall inform the respondent of the effective date of the notice and the right to a hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>307.5.</num>
    <text>Any notice or order served under the authority of the rules of this chapter shall be deemed to be properly served upon the person to whom such notice is directed if a copy of the notice is served upon him personally, or if a copy of the notice is
      mailed postage prepaid to the last known address of the person to be notified.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>307.6.</num>
    <text>For the purpose of these regulations, with respect to any person licensed by the District to operate a motor vehicle or whose motor vehicle is registered in the District, the term &amp;#8220;last known address&amp;#8221; shall mean the most recent
      address shown on the records of the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>307.7.</num>
    <text>Proof of service of any notice or order in the manner specified by this section may be made by the certificate or affidavit of any officer or employee of the District, naming the person on whom the notice or order was served and specifying the time,
      place, and manner of service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 72-13 effective June 30, 1972, 32 DCRR § 2.313, 2.314, Special Edition; as amended by § 105 of the District of Columbia Motor Vehicle Act. D.C. Law 1-133,23 DCR 6720, 6721 (February 25, 1977) and 45 DCR 7872 (NOV 6, 1998); as amended
        by Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 7314 (August 10, 2001); and amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 2065 (Mar 4, 2005); amended by D.C. Act 16-488 published at 53 DCR 8675 (October 27, 2006); amended by D.C. Act 16-518, published
        at 53 DCR 9104 (November 10, 2006); amended by D.C. Act 16-636 published at 54 DCR 903, 908 (February 2, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>