<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-304</num>
  <heading>SUSPENSION FOR FAILURE TO COMPLY WITH TRAFFIC CITATIONS (§ 18-304)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>304.1.</num>
    <text>The Director is authorized to suspend the operator’s license of any resident of the District of Columbia who, having been arrested for a moving traffic violation in the District and, having been permitted to receive a traffic violation notice in lieu
      of being required to post collateral or bond to secure appearance for trial, failed to comply with the terms of the traffic violation notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>304.2.</num>
    <text>The Director may suspend the license of any resident of the District who, having been arrested for a traffic violation in another jurisdiction and, under the terms of an agreement between the District and another jurisdiction, is permitted to receive
      a citation in place of being required to post collateral or bond to secure appearance for trial, and having signed an agreement that he or she shall comply with the terms of a citation served upon him or her at the time of arrest to appear for trial,
      to post bond or collateral or to pay a fine, has failed to comply with the terms of the agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>304.3.</num>
    <text>The suspension shall remain in effect until such person shall furnish evidence satisfactory to the Director that he or she has fully complied with the terms of the citation or traffic violation notice which was the basis for the suspension order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>304.4.</num>
    <text>Pursuant to § 300.7, or under applicable law, the Director may suspend, without a hearing, the license of a resident of the District whose driving privileges have been suspended in another jurisdiction. The Director shall provide at least ten (10)
      days notice of the effective date of the suspension in the District and shall provide such notice by mail or email to the resident’s address as indicated on the Department of Motor Vehicle records.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>304.5.</num>
    <text>The suspension authorized in subsection § 304.4 shall terminate upon proof satisfactory to the Director that the licensee has been reinstated to operate a motor vehicle in the other jurisdiction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 72-13 effective June 30, 1972, 32 DCRR § 2-306, Special Edition; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 5243, 5245 (June 18, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>