<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-3007</num>
  <heading>PAYMENT OF CIVIL FINES (§ 18-3007)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3007.1.</num>
    <text>All payments may be made in cash or by check or money order at the Bureau or by check or money order through the mail.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3007.2.</num>
    <text>Checks and money orders shall be made payable to the order of the “D.C. Treasurer.”</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3007.3.</num>
    <text>Hearing Examiners may permit monetary fines and penalties in excess of fifty dollars ($ 50) to be paid in installments, in accordance with the provisions of the Traffic Adjudication Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3007.4.</num>
    <text>The Director may approve the use of credit card or debit card for the payment of fines, penalties, and fees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3007.5.</num>
    <text>Any District resident seeking a Department service listed in § 3007.6 who has admitted, been found liable, deemed admitted or is in default for at least $ 250 in unpaid fines and penalties resulting from moving or non-moving infractions, or from fines
      assessed for failure to maintain motor vehicle insurance, may participate in a deferred payment plan; provided that the resident pays at least 25% of the total amount of the outstanding debt at the time of service plus all dishonored check fees
      and pays the remaining balance not more than six (6) months after the date of the initial payment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3007.6.</num>
    <text>The deferred payment plan in § 3007.5 is available in conjunction with the following services:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Driver license issuance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Driver license renewal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Motor vehicle registration;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Removal of a boot from a motor vehicle; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Release of a towed motor vehicle.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3007.7.</num>
    <text>Plan participants seeking the removal of a boot from a vehicle or release of a vehicle must pay, in addition to the outstanding debt in § 3007.5, all applicable boot, tow and storage fees prior to receiving service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3007.8.</num>
    <text>Plan participants seeking a driver’s license or vehicle registration shall be entitled to a temporary license or registration, as applicable, valid for six (6) months. If the remainder of the outstanding debt is paid prior to the expiration of the
      six (6) month temporary registration or license, the Director may issue the applicant a full-term license or registration sticker.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3007.9.</num>
    <text>If a participant is deemed to have admitted a moving or parking violation pursuant to D.C. Official Code §§ 50-2302.05 (e) or 50-2303.05 (d) (2) during their participation in the plan, any temporary license or registration issued shall be revoked,
      or the vehicle shall become immediately eligible for booting or towing, as applicable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3007.10.</num>
    <text>All payments made pursuant to this section must be in cash, money order, cashier’s check, credit card or debit card.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3007.11.</num>
    <text>In the event that the Department offers an amnesty program under which monetary penalties are waived if outstanding fines are satisfied, persons may use the deferred payment plan described in § 3007.5 as a means of satisfying their outstanding fines;
      provided, that all penalties waived through the amnesty shall be reinstated in the event that the outstanding fines are not fully paid by the expiration of the six (6) month period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3007.12.</num>
    <text>A person is only eligible to participate in one (1) deferred payment plan at a time and no more than two (2) deferred payment plans in a year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3007.13.</num>
    <text>A person who has failed to successfully complete a deferred payment plan may not participate in another deferred payment plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3007.14.</num>
    <text>(REPEALED)</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3007.15.</num>
    <text>(REPEALED)</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3007.16.</num>
    <text>(REPEALED)</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Revised Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 7952 (Aug 16, 2002) [EMERGENCY]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 10318 (Nov 15, 2002); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 5052 (May 14, 2004); as amended
        by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 00340 (January 11, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>