<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-412</num>
  <heading>REFUSAL OF REGISTRATION (§ 18-412)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>412.1.</num>
    <text>The Director shall refuse registration and shall withhold issuance of any application for re-registration on any of the following grounds:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If the application contains any false or fraudulent statement or if the applicant has failed to furnish required information or reasonable additional information requested by the Director or if the applicant is not entitled to the issuance of certificate
        or registration of the vehicle under this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the vehicle has not been inspected as required, is unsafe or improperly equipped, or is mechanically unfit to be operated upon the highways;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If the required fee has not been paid or if a check given in payment of any fee required by this chapter has been dishonored;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>If the registrant has failed to respond to any warrant issued by request of any police authority in the District as a result of any traffic or motor vehicle parking violation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>If the registrant has failed to pay a civil fine imposed pursuant to the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act, except as provided by § 3007.5 or as otherwise provided by law.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>If the registrant has failed to furnish the insurance information required pursuant to § 413.12;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>If the insurance company listed by the registrant is not licensed by the District of Columbia Department of Insurance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>If the insurance policy number or binder number listed by the registrant is not in the form or manner utilized by the listed insurance company;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>If the certificate of self-insurance listed by the registrant is invalid;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>If the registrant has not complied with the provisions of section 619 of this Title.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Grounds established by the Clean Hands Act (D.C. Code § 47-2861 et seq.).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>If a person holds an out-of-state operator’s permit and fails to surrender that permit to the Department unless that person is a member, or a spouse of a member of the Judicial branch of the Federal government.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>If a person is not domiciled in the District of Columbia, unless the owner is exempted from the domicile requirement under section 2(c)(5) of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, approved August 17, 1937 (50 Stat. 680; D.C. Official Code
        § 50-1501.02(c)(5)).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>Has been issued a Salvage Title or Non-Repairable Vehicle Certificate.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>If the person is required to pay the heavy use vehicle tax, as described in section 4481 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954, added June 29, 1956 (70 Stat. 390, 26 U.S.C. § 4481), and does not submit proof of payment as required by section 141(c)
        of the Federal Aid Highway Amendments of 1974, added January 4, 1975 (Pub. L 93-643, 23 U.S.C. 141).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 5967 (October 17, 1997); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 7314 (August 10, 2001); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 10317 (November 15, 2002); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 50 DCR 4402 (June 6, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 5987 (July 25, 2003); as amended by D.C. Act 15-704, published at 52 DCR 1700 (February 25, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 847
        (February 10, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 1575 (February 16, 2007); as amended by D.C. Act 17-281 published at 55 DCR 1655 (February 22, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 2726 (April 10, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>