<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-413</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION FOR REGISTRATION (§ 18-413)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>413.1.</num>
    <text>REPEALED</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>413.2.</num>
    <text>REPEALED</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>413.3.</num>
    <text>Each application shall contain the information that appears on the certificate that is outstanding for the vehicle, including the current residence address of the applicant and any other information as the Director may determine. The Director shall
      deliver the application to the owner whose name appears on it or to the owner’s agent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>413.4.</num>
    <text>The Director shall not prepare an application for registration for a vehicle unless and until the owner of the vehicle has secured a certificate of title for the vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>413.5.</num>
    <text>When satisfied that the owner named in the application is entitled to registration of the vehicle described in the application, and upon receipt of all fees prescribed in this chapter (including a delivery charge to be determined by the Director in
      the event the owner desires identification tags or special bus identification forwarded to him or her), the Director shall issue to the owner a registration card and two (2) owner’s identification tags, and may also issue a temporary registration
      card that an owner who has renewed registration online may access and print from the Department’s website.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>413.6.</num>
    <text>Only one (1) identification tag shall be issued for a motorized bicycle, motorcycle, or trailer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>413.7.</num>
    <text>Identification tags shall be of the size, color, design, and material prescribed by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>413.8.</num>
    <text>Identification tags are to be used solely for the operation of the vehicle described on the registration card.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>413.9.</num>
    <text>The Director, when satisfied that the owner named in the application is entitled to registration of a prorated interstate bus and does not request identification tags, shall issue to such owner a registration card and in place of identification tags
      a special bus identification sticker. Each sticker shall be used solely for the operation of the bus described on the registration card which accompanied the sticker at the time of issuance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>413.10.</num>
    <text>Any application for a vehicle to be used as a taxicab, bus, for livery, for sightseeing purposes, or as a hearse shall be presented to an inspection station, accompanied by the vehicle. If the inspection station approves the vehicle for such use,
      the approval shall be placed on the application by the inspection station.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>413.11.</num>
    <text>Each application for registration of the following types of vehicles shall be accompanied by a certificate of inspection and approval from an inspection station: motor cranes, commercial vehicles, trailers and semi-trailers, motorcycles, and all vehicles
      sold at public auction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>413.12.</num>
    <text>The application for registration shall contain space for the applicant to furnish the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name of the insurance company that has provided the applicant with a motor vehicle insurance policy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The insurance policy number or binder number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The applicant’s signature;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The applicant’s social security number; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any other information that the Director may require.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>413.13.</num>
    <text>Motor Vehicles, other than buses, displaying irremovable commercial advertisement or insignia may be considered commercial vehicles by the Director for registration purposes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 2067 (March 4, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 847 (February 10, 2006); and Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 339 (January 11, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>