<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-4004</num>
  <heading>ONE-WAY STREETS (ยง 18-4004)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4004.1.</num>
    <text>The streets and alleys listed in this section are designated as one-way and traffic is restricted to one direction, except as provided in this section.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>26th Street, N.W., between M Street and Pennsylvania Avenue, for northbound traffic only;</text>
    </level>
    <text>32nd Street, N.W., from R Street to S Street, 4:00 p.m.-6:30 p.m., Monday-Friday, for southbound traffic only;</text>
    <text>32nd Street, N.W., from R Street to S Street, 7:00 a.m.-9:30 a.m., Monday-Friday, for northbound traffic only;</text>
    <text>47th Place, N. W., from MacArthur Boulevard to a point approximately 40 feet north of MacArthur Boulevard, for southbound traffic only, 7-9:30 a.m., Monday-Friday;</text>
    <text>Bryant Street, NW., between Georgia Avenue and 6th Street, for eastbound traffic only;</text>
    <text>C Street, N.W., from 3rd Street to a point approximately twenty feet (20&amp;#8242;) east of the main Canadian Embassy Driveway, for eastbound traffic only;</text>
    <text>Indiana Avenue, N.W., from 5th Street to 6th Street, for north-east bound traffic only;</text>
    <text>K Street, N.W., from 9th Street to 10th Street, for westbound traffic only;</text>
    <text>On Hamilton Street, N.W., between North Capitol Street and New Hampshire Avenue, for eastbound traffic only;</text>
    <text>Ontario Road, N.W., from Euclid Street to Columbia Road, for northbound traffic only;</text>
    <text>On Shepherd Street, N.W., between Kansas Avenue and 13th Street, for eastbound traffic only;</text>
    <text>On Sheridan Street, N.W., between North Capitol Street and Chillum Street, for westbound traffic only;</text>
    <text>S Street, N.W., from Wisconsin Avenue to 32nd Street, 4:00 p.m.-6:30 p.m., Monday-Friday, for eastbound traffic only;</text>
    <text>S Street, N.W., from Wisconsin Avenue to 32nd Street, 7:00 a.m.-9:30 a.m., Monday-Friday, for westbound traffic only;</text>
    <text>Varnum Street, N.W., between Rock Creek Church Road and 2nd Street, westbound traffic only.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>14th Street, N.E., between Michigan Avenue and South Dakota Avenue, for northbound traffic only;</text>
    </level>
    <text>Brooks Street, N.E., from 9th street to 50th Street, for westbound traffic only;</text>
    <text>Constitution Avenue, N.E., from 3rd Street to North Carolina Avenue, for westbound traffic only, 6:45-9:30 A.M., Except Saturdays, Sundays and Holidays;</text>
    <text>Kennedy Street, N.E., between 1st Street and Blair Road, for westbound traffic only;</text>
    <text>Kennedy Street, N.E., between North Capitol Street and Blair Road, for westbound traffic only;</text>
    <text>Morse Street, N.E., from Holbrook Street to a point approximately 40 feet east of Holbrook Street, for westbound traffic only, 4:00 p.m.-6:30 p.m., Monday-Friday;</text>
    <text>On 52nd Street, N.E., between Hayes Street and Jay Street, for northbound traffic only;</text>
    <text>On Sheridan Street, N.E, between North Capitol Street and Kansas Avenue, for eastbound traffic only.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Erie Street, S.E., between Pomeroy Road and Elvans Road, for eastbound traffic only;</text>
    </level>
    <text>H Street, S.E., between 16th and 17th Streets, for eastbound traffic only;</text>
    <text>M Place, S.E., from Minnesota Avenue to a point approximately 40 feet west of Minnesota Avenue, for eastbound traffic only, 7:00 A.M. to 9:30 A.M., Monday through Friday;</text>
    <text>Nash Place, S.E., from Branch Avenue to a point approximately 40 feet west of Branch Avenue, for westbound traffic only, 7:00 to 9:30 a.m., Monday-Friday;</text>
    <text>On 30th Street, S.E., between Southern Avenue and Naylor Road, for northbound traffic only;</text>
    <text>On C Street, S.E., between 17th Street and Massachusetts Avenue, for eastbound traffic only;</text>
    <text>On Darrington Street, S.E., between 6th Street and Barnaby Road, for eastbound traffic only;</text>
    <text>On Erie Street, S.E., between Branch Avenue and Southern Avenue, for southeast bound traffic only;</text>
    <text>O Street, S.E., from Branch Avenue to Carpenter Street, for eastbound traffic only;</text>
    <text>Stanton Road, S.E., between Trenton Place and Mississippi Avenue, northbound traffic only;</text>
    <text>The north east-west alley between 7th and 8th Streets and Alabama and Malcolm X Avenues, S.E., for westbound traffic only;</text>
    <text>The south east-west alley between 7th an 8th Streets and Alabama and Malcolm X Avenues, S.E., for westbound traffic only.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4004.2.</num>
    <text>Traffic in alleys which intersect one-way streets shall be allowed to move in both directions, except where listed in this section and where indicated by official sign.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>17 DCRR ยง 40.106, Special Edition (September 26, 1970); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 34 (January 7, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 2789 (April 21, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at
        47 DCR 3210 (May 5, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8116 (October 6, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9029 (November 10, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 10063, 10064
        (December 22, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 147 (January 5, 2001); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 5369 (June 8, 2001); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 6111, 6112, 6114 (July 6,
        2001); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 10452, 10455, 10456 (November 16, 2001); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 11134, 11135 (December 7, 2001); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 749 (January
        25, 2002); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 3990, 3991 (May 23, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 4260 (May 30, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 5299 (July 4, 2003); as amended
        by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 9257 (October 31, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 9386 (November 7, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 2723, 2724 (March 12, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 51 DCR 6031, 6033 (June 11, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 7648 (August 6, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 2731 to 2738 (March 18, 2005); as amended by Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking
        published at 52 DCR 4801 (May 20, 2005) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 6680 (July 15, 2005); as amended by Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 10964 (December 16, 2005) [EXPIRED]; as amended by
        Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 1178 (February 17, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 4570 (June 9, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>