<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-401</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION FOR A CERTIFICATE OF TITLE (§ 18-401)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>401.1.</num>
    <text>The application for a certificate of title shall be made by the owner and shall set forth the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The owner’s true and lawful given name, middle name or names, if any, and surname; residence and business address, if any; driver’s license number; and date of birth;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A description of the vehicle including (so far as the following data exists) make, model, year of manufacture, type of body, identifying number, manufacturer’s shipping weight, and whether the vehicle is new or used;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The date of purchase by applicant; the name and address of the person from whom the vehicle was acquired; and the names and addresses of any lien holders in the order of their priority and the dates of their respective security agreements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any further information which is reasonably required by the Director to identify the vehicle and to enable the Director to determine whether the owner is entitled to a certificate and whether there exists any security interest in the vehicle;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A statement as to the kind of identification tags desired or a statement that the applicant does not intend to register the vehicle; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Proof of District of Columbia residency for at least one owner; except that a vehicle owned by an out-of-state lessor and leased to a District of Columbia resident may apply and an out-of-state insurance company may apply in connection with an insurance
        claim if the vehicle is located in the District.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.2.</num>
    <text>If the applicant knows or has reason to know that the vehicle has been registered in the District or in any other jurisdiction as a taxicab, commercial vehicle, or for livery or sightseeing purposes, the application shall indicate the prior registration
      by one of the following, as appropriate: “x taxi,” “x commercial,” “x livery,” or “x sightseeing.”</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.3.</num>
    <text>Each application shall be executed by the owner(s) of the vehicle for which a certificate is sought, except that an application of an owner serving in the Armed Forces outside the borders of the United States may be signed in the name of the owner
      by the owner’s spouse or next of kin upon proof of the relationship satisfactory to the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.4.</num>
    <text>If the application refers to a new vehicle it shall be accompanied by a certificate of manufacture or such other proof of ownership as the Director may reasonably require.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.5.</num>
    <text>If the application refers to a vehicle previously registered in the District, the application shall be accompanied by a certificate or other proof of ownership that the Director may reasonably require.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.6.</num>
    <text>If the application refers to a judicial sale, the application shall be accompanied by a bill of sale from the person authorized to make the sale and a certified copy of the court order that authorized the sale.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.7.</num>
    <text>If the application refers to a vehicle last previously registered elsewhere than in the District, the application shall be accompanied by one (1) of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Any certificate of title issued by the other jurisdiction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If no certificate of title is or, during the period in which the vehicle was last registered, was required by the other jurisdiction, the evidence of ownership shall be in the form which is or was required by the other jurisdiction for the purpose
        of registering the vehicle in that jurisdiction; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If no such proof of ownership is specified in the other jurisdiction, an invoice or bill of sale signed by the transferor(s) of the vehicle to the applicant and bearing the sworn statement of the transferor(s) to the effect that the transferor(s)
        is (are) the sole owner(s) of the vehicle and that, except as specified in the invoice or bill of sale, there is no lien outstanding against the vehicle, if that is true; otherwise a full statement covering any security interest in the vehicle.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.8.</num>
    <text>If the application is submitted by the holder of a lien under any security interest who has possession of the vehicle, the application shall be accompanied by any outstanding certificate and the vehicle registration plates removed from the vehicle
      (or a statement explaining the absence of the certificate and plates satisfactory to the Director), and a duly authenticated copy of the instrument which created the interest(s).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.9.</num>
    <text>If the application is submitted by a purchaser from a lien holder at a sale of a vehicle by the lien holder, the application shall be accompanied by a duly authenticated bill of sale from the person authorized to make the sale and the registration
      plates removed from the vehicle (or a statement explaining the absence of the plates satisfactory to the Director).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.10.</num>
    <text>If the application is submitted by a surviving joint owner or owners, the application shall be accompanied by any outstanding certificate (or a statement explaining its absence to the satisfaction of the Director) and by a duly authenticated death
      certificate referring to the deceased joint owner or owners.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.11.</num>
    <text>If the application indicates that the applicant does not desire to register the vehicle, the application shall contain the number of the current District of Columbia inspection sticker or any further reasonable proof of identification of the vehicle
      that may be required by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.12.</num>
    <text>Except when a District of Columbia title accompanies the application, each application must be accompanied by a certificate of a person authorized by the Director stating that the identifying number of the vehicle has been inspected and found to conform
      to the description given in the application, or any other proof of the identity of the vehicle which the Director may reasonably require.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.13.</num>
    <text>If the identification number of any vehicle is defaced or missing, the owner of the vehicle shall make application to the Director for a DMV number. The Director shall issue a plate or plates bearing a DMV number which shall be affixed to the vehicle
      in the manner prescribed by him or her. That number shall thereafter be the lawful identification number of the vehicle. The affixation of the plate or plates shall be verified by the Director prior to the issuance of any certificate of title for
      the vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.14.</num>
    <text>Motor numbers shall not be used as a means of identification on certificates. In place of motor numbers, the Vehicle Identification Number or, if none, the serial number, of the vehicle will be used in all title applications and on the face of titles,
      as well as on other documents issued or kept for record purposes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.15.</num>
    <text>In the event an application for title involves a vehicle for which District certificate is outstanding, no verification by a inspection station shall be required if the application is accompanied by the sticker number of an official inspection sticker
      affixed to the windshield, a legible tracing of the serial number, and the certificate number.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.16.</num>
    <text>In determining the fair market value of a vehicle for the purposes of calculating the amount of tax due under § 6(j) of the Traffic of 1925, approved July 3, 1926 (43 Stat. 1121; D.C. Official Code § 50-2201.03(j)) (2001), the Director shall use the
      then current National Automobile Dealers Association (NADA) Guide for the Eastern Region. If the NADA guide does not provide the fair market value for a particular vehicle, the applicable bill of sale shall be used.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.17.</num>
    <text>An application for a title, other than a duplicate title, shall not be accepted unless all of the new owner’s outstanding fines, fees, and penalties imposed pursuant to the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act of 1978, effective September
      12, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-104; D.C. Official Code § 50-2301.01 et seq.) have been satisfied.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>401.18.</num>
    <text>If the application is submitted by a purchaser of a vehicle sold by a trustee in bankruptcy, the application shall be accompanied by a duly authenticated bill of sale from the trustee in bankruptcy and a certificate of title signed by the current
      owner or assigned by the trustee in bankruptcy in accordance with § 406.11.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 930 (February 4, 2005); as amended by D.C. Act 15-704 published at 52 DCR 1700 (February 25, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 5754 (June 17, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published
        at 54 DCR 1575 (February 16, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>