<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-408</num>
  <heading>OFFICIALLY ALTERED CERTIFICATES OF TITLE (§ 18-408)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>408.1.</num>
    <text>Upon the delivery to the Director of a certificate which contains an error which, in the judgment of the Director, does not necessitate the issuance of another certificate, the Director shall make the necessary correction and place the words “officially
      altered,” the date, and his or her signature on the certificate, and deliver it to the person entitled thereto or his or her agent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>408.2.</num>
    <text>Official alterations of certificates by the Department shall be limited to correction of the spelling of owner’s name, correction in address of owner, correction of the spelling of the make of vehicle, and corrections in the model or year of the vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>408.3.</num>
    <text>A person who is the owner of a vehicle for which a certificate is outstanding and who changes his or her name by marriage, shall, within thirty (30) days after the marriage, deliver to the Director the certificate accompanied by an executed statement
      the form provided and containing the information required by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>408.4.</num>
    <text>A person, who is an owner of a vehicle for which a certificate is outstanding, and who changes his or her name other than by marriage shall, within five (5) business days after the change in name, deliver to the Director the certificate accompanied
      by an executed statement on the form provided and containing the information required by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>408.5.</num>
    <text>The Director, when satisfied that an owner is entitled to a change in the name appearing on a certificate of title, shall make the change and place the words “OFFICIALLY ALTERED,” the date, and the Director’s signature on the certificate, and deliver
      it to the person entitled to the altered certificate or the person’s agent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>