<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-435</num>
  <heading>VINTAGE TAGS (§ 18-435)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>435.1</num>
    <text>435.1 Vintage license tags shall be permitted on historic motor vehicles in place of historic motor vehicle license tags if approved by the Director pursuant to this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>435.2</num>
    <text>435.2 A person who seeks to display vintage license tags shall submit an application to the Director by letter, or at the discretion of the Director, by email or through the Department’s website.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>435.3.</num>
    <text>The application shall include the applicant’s name, address, vehicle information number (“VIN”), make, model, year of manufacture, and a color photograph of the vintage tag. The Director may request the applicant to appear in person with the vintage
      tag for the purposes of inspection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>435.4</num>
    <text>435.4 The Director may deny the application if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The tag does not meet reflective or safety standards as set forth in §§ 422.5 and 422.8;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The tag is illegible;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The letters, numbers, or combination of letters and numbers of the tag is the same as the configuration of letters, numbers, or combination of letters and numbers of any tag either issued or for which application has been made pursuant to § 423;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Director is unable to verify the tag is from the same year as the model year of the historic vehicle; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The Director concludes that the use of the vintage tags would adversely impact public safety.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>435.5.</num>
    <text>The Director may rescind or revoke the use of a vintage tag for violation of any District of Columbia law or regulation relating to motor vehicles, or for any reason described in § 435.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 5243, 5245 (June 18, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>