<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-507</num>
  <heading>REFUSAL TO REGISTER[COLON] SUSPENSION AND REVOCATION OF REGISTRATION (ยง 18-507)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>507.1.</num>
    <text>If the Director shall determine that an applicant to be registered as a new or used car dealer is not entitled to be registered, he or she shall refuse to register the applicant and, upon demand, shall issue an order to the applicant to that effect.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>507.2.</num>
    <text>The Director may suspend or revoke the dealer registration of any person who has violated any provision of Title IV of the Act of August 17, 1937, (D.C. Code, 40-101 through 40-105), as amended, or any rule promulgated under the authority of that
      law pertaining to vehicle registration or to his registration as a dealer, or any violation of Chapters 4 or 5 of this Title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>507.3.</num>
    <text>The Director may suspend or revoke the dealer registration of any person who has ceased to be a dealer as defined in the Act of August 17, 1937, as amended, or this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>507.4.</num>
    <text>Any order of refusal, suspension, or revocation shall set forth the proposed action and the grounds thereof in sufficient detail to permit the person adversely affected by the order to understand fully the nature of the order and the reasons for the
      order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>507.5.</num>
    <text>Any person whose registration as a dealer has been refused, suspended, or revoked by the Director may petition for a hearing subject to the provisions of chapter 10.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>507.6.</num>
    <text>Any order of suspension or revocation under ยง 507.2 shall notify the person that the order will take effect within ten (10) days unless the person files an objection together with a request for a hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>507.7.</num>
    <text>The filing of a request for a hearing under ยง 507.6 shall operate as a stay of the order until the Director or hearing examiner renders a written decision on the objection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>507.8.</num>
    <text>If a person to whom a notice of infraction has been issued fails to appear at a hearing for which he or she received notice, the hearing examiner may enter a default judgment sustaining the charges and order the suspension or revocation proposed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 8109 (August 20, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>