<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-508</num>
  <heading>SURRENDER OF CERTIFICATES AND IDENTIFICATION TAGS BY A DEALER (ยง 18-508)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>508.1.</num>
    <text>A dealer who goes out of business in the District and has valid registration certificates, dealer identification tags, dealer transport identification tags, special use certificates, or special use tags outstanding shall deliver all of the certificates
      and tags to the Director within five (5) business days after going out of business.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>508.2.</num>
    <text>The Director, upon receiving the tags and certificates, shall issue a receipt, upon demand; and shall cancel the tags and certificates.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>508.3.</num>
    <text>Returned dealer identification tags, dealer transport identification tags, and special use tags shall not be issued to any other person during the then current registration year and may be mutilated or otherwise disposed of by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>508.4.</num>
    <text>Any person whose registration as a dealer has been suspended or revoked pursuant to this chapter shall, within five (5) business days after the registration has been suspended or revoked, return to the Director the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>All dealer identification tags;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Special use tags;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Special use certificates;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Transport identification tags;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Registration certificates; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>All sets of the three-part serially numbered forms (each consisting of a temporary registration certificate, notice of issuance, and record of the issuance) then in his or her possession.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>508.5.</num>
    <text>No refund shall be made for dealers&amp;#8217; identification tags, transport identification tags or special use tags returned under the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>