<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-602</num>
  <heading>INSPECTION STICKERS (§ 18-602)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>602.1.</num>
    <text>The Director is authorized to issue inspection stickers and provide for the attachment of inspection stickers to motor vehicles.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.2.</num>
    <text>Inspection stickers may indicate approval, rejection, or condemnation of any vehicle, in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.3.</num>
    <text>Vehicles bearing special bus identification, current dealer tags, transport tags, special use paper tags, or historic motor vehicle tags shall be exempt from the inspection sticker requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.4.</num>
    <text>It shall be unlawful for any person to operate, park, or permit to be operated or parked on public space any vehicle bearing current District of Columbia tags, except a vehicle exempt under the provisions of § 602.3, unless there is displayed on the
      right side of the vehicle’s windshield one of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A current District of Columbia inspection sticker;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A temporary sticker issued by the Director; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A temporary registration certificate issued by a registered District of Columbia dealer or repair shop when transferring ownership for registration purposes.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.5.</num>
    <text>Whenever a person located in the District of Columbia acquires a motor vehicle which displays on the windshield a valid approved inspection sticker issued by any State that has a compulsory motor vehicle inspection law, that vehicle may be operated
      without the requirement of any other inspection sticker for a period of fifteen (15) days from the date of acquisition of the vehicle or until issuance by the Director of a sticker containing the words TEMPORARY STICKER &amp;#8211; NEWLY REGISTERED
      VEHICLE, whichever is the shorter period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.6.</num>
    <text>No later than the fifteenth (15th) day, the vehicle shall be presented for official inspection as required and shall display only the inspection sticker issued by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.7.</num>
    <text>A vehicle owned by a non-resident and currently registered in another jurisdiction shall display the proper inspection sticker issued for the vehicle in accordance with the requirements of the issuing jurisdiction.</text>
    <text>Source: Regulation No. 72-13 effective June 30, 1972, 32 DCRR §§ 4.203, 4.204(a)-(d), Special Edition; as amended by § 4(e) of the Historic Motor Vehicle Act of 1971, D.C. Law 2-41, 24 DCR 3629, 3633 (November 11, 1977); and by Final Rulemaking published
      at 32 DCR 1526, 1532 (March 15, 1985); as amended the Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Act of 2009, effective March 3, 2010 (D.C. Law 18-111), at 57 DCR 181, 290 (January 8, 2010).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>