<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-603</num>
  <heading>VEHICLE INSPECTION[COLON] APPROVED VEHICLES (§ 18-603)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>603.1.</num>
    <text>If, upon inspection of any vehicle, the Director determines it does not conform to the standards in the current edition of the “Lane Operator’s Manual”, or when applicable, the current edition of the “AAMVA Manual” and this Title, the Director shall
      issue to the registrant or person desiring registration a rejection sticker.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.2.</num>
    <text>The inspection sticker will permit the operation and use of the motor vehicle or trailer until the registrant or person desiring registration is notified by the Director to present the motor vehicle or trailer for another inspection; Provided, that
      the registrant or other person has complied with the provisions of this title and all other applicable provisions of law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.3.</num>
    <text>If a registrant or a person who desires registration to whom an approved inspection sticker was issued, loses or disposes of his or her legal title to the vehicle, the person who acquires it, or that person’s agent, may operate the vehicle bearing
      the sticker until such time as that person is required by the Director to present the vehicle for inspection; Provided, that the person has complied with the provisions of this title and all other applicable provisions of law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.4.</num>
    <text>[REPEALED]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 72-13 effective June 30, 1972, 32 DCRR § 4.205, Special Edition; as amended by Regulation 74-17 effective June 29, 1974; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 8196 (October 3, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published
        at 51 DCR 10224 (November 5, 2004); as amended by Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Act of 2009, effective March 3, 2010 (D.C. Law 18-111), at 57 DCR 181, 290 (January 8, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>