<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-601</num>
  <heading>INSPECTION REQUIREMENTS (§ 18-601)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>601.1.</num>
    <text>Inspections shall be made and stickers obtained with respect to the items of equipment designated by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.2.</num>
    <text>Inspections shall be conducted in accordance with the standards contained in the Motor Vehicle Inspection Manual of the District of Columbia (also referred to as the “District Inspection Manual” or “Manual”), and in the event existing standards do
      not apply to a particular piece of equipment, a standard specified by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.3.</num>
    <text>The 1982 and 1999 issues of the Motor Vehicle Inspection Manual of the District of Columbia are incorporated in this chapter by reference. In the event of any inconsistency between a Motor Vehicle Inspection Manual of the District of Columbia and
      this Title, the provisions of this Title shall govern.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.4.</num>
    <text>Vehicles registered in the District of Columbia shall be inspected periodically for, when applicable, safe operating condition, exhaust emissions, and compliance with this title as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Passenger vehicle: every two (2) years;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Bus: every six (6) months; except as provided in (d);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Bus owned or leased by the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority: annually;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Taxicab and other public vehicles for hire: semi-annually;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Commercial vehicle: annually;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Tow truck: annually;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Vehicle registered as a class F(I) historic motor vehicle: one (1) time, at time of registration, plus an inspection limited to confirming the odometer reading every two (2) years;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Vehicle registered as a class F(II) historic motor vehicle: one (1) time, at time of registration; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>All other motor vehicles: every two (2) years.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.5.</num>
    <text>[REPEALED]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.6.</num>
    <text>[REPEALED]</text>
    <text>601 7 At the discretion of the Director, imported vehicles may be exempt from certain inspection requirements, such as emissions, safety glass and headlights.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.8.</num>
    <text>The fees for inspections shall be as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Passenger vehicle, including historic motor vehicle: $ 35;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Commercial vehicles and vehicles for hire, including all buses: $ 35:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Trailers, based upon the manufacturer’s shipping weight: $ 35</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Tow truck: $ 35;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Salvage vehicle: $ 35;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>New vehicles for which an inspection is not required but for which a sticker is required: $ 10; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>All other motor vehicles: $ 35.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.9.</num>
    <text>The inspection fees included above shall include two re-inspections performed within twenty (20) days of the initial inspection. The fee for all other re-inspections shall be in accordance with the above inspection fee schedule.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.10.</num>
    <text>Any re-inspection fees due shall be paid at the time of re-inspection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.11.</num>
    <text>Inspection fees may be collected at the time of registration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>601.12.</num>
    <text>The total cumulative amount of any late inspection penalty assessed pursuant to § 6 of An Act to Provide for annual inspection of all motor vehicles in the District of Columbia, approved February 18, 1938 (52 Stat. 78; D.C. Official Code § 50-1106),
      shall not exceed four hundred and eighty dollars ($ 480), all or part of which may be waived by the Director upon submission of proof that the owner was unable to have the vehicle inspected due to one or more of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Military duty;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Incarceration;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Medical emergency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The vehicle was involved in an accident (police report required); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Exceptional circumstances, as determined by the Director.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 72-13 effective June 30, 1972; 32 DCRR §§ 4.202 (a) &amp;#8211; (c), Special Edition; as amended by §§ 2(7), 2(8) of the District of Columbia Bus Safety Inspection Act, D.C. Law 1-60, 22 DCR 4373 (February 12,1976); 32 DCRR §§ 4.202(b),
        4.202(c); as amended by § 2(n) of the District of Columbia Motorized Bicycle Act, D.C. Law 1-110,23 DCR 4954 (January 21, 1977), 32 DCRR § 4.202(d); as amended by § 4(c)(2) of the Historic Motor Vehicle Act of 1977 (D.C Law 2-41; 24 DCR 3629 (November
        11, 1977)), 32 DCRR § 4.204(a); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 30 DCR 2571 (May 27, 1983); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 4308 (July 18, 1986); as amended by § 4 Motor Vehicle Biennial Inspection Amendment Act
        of 1993 (D.C. Law 10-106; 41 DCR 1014 (March 4, 1994)); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 6618 (September 30, 1994); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 1150 (February 9, 2001); as amended by Final Rulemaking published
        at 48 DCR 6261 (July 13, 2001); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 748 (January 25, 2002); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 11261 (December 13, 2002); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 5031 (May
        14, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 8110 (Aug 20, 2004); as amended by D.C. Act published at 54 DCR 903 (February 2, 2007); as amended by D.C. Act published at 55 DCR 7598 (July 18, 2008); as amended by D.C. Act published
        at 56 DCR 203, 204 (January 9, 2009); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 16843 (December 13, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>