<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-740</num>
  <heading>MOTORCYCLE EQUIPMENT[COLON] GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 18-740)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>740.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall sell, offer for sale, or distribute any protective helmets, goggles, or faceshields for use by the operators or passengers of motorcycles unless such helmets, goggles, or face shields are of the type approved by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>740.2.</num>
    <text>Applications for approval of equipment required by this section shall be submitted to the Director who shall determine when conditions of approval have been met and shall thereupon issue a Certificate of Approval.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>740.3.</num>
    <text>An application for approval of equipment shall be accompanied by a copy of a laboratory test report from a nationally recognized, independent testing laboratory certifying that the item tested meets the specification(s) set forth in the prescribed
      standards, and stating the manufacturer’s trade name and model name (if any), or number appearing on the item tested.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>740.4.</num>
    <text>No sample is required by the Director unless specifically requested. No fee is required for approval.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>740.5.</num>
    <text>Alteration of a helmet, goggles, face shield, or wind screen by or for a user shall invalidate the Director’s approval, and the label required by the identification requirements of §§ 741 through 744 shall no longer be evidence of approval of the
      item altered.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>740.6.</num>
    <text>Provisions of the standards of the American National Standards Institute, Inc., cited in §§ 741 through 744 are incorporated by reference. In case of conflict between the provisions of the Standards and those contained in this chapter, the provisions
      of this chapter shall apply.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>740.7.</num>
    <text>The Director shall have the authority to withdraw approval of any product approved under this section for any cause considered reasonable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>17 DCRR § 110(d) (October 19, 1970); and by Regulation No. 72-13 effective June 30, 1972, 32 DCRR §§ 6.503(a), (b), 6.504, 6.504, 6.505, Special Edition.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>