<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-744</num>
  <heading>MOTORCYCLE WIND SCREENS (§ 18-744)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>744.1.</num>
    <text>The American National Standards Institute, Inc., Specifications for Safety Glazing Materials for Glazing Motor Vehicles Operated on Land Highways, Z26.1-1966, is adopted as the minimum standards for wind screens when used on motorcycles.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>744.2.</num>
    <text>The test procedure for wind screens shall refer to those standards which are applicable to all wind screen devices; Provided, that for rigid plastic material, Item 4 of Table 1 of the standards shall be used; and for flexible plastics, Item 6 of Table
      1 shall be used.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>744.3.</num>
    <text>In addition to the specifications of that portion of the American National Standards Institute, Inc., which are established in this section, no wind screen shall be approved unless it meets the following specifications:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The metal support shall be of a material which shall bend rather than fragment under impact;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Covering material, other than visual material, shall be beaded at the edges to prevent fraying; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Cloth covering material shall be tested for flammability according to the procedures of 5902 of specifications of the American National Standards Institute’s Testing Methods.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>744.4.</num>
    <text>Each wind screen shall be permanently labeled at an easily visible location with the manufacturer’s trade name and number, which shall be the same trade name and number used in the approval application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 72-13 effective June 30, 1972, 32 DCRR §§ 6.509(a) &amp;#8211; (c), Special Edition.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>