<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-734</num>
  <heading>GLAZING MATERIALS (§ 18-734)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>734.1.</num>
    <text>No motor vehicle manufactured or assembled after January 1, 1936, shall be operated in the District unless it is equipped throughout with safety glazing materials of a type approved by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>734.2.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term “safety glazing materials” shall be construed to mean transparent glazing materials so formulated, treated, or combined with other materials as to reduce, in comparison with ordinary sheet glass or plate
      glass, the likelihood of injury to persons by objects from exterior sources or by these safety glazing materials when the glazing materials are cracked or broken.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>734.3.</num>
    <text>The Director shall not register any motor vehicle which is subject to the provisions of this section unless it is equipped with an approved type of safety glazing material.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>734.4.</num>
    <text>The Director shall compile and publish a list of types of safety glazing materials by name which have been approved by him as meeting the requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>734.5.</num>
    <text>The use of rigid-type, clear plastic is restricted to side curtains or readily demountable windows, rear windows in the tops of convertible passenger cars, back lights, rear quarter lights and doors, in truck or truck-tractor cabs, in rear doors or
      taxicabs, in house or freight trailers, in the lights of lower part of folding doors when not over ten inches (10 in.) in the least dimension, in interior partitions and auxiliary wind deflectors, in standee windows in buses, and in openings in
      the roofs of tops.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>734.6.</num>
    <text>The use of flexible-type, clear plastic is restricted to side curtains or readily demountable windows; rear windows in the tops of convertible passenger cars; and house or freight trailers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>734.7.</num>
    <text>Any section of safety glazing materials cut from safety glazing materials marked by the manufacturer of approved type materials shall be marked with the same words, designation, and letters as the sheet from which it was cut.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>734.8.</num>
    <text>No motor vehicle may be operated or parked upon the public streets or spaces of the District of Columbia with window tinting in violation of D.C. Code § 50-2207.02 (2001 Ed.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>734.9</num>
    <text>734.9-734.19 [REPEALED].</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 72-13 effective June 30, 1972, 32 DCRR § 6.406, Special Edition; as amended by § 3 of the Motor Vehicle Tinted Window Amendment Act of 1994, D.C. Law 10-163, 41 DCR 4886, 4887 (July 22, 1994); as amended by Final Rulemaking at 50
        DCR 4403 (Jun 6, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 5987 (Jul 25, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>