<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-732</num>
  <heading>TIRE EQUIPMENT (ยง 18-732)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>732.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall drive or move any motor vehicle equipped with any tire in such condition as to endanger or be likely to endanger any person or property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>732.2.</num>
    <text>Each solid rubber tire on a vehicle shall have rubber on its entire traction surface at least one inch (1 in.) thick above the edge of the flange of the entire periphery.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>732.3.</num>
    <text>No person shall operate or move on any street or highway any motor vehicle, trailer or semi-trailer having any metal tire in contact with the roadway.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>732.4.</num>
    <text>No tire on a vehicle moved on a street or highway shall have on its periphery any block, stud, flange, cleat, or spike or any other protuberance of any material other than rubber which projects beyond the tread of the traction surface of the tire,
      except as provided in ยง 732.5.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>732.5.</num>
    <text>It shall be permissible to use the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Farm machinery with tires having protuberances which will not injure the street or highway;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Tire chains of reasonable proportions upon any vehicle when required for safety because of snow, ice, or other conditions tending to cause a vehicle to skid; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Pneumatic tires containing metal type studs, the tips of which protrude beyond the rubber tread surface of such tire not more than one-eighth of an inch (1/8 in.), and the cross-sectional diameter of which do not exceed one-fourth of an inch (1/4
        in.), inclusive of the casing but not including any flange or flanges embedded in the rubber of the tire; Provided, that the use of studded tires is permitted only from October 15th through April 15th of each year.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 72-13 effective June 30, 1972, 32 DCRR ยง 6.405, 6.408, Special Edition; as amended by Regulation No. 73-8 effective April 24, 1974.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>