<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-707</num>
  <heading>ADDITIONAL EQUIPMENT REQUIRED ON CERTAIN VEHICLES (ยง 18-707)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>707.1.</num>
    <text>In addition to other equipment required in these regulations, all vehicles manufactured or assembled on and after September 15, 1957, shall be equipped as set forth in this section in accordance with the conditions stated in ยง 703.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.2.</num>
    <text>On each bus or truck, whatever its size, there shall be the following: On the rear, two (2) reflectors, one (1) at each side; and two (2) stop lights.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.3.</num>
    <text>On each bus or truck eighty inches (80 in.) or more in overall width, in addition to the requirements in ยง 707.2, there shall be the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>On the front, two (2) clearance lamps, one (1) at each side;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>On the rear, two (2) clearance lamps, one (1) at each side;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>On each side, two (2) side marker lamps, one (1) at or near the front and one (1) at or near the rear; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>On each side, two (2) reflectors, one (1) at or near the front and one (1) at or near the rear.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.4.</num>
    <text>On each truck tractor, there shall be the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>On the front, two (2) clearance lamps, one (1) at each side; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>On the rear, one (1) stop light.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.5.</num>
    <text>On each trailer or semi-trailer having a gross weight in excess of three thousand pounds (3,000 lbs.), there shall be the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>On the front, two (2) clearance lamps, one (1) at each side;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>On each side, two (2) side marker lamps, one (1) at or near the front and one (1) at or near the rear; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>On the rear, two (2) clearance lamps, one (1) at each side, and two (2) reflectors, one (1) at each side, and two (2) stop lights.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.6.</num>
    <text>On each pole trailer in excess of three thousand pounds (3,000 lbs.) gross weight, there shall be the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>On each side, one (1) side marker lamp and one (1) clearance lamp which may be in combination, to show to the front, side, and rear; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>On the rear of the pole trailer or load, two (2) reflectors, one (1) at each side.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.7.</num>
    <text>On each trailer, semi-trailer, or pole trailer weighing three thousand pounds (3,000 lbs.) gross or less, there shall be the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>On the rear, two (2) reflectors, one (1) on each side; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If any trailer or semi-trailer is so loaded or is of such dimensions as to obscure the stop light on the towing vehicle, then that vehicle shall also be equipped with two (2) stop lights.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.8.</num>
    <text>Each tow crane or tow truck shall be equipped with flashing, blinking, or alternating warning lamp or lamps and the lamp or lamps shall be operated only while at the scene of a disabled vehicle or while actually towing a disabled vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.9.</num>
    <text>Each warning lamp shall be of a type approved by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.10.</num>
    <text>When two (2) lamps are used to display the warning on a tow crane or tow truck, they shall be mounted at the same level on the top of the cab and as widely spaced laterally as practicable and shall display a flashing, blinking, or alternating white
      or amber light or any shade of color between white and amber to the front.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.11.</num>
    <text>The lamps used to display the warning to the rear on a tow crane or tow truck shall be mounted at the same level on the top of the cab and as widely spaced laterally as practicable and shall display a flashing, blinking, or alternating amber or red
      light or any shade of color between amber and red.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.12.</num>
    <text>When a single warning lamp is used on a tow crane or tow truck, it shall be mounted on the top of the cab as near center as practicable and shall display a flashing, blinking, or alternating white or amber light or any shade of color between white
      and amber to the front, and an amber or red light or any shade of color between amber and red to the rear.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.13.</num>
    <text>The warning light or lights on a tow crane or tow truck shall be visible from a distance of not less than five hundred feet (500 ft.) under normal atmospheric conditions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 72-13 effective June 30, 1972, 32 DCRR ยง 6.208, Special Edition.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>