<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-730</num>
  <heading>HORNS AND WARNING DEVICES (ยง 18-730)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>730.1.</num>
    <text>Each motor vehicle operated upon a highway shall be equipped with a horn in good working order and capable of emitting sound audible under normal conditions from a distance of not less than two hundred feet (200 ft.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>730.2.</num>
    <text>No horn or other warning device shall emit an unreasonably loud or harsh sound or a whistle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>730.3.</num>
    <text>The driver of a motor vehicle shall, when reasonably necessary to ensure safe operation, give audible warning with his or her horn, but shall not otherwise use the horn when upon a highway.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>730.4.</num>
    <text>No vehicle, other than an authorized emergency vehicle as set forth in ยง 712, shall be equipped with nor shall any person use upon a vehicle any siren, whistle, or bell, except as otherwise permitted in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>730.5.</num>
    <text>The prohibition in ยง 730.4 relating to the use of a bell shall not be applicable to any street car, bicycle, or motor vehicle used by a person licensed under the License Act of July 1, 1902 (D.C. Code, Title 47, Chapter 23), as amended, who customarily
      uses a bell or bells in connection with the sale of services or wares.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>730.6.</num>
    <text>Upon approval by the Director, any vehicle may be equipped with a sound device designed to be used solely as a theft alarm system which shall be so arranged that it cannot be used or controlled by the driver or other person for any purpose other than
      as an alarm system.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 72-13 effective June 30, 1972, 32 DCRR ยง 6.401, Special Edition.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>