<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-800</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 18-800)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>800.1.</num>
    <text>The rules contained in this chapter shall govern the following procedures:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>(REPEALED)</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Verification of insurance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Suspension of operating privileges arising out of motor vehicle accidents occurring in the District of Columbia and elsewhere;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Filing of proof of financial responsibility for the future; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Qualification of applicants for self-insurance certificates.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>800.2.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this chapter, “Act” shall mean the Motor Vehicle Safety Responsibility Act of the District of Columbia (D.C. Code § § 40-401 et seq. (1990 Repl. Vol.)).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>800.3.</num>
    <text>Appeals from any final decision of the Director pursuant to this chapter shall be taken to the Traffic Adjudication Appeals Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>800.4.</num>
    <text>The Director, upon written request and upon payment of a fee of two dollars ($ 2.00) shall furnish to any person the certified name of the insurance company and the certified policy number of the motor vehicle insurance of any owner or operator of
      a motor vehicle registered in the District of Columbia or issued a reciprocity sticker.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>800.5.</num>
    <text>Except for §§ 800.4, 801, 803 and 807, the provisions of this chapter shall not apply to the owner of any motor vehicle who has complied with the requirements of the No-Fault Insurance Act as amended, or the Act approved June 29, 1938 (52 Stat. 1233,
      D.C. Code § 44-302 (1990 Repl. Vol.)).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>800.6.</num>
    <text>Any person who violates any provision of this chapter shall be subject to the penalty prescribed by the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 5053 (May 14, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>