<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-801</num>
  <heading>FEES FOR RECORDS (§ 18-801)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>801.1.</num>
    <text>A certified or uncertified abstract of the operating record of any person who has become subject to the Act shall be furnished to any person upon written request to the Director, accompanied by the fee specified in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.2.</num>
    <text>A certified abstract of an operating record shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An enumeration of the motor vehicle accidents in which the person has been involved which have been reported to the Department;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A record of convictions for violations of motor vehicle laws, rules, or regulations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A record of any vehicles registered in the name of the person.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.3.</num>
    <text>The fee for a certified abstract shall be seven dollars ($ 7.00).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.4.</num>
    <text>An uncertified abstract of an operating record shall not list any vehicles registered in the name of the person, but shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An enumeration of the motor vehicle accidents in which the person has been involved which have been reported to the Department; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any record of convictions for violations of motor vehicle laws, rules and regulations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.5.</num>
    <text>The fee for each uncertified abstract depicting less than ten (10) years is seven dollars ($ 7) and the fee for each uncertified abstract depicting ten (10) or more years is thirteen dollars ($ 13).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.6.</num>
    <text>The annual fee for electronic access to Department of Motor Vehicle driver records shall be one hundred dollars ($ 100).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.7.</num>
    <text>The annual fee for periodic receipt of electronic files containing customers’ registration-related information shall be one thousand two hundred dollars ($ 1,200).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.8.</num>
    <text>The fees in this section may be modified by the Director of the Department of Motor Vehicles to cover administrative costs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.9.</num>
    <text>Persons seeking information under §§ 801.6 or 801.7 shall apply pursuant to procedures established by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.10.</num>
    <text>A person seeking information identified under this section must be eligible to receive the information pursuant to District of Columbia and federal privacy laws.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.11.</num>
    <text>A request for a certified or uncertified abstract pursuant to a subpoena shall be subject to the fee specified in this section, except if the subpoena is submitted by a governmental entity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.12.</num>
    <text>A fee shall not be imposed for a certified or uncertified abstract if the abstract is requested by a person filing an in forma pauperis petition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 5029 (May 14, 2004); as amended by D.C Act 15-704 published at 52 DCR 1700 (February 25, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 5243, 5247 (June 18, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>