<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-1301</num>
  <heading>SPECIAL PERFORMANCE PERMITS (§ 19-1301)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1301.1.</num>
    <text>The owner, operator, manager, or other person in charge of any of the activities listed in § 1300.1 shall either obtain a license from the Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs (the “Director”), in accordance with the License
      Act and applicable regulations, or a permit from the Chief of Police for all of the activities that do not require a license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1301.2.</num>
    <text>The license or permit shall not be issued for any of the activities until the Fire Chief of the Fire Department, the Chief of Police, the Director of Public Health, and the Director of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs, or their respective agents, certify
      that the applicable laws and regulations enforced by each of them have been observed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1301.3.</num>
    <text>Not later than ten (10) days before the date on which an activity is scheduled to commence, the owner, operator, manager, or other person in charge of the activity shall submit to the Director a plat secured from the D.C. Surveyor. On the plat shall
      be shown the location of the proposed activity, together with all of that area within a distance of three hundred feet (300’) from the perimeter of the lot(s), reservation(s), or parcel(s) of ground to be occupied by the activity, and the location
      of all property wholly or in part within that area.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1301.4.</num>
    <text>Not later than ten (10) days before the date on which an activity is scheduled to commence, the owner, operator, manager, or other person in charge of the activity shall obtain the written consent of seventy-five percent (75%) of the resident housekeepers
      and occupants of business establishments within a distance of three hundred feet (300) from the perimeter of the lot(s), reservation(s), or parcel(s) of ground on which the activity is to be conducted. If the owner, operator, manager, or other person
      in charge of the activity is unable to obtain said written consent, and has made a good-faith effort to engage the affected residents and business establishments, and to mitigate objections raised by such persons, the Mayor shall have the discretion
      to issue the license or permit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1301.5.</num>
    <text>The written consents required under § 1301.4 shall be in the form of a list containing, in numerical order by streets, the addresses and names of the resident housekeepers and occupants of business and other establishments domiciled or located on
      properties shown on the plat as being wholly or in part within the area, and the signature of those resident housekeepers and occupants of business and other establishments indicating they have no objection to the activity to be conducted within
      the area.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1301.6.</num>
    <text>Each page of the list described in § 1301.5 shall contain, at the top of the list, in capital letters, an explanation of the proposed activity, including its nature, the dates during which it is to be conducted, and the hours it is to be conducted
      on each of those dates.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1301.7.</num>
    <text>The list described in § 1301.5 shall be subject to investigation by the Metropolitan Police Department. Should the signature of any person be found not authentic, this shall be valid grounds to deny a license for the conduct of the activity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1301.8.</num>
    <text>The requirements of this section shall not apply to any of the activities listed in § 1300.1 when those activities are conducted on public land officially designated by the Mayor or the federal government as a specific site on which any of the activities
      may be conducted or operated, or in any duly licensed stadium.</text>
    <text>1983); as amended by Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Act of 2010, effective September 24,</text>
    <text>2010 (D.C. Law 18-223), published at 57 DCR 6242, 6267 (July 23, 2010).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 6 § 1(a) &amp;#038; (b) of the Police Regulations of the District of Columbia (January</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>