<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-1017</num>
  <heading>SATISFIED LIENS (§ 19-1017)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1017.1.</num>
    <text>When the Harbor Master receives a certificate of title marked “satisfied” according to § 1016, the Harbor Master shall mark on both the certificate of title and the lien instrument the following;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The lien’s record number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The word “released”;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Harbor Master’s signature; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The date.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1017.2.</num>
    <text>If the Harbor Master does not have the lien instrument in the Harbor Master records, the record holder shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Briefly describe the lien in a separate memorandum;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Mark on both the certificate of title and the memorandum describing the lien the record number of the lien and the word “released”;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Sign both the memorandum and the certificate of title; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Mark on both the memorandum and the certificate of title the date of the Harbor Master’s signature.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1017.3.</num>
    <text>If for any reason a lien holder, upon satisfaction of his or her lien, has failed to mark the certificate of title as provided in § 1015 and 1016 and the lien holder cannot be located, or if the certificate of title after being so marked has been
      lost or destroyed and a duplicate certificate issued, the Harbor Master, upon receipt of evidence satisfactory to him or her that the lien has been satisfied, shall indicate in the manner described in this section the satisfaction of the lien.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1017.4.</num>
    <text>If a lien has been released as provided in this section for a period of more than three (3) years, the Mayor may destroy the instrument which created the lien.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 1459 (March 30, 1984); incorporating by reference 30 DCR 6293, 6310-11 (December 9, 1983).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>