<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-1604</num>
  <heading>PUBLIC NOTICE BY THE APPLICANT (ยง 19-1604)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1604.1</num>
    <text>1604.1 The applicant shall post two (2) notices supplied by the Director inonspicuous places on the building for which the license is sought and shallake photographic evidence of the posting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1604.2</num>
    <text>1604.2 The notices shall be posted for at least twenty-eight (28) consecutiveays, with the first consecutive day occurring at least thirty (30) calendarays prior to the noticed hearing date, and shall contain the information setorth in ยง 1603.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1604.3</num>
    <text>1604.3 The notices shall be securely posted on the front of the building. Theottom of the notice may not be less than three (3) feet above the abuttingedestrian level, and the top of the notice may not be more than six (6) feetbove the abutting pedestrian
      level.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1604.4</num>
    <text>1604.4 The notices may be attached to the inside of a window, provided that theotices meet the positioning requirements of ยง 1604.3.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1604.5</num>
    <text>1604.5 Notices posted on the exterior of a building shall be covered with clearlastic to protect them from the weather.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1604.6</num>
    <text>1604.6 On or before the date of the hearing, the applicant shall file anffidavit with the Director certifying that the notice requirements of ยง 1604ave been satisfied.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1604.7</num>
    <text>1604.7 If the notices have been removed or are posted in a manner making themot easily visible from the street, the Director may extend the notice period oray require that the notice be reposted and the notice period begin anew.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 9292, 9294 (December 11, 1992); asmended by Notice of emergency and proposed rulemaking at 52 DCR 8531(September6, 2005) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 521, 524January 8, 2010).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR&amp;#8217;S NOTE</heading>
      <text>Section 1604 published at 39 DCR 9292 (December 11, 1992)as renumbered as section 1602 by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 521January 8, 2010). Section 1606 published at 39 DCR 9292 (December 11, 1992)as renumbered as section 1604 by Final Rulemaking
        published at 57 DCR 521January 8, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>