<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-1036</num>
  <heading>BOAT LIVERIES (§ 19-1036)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1036.1.</num>
    <text>The owner of a boat livery shall cause to be kept a record of the name and addresses of each person renting, leasing, or chartering any vessel; the name and addresses of all persons to be carried on the vessel; the identification number of the vessel;
      the date and time of departure; and the expected date and time of return.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1036.2.</num>
    <text>The record required by § 1036.1 shall be preserved for at least six (6) months, and shall be subject to inspection by the Harbor Master or his or her authorized representatives.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1036.3.</num>
    <text>Neither the owner of a boat livery nor his or her agent or employee shall permit any vessel to depart from his or her possession, unless it has been provided, either by the owner or the leasee, with the equipment required by § 1034 and any regulations
      promulgated under that section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1036.4.</num>
    <text>No person engaged or employed in the business of renting canoes in the District of Columbia shall rent any canoe without first instructing the person or persons renting the canoe in its operation and in the use of the personal floatation devices with
      which it is equipped.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1036.5.</num>
    <text>Instructions under § 1036.4 may be either oral or written, and shall include instructions substantially equivalent to those prescribed by the Mayor pursuant to § 1036.6 of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1036.6.</num>
    <text>The Mayor is authorized to prescribe minimum standards for canoe safety instructions, including standards relating to the need for warning persons renting canoes to avoid standing up in them while underway; and an explanation of basic canoe strokes,
      rules of the road for vessels, the meaning of channel marker buoys, and the meaning of distress signals for small boats.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 29 § 7 of the Police Regulations of the District of Columbia (January 1983).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>