<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-1603</num>
  <heading>PUBLIC NOTICE BY THE DIRECTOR (ยง 19-1603)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1603.1</num>
    <text>1603.1 At least thirty (30) days before granting an application for a new or aenewal license, the Director shall give written notice to the affected Advisoryeighborhood Commission and shall cause the notice to be published in theistrict of Columbia
      Register.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1603.2</num>
    <text>1603.2 The notice shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name of the applicant and the trade name of the public hall;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The address or other designation of the location of the building for whichhe license is sought;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A statement that any resident or owner of residential property, within sixundred (600) feet of the boundary lines of the lot upon which is situated theuilding for which the license is sought, who objects to the granting of thepplication is entitled
        to be heard at a hearing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A concise description of the proposed hours of operation and the kinds ofvents that will occur at the public hall;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The date and manner by which a person or organization must file anbjection with the Director; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The date, time, and location of the hearing to be held if objections areiled.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 9292, 9293 (December 11, 1992); asmended by Notice of emergency and proposed rulemaking at 52 DCR 8531(September6, 2005) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 521, 523January 8, 2010).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR&amp;#8217;S NOTE</heading>
      <text>Section 1603 published at 39 DCR 9292 (December 11, 1992)as renumbered as section 1601 by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 521January 8, 2010). Section 1605 published at 39 DCR 9292 (December 11, 1992)as renumbered as section 1603 by Final Rulemaking
        published at 57 DCR 521January 8, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>