<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-1599</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 19-1599)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1599.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Angling &amp;#8211; fishing by hook and line.</text>
    <text>Resident &amp;#8211; a person who resides in the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Nonresident &amp;#8211; a person who does not reside in the District of Columbia. Commercial &amp;#8211; the taking of fish or other aquatic organisms for sale or profit.</text>
    <text>Department &amp;#8211; the Department of Health.</text>
    <text>Baitfish &amp;#8211; all species of small fish commonly called minnows, shiners, chubs, or by whatever name described, and including small fish of any other species commonly used as bait, less than six inches (6”) in total length, but not including
      any fish with a minimum size limit or protected.</text>
    <text>Conservation or law officer &amp;#8211; any law enforcement official charged with enforcement of the fisheries regulations of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Scientific collecting &amp;#8211; the collection of fish or other aquatic organisms for scientific purposes by educational institutions, other organizations, or individuals engaged in scientific research.</text>
    <text>Indigenous &amp;#8211; species of fish or other aquatic organisms that are native or introduced to the water of the District of Columbia prior to implementation of fisheries regulations.</text>
    <text>Snagging &amp;#8211; the taking of a fish by hooking in any part of the body other than the mouth.</text>
    <text>Total Length &amp;#8211; the length from the anterior-most part of the fish to the tip of the longest caudal fin rays.</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; the Director of the Department of Health, or the Director&amp;#8217;s designee.</text>
    <text>Wildlife &amp;#8211; any wild animal other than a fish.</text>
    <text>National Fishing Week (NFW) &amp;#8211; a weeklong nationwide festivity, usually the first week in June, that brings government agencies, the sport fishing industry, conservation clubs, nonprofit organizations, local and corporate businesses and the
      American public together to sponsor fishing and educational events.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 2028, 2033 (March 27, 1987); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 D.C. Reg. 3361 (May 12, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>