<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-104</num>
  <heading>QUORUM (§ 19-104)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>104.1</num>
    <text>104.1 Six (6) Members shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business at any meeting of the Board, except that if a quorum is not present at a meeting, a majority of the Members present may adjourn the meeting to another time, without further
      notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.2</num>
    <text>104.2 Except as otherwise provided by the Act or these bylaws, an affirmative vote of a majority of the Members present at a meeting at which a quorum exists shall be required for any valid Board action; provided, however, that no resolution authorizing
      the issuance of any bonds or adopting any budget or financial plan shall be deemed approved unless the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia voted in favor of such action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.3</num>
    <text>104.3 A Member may vote either in person or by proxy given to another Member. The proxy shall be executed in writing by the Member who is absent, shall name the Member to whom the proxy is given, and shall be delivered to the Secretary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.4.</num>
    <text>Each proxy shall specifically identify the meeting for which the proxy is valid.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.5.</num>
    <text>A Member’s proxy may be revoked by the Member at any time in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.6</num>
    <text>104.6 No vacancy in membership, except a vacancy in the Office of Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia, shall impair the right of a quorum to exercise all rights and perform all duties of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.7</num>
    <text>104.7 Subject to the provisions of Section 105 below and at the discretion of the Chairperson, any or all Members may participate in a meeting of the Board, or a committee of the Board, by means of telephone conference or by any means of communication
      by which all persons participating in the meeting are able to hear one another, and such participation shall constitute presence in person at the meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 3816, 3818 (June 12, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 10919, 10921 (November 19, 2010); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 8953 (June 14, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>