<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-1031</num>
  <heading>COLLISIONS, ACCIDENTS, AND CASUALTIES (ยง 19-1031)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1031.1.</num>
    <text>To the extent that he or she can do so without serious danger to his or her own vessel or persons aboard, the operator of a vessel involved in a collision, accident, or other casualty shall render all practical and necessary assistance to persons
      affected by the collision, accident, or casualty to save them from or minimize any danger caused by the collision, accident, or casualty.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1031.2.</num>
    <text>An operator of a vessel involved in a collision, accident, or other casualty shall give, in writing, his or her name, address, and the identification of his or her vessel to any person injured and to the owner of any property damaged.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1031.3.</num>
    <text>The duties imposed by this section shall be in addition to any duties otherwise imposed by other law or regulation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1031.4.</num>
    <text>The operator (or the owner if the operator is incapable or unavailable) of a vessel shall file a written accident or casualty report with the Metropolitan Police Department on the form prescribed by the Chief of Police when, as a result of an incident
      that involves the vessel or its equipment, one of the following occurs:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A person dies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A person is injured and requires medical treatment beyond first aid;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Damage to the vessel and other property totals more than two hundred dollars ($200), or there is a complete loss of a vessel; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A person disappears from the vessel under circumstances that indicate death or injury.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1031.5.</num>
    <text>Accident or casualty reports required by ยง 1031.4 shall be filed within ten (10) days of the incident or death, except in the following instances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If a person dies within twenty-four (24) hours of the incident, the report shall be filed within forty-eight (48) hours of the incident; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If a person is injured and requires medical treatment beyond first aid, or disappears from a vessel, the report shall be filed within forty-eight (48) hours of the incident.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1031.6.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of ยง 1031.5, if a person dies or disappears from a vessel as a result of an incident that involves the vessel or its equipment, the operator (or the owner if the operator is incapable) of the vessel shall immediately
      notify the Harbor Master.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1031.7.</num>
    <text>Accident or casualty reports filed under this section shall not be open to public inspection or release; provided, that nothing contained in this subsection shall be construed as prohibiting the inspection of a report by any person named in the report
      or his or her designated representative, or the furnishing of copies of the report to those persons upon the payment of the costs of furnishing the copies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1031.8.</num>
    <text>Nothing contained in this section shall be construed as prohibiting the disclosure of accident or casualty reports to officials of the governments of the United States, the District of Columbia, or any state or subdivision of a state, for official
      purposes, or the use of those reports by those officials in any administrative or judicial proceeding in which such governments are interested.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 29 ยง 14 of the Police Regulations of the District of Columbia (January 1983).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>