<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-1022</num>
  <heading>ENFORCEMENT (§ 19-1022)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1022.1.</num>
    <text>The Harbor Master is authorized to stop and board any vessel subject to the provisions of this chapter for the purpose of inspecting or determining compliance with this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1022.2.</num>
    <text>The Harbor Master is empowered to make a summary arrest, or to issue a summons for appearance in court, for all violations of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1022.3.</num>
    <text>Law enforcement vessels shall be marked so as to identify them as law enforcement vessels.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1022.4.</num>
    <text>While underway and upon being hailed by the Harbor Master or Fire Chief, each vessel subject to the provisions of this chapter shall stop immediately and lay to, or shall maneuver in such a way as to, permit the Harbor Master or Fire Chief to come
      aboard. All vessels shall yield and lay to any emergency law enforcement or fire vessel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1022.5.</num>
    <text>Upon observing any vessel being used in violation of this chapter in any of the following ways, the Harbor Master may order the operator to take any immediate reasonable steps that may be necessary for the safety of those aboard the vessel, including
      ordering the operator to proceed at a location designated by the Harbor Master, and to remain there until the situation creating the hazard is remedied or ended;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Without sufficient lifesaving equipment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>With improper navigation light display;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>In an overloaded condition;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>With an accumulation of fuel in the bilge compartment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>With leaky fuel lines;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Without sufficient firefighting equipment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Without a Coast Guard-approved backflame arrester;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>With inadequate ventilation; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>With any other unsafe condition, and when, in his judgment, such use creates a hazardous condition, may order the operator to take such immediate reasonable steps as may be necessary for the safety of those aboard the vessel, including ordering
        the operator to proceed to a location designated by him and to remain there until the situation creating the hazard is remedied or ended.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1022.6.</num>
    <text>Upon observing any vessel being used in violation of this chapter in any of the following ways, the Fire Chief may order the operator to take any immediate reasonable steps that may be necessary for the safety of those aboard the vessel, including
      ordering the operator to proceed to a location designated by the Fire Chief, and to remain there until the situation creating the hazard is remedied or ended:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>With an accumulation of fuel in the bilge compartment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>With leaky fuel lines;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Without sufficient firefighting equipment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Without a Coast Guard-approved backflame arrester;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>With inadequate ventilation; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>With any other unsafe condition that, in the Fire Chief’s judgment, created a hazardous condition.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 29 § 24 of the Police Regulations of the District of Columbia (January 1983).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>