<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-1203</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION FOR SIGHTSEEING TOUR GUIDE LICENSE (§ 19-1203)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1203.1</num>
    <text>1203.1 A person applying for a sightseeing tour guide license shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be at least eighteen (18) years of age;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be proficient in the English language; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Not have been convicted or have served all or part of a sentence within theast five (5) years for a felony, or an attempt to commit a felony, of theollowing types:</text>
    </level>
    <text>A felony involving violence, the threat of violence, reckless driving, or anyther action impacting the safety of others, if the Director determines that theecord of such a felony indicates that licensure of the applicant as aightseeing tour guide
      may pose a reasonable threat to the safety of others; or</text>
    <text>A felony involving a breach of trust or dishonesty, unless the Directoretermines that the applicant is a person of sufficient honesty and integrity toct as a sightseeing tour guide.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1203.2</num>
    <text>1203.2 An applicant for a sightseeing tour guide license shall make a sworntatement as to the veracity of the statements contained in his or herpplication and pay all required fees related to licensure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1203.3</num>
    <text>1203.3 An applicant for a sightseeing tour guide license must pass anxamination under the supervision of the Director, or the Director’sesignated agent, covering the applicant’s knowledge of buildings and pointsf historical and general interest in
      the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 2 § 8 (a), (b) &amp;#038; (d) of the Police Regulations of theistrict of Columbia (January 1983); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at7 DCR 6116, 6117 (July 16, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>