<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2009</num>
  <heading>PROMOTERS LICENSE (§ 19-2009)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2009.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall promote an event without a promoter’s license issued pursuant to this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2009.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a license as a promoter shall submit the following information with the application:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If the applicant is a corporation, the names and street addresses of its directors, officers, and resident agent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the applicant is a partnership or joint venture, the name and street address of each partner or joint venturer, but if a partner or joint venturer is a corporation, the name and street address of each director, officer and the resident agent
        of the partner or joint venturer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If the applicant is an unincorporated association, the names and street addresses or all trustees and managing directors of the applicant; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any information required by the Commission to determine whether the applicant or any of its principal officers have been convicted of a felony or misdemeanor involving fraud or which has a substantial relationship to the regulation of boxing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2009.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant is not eligible for a license as a promoter if the applicant has been convicted of a misdemeanor within five (5) years, or a felony within ten (10) years, preceding the date of application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2009.4.</num>
    <text>The Commission may take disciplinary action against a promoter in the case of the violation by a matchmaker of § 2011.3.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3710, 3714 (May 20, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>