<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2700</num>
  <heading>ESTABLISHMENT; PURPOSE (§ 19-2700)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2700.1.</num>
    <text>There is established as an independent authority of the District government a District of Columbia Sports Commission (the “Commission”).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.2.</num>
    <text>The Commission is created as a corporate body and instrumentality of the District for the following purposes:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Promoting the District as a location for holding sporting events which will enhance the District’s economic development through, among other things, tourism, job opportunities, entertainment, business development, and national and international
        exposure;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Providing community outreach and grassroots recreation for all residents of the District, especially children;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Coordinating the development, construction, and implementation of new facilities and related infrastructure, and the improvement of existing facilities in the District including issuing bonds, notes, or other obligations to finance the acquisition,
        construction, rehabilitation, or expansion of such facilities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Managing and maintaining facilities in the District which presently exist and which may hereafter be constructed by the Commission or the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Promoting and marketing sports events in the District and participation in such sports events, including, but not limited to, boxing, wrestling, martial arts, track and field, gymnastics, basketball, and other matches, contests, exhibitions, and
        showings, professional as well as amateur, of any kind or nature; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Owning and operating professional sports franchises in the District.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is the Omnibus Sports Consolidation Act of 1994, as amended, D.C. Law 10-152, D.C. Code §§ 2-4001 et seq. (1994 Repl. and 1999 Supp.).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 487 (January 24, 1997), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 43 DCR 3100- 3101 (June 14, 1996).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR’S NOTE</heading>
      <text>These regulations repealed the by-laws of the DC Armory Board and established the District of Columbia Sports Commission By-Laws.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>