<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2415</num>
  <heading>FOULS (ยง 19-2415)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2415.1.</num>
    <text>The following are fouls and will result in penalties if committed:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Butting with the head;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Eye gouging of any kind;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Biting or spitting at an opponent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Hair pulling;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Fish hooking;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Groin attacks of any kind;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Intentionally placing a finger in any opponent&amp;#8217;s orifice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Downward pointing of elbow strikes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Small joint manipulation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Strikes to the spine or back of the head;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Heel kicks to the kidney;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Throat strikes of any kind;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Clawing, pinching, twisting the flesh or grabbing the clavicle;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>Kicking the head of a grounded fighter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>Kneeing the head of a grounded fighter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(p)</num>
      <text>Stomping of a grounded fighter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(q)</num>
      <text>The use of abusive language in fighting area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(r)</num>
      <text>Any unsportsmanlike conduct that causes an injury to opponent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(s)</num>
      <text>Attacking an opponent on or during the break;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(t)</num>
      <text>Attacking an opponent who is under the referee&amp;#8217;s care at the time;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(u)</num>
      <text>Timidity (avoiding contact, or consistent dropping of mouthpiece, or faking an injury);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(v)</num>
      <text>Interference from a mixed martial artist&amp;#8217;s seconds;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(w)</num>
      <text>Throwing an opponent out of the fighting area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(x)</num>
      <text>Flagrant disregard of the referee&amp;#8217;s instructions; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(y)</num>
      <text>Spiking an opponent to the canvas on his or her head or neck.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2415.2.</num>
    <text>Disqualification occurs after any combination of three of the fouls listed in section 2415.1 or after a referee determines that a foul was intentional and flagrant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2415.3.</num>
    <text>Fouls will result in a point being deducted by the official scorekeeper from the offending mixed martial artist&amp;#8217;s score.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2415.4.</num>
    <text>Only a referee can assess a foul. If the referee does not call the foul, judges shall not make that assessment on his or her own and cannot factor such into their scoring calculations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2415.5.</num>
    <text>A fouled fighter has up to five minutes to recuperate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2415.6.</num>
    <text>If a foul is committed, the referee shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Call time;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Check the fouled mixed martial artist&amp;#8217;s condition and safety; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Assess the foul to the offending contestant, deduct points, and notify each corner&amp;#8217;s seconds, the judges, and the official scorekeeper.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2415.7.</num>
    <text>If a bottom contestant commits a foul, unless the top contestant is injured, the fight shall continue, so as not to jeopardize the top contestant&amp;#8217;s superior positioning at the time. In such scenarios, the referee shall act as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The referee shall verbally notify the bottom contestant of the foul;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>When the round is over, the referee shall assess the foul and notify both corners&amp;#8217; seconds, the judges and the official scorekeeper; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The referee may terminate a bout based on the severity of a foul. For such a flagrant foul, a contestant shall lose by disqualification.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 7226 (July 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>