<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2107</num>
  <heading>WEIGHT CLASSIFICATIONS (ยง 19-2107)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2107.1.</num>
    <text>The following weight classifications for boxers are hereby established:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Flyweight, at least one hundred twelve pounds (112 lbs.) but not more than one hundred seventeen pounds (117 lbs.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Bantamweight, over one hundred seventeen pounds (117 lbs.) but not more than one hundred twenty-five pounds (125 lbs.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Featherweight, over one hundred twenty-five pounds (125 lbs.) but not more than one hundred thirty-four pounds (134 lbs.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Lightweight, over one hundred thirty-four pounds (134 lbs.) but not more than one hundred forty-five pounds (145 lbs.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Welterweight, over one hundred forty-five pounds (145 lbs.) but not more than one hundred fifty-nine pounds (159 lbs.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Middleweight, over one hundred fifty-nine pounds (159 lbs.) but not more than one hundred seventy-three pounds (173 lbs.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Light heavyweight, over one hundred seventy-three pounds (173 lbs.) but not more than one hundred eighty-nine pounds (189 lbs.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Cruiserweight, over one hundred eighty-nine pounds (189 lbs.) but not more than one hundred ninety-five pounds (195 lbs.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Heavyweight, over one hundred ninety-five pounds (195 lbs.).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2107.2.</num>
    <text>The Commission may, further recognize subcategories of the categories established in this section according to the rules of the association or federation under whose auspices a championship contest is held.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2107.3.</num>
    <text>The following weight spreads are permissible for matchmaking in boxing events within each weight classification:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Flyweight, no limit;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Bantamweight, not more than four pounds (4 lbs.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Featherweight, not more than five pounds (5 lbs.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Lightweight, not more than six pounds (6 lbs.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Welterweight, not more than seven pounds (7 lbs.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Middleweight, not more than eight pounds (8 lbs.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Light heavyweight, not more than ten pounds (10 lbs.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Cruiserweight, not more than twelve pounds (12 lbs.); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Heavyweight, no limit.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2107.4.</num>
    <text>The Commission may waive the requirements of ยง 2107.3 for good cause.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3731, 3733-34 (May 20, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>