<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2137</num>
  <heading>AMATEUR BOXING EVENTS (§ 19-2137)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2137.1.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall cooperate in the enforcement of United States Amateur Boxing Federation or National Collegiate Athletic Association rules; provided, that these rules are not contrary to this chapter or chapter 16 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2137.2.</num>
    <text>In addition to the requirements of amateur rules, the promoter of an amateur event shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Obtain a contest permit prior to holding the event;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Provide the Commission with the tax exemption number of the promoter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Submit to the Commission, prior to commencement of the event, when admission is charged, a manifest or report on the number, kind, and price of the tickets printed for the event;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Obtain the services of two (2) ringside physicians, licensed and approved by the Commission; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Ensure the availability of an ambulance on site during the event.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2137.3.</num>
    <text>The promoter shall provide, at a minimum, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Rosin boxes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Gloves;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Water buckets and siphon bottles;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Stretcher;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Adequate lighting;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Stools;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Steps leading into the ring at both corners;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>A ring that is ready four (4) hours before the event; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>A ring that is four feet (4’) above the floor, with four (4) strand ropes secured by strings on all sides, corner and canvas paddings one and one-half (1 ½”) inches thick, clean and sanitary.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2137.4.</num>
    <text>Each contestant competing in any amateur event shall be properly fitted with, and at all times during the event shall wear, protective head gear and a mouthpiece, approved by the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2137.5.</num>
    <text>Each contestant competing in any amateur event shall use thumbless or thumb- attached padded gloves approved by the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3731, 3750-52 (May 20, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>