<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2707</num>
  <heading>CONFLICT OF INTEREST (§ 19-2707)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2707.1.</num>
    <text>Any member or employee of the Commission who, in the discharge of his or her official duties, would be required to take action or make a decision that would affect directly or indirectly his or her financial interest, as defined by D.C. Code § 1-1461(b),
      or those of a member of his or her household or a business with which he or she is associated, or must take an official action on a matter as to which he or she has a conflict situation created by a personal, family, or client interest, shall disclose
      the same, in writing, to the Secretary to the Board, or shall submit a statement for the record at the appropriate meeting of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2707.2.</num>
    <text>The Chairperson shall excuse any such member or employee from voting, negotiating, discussing, deliberating, or taking other action on the matter, if the member or employee requests to be excused.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2707.3.</num>
    <text>If a member or employee of the Sports Commission discloses a potential conflict of interest which the Secretary to the Board determines does not prohibit him or her from taking official action pursuant to D.C. Code § 1-1461(b), the member or employee
      may participate in the vote, negotiation, discussion, deliberation, or other action on the matter; however, such disclosure shall be made whenever the member or employee participates in any vote, deliberation, or other action on the matter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2707.4.</num>
    <text>If the member’s or employee’s participation would be prohibited by D.C. Code § 1-1461(b), the member or employee shall not participate in any vote, negotiation, discussion, deliberation, or other action on the matter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2707.5.</num>
    <text>Any contract or agreement made in violation of this section shall be null and void and give rise to no action against the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2707.6.</num>
    <text>Any information disclosed under this section shall be entered upon the minutes of Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 487 (January 24, 1997), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 43 DCR 3100, 3108-09 (June 14, 1996).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>