<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2803</num>
  <heading>SMALL PURCHASES (§ 19-2803)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2803.1.</num>
    <text>Where the procurement is not reasonably expected to exceed the sum of $100,000.00, competitive bidding is not required. The Commission shall, however, promote competition whenever practicable and to the extent that competition is in the best interests
      of the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2803.2.</num>
    <text>The CCO is authorized to determine the appropriate procedure for making small purchases not reasonably expected to exceed the sum of $50,000.00 and may employ such methods as will be both fair, reasonable and in the best interests of the Commission.
      Such methods may include, without limitation:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Purchase orders, as provided in section 2802;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Quotations, written or by telephone, from three or more qualified sources;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Group or cooperative purchasing techniques; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Comparison of proposed prices with those determined reasonable on previous purchases, current price lists, catalogs or advertisements for similar items, value analysis, the CCO’s personal knowledge of the item being purchased, or any other reasonable
        basis.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2803.3.</num>
    <text>The Commission, or a committee thereof, is authorized to determine the appropriate procedure for making small purchases not reasonably expected to exceed the sum of $100,000.00 and may employ such methods as will be both fair, reasonable and in the
      best interests of the Commission. Such methods may include, without limitation:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Purchase orders, as provided in section 2802;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Quotations, written or by telephone, from five or more qualified sources;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Group or cooperative purchasing techniques; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Comparison of proposed prices with those determined reasonable on previous purchases, current price lists, catalogs or advertisements for similar items, value analysis, the CCO’s personal knowledge of the item being purchased, or any other reasonable
        basis.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2803.4.</num>
    <text>No procurement shall be split or divided in terms of time, quantity, supplier, or otherwise so as to circumvent the provisions hereof.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 7420, 7422-23 (October 9, 1998).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>