<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2126</num>
  <heading>PROTECTION OF CONTESTANTS DURING EVENT (§ 19-2126)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2126.1.</num>
    <text>The examining physician shall attend to the contestants at the immediate ringside until the conclusion of the final contest on a program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2126.2.</num>
    <text>After the final contest on a program the examining physician shall go to the dressing room and ascertain whether any contestant has been injured in the ring. If so, the physician shall ensure that the contestant receives the necessary medical treatment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2126.3.</num>
    <text>Before engaging in any contest each contestant shall be physically examined at a time and place designated by the Commission by a licensed physician appointed by the Commission. The inspector shall ensure that all contestants comply with this requirement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2126.4.</num>
    <text>No contestant may take part in a contest without the approval of a licensed physician appointed by the Commission. The physician shall certify the facts of the physical examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2126.5.</num>
    <text>The Commission may revoke or take other action against a contestant’s license if it finds that the contestant, at any time before or during a contest, has used any drug, alcohol, or stimulant that alters the physical or mental state or the performance
      of a contestant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2126.6.</num>
    <text>Immediately before and during a contest a contestant or second may use the following substances and materials or any other substances and materials as approved by the Commission:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Vaseline;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Clean towel (white);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Adrenalin Chloride (1:1,000);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Q-Tips;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Ice bags;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Bandages;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Clean sponges;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Scissors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Gauze pads; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Water.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3731, 3746-47 (May 20, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>