<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2127</num>
  <heading>PROTECTION OF CONTESTANTS AFTER EVENT (§ 19-2127)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2127.1.</num>
    <text>After an event, the Commission, in its discretion, may order a rest period from four (4) to ninety (90) days in length for a contestant, considering the difficulty of the contest for the contestant and the number and severity of the blows absorbed
      by the contestant. The contestant shall not compete again for the duration of such a rest period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2127.2.</num>
    <text>When a contestant has been subject to repeated knockdowns or beatings, or for other reasons of health and safety, the Commission may request that the contestant retire, and should the contestant not do so, move to revoke the contestant&amp;#8217;s
      license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2127.3.</num>
    <text>In case of serious injury to a contestant, the Commission may conduct an investigation to determine if there has been a violation of this chapter on the part of any person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2127.4.</num>
    <text>The Commission may investigate, require a medical examination of, or report to other jurisdictions a contestant who has had six (6) straight defeats.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2127.5.</num>
    <text>If a contestant has had four (4) straight knockouts, the Commission may hold a hearing to determine whether the contestant is any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A “tanker” or contestant who intentionally loses a contest;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Incompetent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Physically unfit; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Under unscrupulous management.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2127.6.</num>
    <text>A contestant who suffers a concussion or six (6) straight knockouts shall not compete again for at least six (6) months following the last knockout. After that period, three (3) physicians appointed by the Commission, one of whom shall be a neurosurgeon,
      shall determine medically whether the contestant is eligible for further competition. The Commission shall then determine whether the contestant’s license may be revoked. The physician’s examination shall include an electroencephalogram (EEG) and
      a computerized axial tomography (CAT) scan. This information shall be provided to the Commission and entered into the Commission&amp;#8217;s record and into the contestant’s passport.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2127.7.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § 2127.8, a contestant who loses by a knockout shall not compete again for sixty (60) days, and a contestant who loses by a technical knockout decision shall not compete again for thirty (30) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2127.8.</num>
    <text>The Commission may permit a contestant to compete before the end of the period provided in § 2127.7 if a physician approved by the Commission examines the contestant and determines that the contestant has fully recovered.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3731, 3747-48 (May 20, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>