<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2900</num>
  <heading>PURPOSE; ENFORCEMENT (§ 19-2900)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2900.1.</num>
    <text>The D.C. Armory Board regulations stated in this chapter shall establish the exclusive policies relating to the posting and display of signs and banners by patrons at events held in facilities owned and operated by the D.C. Armory Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2900.2.</num>
    <text>The General Manager of the Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Stadium/D.C. National Guard Armory Complex (STARPLEX) is vested with the authority to implement the policies stated herein.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2900.3.</num>
    <text>This chapter shall apply to all paid admission events held after the effective date of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2900.4.</num>
    <text>If any provision of this chapter is considered invalid, void or unenforceable by a court of competent jurisdiction, this chapter shall be construed as though the provision does not appear herein. Any such finding by a court of competent jurisdiction
      shall not affect the validity of any other section, paragraph or sentence of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2900.5.</num>
    <text>The proscriptions on the display of signs and/or banners contained in this chapter shall be construed in light of standards set forth in applicable court precedents.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the legal authorities for this chapter is An Act to establish a District of Columbia Armory Board, and for other purposes, 62 Stat. 339, 340 (1948) (codified at D.C. Code §§ 2-301 et seq. (1994 Repl.)).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 6138 (September 2, 1994).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR’S NOTE</heading>
      <text>The nonmilitary functions of the Armory Board were transferred to the D.C. Sports and Entertainment Commission pursuant to D.C. Law 10-152, the “Omnibus Sports Consolidated Act of 1994,” codified at D.C. Code §§ 2-4001 et seq. (1999 Supp.).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>