<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2323</num>
  <heading>TICKETS (§ 19-2323)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2323.1.</num>
    <text>No person, except members of the Metropolitan Police Department assigned to duty at a contest, may be admitted to the event without a ticket.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2323.2.</num>
    <text>Each ticket except those for the working press, Officials, employees, and official photographers, shall have the price, name of the promoter, date, and place of the exhibition printed plainly on it.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2323.3.</num>
    <text>No promoter shall sell a ticket at a price other than the price which appears on the ticket.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2323.4.</num>
    <text>No promoter shall change a ticket price or the place or date of an event without the approval of the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2323.5.</num>
    <text>Tickets of different prices shall be printed on cardboard of different colors.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2323.6.</num>
    <text>An inspector shall check the number and location of ticket boxes at the gates, ensure that the ticket boxes are sealed and padlocked, and open the ticket boxes and count the tickets after the event.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2323.7.</num>
    <text>Each ticket issued to the press shall be marked “Press”.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2323.8.</num>
    <text>A maximum of two percent (2%) of the tickets to a contest may be complimentary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2323.9.</num>
    <text>Each complimentary ticket shall be marked “Complimentary”.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2323.10.</num>
    <text>The promoter shall provide to the Commission, prior to the commencement of an event at which admission is charged, a manifest or report on the number, kind, and price of tickets printed for the event.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2323.11.</num>
    <text>Each ticket shall be separated from the stub when entering through a gate. No person without a stub may occupy a seat.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2323.12.</num>
    <text>After each event where an admission fee is charged, the promoter and the inspector shall submit and sign a detailed report on the results of the event, attendance, number of tickets sold at various prices, and total gate receipts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2323.13.</num>
    <text>At each event, representatives of the promoter and the inspector of the Commission shall supervise the gates and the gate receipts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2323.14.</num>
    <text>The inspector shall ensure that the box in which tickets are deposited has two (2) padlocks. The Commission or its officials shall have the key or combination of one lock and the promoter shall have the key or combination of the other lock.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking at 35 DCR 3759, 3769-70 (May 20, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>