<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2131</num>
  <heading>SECONDS (§ 19-2131)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2131.1.</num>
    <text>Each contestant shall have at least two (2) and not more than three (3) seconds. Only one (1) second is allowed inside the ring between rounds.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2131.2.</num>
    <text>No person who holds only a second&amp;#8217;s license shall act as a manager, assist in procuring matches, or take a share of the contestant’s earnings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2131.3.</num>
    <text>A manager acting as a second shall be neatly attired when in the ring. No headdress may be worn in the ring. A towel used by a second shall be white and clean.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2131.4.</num>
    <text>A second shall submit to the dressing room inspector all equipment and first aid accessories intended for use in the ring.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2131.5.</num>
    <text>During a round, a second shall not assist the contestant vocally or by using the hands, face, or body; shall not attempt to heckle or annoy the opponent; and shall remain seated and silent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2131.6.</num>
    <text>A second shall not enter a ring until the bell indicates the end of a round; shall leave the ring at the sound of the timers whistle, ten (10) seconds before a round is to begin; and shall remove all obstructions, buckets, and the stool promptly at
      the sound of the gong.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2131.7.</num>
    <text>No second shall enter the ring during a round.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2131.8.</num>
    <text>Each contestant shall name for each contest a chief second who shall be responsible for the conduct of the assistant seconds during the contest.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3731, 3749 (May 20, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>