<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2817</num>
  <heading>CONTRACT COST PRINCIPLES (§ 19-2817)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2817.1.</num>
    <text>The contract cost principles shall be used in the pricing of fixed-price contracts, subcontracts, and modifications to contracts and subcontracts whenever cost analysis is performed, or a contract clause requires the determination or negotiation,
      or allowance of costs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2817.2.</num>
    <text>The contract cost principles shall be mandatory and incorporated by reference in contracts as the basis for the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Determining reimbursable costs under cost-reimbursement contracts and cost- reimbursement subcontracts, and the cost-reimbursement portion of time-and-materials contracts, except when material is priced on a basis other than at cost;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Negotiating indirect cost rates;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Proposing, negotiating, or determining costs under terminated contracts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Price revision of fixed-price incentive contracts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Price redetermination of price redetermination contracts; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Pricing changes and other contract modifications.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2817.3.</num>
    <text>The factors to be considered in determining whether a cost is allowable shall include, but not be limited to, reasonableness, allocability, allowability, and the terms of the contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2817.4.</num>
    <text>A cost shall be reasonable if, in its nature and amount, it does not exceed that which would be incurred by a prudent person in the conduct of competitive business.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2817.5.</num>
    <text>A cost shall be allocable to a contract if it is assignable or chargeable to one or more cost objectives on the basis of relative benefits received or other equitable relationship.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2817.6.</num>
    <text>The following shall be a treatment of specific non-allowable cost categories:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Bad debt, penalties and fines, and contingency costs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Depreciation and use allowances made for fully depreciated assets;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Advertising costs and entertainment costs, unless incurred as a direct result of compliance with specific provisions of the contract or written instructions of the contracting officer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Gifts, contributions, and donations (reasonable costs for the morale, health, welfare, food, services, or lodging of contractor’s employees are not gifts and shall be allowable); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Interest expenses incurred by contractors cost unless stated otherwise in the terms and conditions of the solicitation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 4081, 4100-02 (June 22, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>