<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-217</num>
  <heading>ETHICS AND PROCUREMENT (§ 19-217)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>217.1</num>
    <text>217.1 Violation by an employee of any provision of chapter 5 of theuthority’s regulations, relating to ethical conduct, shall be grounds fororrective action pursuant to § 216.1 of these rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>217.2</num>
    <text>217.2 Violation by an employee of § 300.2 of the Authority’s regulations,rohibiting unauthorized obligations, shall be grounds for corrective actionursuant to § 216.1 of these rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>217.3</num>
    <text>217.3 It is the policy of the Authority that any employee who reasonablyelieves that an activity, policy, or practice violates a law or regulation orisuses resources or funds under the control of an official of the Authority orf the District government
      shall report any such violation or misuse to anppropriate supervisor. The Authority shall not take any retaliatory actiongainst an employee who:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Discloses or threatens to disclose to a supervisor or to a public body anctivity, policy, or practice that the employee reasonably believes violates aaw or regulation or misuses resources or funds under the control of an officialf the Authority
        or of the District government;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Provides information to or testifies before any public body conducting annvestigation, hearing, or inquiry into an alleged violation of a law oregulation or into an alleged misuse of resources or funds under the control ofn official of the Authority
        or of the District government; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Objects to or refuses to participate in any activity or practice that themployee reasonably believes to be fraudulent or in violation of a law oregulation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 6236, 6243-44 (July 30, 1999); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8191, 8200 (July 6, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>