<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2099</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 19-2099)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2099.1.</num>
    <text>As used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Act &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia Boxing and Wrestling Commission Act, as amended, D.C. Code §§ 2-601 to 2-610 (1994 Repl. and 1999 Supp.).</text>
    <text>Commission &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia Boxing and Wrestling Commission established by the Act.</text>
    <text>Contestant &amp;#8211; a boxer, wrestler, kickboxer, or mixed martial artist as the context requires.</text>
    <text>Department &amp;#8211; Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; the Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs, or the Director’s designee.</text>
    <text>Event &amp;#8211; a boxing, wrestling, kickboxing, or mixed martial arts contest, match, exhibition, or showing, as the context requires.</text>
    <text>Inspector &amp;#8211; an official of the Commission who enforces the rules applicable to the preparation for and holding of contests, in areas such as the collection of gate receipts, dressing room activity, and readiness and use of equipment, and
      who supervises the activity in the corner of the ring during a contest.</text>
    <text>Judge &amp;#8211; an official of the Commission who scores the performance of contestants.</text>
    <text>Matchmaker &amp;#8211; a person who examines the history and skills of two (2) contestants to determine the reasonable equivalence of skills which will result in a competitive contest.</text>
    <text>Passport &amp;#8211; an international record book containing medical and competitive history.</text>
    <text>Program &amp;#8211; one or more contests held at the same place on the same day or for which a single admission fee is charged.</text>
    <text>Referee &amp;#8211; an official of the Commission who presides over each contest and enforces the rules applicable to the contest.</text>
    <text>Second &amp;#8211; person who tends to a contestant in the corner of ring during a contest.</text>
    <text>Take Down &amp;#8211; clinching or wrestling an opponent to the mat.</text>
    <text>Technical knockout &amp;#8211; a termination of a contest by the referee in order to protect an injured, defenseless contestant, and such that the decision is awarded to the non-injured contestant unless that contestant has caused injury by fouling.</text>
    <text>Telecast &amp;#8211; a presentation or showing of an event on closed circuit telecast or subscription television viewed within the District, whether or not originating within the District.</text>
    <text>Timekeeper &amp;#8211; an official of the Commission who keeps official time in each contest and who marks the passing of seconds, or count.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3710, 3729-30 (May 20, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 D.C. Reg. 7220 (July 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>