<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2499</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 19-2499)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2499.1.</num>
    <text>As used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Decision via scorecards &amp;#8211; A decision made based upon the scores recorded by the judges on the scorecard during the bout. Decisions may be unanimous, split, or majority as defined below:</text>
    <text>1. Unanimous decision: When all three judges score the bout for the same contestant;</text>
    <text>2. Split decision: When two judges score the bout for one contestant and one judge scores for the opponent; or</text>
    <text>3. Majority decision: When two judges score the bout for the same contestant and one judge scores a draw.</text>
    <text>Disqualification: When an injury sustained during competition as a result of an intentional foul is severe enough to terminate the contest.</text>
    <text>Draw: When the bout is scored a tie by the judges unanimously, by a majority, or by a split as defined below:</text>
    <text>1. Unanimous decision &amp;#8211; When all three judges score the bout a draw;</text>
    <text>2. Majority decision &amp;#8211; When two judges score the bout a draw; or</text>
    <text>3. Split decision &amp;#8211; When all three judges score differently and the score total results in a draw.</text>
    <text>Forfeit &amp;#8211; When a contestant fails to begin competition or prematurely ends the contest for reasons other than injury or by indicating a tap out.</text>
    <text>Knockout &amp;#8211; The failure of a contestant to rise from the canvas.</text>
    <text>Majority decision &amp;#8211; When two judges score the bout for the same contestant and one judge scores a draw.</text>
    <text>No contest &amp;#8211; When a contest is prematurely stopped due to accidental injury and a sufficient number of rounds have not been completed to render a decision via the scorecards.</text>
    <text>Split decision &amp;#8211; When two judges score the bout for one contestant and one judge scores for the opponent.</text>
    <text>Tap out &amp;#8211; When a contestant physically uses his hand to indicate that he or she no longer wishes to continue.</text>
    <text>Technical decision &amp;#8211; When the bout is prematurely stopped due to injury and a contestant is leading on the scorecards.</text>
    <text>Technical draw &amp;#8211; When an injury sustained during competition as a result of an intentional foul causes the injured contestant to be unable to continue and the injured contestant is even or behind on the score cards at the time of stoppage.</text>
    <text>Technical knockout &amp;#8211; When a referee stops bout, a ringside physician stops bout, or when an injury as a result of a legal maneuver is severe enough to terminate a bout.</text>
    <text>Unanimous Decision &amp;#8211; When all three judges score the bout the same for each contestant.</text>
    <text>Verbal tap out &amp;#8211; When a contestant verbally announces to the referee that he or she does not wish to continue.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2424.2.</num>
    <text>The definitions in ยง 2099 of Chapter 20 of this title are incorporated by reference into and are applicable to this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 7230 (July27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>