<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2117</num>
  <heading>HEAD BUTTS (ยง 19-2117)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2117.1.</num>
    <text>When a contestant is cut as a result of an unintentional head butt, the referee may stop the contest, and may consult with the ringside physician in making such a determination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2117.2.</num>
    <text>If the contest has been stopped pursuant to ยง 2117.1 during the first (3) rounds of the contest, there shall be no decision in the contest.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2117.3.</num>
    <text>If the contest has been stopped pursuant to ยง 2117.1 after the first three (3) rounds of the contest, the decision shall be made on the basis of the points accumulated by the contestants at the time the contest is stopped.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2117.4.</num>
    <text>If a cut caused by an unintentional head butt is enlarged by subsequent legal blows, and the referee stops the contest as a result, the contest shall be decided on the basis of the points accumulated by the contestants at the time the contest is stopped.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2117.5.</num>
    <text>If a cut caused by an unintentional head butt is enlarged by subsequent head butts, and the referee stops the contest as a result, the contestant who has caused the cut is disqualified, and the opponent shall be declared the winner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2117.6.</num>
    <text>When the referee determines that a head butt has been intentional, the referee may order a two (2) point deduction to be made, or disqualify the contestant who has committed the head butt and stop the contest.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2117.7.</num>
    <text>This section does not apply to championship contests.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3731, 3740 (May 20, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>