<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2119</num>
  <heading>FOULS (§ 19-2119)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2119.1.</num>
    <text>No contestant shall commit any of the following fouls:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Hitting the opponent below the belt;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Hitting an opponent who is down or who is rising after being down.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Holding the opponent with one hand and hitting the opponent with the other hand.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Holding the opponent or deliberately maintaining a clinch.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Wrestling with or roughing the opponent to maintain a clinch;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Punching the opponent after being instructed to stop fighting, as when the opponent is helpless and leaning on the ropes to avoid falling;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Hitting the opponent with the head, elbow, or knee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Hitting the opponent with an open glove, including the inside of the hand, the back of the hand, or the wrist;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Intentionally going down without being hit, to avoid a blow:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Using a pivot blow or rabbit punch, including hitting the back of the opponent’s neck near the base of the skull;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Using a kidney punch, including hitting the part of the back near the spine and over the kidneys;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Hitting the opponent’s eye with the thumb of the glove;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Using the ring ropes to deliver a punch.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>Using abusive language in the ring; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>Engaging in any unsportsmanlike trick or action that injures the opponent.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2119.2.</num>
    <text>The referee shall determine whether or not a foul has been committed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2119.3.</num>
    <text>Upon determining that a foul has been committed, the referee may take the following actions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Warn the contestant that the contestant has committed the foul;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Assess a scoring penalty against the contestant who has committed the foul, as set forth in § 2118.5;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Disqualify the contestant who committed the foul;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Stop the contest; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Take any other action that the referee deems appropriate not inconsistent with these rules.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2119.4.</num>
    <text>The referee shall determine whether a fouled contestant can continue.</text>
    <text>If the referee decides the fouled contestant can continue, but needs a reasonable time to recover, the referee shall interrupt the contest and instruct the timekeeper.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2119.5.</num>
    <text>When the referee has disqualified a contestant for an intentional foul, the contestant shall not take part in a contest for thirty (30) days following the day of the contest in which the contestant was disqualified.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2119.6.</num>
    <text>When the referee determines that a contestant has committed a foul intentionally, the Commission shall order that contestant’s purse be withheld pending a final decision as to whether the purse is forfeited.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3731, 3741-43 (May 20, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>