<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2413</num>
  <heading>JUDGING (ยง 19-2413)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2413.1.</num>
    <text>All bouts will be evaluated and scored by three judges.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2413.2.</num>
    <text>The 10-Point Must Scoring System will be the standard system of scoring a bout. Under the 10-Point Must Scoring System, 10 points must be awarded to the winner of the round and nine points or less must be awarded to the loser, except for a rare even
      round, which is scored (10-10).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2413.3.</num>
    <text>Judges shall evaluate mixed martial arts techniques, such as effective striking, effective grappling, control of the fighting area, effective aggressiveness and defense.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2413.4.</num>
    <text>Evaluation shall be made in the order in which the techniques appear in section 2413.3 above, giving the most weight in scoring to effective striking, effecting grappling, control of the fighting area and effective aggressiveness and defense.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2413.5.</num>
    <text>Effective striking is judged by determining the total number of legal heavy strikes landed by a contestant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2413.6.</num>
    <text>Effective grappling is judged by considering the amount of successful executions of a legal takedown and reversals. Examples of factors to consider are take downs from standing position to mount position, passing the guard to mount position, and bottom
      position fighters using an active, threatening guard.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2413.7.</num>
    <text>Fighting area control is judged by determining who is dictating the pace, location and position of the bout. Examples of factors to consider are countering a grappler&amp;#8217;s attempt at takedown by remaining standing and legally striking; taking
      down an opponent to force a ground fight; creating threatening submission attempts; passing the guard to achieve mount; and creating striking opportunities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2413.8.</num>
    <text>Effective aggressiveness means moving forward and landing a legal strike.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2413.9.</num>
    <text>Effective defense means avoiding being struck, taken down or reversed while countering with offensive attacks.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2413.10.</num>
    <text>Judges shall utilize the following objective scoring criteria when scoring a round:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A round is to be scored as a 10-10 round when both contestants appear to be fighting evenly and neither contestant shows clear dominance in a round;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A round is to be scored as a 10-9 round when a contestant wins by a close margin, landing the greater number of effective legal strikes, grappling and other maneuvers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A round is to be scored as a 10-8 round when a contestant overwhelmingly dominates by striking or grappling in a round; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A round is to be scored as a 10-7 round when a contestant totally dominates by striking or grappling in a round.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2413.11.</num>
    <text>Judges shall use a sliding scale and recognize the length of time the fighters are either standing or on the ground, as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If the mixed martial artists spent a majority of a round on the canvas, then:</text>
    </level>
    <text>1. Effective grappling is weighed first; and</text>
    <text>2. Effective striking is then weighed.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the mixed martial artists spent a majority of a round standing, then:</text>
    </level>
    <text>1. Effective striking is weighed first; and</text>
    <text>2. Effective grappling is then weighed.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If a round ends with a relatively even amount of standing and canvas fighting, striking and grappling are weighed equally.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 7224 (July 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>