<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2808</num>
  <heading>PROTESTS AND DISPUTES (§ 19-2808)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2808.1.</num>
    <text>All protests and supporting documentation shall be filed with the CCO within 7 days of the date the protester knew or should have known of the facts upon which the protest is based. Upon receipt, the CCO shall forthwith notify any interested parties
      of the filing of the protest and shall determine whether to proceed with, or suspend, contract award or performance pending a final decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2808.2.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall issue a decision on the protest within 10 days of its receipt, and any dissatisfied party may appeal that decision to the Commission within 7 days of the CCO’s determination. The decision of the Commission shall be final, subject to
      judicial review in accordance with applicable law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2808.3.</num>
    <text>All claims by a supplier or contractor must be submitted in writing to the CCO for determination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2808.4.</num>
    <text>Each claim must include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A statement of the facts giving rise to the complaint, and any supporting documentation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The specific relief requested.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2808.5.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall investigate and evaluate the claim, and issue a decision thereon within 30 days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2808.6.</num>
    <text>Claimant may appeal an adverse decision by the CCO to the Commission by filing a written request for review within 7 days of the CCO’s determination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2808.7.</num>
    <text>The decision of the Commission shall be final, subject to judicial review in accordance with applicable law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2808.8.</num>
    <text>Pending final resolution of the dispute, claimant shall comply with any of the decisions rendered by the CCO or Commission, and shall proceed diligently with the performance of the contract, except to the extent of any terminations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 7420, 7428-29 (October 9, 1998).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>