<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2825</num>
  <heading>ETHICS IN PUBLIC CONTRACTING (§ 19-2825)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2825.1.</num>
    <text>The Board’s General Counsel may render written advisory opinions regarding the appropriateness of a particular course of conduct to be followed in proposed contracting transactions. The advisory opinions shall be duly published in the manner in which
      regulations of the Board are published.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2825.2.</num>
    <text>It shall be the policy of the Board to promote and balance the objective of protecting government integrity and that of facilitating the recruitment and retention of personnel needed by the Board. Such policy shall be implemented by prescribing essential
      standards of ethical conduct without creating unnecessary obstacles to entering public service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2825.3.</num>
    <text>It shall be a breach of ethical standards for any employee of the Board to participate directly or indirectly in a procurement when the employee knows that the employee or any member of the employee’s immediate family has a financial interest pertaining
      to the procurement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2825.4.</num>
    <text>When a Board employee knows that he or she has an actual or potential conflict of interest, or when the General Manager has determined that an actual conflict of interest exists, the employee shall disqualify himself or herself from the procurement
      involved. The employee may apply to the General Manager for a waiver of the conflict of interest provision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2825.5.</num>
    <text>It shall be a breach of ethical standards for any person to offer, give, or agree to give any employee or former employee, or for any employee or former employee to solicit, demand, accept, or agree to accept from another person, a gratuity or an
      offer of employment in connection with any decision, approval, disapproval, recommendation, or preparation of any part of a procurement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2825.6.</num>
    <text>It shall be a breach of ethical standards for any payment, gratuity, or offer of employment to be made by or on behalf of a subcontractor under a contract to the prime contractor, or higher tier subcontractor, as an inducement for the award of a subcontract
      or order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2825.7.</num>
    <text>It shall be a breach of ethical standards for any employee, former employee or any other person knowingly to use confidential information for actual or anticipated gain.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 4081, 4111-12 (June 22, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>