<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-211</num>
  <heading>HEALTH INSURANCE, LIFE INSURANCE AND RETIREMENT (§ 19-211)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>211.1</num>
    <text>211.1 Regular full-time and regular part-time employees shall be eligible fornrollment on a single or dependent basis in one (1) or more group healthnsurance plans selected by the Authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>211.2</num>
    <text>211.2 The Authority shall contribute a share, determined by the Board ofirectors, of the cost of such single or dependent health insurance coverage foregular full-time employees. The Authority&amp;#8217;s contribution for regularart-time employees
      shall be a prorated amount, which is based on the actualumber of hours worked per week by a regular part-time employee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>211.3</num>
    <text>211.3 Regular full-time employees shall be eligible for enrollment in a lifensurance plan selected by the Authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>211.4</num>
    <text>211.4 The Authority shall pay the cost of such life insurance coverage foregular full-time employees and a portion of the cost for regular part-timemployees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>211.5</num>
    <text>211.5 The Authority shall not contribute to an employee’s health coverage orife insurance if the employee is on general or military leave for more thanhirty (30) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>211.6</num>
    <text>211.6 Regular full-time and regular part-time employees shall participate in anmployees’ Retirement Plan approved by the Board of Directors. In addition,asual employees who work at least one thousand (1,000) hours in a “retirementlan year” shall become
      eligible for participation. The Authority shallontribute to the Employees&amp;#8217; Retirement Plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 6236, 6241 (July 30, 1999); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8191, 8197 (July 6, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>