<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-216</num>
  <heading>CORRECTIVE ACTION PROCESS AND TERMINATION (§ 19-216)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>216.1</num>
    <text>216.1 A supervisor may recommend or take corrective action against an employeeecause of unsatisfactory job performance, neglect of duty or misconduct.orrective actions may include, but are not limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Oral reprimand;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Written reprimand;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Demotion;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Reduction in pay;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Suspension; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Dismissal or termination.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>216.2</num>
    <text>216.2 An employee who fails to notify his or her supervisor of a pendingbsence and who does not report to work for three (3) consecutive workdays maye deemed to have abandoned and voluntarily resigned his or her position. His orer employment may be
      terminated as of the close of business on the third (3rd)ay of absence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>216.3</num>
    <text>216.3 The President and Chief Executive Officer shall review and approve alluspensions, dismissals, and terminations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>216.4</num>
    <text>216.4 The President and Chief Executive Officer may terminate an employeeithout cause for business reasons, such as when:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A position is eliminated because of financial considerations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A position is reclassified or a work unit is restructured; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Segments of the Authority’s services or operations are terminated.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>216.5</num>
    <text>216.5 The President and Chief Executive Officer shall give reasonable advanceotice of intent to eliminate any position or positions to affected employees;rovided that the President and Chief Executive Officer shall provide 60 (sixty)ays notice of
      the elimination of positions if more than one-third (1/3) of theegular full-time positions of the Authority are to be eliminated, in accordanceith the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act, 29 U.S.C. §§ 2101,t seq.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 6236, 6243 (July 30, 1999); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8191, 8199 (July 6, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>