<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-2041</num>
  <heading>DENIALS AND DISCIPLINARY ACTIONS (§ 19-2041)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2041.1.</num>
    <text>The Commission may take one or more of the actions listed in § 2041.4 against an applicant or licensee for the violation of this chapter or chapters 21, 22, or 23 of this title, and in the case of an applicant, for conduct that would constitute a
      violation if committed by a licensee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2041.2.</num>
    <text>The Commission may deny a license to an applicant, or may revoke or suspend a license, or take other adverse action against a licensee, when the applicant or licensee has been denied a license or has been made subject to a disciplinary action, in
      another jurisdiction for reasons of health and safety, or for conduct that, if committed in the District, would be grounds for denial or disciplinary action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2041.3.</num>
    <text>The Commission may deny a license to an applicant who has provided false or fraudulent information on the applicant’s application, and may revoke or suspend any license that was granted on the basis of information subsequently shown to have been false
      or fraudulent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2041.4.</num>
    <text>The Commission may take the following disciplinary actions against an applicant or licensee:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Deny a license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Revoke a license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Suspend a license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Restrict or place conditions on a license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Censure or reprimand a licensee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Impose a civil fine or penalty on a licensee; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Withhold the purse from a contestant and order that it be forfeited, in whole or part.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2041.5.</num>
    <text>Alternative civil sanctions for infractions of the Act of this chapter or chapters 21, 22 or 23 of this title may be imposed pursuant to the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985, D.C. Law 6-42, D.C. Code §§ 6-2701
      et seq. (1995 Repl. and 1999 Supp.), and rules promulgated thereunder, 16 DCMR chapters 31 and 32.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3710, 3720-21 (May 20, 1988).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR’S NOTE</heading>
      <text>The text of section 2041.5 has been changed without formal rulemaking to denote that the regulations which implement the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 were removed from Title 1 of the District of Columbia
        Municipal Regulations and republished at Title 16 of the DCMR (Consumers, Commercial Practices and Civil Infractions).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>