<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-3422</num>
  <heading>CONFLICT OF INTEREST (§ 19-3422)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3422.1.</num>
    <text>Commission employees shall not participate in transactions that may result in conflict, or apparent conflict, between the private interests of the employee and the interests of the organization. Specifically, no employee shall do any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Have a direct or indirect financial interest that conflicts substantially, or appears to conflict substantially, with the employee’s responsibilities for the organization;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Engage directly or indirectly in financial transactions as a result of or primarily in reliance upon information obtained as a result of performing services for the organization as an employee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Solicit or accept, directly or indirectly, any gift, gratuity, favor, compensation, or any other thing of significant monetary value from any person, corporation, or other entity that has, or is seeking to obtain contractual or other business or
        financial relationships with the organization.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3422.2.</num>
    <text>Employees may participate in a political campaign on their own time by using either annual leave or leave without pay. Employees shall not use organization time, facilities, resources or their personal affiliation with the Commission to participate
      in campaign activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3422.3.</num>
    <text>Employees may engage in professional activities and ventures outside the organization provided that the following conditions are met:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Each independent outside professional activity shall be conducted on the employee’s own time without the use of organizational facilities, funds, supplies, staff or resources; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Each outside professional service is not in conflict with any activity or policy of the commission.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3422.4.</num>
    <text>Personal visits by friends or relatives during working hours shall be kept to a minimum. Employees shall not bring their children to the office as a substitute for other child care arrangements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3422.5.</num>
    <text>The official hours of work of the organization shall be 8:30 a.m. to 5:00 p.m., Monday through Friday, unless otherwise designated and approved by the Executive Director, for a total of 40 regular hours in a work week or a total of 2,080 regular hours
      in a year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3422.6.</num>
    <text>Employees who work at least eight (8) hours in a day shall be entitled to take a one (1) hour lunch break. Employees who work fewer than eight (8) hours per day shall be entitled to a lunch break at the discretion of their immediate supervisor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3422.7.</num>
    <text>Employees under the age of eighteen (18) shall not be employed by the Commission unless, and until, the employee had procured a work permit issued by the Board of Education which conforms to the requirements of D.C. Code § 39-508.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 4938, 4950-51 (August 29, 1997).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>