<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-304</num>
  <heading>INVITATIONS FOR BIDS (ยง 19-304)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>304.1.</num>
    <text>Each invitation for bids shall set forth at least the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>bid submission requirements, including the address where bids are to be delivered and the time and date for receipt and opening of bids, which shall be at least 30 days from the date of issuance unless the CCO determines that the nature of the procurement
        requires a quicker response;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>a description of the purchase, delivery or performance schedule, and any special requirements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>instructions to bidders and all applicable standard contract provisions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>the basis on which the award will be made;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>a requirement that bids are irrevocable for 90 days after bid opening; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>a requirement that each prospective bidder receiving an invitation acknowledge receipt of any subsequent amendment to the invitation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>304.2.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall publish a notice of each invitation for bids in a newspaper of general circulation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>304.3.</num>
    <text>The CCO may, in the CCO&amp;#8217;s sole discretion, conduct a pre-bid conference to explain the procurement requirements. The CCO shall announce the conference to all prospective bidders known to have received the invitation for bids.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>304.4.</num>
    <text>The CCO may amend an invitation for bids by sending written notice to all prospective bidders known to have received the invitation for bids.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>304.5.</num>
    <text>A bidder may modify or withdraw a bid by giving written notice at the office designated in the invitation for bids at any time prior to the time set for bid opening.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>304.6.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall not consider a late bid, modification or withdrawal unless: a late bid is the only one received; or the CCO determines that a late modification makes the terms of a timely bid that would have been successful more favorable to the Authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>304.7.</num>
    <text>If the CCO determines, in the CCO&amp;#8217;s sole discretion, that it is in the best interests of the Authority, the CCO may waive, or allow a bidder to correct, minor irregularities after bid opening. A minor irregularity is a matter of form not
      of substance, and one that can be corrected without prejudice to other bidders, such as: a bidder&amp;#8217;s failure to specify the number of its employees; or a bidder&amp;#8217;s failure to acknowledge receipt of an amendment where the bid is
      clearly responsive to the amendment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>304.8.</num>
    <text>The CCO may cancel an invitation for bids at any time prior to bid award, if the CCO determines that cancellation is in the best interests of the Authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>304.9.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall make award to the lowest responsive bidder whose bid meets the requirements and criteria set forth in the invitation for bids, if the CCO determines in writing that the bidder is responsible and the prices offered are reasonable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>304.10.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall give written notice of award to the successful bidder after all required approvals have been obtained.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 4907, 4911-12 (August 22, 1997); and as amended by Final Rulemaking at 49 DCR 10814 (November 29, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>