<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-3418</num>
  <heading>SALARY INCREASE (ยง 19-3418)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3418.1.</num>
    <text>An employee occupying a permanent position who has not reached the maximum step of pay in his/her salary schedule, is entitled to the next higher rate of pay in the salary schedule provided:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The employee has completed the required waiting period;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The employee has performed at an acceptable level of competence based on the most recent performance rating; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The employee has not received an equivalent increase during that period.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3418.2.</num>
    <text>Subject to the availability of funds, the Commission may grant a quality increase in salary equal to the next higher step in the salary schedule of an employee occupying a permanent position who substantially exceeds normal requirements in the most
      important functions (duties) of his/her job. Not more than one quality increase may be granted to the same employee during any 52-week period. Quality increases are in addition to within-grade step increases. Therefore, an employee who receives
      a quality increase does not thereby begin a new waiting period to meet the time requirements for a next within-grade step increase.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3418.3.</num>
    <text>The Personnel Office shall determine which employees are covered by the overtime provisions of the Fair Labor Standards Act. The Executive Director or his/her designee(s) shall approve all overtime work.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3418.4.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director or his/her designee shall grant compensatory time accrual and leave to employees who are exempted from the Fair Labor Standards Act overtime provisions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 4938, 4947 (August 29, 1997).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>