<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-3406</num>
  <heading>PROBATIONARY PERIOD AND REINSTATEMENT (§ 19-3406)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3406.1.</num>
    <text>The probationary period of employment for Commission staff is one (1) year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3406.2.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall evaluate an employee’s performance before the end of the probationary period. If the evaluation is satisfactory, the Personnel Office of the Commission shall remove the employee from probationary status and place him or her on
      permanent status.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3406.3.</num>
    <text>If an employee fails to pass probation, the Commission shall terminate his or her employment. Employees terminated during the probationary period shall not be eligible for severance pay.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3406.4.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, a reinstated employee is one who is terminated and is later rehired. Provided the reinstatement occurs within six months of resignation, reinstated employees shall receive full credit for prior employment determining:
      annual leave accrual, eligibility for Commission contributions to the retirement plan, or any other fringe benefits.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3406.5.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall treat reinstated employees as old employees for the purpose of determining: starting salaries, probationary period, performance evaluations, and eligibility for salary increases.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3406.6.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall treat employees reinstated after a period of six months as new employees for the purposes of determining the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Starting salaries;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Probationary period;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Performance evaluations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Eligibility for salary increases.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 4938, 4941 (August 29, 1997).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>