<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-3411</num>
  <heading>LEAVE OF ABSENCE (§ 19-3411)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3411.1.</num>
    <text>The Commission may grant a medical leave of absence for 240 hours to a permanent full-time employee who has depleted his or her sick leave and annual leave if the following steps are taken:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The employee requests the leave of absence in writing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The employee provides certification from a licensed physician stating the necessity for the leave of absence;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The employee provides a return-to-work authorization from the licensed attending physician; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>There is no history of sick leave abuse.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3411.2.</num>
    <text>The Commission may grant a general leave of absence without pay to the maximum of one (1) year (including extensions) to a regular full-time employee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3411.3.</num>
    <text>Commission employees may take up to sixteen (16) weeks of unpaid leave over a twenty-four (24) month period for family or medical purposes as more fully defined in the Commission’s Personnel Procedures Manual.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3411.4.</num>
    <text>Approval of leave for maternity or paternity reasons shall be consistent with the Commission’s policy for granting leave for similar situations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3411.5.</num>
    <text>An employee who has been summoned to report for jury duty shall be placed on administrative leave for that time period. However, the Commission shall not compensate any such difference in salary or pay for jury duty served on Commission holidays or
      non-working days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3411.6.</num>
    <text>The Commission may grant military leave of absence for a period not to exceed five (5) years. During this period, the employee’s salary and benefit levels shall be frozen, and he or she shall be considered to be on extended leave of absence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3411.7.</num>
    <text>In addition to other types of leave, the Executive Director may grant administrative leave with pay for a variety of reasons to include:</text>
    <text>bereavement not to exceed three (1) days (immediate family consisting of spouse, children, siblings, parents, grandparents, and grandchildren), bad weather conditions or problems associated with physical conditions in the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 4938, 4944 (August 29, 1997).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>