<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-3001</num>
  <heading>PROHIBITED CONDUCT (§ 19-3001)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3001.1.</num>
    <text>The Commission, in accordance with applicable law, prohibits any performance, presentation, show, exhibition, display, address, dramatization, act, routine, simulation, concert, or any part thereof, by licensees, their agents, or assigns, at events
      held in facilities owned and operated by the Commission which contain:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Lewd, indecent, or obscene acts, as defined at D.C. Code § 22-1112;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Nudity, as defined at D.C. Code § 22-2001(b)(2);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Sexual conduct, as defined at D.C. Code § 22-2011(5);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Disorderly conduct, as defined at D.C. Code § 22-1121;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Language likely to provoke a breach of the peace, incite violence or imminent lawless action; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Conduct, behavior, or language otherwise violative of the laws of the United States or the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3001.2.</num>
    <text>Licensees, their agents, or assigns, during any performance, presentation, show, exhibition, display, address, dramatization, act, routine, simulation, concert, or any part thereof, held in facilities owned and operated by the Commission, shall not
      assist, incite, urge, or encourage any person to engage in any conduct, language, or behavior prohibited by this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3001.3.</num>
    <text>In addition to any remedies provided by law, the Commission shall reserve the right to cancel or interrupt, in whole or in part, any performance, presentation, show, exhibition, display, address, dramatization, act, routine, simulation, concert, or
      any part thereof, held in facilities owned and operated by the Commission, which contain any of the conduct, language, or behavior prohibited by this chapter, or remove from the premises any person engaged in conduct, language, or behavior prohibited
      by this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 42 DCR 5232, 5233 (September 15, 1995).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>