<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-3516</num>
  <heading>NEIGHBORHOOD PLANNING COUNCIL OPERATING PROGRAM REQUIREMENTS (§ 19-3516)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3516.1.</num>
    <text>Beginning October 1, 1991, all programs supported either by District Appropriated or Community Services Block Grant funds shall establish quarterly spending plans for all items of purchase to include personnel expenditures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3516.2.</num>
    <text>NPC Program Operators shall be required to explain, in writing to the NPC’s Chairpersons and the Administrator, CBPA, why spending is out of line with the plan, if the program is identified by the Administrator, CBPA, as overspending or underspending
      by ten percent (10%).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3516.3.</num>
    <text>All monies remaining, as a result of underspending, for 15 days after the end of the planned spending quarter shall be declared lapsed and shall be subject to reassignment as follows:</text>
    <text>a. The Program Operator and the NPC’s Chairpersons shall immediately submit to the CBPA Administrator a plan for reprogramming funds and spending them in line with the original purpose and objectives of the program. Copies of all such plans shall
      be provided to the Council of Chairpersons.</text>
    <text>b. All NPC funds remaining unspent 45 days after the end of the planned spending quarter will be placed in the custody of the Council of Chairpersons for reprogramming among eligible NPC programs. All lapsed NPC funds remaining unspent as of May 15
      of each fiscal year shall be redistributed immediately to eligible NPC programs by the Council of Chairpersons.</text>
    <text>c. The CBPA Administrator shall ensure the immediate distribution of lapsed funds in accordance with the directive of the Council of Chairpersons.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3516.4.</num>
    <text>[RESERVED]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3516.5.</num>
    <text>Beginning with fiscal year 1991, if the Community Development Specialist evaluation shows that the actual attendance in a program is consistently below the planned attendance (number served), the Administrator, CBPA, shall take action as follows:</text>
    <text>a. First occurrence: Warning to Program Operator to increase attendance to planned level.</text>
    <text>b. Second Occurrence: Community Development Specialists shall immediately assist Program Operator through use of public service announcements, distribution of flyers and other such actions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3516.6.</num>
    <text>If the NPC, for any reason, fails to submit its proposal for funding by the deadline set by CBPA, the Administrator, CBPA shall immediately move to approve and set funding so as not to inhibit the timely start of program operations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 2521, 2529-30 (April 10, 1992).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>