<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-4357</num>
  <heading>BONDS, INSURANCE AND OTHER FINANCIAL PROTECTIONS (ยง 19-4357)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4357.1.</num>
    <text>The CCO has the discretion to require any types of security specified in this section for any solicitation or contract including the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Bid bonds or proposal bonds;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Performance or payment bonds for construction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Performance or payment bonds or other security for non-construction contracts;</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4357.2.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall consider the following factors in non-construction contracts:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Whether Library property or funds are to be provided to the contractor for use in performing the contract or as partial compensation (such as retention of salvaged material);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>When a contractor sells assets to or merges with another business entity, whether the Library (after recognizing the other entity as the successor in interest) needs assurance that it is financially capable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Whether substantial progress payments are to be made before delivery of end items starts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Whether the contract is for dismantling, demolition, or removal of improvements; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any other factors which might favor the use of security instruments to protect the best interests of the Library.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4357.3.</num>
    <text>A payment security shall be required only when a performance security is required and the use of the payment security is in the best interests of the Library.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4357.4.</num>
    <text>When a security is required by the Library, the CCO may accept any of the following types of security:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A bond provided by a surety in accordance with Section 4358;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A certified check or irrevocable letter of credit issued by an insured financial institution in the equivalent amount of the security; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>United States government securities that are assigned to the Library which pledge the full faith and credit of the United States.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4357.5.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall determine a contractor&amp;#8217;s responsibility even though security has been or can be obtained.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 493 (January 18, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>