<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-4346</num>
  <heading>ARCHITECT-ENGINEER SERVICES (ยง 19-4346)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4346.1.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall publicize all requirements for architect-engineer services in accordance with Section 4302.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4346.2.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall negotiate contracts for these services based on demonstrated competence and qualifications of prospective contractors to perform the services required at fair and reasonable prices.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4346.3.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall select a contractor for architect-engineer services in accordance with the provisions of this section rather than the solicitation procedures specified elsewhere in these regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4346.4.</num>
    <text>Compliance with the provisions of Sections 4346 through 4355 of these regulations shall constitute a competitive procedure of the procurement of architect-engineer services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4346.5.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall evaluate each potential contractor based on the following criteria:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Professional qualifications necessary for satisfactory performance of the required services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Specialized experience and technical competence in the type of work required;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Capacity to accomplish the work in the required time;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Acceptability under other appropriate evaluation criteria.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4346.6.</num>
    <text>When design competition is used by the Library, the CCO may evaluate firms on the basis of their conceptual design of the project.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4346.7.</num>
    <text>Design competition may be used in the following circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>When unique situations exist involving prestigious projects, such as the design of memorials or structures of unusual national or local significance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>When sufficient time is available for the production and evaluation of conceptual designs; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>When the design competition, with its costs, will substantially benefit the project.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 493 (January 18, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>