<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-4364</num>
  <heading>SUBCONTRACTING (ยง 19-4364)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4364.1.</num>
    <text>The CCO may require his or her consent for the contractor to subcontract when the CCO determines that it would be in the best interest of the Library.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4364.2.</num>
    <text>The requirement for consent to subcontract shall also apply to teaming arrangements and joint ventures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4364.3.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall require consent to subcontract in those instances where approval of subcontracts is required by this chapter or this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4364.4.</num>
    <text>When a solicitation contains a requirement for consent to subcontract, before a contractor can enter into a subcontract, the contractor must submit to the CCO a written request for consent to subcontract and the CCO must grant consent in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4364.5.</num>
    <text>The CCO may require, as part of an invitation for bids (IFB) or request for proposals (RFP), that each bidder or offeror responding to a solicitation include in its response a list of proposed subcontractors, teaming arrangements or joint ventures,
      a list of tasks or items which the bidder or offeror intends to subcontract, team or joint venture with.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4364.6.</num>
    <text>In determining whether to require consent to subcontract, the CCO shall consider the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The complexity of the work to be done under subcontracts, teaming arrangements or joint ventures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The value of the subcontract, joint venture, teaming arrangement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Whether the Library&amp;#8217;s interests can be adequately protected without requiring consent; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any other relevant factors.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4364.7.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall ensure that any requirements for consent to subcontract are included in the solicitation for the prime contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4364.8.</num>
    <text>After receipt of the contractor&amp;#8217;s request for consent to subcontract, the CCO shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Promptly evaluate the contractor&amp;#8217;s request for consent to subcontract;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Obtain assistance in the evaluation from audit, pricing, technical, or other specialists as necessary;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Notify the contractor in writing of consent to subcontract or the withholding of consent to subcontract, including any changes or corrections required.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4364.9.</num>
    <text>The CCO&amp;#8217;s consent to subcontract shall not constitute a determination of the acceptability of the subcontract terms, price or other allowability of costs unless the consent to subcontract specifies acceptance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4364.10.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall not consent to subcontract in any of the following circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>When the fee in a cost-reimbursement subcontract exceeds any applicable fee limitations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>When payment under the subcontract is on a cost-plus-a-percentage-of-cost basis;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>When the CCO is obligated to deal directly with the subcontractor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>When the results of arbitration, judicial determination, or voluntary settlement between the prime contractor and subcontractor are made binding on the Library; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>When the subcontract violates any statute or the provisions of these regulations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4364.11.</num>
    <text>Prospective prime contractors shall be responsible for determining the responsibility of their subcontractors to include teaming arrangements and joint ventures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4364.12.</num>
    <text>Determinations of prospective subcontractor responsibility may affect the Library&amp;#8217;s determination of the prospective prime contractor&amp;#8217;s responsibility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4364.13.</num>
    <text>The CCO may require a prospective prime contractor to provide written evidence of a prospective subcontractor&amp;#8217;s responsibility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 493 (January 18, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>