<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-4314</num>
  <heading>SPECIFICATIONS, STATEMENTS OF WORK, PURCHASE DESCRIPTIONS (ยง 19-4314)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4314.1.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall provide specifications, statements of work or purchase descriptions in a manner designed to promote competition to the maximum extent possible.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4314.2.</num>
    <text>Specifications, statements of work or purchase descriptions shall reflect the minimum needs of the Library. Specifications and purchase descriptions may be stated in terms of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Function, so that a variety of supplies or services may qualify;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Performance, including the range of acceptable characteristics or the minimum acceptable standards; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Design requirements, providing exact dimensions, materials or characteristics.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4314.3.</num>
    <text>Performance specifications or statements of work shall be the preferred description for Library procurements to encourage offerors to propose innovative solutions and approaches.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4314.4.</num>
    <text>Brand name or equal purchase descriptions shall include the brand name, along with the salient physical, functional or performance characteristics of the brand name item that the equal item must meet to be acceptable for award.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4314.5.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall not develop agency requirements to favor a particular brand name product or a feature of a brand name product specific to one manufacturer, unless the specific brand name product or feature is necessary to the Library&amp;#8217;s requirements
      and market research of other products or features do not meet or cannot be modified to meet the Library&amp;#8217;s needs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 493 (January 18, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>