<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-4313</num>
  <heading>SPECIAL SIMPLIFIED PROCUREMENT PROCEDURES (ยง 19-4313)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4313.1.</num>
    <text>The CCO may use the simplified procurement procedures set forth in Section 4305 for procurement of commercial items (supplies and services), except for the requirements specified in Sections 4334 for construction and architect-engineer services, up
      to five million dollars ($5,000,000), including options.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4313.2.</num>
    <text>The Library shall use firm-fixed-price contracts or fixed-price contracts with economic price adjustments for the procurement of commercial items.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4313.3.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall publicize requirements utilizing these procedures for requirements in excess of the simplified procurement threshold of one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4313.4.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall use the procedures in Section 4305 to solicit, evaluate and award commercial items utilizing simplified procurement procedures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4313.5.</num>
    <text>This process shall allow the CCO to maximize efficiency and economy and reduce the administrative costs to the Library and industry in the award of commercial items utilizing this simplified procurement procedure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4313.6.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall utilize the special simplified procedure for competitive commercial supplies or services, to include books, periodicals, and publications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4313.7.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall not utilize this special procedure for non-commercial items or for construction and architect-engineer services specified in Section 4334.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4313.8.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall ensure all the necessary approvals are obtained for contracts awarded utilizing the simplified procurement procedures outlined in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4313.9.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall ensure all appropriate clauses, provisions, representations and certifications are included in solicitations and contracts awarded utilizing the simplified procurement procedures outlined in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 493 (January 18, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>