<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-4305</num>
  <heading>USE OF SIMPLIFIED PROCUREMENT PROCEDURES (ยง 19-4305)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4305.1.</num>
    <text>The CCO has the authority to use the simplified procurement procedures set forth in this section for the procurement of supplies, services, books and equipment when the total amount of the procurement does not exceed one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4305.5.</num>
    <text>For each procurement in an amount over three thousand dollars ($3,000) but less than one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000) the CCO shall solicit quotations from at least three (3) sources to promote competition to the maximum extent practicable
      and to ensure that the purchase is in the best interests of the Library considering price and other factors (including the administrative cost of the purchase).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4305.6.</num>
    <text>The CCO may solicit oral price quotations for procurements over three thousand dollars ($3,000) up to twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4305.7.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall solicit written price quotations for procurements over twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000) up to one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000), except as required by Section 4313.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4305.8.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall maintain records of all oral and written price quotations in the procurement file for each requirement. The records shall include the names of the sources contacted, the price(s) and other terms quoted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4305.9.</num>
    <text>If practicable, three (3) sources not included in previous solicitations for similar items shall be requested to furnish quotations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4305.10.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall prepare a written justification if it is impractical to solicit more than three (3) sources based on factors set forth in subsection 4305.12.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4305.11.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall follow the provisions in Section 4320 if quotations are solicited from only one source.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4305.12.</num>
    <text>The CCO may consider the following factors when deciding how many quotations will be solicited:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The dollar value of the proposed procurement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The urgency of the proposed procurement; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Information received in making recent purchases of the same or similar supplies or services.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4305.13.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall not use simplified procurement procedures when the requirement can be met by using a Library or District-wide requirements contract, a District or Federal Supply Schedule or other required source of supply unless the CCO justifies the
      rationale in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4305.14.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall ensure that procurements are not split, parceled, divided or purchased over a period of time to circumvent the dollar limitations for use of simplified procurement procedures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4305.15.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall use the simplified procurement procedure that is most suitable, economical and efficient based on the circumstances of each procurement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4305.16.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall establish and maintain a simplified procurement procedure source list to include sources for micro-purchases.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4305.17.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall retain records supporting all oral and written quotations for three (3) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 493 (January 18, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>