<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-4300</num>
  <heading>PURPOSE AND APPLICATION (ยง 19-4300)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4300.1.</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Public Library Procurement Regulations (the &amp;#8220;Regulations&amp;#8221;) issued by the Board of Trustees of the District of Columbia Public Library (the &amp;#8220;Board&amp;#8221;) establish policies, procedures and
      guidelines relating to the procurement, management, control and disposal of supplies, services and construction, as applicable under the authority of D.C. Official Code 39-105 (a) (1) and (3) et seq.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4300.2.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director/Chief Librarian of the District of Columbia Public Library (the &amp;#8220;Executive Director/Chief Librarian&amp;#8221;) is vested with the authority to administer operating policies, procedures and regulations adopted by the
      Board in accordance with D.C. Official Code Section 39-101.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4300.3.</num>
    <text>This chapter applies only to contracts solicited or entered into after the effective date of these Regulations, unless the parties agree to its application to a contract solicited or entered into prior to the effective date.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4300.4.</num>
    <text>Any contract totaling two hundred fifty thousand dollars ($250,000) or more shall be approved by the Executive Director/Chief Librarian before it shall be effective.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4300.5.</num>
    <text>Where any statute or regulations is referred to in this chapter, the reference shall be the most recent version and any amendments or revisions to the statute or regulation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4300.6.</num>
    <text>If any provision of this chapter is deemed invalid, void or unenforceable by a court of competent jurisdiction, this chapter shall be construed as though the provision does not appear herein. Any such finding by a court of competent jurisdiction shall
      not affect the validity of any other section, paragraph or sentence of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is section 5 of An Act To establish and provide for the maintenance of a free public library and reading room in the District of Columbia, as amended 29 Stat. 244 (June 3, 1896), codified at
        D.C. Code ยง 39-105.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 493 (January 18, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>