<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-499</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 19-499)
    <text>When used in this chapter the following words shall have the following meanings:</text>
    <text>Authority &amp;#8211; the Washington Convention and Sports Authority.</text>
    <text>Board of Directors – the Board of Directors of the Authority.</text>
    <text>Convention Center &amp;#8211; the Walter E. Washington Convention Center located at01 Mount Vernon Place, NW, Washington, DC.</text>
    <text>Convention event &amp;#8211; an event for which a reservation of space at theonvention Center includes a commitment to purchase at least 2,500 peak roomights in hotels within the District of Columbia, as determined by DestinationC.</text>
    <text>First priority &amp;#8211; a “Convention event” as defined in this section.</text>
    <text>Fourth priority &amp;#8211; a Non-convention event for which a reservation of spacet the Convention Center may or may not include a commitment to purchase roomights in hotels within the District of Columbia and which describes a one-dayeeting or assembly.</text>
    <text>Non-convention event &amp;#8211; an event other than a Convention event for which aeservation of space at the Convention Center may or may not include aommitment to purchase room nights in hotels within the District of Columbia andhich describes a
      second, third or fourth priority booking.</text>
    <text>President and Chief Executive Officer – the President and Chief Executivefficer of the Authority.</text>
    <text>Second priority &amp;#8211; a Non-convention event for which a reservation of spacet the Convention Center may or may not include a commitment to purchase roomights in hotels within the District of Columbia and which describes a publiconsumer show,
      tradeshow or similar assembly.</text>
    <text>Third priority &amp;#8211; a Non-convention event for which a reservation of spacet the Convention Center may or may not include a commitment to purchase roomights in hotels within the District of Columbia and which describes a local oregional multiple
      day meeting or assembly.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 3035 (April 18, 2003); and asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 1815 (February 27, 2009); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 8962 (June 14, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>