<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-502</num>
  <heading>DIRECTORS AND EMPLOYEES[COLON] ETHICAL CONDUCT (ยง 19-502)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>502.1.</num>
    <text>No Director or employee shall use facilities or property owned or occupied by the Authority for any purpose other than the conduct of Authority business.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>502.2.</num>
    <text>No Director or employee shall make or solicit any contribution to any political candidate, political campaign organization, political party, or constituent services fund while the Director or employee is:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>In the discharge of his or her duties as a Director or employee of the Authority;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>In a facility of the Authority; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Using the resources of the Authority.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>502.3.</num>
    <text>No Director or employee shall use his or her official position to secure a financial gain, special privilege, exemption or other benefit for himself or herself, any member of his or her immediate family or household, or any business with which he
      or she is associated, other than the compensation provided by law for such Director or employee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>502.4.</num>
    <text>No Director or employee shall solicit or receive anything of value, including a gift, favor, service, loan, gratuity, discount, hospitality, contribution, or promise of future employment, either personally or for another person or entity, based on
      any understanding that an official action, judgment or duty would be influenced thereby, or where it could reasonably be inferred that acceptance of the thing of value would influence the discharge of an official duty.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>502.5.</num>
    <text>No Director or employee shall receive any supplementation of salary from any private source for his or her services as a Director or employee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>502.6.</num>
    <text>No Director or employee shall accept anything of value for or because of any official act, otherwise than as provided by law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>502.7.</num>
    <text>Subsection 502.6 shall not prohibit a Director or employee from accepting an in- kind gift (i.e., a gift other than cash or liquid assets) having a market of less than $20.00, provided, that the aggregate value of individual in-kind gifts from any
      one source does not exceed $50.00 in any one calendar year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 7140-41 (November 21, 1997).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>