<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-735</num>
  <heading>DOG PARKS[COLON] OPERATING RULES (ยง 19-735)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>735.1.</num>
    <text>Each dog park shall have a carrying capacity of one dog per 450 square feet, and the number of dogs allowed in the dog park at any one time shall be posted. Handlers are expected to enforce the carrying capacity to prevent conflicts due to overcrowding
      and detriment to the environment. When carrying capacity is reached, handlers shall limit their stay to thirty (30) minutes when others are waiting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>735.2.</num>
    <text>Each handler shall comply with all animal control, dangerous dog and communicable disease laws and regulations before entering a dog exercise area with a dog.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>735.3.</num>
    <text>A handler shall be sixteen (16) years of age or older.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>735.4.</num>
    <text>A child under sixteen (16) years of age may enter a dog park only when accompanied and supervised by an adult.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>735.5.</num>
    <text>A handler shall ensure that each dog within his or her control is wearing a current vaccination and registration tag in a dog park, as well as a current dog park registration tag obtained from the Department of Health Animal Control Division.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>735.6.</num>
    <text>A handler shall leash each dog within his or her control until entering and upon exiting the dog park. To prevent conflicts, a handler shall keep his or her dog off-leash in the dog park, unless no other dogs are present.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>735.7.</num>
    <text>A handler shall collect and bag all solid waste from his or her dog and dispose of it in the designated on-site receptacle in the dog park.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>735.8.</num>
    <text>A handler shall accompany, maintain visual contact, and have voice control over his or her dog(s) at all times.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>735.9.</num>
    <text>A handler shall not have more than three (3) dogs in a dog park at any one time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>735.10.</num>
    <text>A handler shall not have a dog that is less than four (4) months old in a dog park.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>735.11.</num>
    <text>A handler shall not have a female dog that is in heat in the dog park.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>735.12.</num>
    <text>A handler shall not use a spike or choke collar on a dog in the dog park.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>735.13.</num>
    <text>A handler shall immediately leash and remove from a dog park his or her aggressive dog.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>735.14.</num>
    <text>A handler shall not have a dog designated as a dangerous dog or a potentially dangerous dog in the dog park.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>735.15.</num>
    <text>A handler shall control excessive barking.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>735.16.</num>
    <text>A handler shall report all animal bites to the Department of Health within twenty-four (24) hours in accordance with communicable disease laws.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 11714 (December 7, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>