<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-719</num>
  <heading>ESTABLISHMENT OF USER FEES FOR THE SOUTHEAST TENNIS AND LEARNING CENTER ANDTHER SIMILAR TENNIS FACILITIES (ยง 19-719)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>719.1.</num>
    <text>Listed below are the service fees by category type for the Southeast Tennis and Learning Center and any future newly built or renovated Department of Parks and Recreation facility that offers services that are similar to those offered by the Southeast
      Tennis and Learning Center. The Southeast Tennis and Learning Center offers four (4) year round Indoor courts, six (6) outdoor courts, a weight/conditioning room, and a computer learning center for youths that are participating in its tennis programs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>719.2.</num>
    <text>The fees for indoor court rental shall be as follows:</text>
    <text>a) There is no fee for D.C. youth not affiliated with an organization.</text>
    <text>b) D.C. Sponsoring Organizations will be charged seventy-five percent (75%) of the applicable D.C. resident, adult hourly court fee per court. In order to qualify for this discount, the organization must provide proof that it meets the requirements
      of section 720 and that the sponsored youths utilizing the facilities are residents of the District of Columbia. Except as otherwise expressly provided in these rules, all other sponsoring organizations and individuals will be charged the full applicable
      hourly, adult, non-D.C. resident court fee per court. All patrons of the DC sponsoring organization(s) must also show proof of residency to insure that the appropriate applicable fees are charged.</text>
    <text>c) Fee rates for adults per hour for a 40 week season on in-door courts shall be as follows:</text>
    <text>1) Fee rates per hour for 40-Week Season: September 1 &amp;#8211; May 31</text>
    <text>Day</text>
    <text>Time</text>
    <text>D.C. Resident</text>
    <text>Non-Resident</text>
    <text>Off Peak</text>
    <text>Monday &amp;#8211; Friday</text>
    <text>7 am &amp;#8211; 5 pm</text>
    <text>$ 20.00</text>
    <text>$ 30.00</text>
    <text>Saturday &amp;#8211; Sunday</text>
    <text>5 pm &amp;#8211; 10 pm</text>
    <text>$ 25.00</text>
    <text>$ 35.00</text>
    <text>Holidays</text>
    <text>2 pm &amp;#8211; 7 pm</text>
    <text>$ 25.00</text>
    <text>$ 35.00</text>
    <text>Peak</text>
    <text>Monday &amp;#8211; Friday</text>
    <text>5 pm &amp;#8211; 10 pm</text>
    <text>$ 25.00</text>
    <text>$ 38.00</text>
    <text>Saturday &amp;#8211; Sunday</text>
    <text>7 am &amp;#8211; 5 pm</text>
    <text>$ 28.00</text>
    <text>$ 38.00</text>
    <text>Holidays</text>
    <text>7 am &amp;#8211; 2 pm</text>
    <text>$ 28.00</text>
    <text>$ 38.00</text>
    <text>Holidays</text>
    <text>7 pm &amp;#8211; 10 pm</text>
    <text>$ 28.00</text>
    <text>$ 38.00</text>
    <text>2) Fee rates per hour for 12-Week Summer Season: June 01 &amp;#8211; August 31</text>
    <text>Day</text>
    <text>Time</text>
    <text>D.C. Resident</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>