<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-720</num>
  <heading>SPONSORSHIP OF PROGRAMS AND ACTIVITIES (§ 19-720)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>720.1.</num>
    <text>Sponsorship of the Department may be extended to a program presented by a responsible organization (also referred to as “Organization”) under the conditions set forth in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>720.2.</num>
    <text>The quality of the program offered must justify the expenditure of public funds and the attention of the Department officers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>720.3.</num>
    <text>Sufficient interest by the community must be demonstrated. This interest may be evidenced by the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The number of persons requesting sponsorship of the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The formation by the Organization of an advisory committee or board which includes lay members and which will publicize and guarantee the program against deficit; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The offer from one (1) or more responsible citizens, or civic, parent-teacher, or other responsible organizations to support and publicize the program.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>720.4.</num>
    <text>The project shall be of a community nature, open under conditions acceptable to the Department to participation by District residents who demonstrate the necessary talent and training.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>720.5.</num>
    <text>Auditions or some similar means of recruiting participants shall be offered to the public by the Organization at convenient times and places, and with impartial judges.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>720.6.</num>
    <text>All publicity releases, posters, and other printed matter shall be approved by the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>720.7.</num>
    <text>The Organization shall be responsible for the assembly of publicity material, placing of posters, personal advertising, etc.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>720.8.</num>
    <text>Personnel, both paid and volunteer, selected for technical phases of the program, shall have the approval of the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>15 DCRR § 5.1 (August 10, 1970 and December 23, 1970).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>