<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-703</num>
  <heading>RESPONSIBILITY FOR GOVERNMENT PROPERTY (§ 19-703)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>703.1.</num>
    <text>Every employee of the Department, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Mayor, shall be held responsible for the proper use and protection of any government property that comes under his or her custody or control.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>703.2.</num>
    <text>The property officer shall be accountable for all personal property under the Department’s control.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>703.3.</num>
    <text>Every employee to whom personal property is issued shall be responsible for the property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>703.4.</num>
    <text>Unit directors shall be responsible and accountable for all property issued to them for use at their center.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>703.5.</num>
    <text>Loss or theft of property shall be reported immediately to the nearest police precinct and to the central office.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>703.6.</num>
    <text>Sworn affidavit covering a loss or theft shall be filed with the property officer within thirty (30) days from the date of the loss or theft in the event the property is not recovered.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>703.7.</num>
    <text>No terminal salary check shall be issued to an employee or to the employee’s estate, until satisfactory certification has been furnished to the Department that the employee has done one (1) of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Returned the property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Reimbursed the District for the value of the property; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Otherwise satisfactorily accounted for all District property issued to him or her.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>703.8.</num>
    <text>Normally, certification as required by § 703.7 shall accompany the final time and attendance report.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>703.9.</num>
    <text>If any property is reported as lost, stolen, damaged, or destroyed, the final release of responsibility shall not be furnished until action in accordance with section 7 of the D.C. Personal Property Regulations, effective July 1, 1958, has been completed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>15 DCRR §§ 1.6 and 1.7 (August 10, 1970 and December 23, 1970).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>