<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-816</num>
  <heading>IN-KIND AND FIXED ASSET DONATIONS (ยง 19-816)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>816.1.</num>
    <text>The Donor must complete all appropriate data fields of the AAD form and sign the form.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>816.2.</num>
    <text>The Branch Manager and/or designee shall access whether the acceptance of the proposed donation would be a greater cost than benefit to the DCPL.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>816.3.</num>
    <text>The Branch Manager and/or designee shall determine if the donation is in a usable condition for the DCPL, if not, the donation shall be declined.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>816.4.</num>
    <text>The Branch Manager and/or designee is to immediately complete the AAD form electronically and forward to the Office of the General Counsel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>816.5.</num>
    <text>The Branch Manager is to forward the signed donor copy of the AAD Form to the Office of the General Counsel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>816.6.</num>
    <text>The Office of the General Counsel will complete the legal sufficiency and obtain all necessary signed approvals.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>816.7.</num>
    <text>The donation is considered approved once all required signatures are signed on the AAD form.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>816.8.</num>
    <text>Upon approval, the DCPL employee shall notify the donor of whether the donation was accepted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>816.9.</num>
    <text>The DCPL shall proceed to use the donation as conditioned by the Donor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>816.10.</num>
    <text>The Office of the General Counsel shall send a thank you letter to the Donor for the donation and give a copy to the Office of Budget and Finance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 9176-9177 (September 21, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>