<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-812</num>
  <heading>ACCEPTING AND DEPOSITING FINANCIAL GIFT DONATIONS (ยง 19-812)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>812.1.</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Public Library&amp;#8217;s (&amp;#8220;DCPL&amp;#8221;) Director of the Board of Library Trustees and/or Chief Librarian authorizes the acceptance of all financial donations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>812.2.</num>
    <text>All financial donations to the DCPL must be in the form of check, wire transfer, or other negotiable instruments.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>812.3.</num>
    <text>All financial donations must be made payable to the D.C. Treasury and these donations shall be made available to the DCPL through the private grant revenue source of DCPL&amp;#8217;s annual operating budget.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>812.4.</num>
    <text>The DCPL will not accept cash donations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>812.5.</num>
    <text>The DCPL&amp;#8217;s Chief Fiscal Officer (&amp;#8220;CFO&amp;#8221;) or financial manager shall establish the account, provide the appropriate revenue codes, prepare a budget for depositing the funds, and track the disbursement of donated funds.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>812.6.</num>
    <text>All donated funds shall be deposited into the city&amp;#8217;s agency fund 0400 (private grant revenue). In addition the following actions shall occur between other District agencies to complete the financial process:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Office of Finance and Treasury (&amp;#8220;OFT&amp;#8221;) shall notify the Director of Budget and Formulation in the Office of Budget and Planning that the check has cleared;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Director of Budget Formulation will establish a budget for the Donation in consultation with the recipient agency&amp;#8217;s fiscal officer or designee; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Office of Budget and Planning shall load the funds based on the budget.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 9173-9174 (September 21, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>