<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-806</num>
  <heading>USE OF MEETING ROOMS IN THE D.C. PUBLIC LIBRARY BRANCHES (ยง 19-806)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>806.1.</num>
    <text>Meeting rooms shall be open for use by private groups and individuals for as wide a range of civic, educational, political, and cultural discussions and activities as possible, consistent with the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.2.</num>
    <text>Use of facilities shall be at times and under circumstances that do not adversely affect public library needs and services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.3.</num>
    <text>Meeting rooms shall not be used for personal or commercial interests.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.4.</num>
    <text>A series of meetings shall be approved on a three (3) month basis only.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.5.</num>
    <text>The public library reserves the right to change or cancel reservations in the event of emergencies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.6.</num>
    <text>The public library reserves the right to cancel meeting-room privileges if library property is not cared for properly.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.7.</num>
    <text>There shall be no charge for meetings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.8.</num>
    <text>Meetings shall be conducted in a orderly manner, disturbances of others using the same building shall be avoided, all public safety regulations shall be observed, and the group shall be fully responsible for all damage to library property occasioned
      by its use of the facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.9.</num>
    <text>Meetings shall be open to the general public, and admission to the meetings shall be free of charge.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.10.</num>
    <text>No regular classroom meetings shall be permitted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.11.</num>
    <text>No collection of funds or any other thing of value shall be made during any gathering.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.12.</num>
    <text>All members of the organization and the audience shall leave the building by the time specified by the library.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.13.</num>
    <text>A count of the number of people present at the meeting shall be left with the building engineer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.14.</num>
    <text>If audio-visual equipment is to be used, a separate application form shall be signed in duplicate in advance of the meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.15.</num>
    <text>The number attending a meeting a one time shall not exceed the capacity of the room as established by the fire marshal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.16.</num>
    <text>Tipping of library employees is not permitted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.17.</num>
    <text>All private groups and individuals are eligible to use library meeting rooms; provided, that all requirements and restrictions set forth in this chapter are observed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>27 DCRR ยง 3.2, 30 DCR 11011, 11015-17 (June 30, 1978).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>