<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-100</num>
  <heading>PURPOSE, SCOPE, AND CONSTRUCTION (§ 20-100)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>100.1.</num>
    <text>The purpose of this subtitle is to prevent or minimize emissions, as defined in this chapter, into the atmosphere and thereby protect and enhance the quality of the District&amp;#8217;s air resources so as to do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>To promote the public health and welfare and the productive capacity of the people of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>To foster their comfort and convenience;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>To increase the enjoyment of all of the attractions of the Nation&amp;#8217;s Capital; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>To enhance the environment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>100.2.</num>
    <text>This subtitle shall apply to all operations in the District, including Federal operations to the full extent permitted by the Clean Air Act (42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq.), as amended, and regulations promulgated thereunder.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>100.3.</num>
    <text>All regulations and parts of regulations in effect in the District which are inconsistent with the provisions of this subtitle are superseded with respect to matters covered by this subtitle, unless specifically stated otherwise.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>100.4.</num>
    <text>The English system of measurement shall be the official system of measurement under this subtitle, unless specified otherwise.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>100.5.</num>
    <text>Reference in this subtitle to a specific introductory section or subdivision of the section (such as §204 or 204.1(a) is intended to include a reference to all subdivisions of the specific section of subdivision (such as §§204.1, 204.2, 204.1(a),
      and 204.1(a)(1)).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>100.6.</num>
    <text>Civil fines, penalties and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of the Act, or the rules or regulations issued under the authority of the Act, pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and
      Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infractions shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 3 of the District of Columbia Air Pollution Control Act of 1984, D.C. Law 5-165, §100, 32 DCR 562, 567 (February 1, 1985); as amended by §485(a) of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985, D.C. Law
        6-42, 32 DCR 4450, 4481 (August 2, 1985); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 11286, 1187 (December 30, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>