<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-1007</num>
  <heading>EMISSION MONITORING (§ 20-1007)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1007.1.</num>
    <text>The owner or operator of each budget source shall comply with the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An owner or operator of a budget source shall monitor NOx emissions from each budget source as specified by this section and &amp;#8220;Guidance for Implementation of Emission Monitoring Requirements for the NOx Budget Program,&amp;#8221; prepared
        for the Ozone Transport Commission and EPA&amp;#8217;s Acid Rain Division by Perrin Quarles Associates, Inc., and published January 28, 1997. Wherever the referenced guidance document allows for the Director&amp;#8217;s approval of alternative
        testing, monitoring, or record keeping, EPA approval shall also be required.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Within thirty (30) days of the effective date of this section, an owner or operator shall submit to the Director a monitoring plan that describes the monitoring approach to be used at the budget source. Any budget source not subject to 40 CFR Part
        75 (July 1, 1999) shall also include the information outlined in § 1007.5.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An owner or operator shall install emission monitoring systems, as required and specified by this section, that are operational and meet all of the certification testing requirements by no later than thirty (30) days after the effective date of
        this Chapter.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Budget sources that commence operation after January 1, 2000 shall submit a monitoring plan and install, operate and certify emission- monitoring systems required by this section no later than May 1st of the year following the date when operations
        commenced.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>All monitoring systems are subject to initial performance testing and periodic calibration, accuracy testing and quality assurance/quality control testing as specified in &amp;#8220;Guidance for Implementation of Emission Monitoring Requirements
        for the NOx Budget Program&amp;#8221;.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>During a period when valid data is not being recorded by monitoring devices approved for use to demonstrate compliance with this Chapter, missing or invalid data shall be replaced with representative default data pursuant to the provisions of 40
        CFR Part 75 and &amp;#8220;Guidance for Implementation of Emission Monitoring Requirements for the NOx Budget Program&amp;#8221;.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>NOx emissions data shall be reported to the Administrator pursuant to the provisions of § 1009.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Each budget source that operates or commences operation before January 1, 2000 shall begin reporting data no later than thirty (30) days after the effective date of this Chapter.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Budget sources that commence operation after January 1, 2000 shall begin reporting data in the first hour that the budget source is operating during an ozone season.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1007.2.</num>
    <text>The owner or operator of each budget source subject to 40 CFR Part 75, shall demonstrate compliance with this Chapter using a certified Part 75 monitoring system. If the owner or operator of the budget source has a flow monitor certified pursuant
      to 40 CFR Part 75, NOx emissions in pounds per hour (lb./hr) shall be determined using a NOx continuous emissions monitoring system (CEMS) and the flow monitor. NOx in lb./mmBtu shall be determined by using the procedure in § 3 of Appendix F of
      40 CFR Part 75. The hourly heat input shall be determined by using the procedures in § 5 of Appendix F of 40 CFR Part 75. NOx, in lb./hr shall be determined by multiplying the results of the two determinations described above.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1007.3.</num>
    <text>If a Part 75 budget source does not have a certified flow monitor, but does have a NOx CEMS, NOx emissions in lb./hr should be determined using the NOx CEMS and procedures contained in &amp;#8220;Guidance for Implementation of Emission Monitoring
      Requirements for the NOx Budget Program&amp;#8221; and other procedures as applicable in the following circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If the owner or operator of a budget source uses the procedures in Appendix E of 40 CFR Part 75 to estimate the NOx emission rate, NOx emissions in lb./hr- should be determined using Appendix E procedures and the heat input for the unit.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the owner or operator of a budget source uses the procedures in Subpart E of 40 CFR Part 75 to determine the NOx emission rate, NOx emissions in lb./hr shall be determined using the alternative monitoring method approved under 40 CFR Part 75,
        Subpart E, and the procedures contained in &amp;#8220;Guidance for Implementation of Emission Monitoring Requirements for the NOx Budget Program&amp;#8221;.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1007.4.</num>
    <text>Where unusual stack configurations complicate the monitoring protocol, the relevant procedures contained in &amp;#8220;Guidance for Implementation of Emission Monitoring Requirements for the NOx Budget Program&amp;#8221; shall apply.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1007.5.</num>
    <text>The owner or operator of a budget source not subject to 40 CFR Part 75 shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Prepare and obtain approval of a monitoring plan as specified in § 1007.6;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Determine the NOx emission rate using a methodology specified in § 1007.7;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Determine the heat input rate using the methodology described in § 1007.8; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Convert the NOx emission rate and heat input rate to NOx emissions in lb./hr using the procedure described in § 1007.9.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1007.6.</num>
    <text>The owner or operator of a budget source not subject to 40 CFR Part 75, who seeks to use an alternative monitoring method to comply with this section, shall develop and submit an alternative monitoring plan to the Director and the Administrator. The
      owner or operator shall not commence construction or testing of any alternative monitoring system unless the Director and the Administrator approve the plan. The plan shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A description of the monitoring approach to be used;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A description of the major components of the monitoring system including the manufacturer, serial number of the component, the measurement span of the component, and documentation to demonstrate that the measurement span of each component is appropriate
        to measure all of the expected values (this requirement applies to all monitoring systems including NOx CEMS&amp;#8217;s that have not been certified pursuant to 40 CFR Part 75);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An estimate of the accuracy of the system and documentation to demonstrate how the estimate of accuracy was determined;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A description of the tests that will be used for initial certification, initial quality assurance, periodic quality assurance and relative accuracy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A description of the test to determine boiler efficiency, if the alternative monitoring method for determining heat input involves boiler efficiency testing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A description of the test to be used in the fuel-sampling program, if the alternative method uses fuel sampling;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A description of all components of the fuel flow meter, the estimated accuracy of the fuel flow meter, the most recent calibration of each of the components and the original accuracy specifications from the manufacturer of the fuel flow meter, if
        the alternative method utilizes fuel flow meters to determine heat input and the meters have not been certified pursuant to 40 CFR Part 75; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>If the alternative method utilizes a default emission rate or unit specific emission factor, as specified in § 1007.7(c)(3), the monitoring plan shall include the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>All information necessary to support the emission rate including historical monitoring and fuel usage data. If the source plans to conduct emission testing to determine emission rate, the plan should include a test protocol explaining the testing
        to be conducted;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Procedures that will be used to demonstrate that any control equipment in operation during the testing to develop source specific emission factors, or during development of load-based emissions curves, are in use when those factors or emission curves
        are applied to estimate NOx emissions; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Alternative uncontrolled emission rates to be used to estimate NOx emissions during periods when control equipment is not being used or is inoperable.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1007.7.</num>
    <text>The owner or operator of a budget source not subject to Part 75 who chooses to implement an alternative emission rate monitoring method shall determine the NOx emission rate in lb./mmBtu using one of the following methods:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The owner or operator of a budget source may implement monitoring pursuant to Part 75.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The owner or operator of a budget source that is required to install and operate a NOx CEMS to meet the requirements of 40 CFR Part 75 or to meet other District requirements or permits, shall use the NOx CEMS to meet the requirements of this Chapter.
        Part 75 monitors used for this purpose shall meet quality assurance criteria as described in &amp;#8220;Guidance for Implementation of Emission Monitoring Requirements for the NOx Budget Program&amp;#8221;. Any time a Part 75 CEMS cannot be used
        to report data for this program because it does not meet the requirements of &amp;#8220;Guidance for Implementation of Emission Monitoring Requirements for the NOx Budget Program&amp;#8221;, missing data shall be substituted using the procedures
        in 40 CFR Part 75, Subpart D. In addition, a NOx CEMS that has not undergone initial certification testing to meet the requirements of 40 CFR Part 75, or 40 CFR Part 60, shall meet the initial certification requirements contained in &amp;#8220;Guidance
        for Implementation of Emission Monitoring Requirements for the NOx Budget Program&amp;#8221;.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The owner or operator of a budget source that does not have a NOx CEMS may request approval from the Director to use any of the following appropriate methodologies to determine NOx emission rate:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Boilers or turbines may use the procedures contained in 40 CFR Part 75, Appendix E, to measure NOx emission rate in lb./mmBTU, consistent with the provisions in &amp;#8220;Guidance for Implementation of Emission Monitoring Requirements for the NOx
        Budget Program&amp;#8221;.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Owners or operators of combustion turbines that are subject to this Chapter may meet the monitoring requirements of this Chapter by using default emission factors to determine NOx emissions in lb./hr as follows:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>For gas-fired turbines, the default NOx emission factor shall be seven tenths (0.7) lb./mmBtu; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>For oil-fired turbines, the default NOx emission factor shall be one and two tenths (1.2) lb./mmBtu.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Owners or operators of gas or oil fired turbines may perform testing, with a protocol approved by the Director, to determine unit specific maximum potential NOx emission rates.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Owners or operators of boilers that are subject to this Chapter may meet the monitoring requirements of this Chapter by using default emission factors to determine NOx emissions in lb./hr as follows:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>For gas-fired boilers, the default NOx emission factor shall be one and five tenths (1.5) lb./mmBtu;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>For oil-fired boilers, the default NOx emission factor shall be two (2.0) lb./mmBtu; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Owners or operators of gas or oil fired boilers may perform testing, with a protocol approved by the Director, to determine unit specific maximum potential NOx emission rates.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1007.8.</num>
    <text>The owner or operator of a budget source that does not have a flow CEMS may request approval from the Director to use any of the following methodologies to determine heat input rate:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The owner or operator of a budget source may determine heat input using a flow monitor and a diluent monitor meeting the requirements of 40 CFR Part 75 and the procedures in § 5 of Appendix F of 40 CFR Part 75.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The owner or operator of a budget source that combusts only oil or natural gas may determine heat input using a fuel flow monitor meeting the requirements of Appendix D of 40 CFR Part 75, and the procedures of § 5 of Appendix F of 40 CFR Part 75.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The owner or operator of a budget source of less than twenty-five (25) megawatt (MWe) rated capacity that combusts only oil or natural gas may determine heat input by measuring the fuel used at a frequency of no less than once per week. This fuel
        usage must then be reported on an hourly basis by apportioning the fuel based on electrical load pursuant to the following formula:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Hourly fuel usage</text>
    <text>=</text>
    <text>Hourly electrical load</text>
    <text>×</text>
    <text>Total fuel usage</text>
    <text>Total electrical load</text>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The owner or operator of a budget source that combusts any fuel other than oil or natural gas may request permission from the Director to use an alternative method of determining heat input. Alternative methods include:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Conducting fuel sampling and analysis and monitoring fuel usage;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Using boiler efficiency curves and other monitored information such as boiler steam output; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any other methods approved by the Director that meet the requirements contained in &amp;#8220;Guidance for Implementation of Emission Monitoring Requirements for the NOx Budget Program&amp;#8221;.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Alternative methods for determining heat input are subject to both initial and periodic relative accuracy and quality assurance testing as prescribed by &amp;#8220;Guidance for Implementation of Emission Monitoring Requirements for the NOx Budget
        Program&amp;#8221;.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1007.9.</num>
    <text>Once the NOx emission rate in lb./mrnBtu has been determined pursuant to § 1007.7 and heat input rate in mmBtu/hr has been determined pursuant to § 1007.8, the two (2) values shall be multiplied to provide NOx emissions in lb./hr and shall be reported
      to the Administrator pursuant to § 1009.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by final rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8646(October 10, 2000); as amended by final rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9686 (December 8, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>