<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-2202</num>
  <heading>DENIAL, SUSPENSION, AND REVOCATION OF REGISTRATION (ยง 20-2202)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2202.1.</num>
    <text>If it does not appear to the Director that a pesticide registered under the Director&amp;#8217;s authority warrants the proposed claims for it, or if the pesticide and its labeling and other material required to be submitted do not comply with the
      pesticide provisions of this title, the Director shall notify the applicant of the manner in which the pesticide, labeling, or other material required to be submitted fails to comply with the provisions of the Act so as to afford the applicant an
      opportunity to make the necessary corrections.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2202.2.</num>
    <text>If, upon receipt of the notice required by ยง 2202.1, the applicant does not make the required changes, the Director may refuse to register the pesticide.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2202.3.</num>
    <text>The Director may refuse, suspend, or cancel the registration of any pesticide if he or she determines the following conditions exist:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That the pesticide, its labeling, or other material required to be submitted do not comply with the pesticide provisions of this title; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That the refusal, suspension, or cancellation is necessary to prevent unreasonable adverse effects on the environment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2202.4.</num>
    <text>When the Director determines that there is an imminent hazard, the Director may suspend, on his or her own motion, the registration of a pesticide registered under the Director&amp;#8217;s authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2202.5.</num>
    <text>In refusing an application for registration, or before suspending or canceling a registration, the Director shall notify the registrant in writing of the proposed action and the basis for the proposed action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2202.6.</num>
    <text>The registrant shall have thirty (30) business days from the date of receipt of the notice of the proposed action to request a hearing before the Director to show cause why registration should not be refused, canceled, or suspended.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 3044, (October 6, 1978), incorporating Proposed Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 2118 (August 25, 1978).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>