<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-2806</num>
  <heading>TRASH COLLECTION IN AND ADJACENT TO RESIDENTIAL ZONES (§ 20-2806)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2806.1.</num>
    <text>Noise emanating from trash collection in any residential, special purpose, or waterfront zone shall be prohibited during the hours specified in this section irrespective of its compliance with § 2701 of this subtitle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2806.2.</num>
    <text>No person shall operate or permit the operation of any refuse collection vehicle in, or within three hundred (300) feet of, any residential, special purpose, or waterfront zone, at nighttime on any day of the week. The terms “operate” and “operation”
      in this section shall mean the stopping of the vehicle and the collection of trash by the refuse vehicle. This prohibition shall not apply to vehicles owned by the District government employed for emptying litter receptacles. Violation of this paragraph
      on more than one occasion within a 6-month period may be deemed a nuisance under subsection 709.7 of Title 21 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations and shall constitute grounds for suspension or revocation of the endorsement issued for
      solid waste collectors or solid waste vehicles pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 47-2851.03(d).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2806.3.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the prohibitions in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, the collection of residential refuse by District government-owned vehicles may commence at 6 a.m. during the months of June, July, and August or when the daily high temperature
      is forecast to be above 90 degrees Fahrenheit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 5 of the District of Columbia Noise Control Act of 1977, D.C. Law 2.53, 24 DCR 5293, 5311 (December 30, 1977); as amended by § 2 of the Noise Control Amendment Regulation Act of 185, D.C. Law 6-93, 33 DCR 314 (January 17, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>