<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-202</num>
  <heading>MODIFICATION, REVOCATION AND TERMINATION OF PERMITS (ยง 20-202)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>202.1.</num>
    <text>The terms and conditions of each permit shall be subject to amendment, revision, or modification, and a permit may be suspended or revoked by reason of amendments to this subtitle, or by requirements and orders issued by the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.2.</num>
    <text>Any permit may be revoked, suspended, or modified, in whole or in part, for any false statement in the application; any false statement of fact required under this subtitle; or because of any condition revealed by the application, any statement of
      fact, or any report, record or inspection, or other means which would do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Warrant the Mayor to refuse to grant a permit on an original application; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Qualify as a violation of or failure to observe any of the terms and conditions of the permit, or of this subtitle, or order of the Mayor.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.3.</num>
    <text>Except in cases of willfulness or cases in which the public health or welfare requires otherwise, no permit shall be modified, suspended, or revoked unless, prior to the institution of proceedings, facts or conduct which may warrant action shall have
      been called to the attention of the permittee in writing, and the permittee shall have been given an opportunity to demonstrate or achieve compliance with all lawful requirements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.4.</num>
    <text>The Mayor may terminate a permit upon the written request of the permittee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.5.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in ยง 302.2, a permit to construct or modify a source shall be valid only if used within one (1) year from the date of issuance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 3 of the District of Columbia Air Pollution Control Act of 1984, D.C. Law 5-165, ยง 202, 32 DCR 565, 594 (February 1, 1985).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>