<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-2700</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 20-2700)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2700.1.</num>
    <text>It is the declared public policy of the District that every person is entitled to ambient noise levels that are not detrimental to life to life, health, and enjoyment of his or her property. It is hereby declared that excessive or unnecessary noises
      within the District are a menace to the welfare and prosperity of the residents and businesses of the District. It is the declared public policy of the District to reduce the ambient noise level in the District to promote public health, safety,
      welfare, and the peace and quiet of the inhabitants of the District, and to facilitate the enjoyment of the natural attraction of the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.2.</num>
    <text>It is the intent of the Council of the District of Columbia that D.C. Law 2-53 (the &amp;#8220;Act&amp;#8221;) be liberally construed to carry out its general purpose.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.3.</num>
    <text>Certain noise-producing activities are subject to limitations other than the general decibel limitations pursuant to § 2701. The activities set forth in §§ 2702 through 2704, and §§ 2800 through 2807 are subject to the noise disturbance standard or
      other specific limitations and include, among others, the use of musical instruments, loud speakers, amplifiers, or unamplified speech, construction (which is subject to specific decibel limitations), and use of vehicle-mounted loud speakers or
      amplifiers (which are subject to the noise disturbance standard during permitted hours). All other noise-producing activities are subject to the general decibel limitations set forth in §§ 2701 and 2810.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.4.</num>
    <text>The agency that administers the noise control program shall conduct programs of public education regarding the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The causes, effects, and general methods of abatement and control of noise and vibration;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The actions prohibited by the Act; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The procedures for reporting violations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.5.</num>
    <text>The agency that administers the noise control program shall encourage the participation of public interest groups in related public information efforts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.6.</num>
    <text>The agency that administers the noise control program shall request any other department or agency responsible for any proposed or final standard, regulation, or similar action to consult with it on the advisability of revising the action, if there
      is reason to believe that the action is not consistent with Chapters 27 and 28 of this subtitle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.7.</num>
    <text>The agency that administers the noise control program shall establish and publish on or before November 15, 1978, the test procedures to be used for measuring sound levels to determine compliance with Chapters 27 and 28 of this subtitle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.8.</num>
    <text>The test procedures for measuring sound levels, as required by § 2700.7, shall be revised periodically, as necessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.9.</num>
    <text>The public shall be given thirty (30) days to comment on all proposed test procedures before they are made final.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.10.</num>
    <text>On or before May 15, 1979, the agency that administers the noise control program shall establish noise assessment guidelines for the evaluation of proposed projects for the capital improvements budget and program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.11.</num>
    <text>The guidelines required by § 2700.10 may be used in the determination of the relative priority of each project in terms of noise impact.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.12.</num>
    <text>The agency that administers the noise control program shall evaluate and report to the Council of the District of Columbia every year on the effectiveness of the noise control program, and shall make recommendations for any legislative or budgetary
      changes necessary to improve the program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.13.</num>
    <text>Noise of safety signals, emergency pressure relief valves, and warning or alarm devices shall be exempt (including horns when necessary as a danger warning); Provided, that no person shall knowingly permit the noise to be made or to continue beyond
      that necessary for the emergency safety purpose, or necessary testing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.14.</num>
    <text>Unless specifically provided otherwise by the Act, a sound that constitutes a noise disturbance shall be considered a violation of the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.15.</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall consult with the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to recommend changes in airport operations to minimize noise disturbances resulting from the landing and the taking off of planes at the Washington National Airport.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.16.</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall require all departments responsible for a capital improvements budget and program to prepare an analysis of the noise impact of any proposed capital projects in accordance with noise assessment guidelines established by the administering
      agency pursuant to §§2700.3 through 2700.12 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.17.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term &amp;#8220;proposed capital projects&amp;#8221; includes land acquisition, building construction, highway improvements, and fixed equipment installation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.18.</num>
    <text>All contracts signed by the District for capital projects shall contain provisions requiring compliance with the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.19.</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall ensure that any written contract, agreement, purchase order, or other instrument by which the District is committed to the expenditure of monies in return for goods or services shall contain provisions requiring compliance with the
      Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.20.</num>
    <text>Noise levels under the Act may be measured by any official designated by the Mayor or by any person who is a qualified acoustical engineer who holds a certificate of registration as a professional engineer issued by the District. The measurements
      shall be admissible as evidence in any civil, criminal, or administrative proceeding relating to the enforcement of any provision of the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.21.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this act shall be construed as repealing or limiting the effectiveness of noise limiting provisions contained in the D.C. Harbor Regulations (DCMR Title 19).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.22.</num>
    <text>Each separate provision of Chapters 28 and 29 of this subtitle shall be considered independent of any other provision of those chapters and, if all or part of any provision, sentence, clause, or section is held illegal, invalid, unconstitutional,
      or inapplicable to any person or circumstance, the illegality, invalidity, unconstitutionality, or inapplicability shall not affect or impair any of the remaining provisions, sentences, clauses, sections, or parts of those chapters or their application
      to other parts or circumstances.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2700.23.</num>
    <text>It is the legislative intent that the Act would have been enacted if an illegal, invalid, or unconstitutional provision, sentence, clause, section, or part had not been included in the Act, and if the person or circumstances to which all or part of
      the Act is inapplicable had been specifically exempted from the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is An Act approved January 26, 1887, 24 Stat. 368, ch. 49, as amended; D.C. Code § 1-315 (1992 (Repl. Vol.); the §§ 422(6) and 422(11) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental
        Reorganization Act; the District of Columbia Noise Control Act of 1977, D.C. Law 2-53; as amended; Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 79-28 dated February 5, 1979.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Sections 2, 4,5, 7, 9, 15, 16 of the District of Columbia Noise Control Act of 1977, D.C. Law 2-53, 24 DCR 5293 (December 30, 1977); as amended by § 2 of the Noise Control Amendment Act of 1996, D.C. Law 11-161, 43 DCR 3727, 3728 and 3730 (July
        19, 1996).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR&amp;#8217;S NOTE</heading>
      <text>Chapter 30, Noise Control was renumbered Chapter 27.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>