<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-2307</num>
  <heading>PRIVATE APPLICATORS[COLON] CERTIFICATION AND LICENSING (ยง 20-2307)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2307.1.</num>
    <text>Each applicant shall advise the Director, in writing, of the nature for which private applicator certification is requested.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2307.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant&amp;#8217;s written notification shall include the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name of the restricted pesticide;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The intended use of the pesticide; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The address of the site where the pesticide will be applied.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2307.3.</num>
    <text>If the application is approved by the Director, the applicant may then apply for certification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2307.4.</num>
    <text>Licensed certified applicators shall be required to renew their certification every three (3) years by presenting documentation indicating satisfactory completion of a minimum of one (1) refresher training course which meets the requirements of ยง
      2310 of this chapter, combined with a history of satisfactory performance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2307.5.</num>
    <text>Training courses required by ยง 2307.4 may be in the form of educational courses, programs, seminars, or workshops.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2307.6.</num>
    <text>Each applicant having fulfilled the requirement for certification shall be recommended for licensure and issued appropriate credentials as being authorized to purchase and use those restricted use pesticides for which competency has been demonstrated.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 3044 (October 6, 1978), incorporating Proposed Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 2118 (August 25, 1978); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 30 DCR 2204, 2206 (May 13, 1983).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>