<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-2403</num>
  <heading>LIABILITY INSURANCE (ยง 20-2403)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2403.1.</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall not issue a pesticide operator&amp;#8217;s license until the applicant has furnished evidence of financial responsibility in the form of liability insurance for the protection of persons who may suffer damages as a result of the operations
      of the applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2403.2.</num>
    <text>The amount of minimum financial responsibility shall be established by the Mayor and shall be maintained at not less than that sum as long as the pesticide operator engages in business in those categories for which his or her license is issued.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2403.3.</num>
    <text>The insurer of a pesticide operator shall notify the Mayor in writing at least ten (10) days prior to the effective date of cancellation, if a licensee&amp;#8217;s policy is to be canceled. It shall be the licensee&amp;#8217;s responsibility to inform
      his insurer of this requirement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2403.4.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to relieve any person from liability for any damages to the person or lands of another caused by the use of pesticides even though the use conforms to regulations prescribed by the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2403.5.</num>
    <text>A pesticide operator&amp;#8217;s license shall not be issued until the applicant has filed with the Director of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs evidence of financial security in the form of liability insurance from an insurer authorized to do business
      in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2403.6.</num>
    <text>The liability insurance shall be kept in full force and effect as long as the licensee is engaged in those categories for which the license is issued.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2403.7.</num>
    <text>The requirements for minimum financial responsibility for bodily injury and property damage shall consist of liability insurance with limits not less than the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>For bodily injury $100,000 each person, $300,000 each occurrence; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For property damage $15,000 each occurrence, $30,000 annual aggregate provision.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 8 of the Pesticide Operations Act of 1977, D.C. Law 2-70, 25 DCR 6867, 6885, and 6886 (February 17, 1978), as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 3044 (October 6, 1978), incorporating Proposed Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 2118
        (August 25, 1978).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>