<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-2215</num>
  <heading>PEST CONTROL BY FUMIGATION (ยง 20-2215)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2215.1.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provisions of Chapters 22 through 25 of this subtitle, each fumigation operation shall be performed or supervised only by a licensed applicator certified to perform fumigation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2215.2.</num>
    <text>Each member of the fumigation crew shall be trained in those aspects of the fumigation process in which the member participates, have adequate knowledge of the fumigant, and be provided with all the safety equipment necessary for his or her protection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2215.3.</num>
    <text>Before performing fumigation, the nearest fire station and the Director shall be notified.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2215.4.</num>
    <text>The notice to the nearest fire station required by ยง 2215.3 shall be in writing and shall include the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the pesticide operator;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name of the fumigant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The name of the licensed certified applicator and the applicator&amp;#8217;s day and night telephone numbers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The location and type of structure; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The date and approximate time of fumigation, and the estimated length of the fumigation period.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2215.5.</num>
    <text>The structure, vault, vehicle, commodity, or area (where applicable) to be treated shall be conspicuously posted with warning signs on all sides.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2215.6.</num>
    <text>Warning signs required by ยง 2215.5 shall carry the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The skull and crossbones;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name of the fumigant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A warning statement that reads: &amp;#8220;DANGER POISON KEEP OUT&amp;#8221;;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The name of the company; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The name and telephone number of the licensed certified applicator in charge.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2215.7.</num>
    <text>A guard shall be on the site during the entire fumigation period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2215.8.</num>
    <text>Guards shall be capable, awake, alert, and remain on duty at the site at all times to prevent unauthorized persons from gaining entrance into the structure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2215.9.</num>
    <text>The licensed certified applicator shall be responsible for the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>To see that all persons are out of the structure before fumigation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>To ensure that the structure is secure; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>To ensure that the structure is safe for reoccupancy.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2215.10.</num>
    <text>The introduction of the fumigant shall be performed only by an applicator licensed and certified in fumigation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 3044 (October 6, 1978), incorporating Proposed Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 2118 (August 25, 1978).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>