<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-2108</num>
  <heading>PENALTIES AND FINES (§ 20-2108)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2108.1.</num>
    <text>Any person who fails to comply with any of the applicable provisions of this chapter shall, upon conviction, be punished as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Any person smoking in a posted &amp;#8220;NO SMOKING&amp;#8221; area, disfiguring or removing a “NO SMOKING” sign, or failing to post warning signs as set forth in this Chapter shall, upon conviction, be punishable by a fine of not less than one
        hundred dollars ($100) nor more than one thousand ($1,000) for a first offense; and not less than two hundred dollars ($200) nor a more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) for each subsequent offense;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Each person found covering, removing, disfiguring, or otherwise destroying any sign posted under the provisions of this Chapter shall, upon conviction, be fined five hundred dollars ($500).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Each person who fails to post or maintain &amp;#8220;No Smoking&amp;#8221; signs as required by this chapter shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500). Each day that the violation continues shall constitute a separate
        offense and the penalties provided in this paragraph shall be applicable to each offense.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Each person who fails to warn a smoker observed to be smoking in violation of the Acts and as required by this chapter, shall be punished by a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500). Each day that the violation continues shall constitute
        a separate offense and the penalties provided in this paragraph shall be applicable to each offense.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2108.2.</num>
    <text>Hearings or adjudication of violations under this chapter shall be conducted pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 2-1801.01 et seq., (2001).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2108.3.</num>
    <text>Pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 22-1320(c), any person licensed to sell tobacco products who violates § 2104.1 or 2104.2 of this chapter shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction, shall be fined not more than five hundred dollars ($500)
      or less than one hundred dollars ($100), or imprisoned not more than thirty (30) days, or both, for the first offense.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2108.4.</num>
    <text>Pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 22-1320(c), any person who commits a subsequent violation of § 2104.1 or 2104.2 shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction, shall be fined not more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) or less than five hundred
      dollars ($500), or imprisoned not more than ninety (90) days, or both.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2108.5.</num>
    <text>Pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 7-1731(b), any person who violates § 2107.1 of this chapter shall, upon conviction, be fined not less than two hundred fifty dollars ($250) for each violation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 10623 (November 2, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>