<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-2305</num>
  <heading>COMMERCIAL APPLICATORS[COLON] CERTIFICATION RENEWAL (ยง 20-2305)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2305.1.</num>
    <text>A licensed certified applicator shall be required to renew his or her certificate every three (3) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2305.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant for the renewal of a certificate shall be required to present documentation indicating satisfactory completion of a minimum of one (1) refresher training course approved by the Director and pertinent to the applicator&amp;#8217;s competency
      within the previous three (3) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2305.3.</num>
    <text>The refresher courses may be approved in the form of educational courses, programs, seminars or workshops.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2305.4.</num>
    <text>One of the refresher courses shall have been completed within the last year of the three (3) year term, and shall be combined with a history of satisfactory performance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2305.5.</num>
    <text>The refresher courses may be in the form of educational courses, programs, seminars, or workshops.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2305.6.</num>
    <text>If the Director determines after consultation with the EPA and other qualified professionals in the field of pest control that a significant change in technology has occurred and that additional training is vital for the protection of the environment,
      the applicator may be required to take an examination prior to the issuance of the renewed certificate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 3044 (October 6, 1978), incorporating Proposed Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 2118 (August 25. 1978); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 30 DCR 2204, 2205 (May 13, 1983).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>