<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-2199</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 20-2199)
    <text>Acts &amp;#8211; D.C. Law 3-22, the District of Columbia Smoking Restriction Act of979 (D.C. Official Code ยง 7-1701 et seq.) and D.C. Law 16-90, the Departmentf Health Functions Clarification Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Official Code ยง-741 et seq.).</text>
    <text>Bar area of a restaurant &amp;#8211; the area immediately adjacent to the bar in aestaurant where there are no dining tables or that is primarily the area whereersons of legal drinking age consume alcoholic beverages purchased at the bar.</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; the Director of the Department of Health.</text>
    <text>Employee &amp;#8211; the license holder, person in charge, person having supervisoryr management duties, person on the payroll, volunteer, or person performingork under contractual agreement at a place of employment.</text>
    <text>Enclosed area &amp;#8211; the space between a floor and ceiling that is enclosed onll sides by solid walls, windows, or doors, exclusive of doorways, that extendrom the floor to the ceiling, regardless of whether windows or doors are open.</text>
    <text>Existing building &amp;#8211; a building that was built, under construction, or had building permit issued on or before August 3, 1991.</text>
    <text>Place of employment &amp;#8211; an enclosed area under the control of a public orrivate employer that employees normally frequent during the course ofmployment, including work areas, employee lounges, restrooms, conference rooms,lassrooms, employee
      cafeterias, hallways, and vehicles owned by a privatemployer, if the vehicle is used by more than one person. This term does notpply to a private residence unless it is used as a child development center,dult day care facility, or health care facility.</text>
    <text>Public place &amp;#8211; an enclosed area to which the public is invited or in whichhe public is permitted, including banks, educational facilities, health careacilities, laundromats, public transportation facilities, reception areas,estaurants, retail
      food production and marketing establishments, nightclubs,etail service establishments, retail stores, shopping malls, sports arenas,averns, theaters, and waiting rooms. This term does not apply to a privateesidence unless it is used as a child development
      center, adult day careacility, or health care facility.</text>
    <text>Review &amp;#8211; a critical evaluation, examination, or study on a retrospectiveasis that may or may not include a formal examination of accounting recordsith applicable audit standards.</text>
    <text>Smoking &amp;#8211; the act of burning a cigar, cigarette, pipe, or any other matterr substance that contains tobacco.</text>
    <text>Tobacco bar &amp;#8211; a restaurant, tavern, brew pub, club, or nightclub thatenerates ten percent (10%) or more of its total annual revenue from the on-siteale of tobacco products, excluding sales from vending machines or the rental ofn-site humidors.</text>
    <text>Tobacco product &amp;#8211; any product made from or containing any percentage ofhe dried processed leaves of the plant genus nicotiana or any byproduct thereofsed primarily for the purpose of smoking.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 5926, 5931 (August 7, 1992); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 10623 (November 2, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>