<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-2203</num>
  <heading>REGISTRATION OF PESTICIDE DEALERS (ยง 20-2203)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2203.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall act in the capacity of, or advertise as, or assume to act as a pesticide dealer at any time unless he or she is licensed by the Mayor in accordance with the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2203.2.</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall provide for the licensing of pesticide dealers located within the District; Provided, that any manufacturer, registrant, or distributor whose products are distributed or who distributes products in the District, and who has no pesticide
      dealer outlet licensed within the District shall obtain a pesticide dealer&amp;#8217;s license from the Mayor for his or her principal out-of-state location or outlet.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2203.3.</num>
    <text>An application for a pesticide dealer&amp;#8217;s license shall be made in writing on a form prescribed by the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2203.4.</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall establish fees in an amount sufficient to cover the cost of the licensing, and shall prescribe the time period for which each license issued under this chapter shall be valid.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2203.5.</num>
    <text>A pesticide dealer shall be responsible for the acts of each of the dealer&amp;#8217;s employees in the solicitation and sale of restricted use pesticides, and for all claims and recommendations for the use of restricted use pesticides.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2203.6.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section shall not apply to a licensed pesticide operator who sells restricted use pesticides only as an integral part of his or her pesticide application service, or to any District or other governmental agency that provides
      pesticides only for its own programs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 6 of the Pesticide Operations Act of 1977, D.C. Law 2-70, 24 DCR 6867, 6882 (February 19, 1978).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>