<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-2508</num>
  <heading>RECORDS AND REPORTS (§ 20-2508)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2508.1.</num>
    <text>The following general information shall be recorded where applicable:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Name or identification of applicator;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Name of supervising licensed certified applicator;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Address of treated property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Date of application, including the month, day, and year;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Time of application;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Type of plant, animal, or structure treated and target pest;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Acreage, or number of plants or animals, or a description of or square or cubic footage of the structure treated;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Wind direction, estimated velocity, and weather conditions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Pesticide applied (the name brand) and the type of formulation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Dilution rate of the product as applied (the percent of active ingredient);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>The amount of diluted material applied; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>The type of equipment used.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.2.</num>
    <text>Commercial applicators and pesticide operators shall maintain records containing the information the Mayor may promulgate by regulation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.3.</num>
    <text>Pesticide dealers shall maintain records containing the information required by rules promulgated by the Mayor to adequately identify purchases of restricted use pesticides and other materials purchased.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.4.</num>
    <text>The Mayor may, pursuant to regulations the Mayor promulgates, require private applicators to maintain records or to file reports or other documents.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.5.</num>
    <text>Each person shall, upon written request, furnish the Mayor with copies of any requested records or any other information the Mayor requests.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.6.</num>
    <text>The records required to be maintained by §§ 2508.2 through 2508.5 shall be subject to inspection by the Mayor at any time during business hours.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.7.</num>
    <text>The applicator or operator who prepares the required records shall transfer to the Mayor as required by appropriate regulations all the records that are prepared during the period that is determined by the regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.8.</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall preserve the required records for not less than ten (10) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.9.</num>
    <text>If an applicator or operator who prepares records go out of business, all the records in his or her possession shall be transferred immediately to the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.10.</num>
    <text>The Mayor may require the reporting of significant pesticide accidents or incidents to a designated District agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.11.</num>
    <text>Records of each application of both general and restricted pesticides by all licensed certified commercial applicators and pesticide operators, and records of application of restricted use pesticides by licensed certified private applicators shall
      be maintained and held for a period of three (3) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.12.</num>
    <text>A duplicate of the records specified in § 2508.11 shall be transferred to the Director upon request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.13.</num>
    <text>The records specified in § 2508.11 shall be filed systematically and maintained separately or distinguishable from the customary sales invoices provided to customers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Sections 10 and 14 of the Pesticide Operations Act of 1977, D.C. Law 2-70, 25 DCR 6867, 6867 and 6894 (February 17, 1978), as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 3044 (October 6, 1978), incorporating Proposed Rulemaking published at
        25 DCR 2118 (August 25, 1978).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>