<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-2214</num>
  <heading>POSTING (§ 20-2214)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2214.1.</num>
    <text>Any person required to have a license under D.C. Official Code § 8-403 who is applying a pesticide to a lawn or to exterior landscape plants shall post, at the time of application, a sign that conforms to the requirements of this section. This section
      applies only to those persons required to be certified in pest control pursuant to 20 DCMR § 2301.1(a)(1) and (2).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2214.2.</num>
    <text>The sign required by § 2214.1 shall meet the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be no smaller than four (4) inches in height x five (5) inches in width;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be constructed of a sturdy, weather resistant material;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Be rigid, as opposed to a flag;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Be on a flexible stake, preferably not wire;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Have yellow background with black, bold-faced lettering; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Be posted so that the bottom of the sign shall be at least twelve (12) inches but not more than sixteen (16) inches above the surface of the soil.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2214.3.</num>
    <text>The information contained on the sign shall meet the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Information contained on the front of the sign shall be the same words and symbols and in the sizes specified in Figure A shown at the end of this chapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Information contained on the back of the sign shall be at least eighteen (18) point type (5/32 inch) in size and indicate the following:</text>
    </level>
    <text>i. Date applied;</text>
    <text>ii. Name of applicator; and</text>
    <text>iii. Telephone number of applicator.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2214.4.</num>
    <text>The person applying the pesticide shall place the sign at each primary access to the property treated, with the front of the sign facing the access. If only a spot pesticide application is made, or only a small area of a large area receives a pesticide
      application, the sign may be posted at the location where the pesticide application was made, with the front of the sign facing the probable path of access to the area.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2214.5.</num>
    <text>The sign shall remain in place for forty-eight (48) hours following the pesticide application, after which time the property owner is responsible for removal of the sign.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2214.6.</num>
    <text>Subject to the penalties provided in D.C. Official Code § 8-418, no person, acting alone or in concert with others, may remove, alter, or deface the sign within forty-eight (48) hours of its posting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 9839 (September 19, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>