<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-3100</num>
  <heading>PURPOSE AND AUTHORITY (§ 20-3100)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3100.1.</num>
    <text>The Department has authority to implement and enforce this Chapter pursuant to the District Department of the Environment Establishment Act of 2005, effective February 15, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-51; D.C. Official Code § 8-151.01 et seq.), the Water Pollution
      Control Act of 1984, as amended, effective March 16, 1985 (D.C. Law 5-188; D.C. Official Code § 8-103.01, et seq.), the Soil Erosion and Sedimentation Control Act of 1977 (D.C. Law 2-23; codified at Chapter 21 of District of Columbia Municipal Regulations
      [DCMR], §§ 500 through 507), the District of Columbia Applications Insurance Implementation Act, (District of Columbia Law 1-64, D.C. Official Code § 6-501, et seq.), and Mayor’s Order 2006-61, dated June 14, 2006.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3100.2.</num>
    <text>The purpose of this Chapter is to promote the public health, safety, and general welfare, and to minimize public and private losses due to flood conditions in specific areas by:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Regulating uses, activities, and development which, acting alone or in combination with other existing or future uses, activities, and development, will cause unacceptable increases in flood heights, velocities, and frequencies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Restricting or prohibiting certain uses, activities, and development from locating within areas subject to flooding;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Requiring all those uses, activities, and developments that do occur in flood-prone areas to be protected in order to prevent flood damage; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Protecting individuals from buying lands and structures which are unsuited for intended purposes because of flood hazards.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 32 DCR 6547 (November 15, 1985); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 10764 (November 19, 2010).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR&amp;#8217;S NOTE</heading>
      <text>Chapter 41, Flood Hazard Rules was renumbered Chapter 31.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>