<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-3107</num>
  <heading>SPECIAL REQUIREMENTS FOR MANUFACTURED HOMES AND RECREATIONAL VEHICLES (ยง0-3107)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3107.1.</num>
    <text>This section applies to all new construction of and substantial improvements to manufactured homes, including recreational vehicles which have been on site for one hundred eighty (180) days or more.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3107.2</num>
    <text>3107.2 Within any SFHA with a floodway, manufactured homes are prohibited.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3107.3.</num>
    <text>Within any SFHAs designated as Zone A, manufactured homes shall be prohibited within the area measured fifty feet (50 ft.) landward from top-of-bank of any watercourse.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3107.4.</num>
    <text>Where permitted within any SFHA without a floodway, all manufactured homes and any additions thereto shall, in addition to any other requirements of law:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be anchored to resist flotation, collapse, or lateral movement by providing over-the-top and frame ties to ground anchors in accordance with the American National Standards as specified in the Standard for the Installation of Manufactured Homes,
        including Manufactured Home Park Requirement (NFPA No. 501A-1974 and ANSI A119.31975) as amended for Manufactured Homes in Hurricane Zones or other appropriate standards such as the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Over-the-top ties shall be provided at each of the four (4) corners of the manufactured home, with two (2) additional ties per side at intermediate locations for units fifty feet (50 ft.) or more in length, and one (1) additional tie per side for
        units less than fifty feet (50 ft.) in length;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Frame ties shall be provided at each corner of the manufactured home, with five (5) additional ties per side at intermediate locations for units fifty feet (50 ft.) or more in length, and four (4) additional ties per side for units less than fifty
        feet (50 ft.) in length; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>All components of the anchoring system shall be capable of carrying a force of four thousand eight hundred pounds (4,800 lbs.).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be elevated on a permanent foundation in accordance with the following requirements:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The stands or lots shall be elevated on compacted fill, or on pilings so that the lowest floor of the manufactured home will be one and one-half feet (1-1/2 ft.) or more above the base flood elevation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Adequate surface drainage shall be provided;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Adequate access for a hauler shall be provided; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Where pilings are used for elevation:</text>
    </level>
    <text>The lots shall be large enough to permit step;</text>
    <text>Piling foundations shall be placed in stable soil no more than ten feet (10 ft.) apart; and</text>
    <text>(iii) Reinforcement shall be provided for pilings that will extend for six feet (6 ft.) or more above the ground level.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3107.5.</num>
    <text>An evacuation plan indicating alternate vehicular access and escape routes shall be filed with the D.C. Homeland Security and Emergency Management Agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3107.6.</num>
    <text>An application for a building permit and any plans for construction or development shall comply with all other applicable building regulations and other laws and regulations of the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3107.7.</num>
    <text>Recreational vehicles placed in any SFHA shall either:</text>
    <text>Be on the site for fewer than one hundred eighty (180) consecutive days;</text>
    <text>Be registered with the Department of Motor Vehicles for operation in the District and ready for highway use. A recreational vehicle is ready for highway use if it is on its wheels or jacking system, is attached to the site only by quick disconnect
      type utilities and security devices, and has no permanently attached additions; or</text>
    <text>Meet the building permit requirements in ยง 3103 and the elevation and anchoring and elevation requirements for manufactured homes in ยง 3107.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 32 DCR 6547, 6559 (November 15, 1985); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 10777 (November 19, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>