<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-3304</num>
  <heading>PROHIBITED PRACTICES (§ 20-3304)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3304.1.</num>
    <text>The practices listed in this subsection are prohibited when performing any lead based paint activity or any renovation activity that disturbs presumed lead-based paint. No individual, firm or business entity shall use:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Open flame burning or torching of paint;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Machine sanding, planing, or grinding, or use of a needle gun to remove paint or other surface coatings, without a high-efficiency particulate air (HEPA) local exhaust control and without a shroud or containment system that allows no visible dust
        or release of air to occur outside the shroud or containment system;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Abrasive blasting, water blasting, or sandblasting without HEPA local exhaust control or an effective containment system;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Heat guns operating at or above eleven hundred degrees Fahrenheit (1100°F) or charring the paint;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Dry sanding or dry scraping, except:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Dry scraping within one foot (1 ft.) of electrical outlets;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Dry scraping in conjunction with heat guns operating below eleven hundred degrees Fahrenheit (1100°F); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Dry scraping when treating defective paint spots totaling no more than two square feet (2 sq. ft) in any one interior room or space;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Methylene chloride;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Stripping paint in a poorly ventilated space using a volatile stripper that is a hazardous substance as defined in 16 CFR § 1500.3, or any chemical that is a physical hazard or a health hazard; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Scraping, sanding, drilling into, cutting, or otherwise disturbing more than two square feet (2 sq. ft.) of paint in or on a residential property or a child occupied facility built before 1978 without the use of appropriate containment measures.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3304.2.</num>
    <text>No individual, firm or business entity shall apply paint with a lead content of more than 0.009 percent (0.009%), in accordance with 16 CFR § 1303.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10909 (July 26, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>