<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-3311</num>
  <heading>CERTIFICATION OF BUSINESS ENTITIES PERFORMING LEAD-BASED PAINT ACTIVITIES AND OFIRMS CONDUCTING RENOVATION ACTIVITIES (§ 20-3311)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3311.1.</num>
    <text>To become certified, a business entity or a firm shall comply with all applicable requirements of this section before any employee or sub-contractor of the business entity or firm may conduct a lead-based paint activity, clearance examination, or
      renovation in a dwelling unit or child-occupied facility built before 1978.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3311.2.</num>
    <text>The business entity or firm shall be responsible for ensuring that each employee and subcontractor of the business entity conducting a lead-based paint activity, clearance examination, or renovation for the entity, is:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Certified pursuant to §§ 3307 or 3308;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>In compliance with the provisions of §§ 3302, 3304 and 3310; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>In compliance with all applicable federal and District laws, regulations, and rules governing the disposal of all waste containing lead.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3311.3.</num>
    <text>An entity applying for certification as a business that conducts lead-based paint activities or as a firm that conducts renovation activities in the District of Columbia shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Document that the entity has a valid DCRA license, if required, to do business in the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Submit documentation to DDOE that proves that the entity has liability insurance for at least one million dollars ($1,000,000), which the entity shall maintain for the entire period of the DDOE business entity certification;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Execute a District of Columbia Clean Hands Self-Certification Form stating that paragraph (c) above has been met; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Pay the applicable certification fee required under § 3322.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3311.4.</num>
    <text>The business entity or firm shall comply with the recordkeeping requirements of D.C. Official Code § 8-231.01 et seq.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3311.5.</num>
    <text>A business entity or firm’s certification shall expire after five (5) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10909 (July 26, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>