<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-4201</num>
  <heading>RULES OF INTERPRETATION FOR FEDERAL REGULATIONS INCORPORATED BY REFERENCE (§0-4201)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4201.1.</num>
    <text>The Hazardous Waste Management Regulations in 20 DCMR §§ 4260 through 4279 incorporate by reference the federal Resource Conservation and Recovery Act regulations in 40 CFR Parts 260 through 266, 268, 270, 273, and 279, as well as the provisions of
      40 CFR Part 124 pertaining to RCRA permits (hereafter collectively referred to as the &amp;#8220;RCRA regulations&amp;#8221;), promulgated by the United States Environmental Protection Agency (EPA).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4201.2.</num>
    <text>The incorporation by reference of the RCRA regulations in 20 DCMR §§ 4260 through 4279 is subject to the general modifications in §§ 4200 through 4206, as well as the corrections in Appendix A to this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4201.3.</num>
    <text>Unless specified otherwise, whenever a provision in the Hazardous Waste Management Regulations refers to Volume 40 of the Code of Federal Regulations (40 CFR), the provision shall refer to the most recently updated Volume 40 in publication and any
      amendments thereto.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4201.4.</num>
    <text>Unless specified otherwise, whenever a provision in the Hazardous Waste Management Regulations refers to a volume of the Code of Federal Regulations other than Volume 40, the provision shall refer to the most recently updated volumes in publication
      and any amendments thereto.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4201.5.</num>
    <text>Federal regulations that are incorporated by reference in the Hazardous Waste Management Regulations, or that are cross-referenced in the federal regulations that are incorporated by reference, include any District modifications to the federal regulations,
      such that whenever a District analog to a federal regulation is more stringent, broader, or different than the federal regulation, the District analog shall be substituted for the federal regulation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4201.6.</num>
    <text>The following table shows the correspondence between the RCRA regulations and the Hazardous Waste Management Regulations:</text>
    <text>Federal Regulation</text>
    <text>Subject Matter</text>
    <text>District Regulation</text>
    <text>40 CFR Part 260</text>
    <text>Hazardous Waste Management</text>
    <text>System: General Provisions</text>
    <text>20 DCMR § 4260</text>
    <text>40 CFR Part 261</text>
    <text>Identification and Listing of</text>
    <text>Hazardous Waste</text>
    <text>20 DCMR § 4261</text>
    <text>40 CFR Part 262</text>
    <text>Standards Applicable to Generators</text>
    <text>of Hazardous Waste</text>
    <text>20 DCMR § 4262</text>
    <text>40 CFR Part 263</text>
    <text>Standards Applicable to Transporters of Hazardous Waste</text>
    <text>20 DCMR § 4263</text>
    <text>40 CFR Part 264</text>
    <text>Standards for Owners and Operators of Hazardous Waste Treatment, Storage, and Disposal Facilities</text>
    <text>20 DCMR § 4264</text>
    <text>40 CFR Part 265</text>
    <text>Interim Status Standards for Owners and Operators of Hazardous Waste Treatment, Storage, and Disposal Facilities</text>
    <text>20 DCMR § 4265</text>
    <text>40 CFR Part 266</text>
    <text>Standards for the Management of Specific Hazardous Wastes and Specific Types of Hazardous Waste Management Facilities</text>
    <text>20 DCMR § 4266</text>
    <text>40 CFR Part 268</text>
    <text>Land Disposal Restrictions</text>
    <text>20 DCMR § 4268</text>
    <text>40 CFR Part 270</text>
    <text>Hazardous Waste Permit Program</text>
    <text>20 DCMR § 4270</text>
    <text>40 CFR Part 124</text>
    <text>Decision-Making Procedures for Hazardous Waste Permit Program</text>
    <text>20 DCMR § 4271</text>
    <text>40 CFR Part 273</text>
    <text>Standards for Universal Waste Management</text>
    <text>20 DCMR § 4273</text>
    <text>40 CFR Part 279</text>
    <text>Standards for the Management of Used Oil</text>
    <text>20 DCMR § 4279</text>
    <text>N/A</text>
    <text>Inspections, Enforcement, and</text>
    <text>Fee Schedule</text>
    <text>20 DCMR chapter 43</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4201.7.</num>
    <text>In the incorporation by reference of the RCRA regulations, for all instances in which the RCRA regulations contain a cross-reference to 40 CFR Parts 124, 260 through 266, 268, 270, 273, or 279, the federal cross-reference shall be replaced with the
      corresponding section in the District regulations shown in the table in 20 DCMR § 4201.6.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4201.8.</num>
    <text>For purposes of interfacing with the RCRA regulations, the following terms apply, unless specified otherwise or unless the context requires otherwise:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Except in those federal provisions that are not delegable by law, or that have not been delegated by EPA, to the District of Columbia, the term &amp;#8220;Director&amp;#8221; shall supplant the terms &amp;#8220;Administrator,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Assistant
        Administrator,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Assistant Administrator for Solid Waste and Emergency Response,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;EPA Administrator,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Regional Administrator,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Regional Administrator for the Region
        in which the generator is located,&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;State Director&amp;#8221;;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The terms &amp;#8220;District of Columbia Department of the Environment&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;Department&amp;#8221; shall supplant the terms &amp;#8220;United States Environmental Protection Agency,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;U.S. Environmental Protection
        Agency,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;EPA,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Agency,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;EPA Headquarters,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;EPA Regions,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Regional Office,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;EPA Regional Office,&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;appropriate
        Regional EPA Office,&amp;#8221; except as follows:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In those federal provisions that are not delegable by law, or that have not been delegated by EPA, to the District, the terms &amp;#8220;District of Columbia Department of the Environment&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;Department&amp;#8221; shall not
        be substituted for the federal terms;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The abbreviation &amp;#8220;EPA,&amp;#8221; when used as an adjective in the terms &amp;#8220;EPA Acknowledgement of Consent,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;EPA form,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;EPA guidance,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;EPA hazardous waste number,&amp;#8221;
        &amp;#8220;EPA identification number,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;EPA publication,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;EPA Region,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;EPA test methods,&amp;#8221; or similar phrases, shall not be supplanted and shall remain as in the Code of Federal
        Regulations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The terms &amp;#8220;U.S. Environmental Protection Agency&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;Environmental Protection Agency&amp;#8221; shall not be supplanted when it appears in a mailing or physical address;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The terms &amp;#8220;Department of Transportation&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;DOT&amp;#8221; shall mean the United States Department of Transportation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The term &amp;#8220;notification requirements of § 3010 of RCRA&amp;#8221; shall mean the requirements, under § 3010 of RCRA, 42 USC § 6930, to notify the Administrator or states having an EPA-authorized RCRA Subtitle C program, including the District
        of Columbia, of the person&amp;#8217;s regulated waste activities (hazardous waste activities, universal waste activities, and used oil management activities). The EPA-authorized state where the activity takes place is the primary point of contact
        for submission of notifications;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The term &amp;#8220;RCRA permit,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;permit issued under subtitle C of RCRA,&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;permit issued under RCRA § 3005&amp;#8243; shall mean a permit, as defined in 40 CFR § 270.2, issued by the Department or EPA
        to implement the provisions of 40 CFR Parts 270, 271, and 124, including a hazardous waste permit issued by the Department pursuant to 20 DCMR § 4270;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The term &amp;#8220;revocation and reissuance&amp;#8221; in the federal regulation is equivalent to the &amp;#8220;suspension&amp;#8221; and granting of a new permit under §§ 4 and 10 of the District of Columbia Hazardous Waste Management Act of
        1977, effective March 28, 1978, as amended (D.C. Law 2-64; D.C. Official Code §§ 8-1303 and 8-1309 (2001)), and the Hazardous Waste Management Regulations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The term &amp;#8220;termination&amp;#8221; in the RCRA regulations is equivalent to the term &amp;#8220;revocation&amp;#8221; in §§ 4 and 10 of the District of Columbia Hazardous Waste Management Act of 1977, D.C. Official Code §§ 8-1303 and 8-1309,
        and the Hazardous Waste Management Regulations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4201.9.</num>
    <text>The incorporation by reference of the RCRA regulations excludes all site-specific provisions pertaining to Project XL (Excellence in Leadership) facilities located in other states.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>NOTE The Code of Federal Regulations may be viewed online at http://www.gpoaccess.gov or at certain public libraries; or purchased by calling (202) 512-1800 or toll-free (866) 512-1800; by writing to the Superintendent of Documents, U.S. Government
        Printing Office, attn: New Orders, P.O. Box 371954, Pittsburgh, PA 15250-7954; or online, at http:</heading>
      <text>//bookstore.gpo.gov.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 9653 (October 28, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 5586 (June 8, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>