<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-4301</num>
  <heading>RIGHT OF ENTRY (ยง 20-4301)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4301.1.</num>
    <text>For the purpose of enforcing the laws and rules listed in ยง 4300, the Director shall have the right, upon presentation of appropriate credentials to the owner, operator, or agent in charge, to enter without delay, subject to ยง 4301.3, any place or
      vehicle where hazardous waste, used oil, or regulated medical waste are, or have been generated, handled, transported, treated, stored, or disposed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4301.2.</num>
    <text>Appropriate credentials for making an inspection shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A duly issued photo identification card or badge showing the name of the inspector and proof of employment with the Department; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A notice of inspection issued by the Director, containing the following information:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Name of the owner, operator, or agent in charge;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Address of the place or identification of the vehicle to be inspected;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Date of the inspection; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Signature of the inspector.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4301.3.</num>
    <text>Entry by the Director may be made, with or without prior notice, as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>At any time, in emergency situations, or where there is a potential immediate threat to human health and safety or the environment; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>At any reasonable time in non-emergency situations. The following times shall be deemed reasonable for purposes of entry:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Between the hours of 7:30 a.m. and 6:00 p.m. on weekdays; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any hours during which the facility is open for business or operation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 9653 (October 28, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>