<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-6204</num>
  <heading>REMOVAL OF FREE PRODUCT (§ 20-6204)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6204.1.</num>
    <text>At sites where investigations under § 6203.12 indicate the presence of any free product, the responsible party shall remove measurable free product to the maximum extent practicable as determined by the Director, in accordance with a schedule determined
      or approved by the Director on a case by-case basis, while continuing, as necessary, any actions initiated under §§ 6203 through 6205, or preparing for actions required under § 6206. Fulfillment of the requirements of this section is a pre-requisite
      to the use of risk-based decisionmaking to develop a risk-based corrective action (RBCA) plan pursuant to § 6206.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6204.2.</num>
    <text>The responsible party shall conduct the removal of free product in a manner that minimizes the spread of contamination into previously uncontaminated zones by using recovery techniques appropriate to the hydrogeologic conditions at the site.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6204.3.</num>
    <text>The responsible party shall conduct the recovery and disposal of free product in a manner that properly treats, discharges, recycles or disposes of recovery byproducts in compliance with all applicable laws and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6204.4.</num>
    <text>The minimum objective for the design of the free product removal system shall be the abatement of free product migration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6204.5.</num>
    <text>The responsible party shall ensure that any flammable substances are handled in a manner that will prevent fire and explosion.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6204.6.</num>
    <text>Unless directed to do otherwise by the Director, the responsible party shall prepare and submit to the Director, commencing forty-five (45) days after release confirmation and quarterly thereafter, a status report on the removal of any free product,
      in the format prescribed by the Director, that provides at least the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name of the person(s) responsible for implementing the free product removal measures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The estimated quantity, type, and thickness of free product observed or measured in wells, boreholes, and excavations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The type of free product recovery system used;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Whether any groundwater discharge will take place on-site or off-site during the recovery operation and where this discharge point will be located;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The type of treatment applied to, and the effluent quality expected from, any such discharge;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The steps that have been or are being taken to obtain necessary permits for any discharge; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The disposition of the recovered free product.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 7835, 7887 (November 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7699 (October 1, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>