<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-6001</num>
  <heading>RELEASE DETECTION RECORDKEEPING (ยง 20-6001)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6001.1.</num>
    <text>The owner or operator of each UST system shall maintain records, in accordance with this section and ยง 5602 of this Subtitle, demonstrating compliance with all applicable requirements of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6001.2.</num>
    <text>All written performance claims pertaining to any release detection system that is in use, including the manner in which those claims have been justified or tested by the equipment manufacturer or installer, shall be maintained for at least ten (10)
      years after the date of installation. Owners or operators shall retain any written performance claims that were in their possession on January 1, 1996 or thereafter and that are currently in their possession in accordance with the times set forth
      in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6001.3.</num>
    <text>The results of any sampling, testing, or monitoring of an UST system shall be maintained for at least three (3) years, except as provided in ยง 6001.4 of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6001.4.</num>
    <text>The results of tank tightness testing conducted in accordance with ยง 6007 of this chapter shall be retained until the next test of the UST system is conducted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6001.5.</num>
    <text>Written documentation of all calibration, maintenance, and repair of release detection equipment permanently located at the UST system facility shall be maintained for at least three (3) years after the servicing work is completed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6001.6.</num>
    <text>All schedules of required calibration and maintenance provided by the release detection equipment manufacturer shall be retained for at least ten (10) years from the date of installation of the release detection system. Owners or operators shall maintain
      all calibration and maintenance schedules that were in their possession on January 1, 1996 or thereafter and are currently in their possession.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 7835, 7867 (November 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7699 (October 1, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>