<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-6002</num>
  <heading>HAZARDOUS SUBSTANCES (§ 20-6002)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6002.1.</num>
    <text>Each owner or operator of a hazardous substance UST system shall provide release detection that meets the requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6002.2.</num>
    <text>Release detection for new hazardous substance UST systems shall meet the requirements set forth in §§ 6003 and 6004 of this Chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6002.3.</num>
    <text>Secondary containment systems shall be checked for evidence of a release at least every thirty (30) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6002.4.</num>
    <text>An alternative method of release detection for a hazardous substance system may be approved if the owner or operator does the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Demonstrate to the satisfaction of the Director that the proposed alternative method can detect a release of the stored substance as effectively as any of the methods allowed in §§ 6006 through 6012 can detect a release of petroleum; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Provide information satisfactory to the Director on effective corrective action technologies, known and potential health risks, the chemical and physical properties of the stored substance, and the characteristics of the UST site.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6002.5.</num>
    <text>The owner or operator shall obtain approval of the Director to use an alternate release detection method prior to the installation and operation of the new UST system.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6002.6.</num>
    <text>All existing hazardous substance systems shall meet the release detection requirements for new petroleum UST systems as set forth in §§ 6003 and 6004.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 7835, 7868 (November 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7699 (October 1, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>