<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-6600</num>
  <heading>JURISDICTION AND DELEGATION OF AUTHORITY (§ 20-6600)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6600.1.</num>
    <text>In every case in which a hearing is requested or is required pursuant to the Act or pursuant to this Subtitle, the hearing authority of the Director is delegated to the authorized hearing body(ies) for the Department which shall have jurisdiction
      to hear and render a final decision in the case.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6600.2.</num>
    <text>The contested case provisions of the D.C. Administrative Procedures Act, D.C. Code Section 1-1509, as supplemented by this chapter shall govern all cases in which a hearing is requested or otherwise required by the Act or this Subtitle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6600.3.</num>
    <text>The Director or his or her designee, shall be authorized to pursue enforcement actions through:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The issuance of notices of violation pursuant to § 6601, proposed compliance orders and proposed cease and desist orders pursuant to § 6602, and notices of intention to suspend, deny or revoke a license or certification pursuant to § 6603;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The development and presentation of cases before an authorized hearing body; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The issuance of immediate cease and desist orders and compliance orders pursuant to § 6606.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6600.4.</num>
    <text>The Director or his or her designee shall be authorized to issue summary suspension orders pursuant to § 6607.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is §13 of the District of Columbia Underground Storage Tank Management Act of 1990, as amended, D.C. Law 8-242, D.C. Code §6-995.1 et seq. (1995 Repl. Vol.), Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 91-160 dated
        October 9, 1991; and the District of Columbia Water Pollution Control Act of 1984, D.C. Law 5-188, D.C. Code 6-921 (1995 Repl. Vol.), Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 85-152 dated September 12, 1985.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 7835, 7914 (November 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7699 (October 1, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>