<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-6212</num>
  <heading>PUBLIC PARTICIPATION IN CORRECTIVE ACTION (§ 20-6212)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6212.1.</num>
    <text>For each release that requires a corrective action plan, the Director shall provide a public notice designed to reach those members of the public directly affected by the release and the planned corrective action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6212.2.</num>
    <text>Notice may be provided by any of the following methods: publication of notices in local newspapers or the D.C. Register, block advertisements, public service announcements, letters to individual households, personal contacts by field staff, notification
      to the affected Advisory Neighborhood Commissioners (ANCs) and civic associations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6212.3.</num>
    <text>Any person directly impacted by a release that has migrated onto their property shall have a right to request a copy of the comprehensive site assessment, any Tier 2 site evaluation and any corrective action plan, and if requested, shall be given
      an opportunity to comment on the CAP.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6212.4.</num>
    <text>The Director shall give public notice that complies with §§ 6212.1 and 6212.2 of this section if implementation of an approved corrective action plan does not achieve the established clean-up levels in the plan and termination of that plan is under
      consideration by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6212.5.</num>
    <text>The Director shall receive citizens&amp;#8217; written complaints that allege violations of the provisions of this Subtitle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6212.6.</num>
    <text>The Director shall investigate each bona fide complaint filed under § 6212.5, and shall notify the complainant and the owner or operator of the UST or UST system of the results of that investigation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6212.7.</num>
    <text>The Director shall not request Corporation Counsel to oppose any application by a private citizen for permissive intervention under Rule 24(b) of the Rules of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia in any civil action to enforce the provisions
      of the Act or the applicable provisions of this chapter on the ground that the applicant&amp;#8217;s interest is adequately represented by the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 7835, 7896 (November 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7699 (October 1, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>