<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-6404</num>
  <heading>DOCUMENTATION OF FUND EXPENDITURES (ยง 20-6404)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6404.1.</num>
    <text>Disbursements of monies from the Fund shall be documented in accordance with the requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6404.2.</num>
    <text>The Director shall maintain original records, as are kept in the ordinary course of business, for all Fund expenditures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6404.3.</num>
    <text>The Director shall maintain documentation that tracks the cost of cleanup and enforcement actions on a site-specific basis.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6404.4.</num>
    <text>Documentation of direct costs shall identify costs by activity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6404.5.</num>
    <text>Any District agency contracting with or procuring services for the Director shall maintain and make available to the Director upon request, site-specific documentation of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Time and attendance records including a description of employee activities, and fringe benefit calculations for all payroll expenses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Copies of any advertisements, requests for proposals, proposals, contractor cost data, proposal evaluations, work change orders, reports on contractor work, audits of contractors, contracts, or other documents related to procurement of contractors
        to perform corrective actions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Invoices, approval of invoices, and proof of payments for all contractor services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Invoices, leases, proof of payment, receipts and, where feasible, hourly records of equipment use for any equipment leased or purchased;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Worksheets showing allocation of time to project and calculation of indirect costs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Any authorizations, vouchers or receipts related to travel; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Any other records kept in the normal course of accounting or required by federal regulation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6404.6.</num>
    <text>Any contractor who performs corrective action work pursuant to a contract with the District, shall maintain records on a site-specific basis and shall bill the District for activities performed on a site-specific basis in accordance with District
      procurement regulations and policies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6404.7.</num>
    <text>The Director shall maintain hard copies of all original cost documents for at least three(3) years from completion of the final expenditure report. If any litigation, audit or other action has been started before expiration of the three (3) year period,
      the records must be retained until completion of the action or resolution of all issues.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 7835 (November 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7699 (October 1, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>