<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-6500</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (ยง 20-6500)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6500.1.</num>
    <text>The owner or operator of each UST system shall ensure that the UST system or any component of the UST system, including the release detection system, is installed under the continuous on-site supervision of a UST System Technician who is certified
      in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and who is licensed to do business in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6500.2.</num>
    <text>The owner or operator of each UST system that is to be permanently closed or that the type of service will change shall ensure that the UST system is abandoned or removed under the continuous on-site supervision of a UST System Technician or UST Closer
      Specialist who is certified in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and who is licensed to do business in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6500.3.</num>
    <text>The owner or operator of each UST system to be tested for rightness shall ensure that the test is conducted under the continuous on-site supervision of a UST System Tester who is certified in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and licensed
      to do business in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6500.4.</num>
    <text>Each business that provides services for UST system installation, upgrade, retrofit, repair or permanent closure in the District of Columbia shall be certified to perform UST activities by the Director in accordance with the provisions of this chapter
      and licensed to do business in the District of Columbia. A business may be certified to perform only those UST activities for which it employs a UST System Technician, UST Closer Specialist, UST System Tester who has a current valid District of
      Columbia certification and license for the applicable UST activity or an equivalent category.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6500.5.</num>
    <text>Each UST System Technician, UST Closure Specialist and UST System Tester who provides his or her services for UST system installation, upgrade, retrofit, repair, or permanent closure in the District of Columbia shall be certified to perform UST system
      activities by the Director in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and licensed to do business in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6500.6.</num>
    <text>Each business that is certified to perform UST system activities in the District of Columbia shall provide the Director with a list of employees, who are not certified as UST System Technicians, Closer Specialists or Testers, but who perform supervised
      on-site UST activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6500.7.</num>
    <text>Each certified UST System Technician, Closure Specialist and Tester shall carry the identification card or the certificate issued by the Director at all times while conducting the applicable UST activity. The identification card shall be available
      for inspection by the owner, operator or the Director when the technician, specialist or tester is engaged in the UST activity for which he or she is certified.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6500.8.</num>
    <text>No business may transfer the UST System certification or license issued to it by the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6500.9.</num>
    <text>Within ten (10) business days after close or termination of the business, the licensee shall surrender the certification and license to the Director for cancellation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6500.10.</num>
    <text>An owner of any active regulated UST system in the District shall designate at least one Class A, one Class B, and one Class C operator for each active UST facility, and all designated classes shall comply with the requirements of ยง 6502.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7699 (October 1, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 6678 (August 21, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>