<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-727</num>
  <heading>CONSUMER PRODUCTS – CONTACT ADHESIVES, ELECTRONIC CLEANERS, FOOTWEAR ANDEATHER CARE PRODUCTS, AND GENERAL PURPOSE DEGREASERS (§ 20-727)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>727.1</num>
    <text>727.1 Except as provided in sections § 727.2 and 727.4, effective January 1,012, no person shall sell, supply, offer for sale, or manufacture for use inhe District of Columbia any contact adhesive, electronic cleaner, footwear oreather care product,
      or general purpose degreaser that contains methylenehloride, perchloroethylene, or trichloroethylene.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>727.2</num>
    <text>727.2 Contact adhesives, electronic cleaners, footwear or leather careroducts, or general purpose degreasers that contain methylene chloride,erchloroethylene, or trichloroethylene and were manufactured before January 1,012, may be sold, supplied,
      or offered for sale until May 1, 2012, so long ashe product container or package displays the date on which the product wasanufactured, or a code indicating such date, in accordance with § 732.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>727.3</num>
    <text>727.3 Any person who sells or supplies a consumer product identified above in 727.1 shall notify the purchaser of the product, in writing, that theell-through period for that product will end on May 1, 2012, provided, however,hat this notification
      must be given only if both of the following conditionsre met:</text>
    <text>The product is sold or supplied through a distributor or retailer; and</text>
    <text>The product is sold or supplied on or after January 1, 2012.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>727.4</num>
    <text>727.4 The requirements of § 727.1 and 721.3 shall not apply to any contactdhesives, electronic cleaner, footwear or leather care product, or generalurpose degreaser containing methylene chloride, perchloroethylene, orrichloroethylene that is present
      as an impurity in a combined amount equal tor less than one one-hundredth of a percent (0.01%) by weight.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 3879 (April 16, 2004); as amendedy Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 10781 (November 26, 2004); as amended byotice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 11286, 11315 (December 30, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>