<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-774</num>
  <heading>ARCHITECTURAL AND INDUSTRIAL MAINTENANCE COATING – STANDARDS (§ 20-774)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>774.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall manufacture, blend, supply, sell, offer for sale, apply, or solicit the application of any architectural coating with a VOC content in excess of the corresponding limit specified in the Table of Standards in § 774.10, except as provided
      in §§ 774.2, 774.3, 774.8, and 774.10.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>774.2</num>
    <text>774.2 The most restrictive VOC content limit shall apply if anywhere on the container of any architectural coating, or any label or sticker affixed to the container, or in any sales, advertising, or technical literature supplied by a manufacturer
      or anyone acting on their behalf, any representation is made that indicates that the coating meets the definition of or is recommended for use for more than one (1) of the coating categories listed in the Table of Standards in § 774.10. This provision
      does not apply to the following coating categories:</text>
    <text>Lacquer coatings (including lacquer sanding sealers);</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Metallic pigmented coatings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Shellacs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Fireretardant coatings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Pretreatment wash primers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Industrial maintenance coatings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Lowsolids coatings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Wood preservatives;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Hightemperature coatings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Temperatureindicator safety coatings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Antenna coatings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Antifouling coatings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Flow coatings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>Bituminous roof primers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>Specialty primers, sealers, and undercoaters;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(p)</num>
      <text>Thermoplastic rubber coating and mastic;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(q)</num>
      <text>Calcimine recoaters;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(r)</num>
      <text>Impacted immersion coatings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(s)</num>
      <text>Nuclear coatings; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(t)</num>
      <text>Concrete surface retarders.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>774.3.</num>
    <text>A coating manufactured before the effective date specified for that coating in the Table of Standards in § 774.10, may be sold, supplied, or offered for sale after the specified effective date. In addition, a coating manufactured before the effective
      date specified for that coating in the Table of Standards in § 774.10 may be applied at any time, both before and after the specified effective date, so long as the coating complied with the standards in effect at the time the coating was manufactured.
      This subsection does not apply to any coating that does not display the date or date code required by § 776.1(a).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>774.4.</num>
    <text>All architectural coating containers used to apply the contents therein to a surface directly from the container by pouring, siphoning, brushing, rolling, padding, ragging, or other means shall be closed when not in use. These architectural coatings
      containers include, but are not limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Drums, buckets, cans, pails, trays, or other application containers; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Containers of any VOCcontaining materials used for thinning and cleanup shall also be closed when not in use.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>774.5.</num>
    <text>No person who applies or solicits the application of any architectural coating shall apply a coating that is thinned to exceed the applicable VOC limit specified in the Table of Standards in § 774.10.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>774.6.</num>
    <text>No person shall apply or solicit the application of any rust preventive coating for industrial use, unless such a rust preventive coating complies with the industrial maintenance coating VOC limit specified in the Table of Standards in § 774.10.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>774.7.</num>
    <text>For any coating that does not meet any of the definitions for the specialty coatings categories listed in the Table of Standards in § 774.10, the VOC content limit shall be determined by classifying the coating as a flat coating or a nonflat coating,
      based on its gloss, as defined in § 799, and the corresponding flat or nonflat coating limit shall apply.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>774.8.</num>
    <text>A manufacturer, seller, or user of an industrial maintenance coating may petition the Department to apply an industrial maintenance coating with a VOC content greater than three hundred forty gallons per liter (340 g./L) if all of the following conditions
      are met:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The industrial maintenance coating is applied outside the ozone season, normally May through September every year;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The petition submitted to the Department shall contain the following information, as applicable: job requirements and descriptions, volume of coating, maximum VOC content, and a certification that a complying coating meeting the job performance
        requirements is not available; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If the Department grants written approval, such approval shall contain volume and VOC limit conditions. Until written approval is granted by the Department and received by the petitioner, all provisions of this section shall apply.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>774.9.</num>
    <text>The Department shall not approve any petition under § 774.8 if the approvals previously granted by the Department during the calendar year, when combined with the petition under consideration, would result in excess VOC emissions for that calendar
      year that would exceed five percent (5%) of the annual emission reduction achieved within the District of Columbia from implementing the January 1, 2005, VOC limit for industrial maintenance coatings. Coatings subject to this provision shall be
      sold only if an approved petition (or a copy of it) is provided before the sale. Coatings subject to this provision shall not be available to the general public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>774.10.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of § 774.1, a person or facility may add up to ten percent (10%) by volume of VOC to a lacquer to avoid blushing of the finish during days with relative humidity greater than seventy percent (70%) and temperature below
      sixty-five degrees Fahrenheit (65° F) or eighteen degrees Celsius (18º C) at the time of application, provided that the coating contains acetone and no more than five hundred fifty grams (550 g.) of VOC per liter of coating, less water and exempt
      compounds, before the addition of VOC.</text>
    <text>Table of Standards. VOC Content Limits for Architectural Coatings.</text>
    <text>Coating Category</text>
    <text>VOC Content Limit</text>
    <text>(Grams VOC per liter)</text>
    <text>Flat coatings</text>
    <text>100</text>
    <text>Nonflat coatings</text>
    <text>150</text>
    <text>Nonflat high gloss coatings</text>
    <text>250</text>
    <text>Specialty Coatings</text>
    <text>Antenna coatings</text>
    <text>530</text>
    <text>Antifouling coatings</text>
    <text>400</text>
    <text>Bituminous roof coatings</text>
    <text>300</text>
    <text>Bituminous roof primers</text>
    <text>350</text>
    <text>Bond breakers</text>
    <text>350</text>
    <text>Calcimine recoater</text>
    <text>475</text>
    <text>Clear wood coatings:</text>
    <text>• Clear brushing lacquers</text>
    <text>680</text>
    <text>• Lacquers (including lacquer sanding sealers)</text>
    <text>550</text>
    <text>• Sanding sealers (other than lacquer sanding sealers)</text>
    <text>350</text>
    <text>• Varnishes</text>
    <text>350</text>
    <text>Concrete curing compounds</text>
    <text>350</text>
    <text>Concrete surface retarders</text>
    <text>780</text>
    <text>Conjugated oil varnish</text>
    <text>450</text>
    <text>Conversion varnish</text>
    <text>725</text>
    <text>Dry fog coatings</text>
    <text>400</text>
    <text>Faux finishing coatings</text>
    <text>350</text>
    <text>Fireresistive coatings</text>
    <text>350</text>
    <text>Fireretardant coatings</text>
    <text>• Clear</text>
    <text>650</text>
    <text>• Opaque</text>
    <text>350</text>
    <text>Floor coatings</text>
    <text>250</text>
    <text>Flow coatings</text>
    <text>420</text>
    <text>Formrelease compounds</text>
    <text>250</text>
    <text>Graphic arts coatings (sign paints)</text>
    <text>500</text>
    <text>Hightemperature coatings</text>
    <text>420</text>
    <text>Industrial maintenance coatings</text>
    <text>340</text>
    <text>Impacted immersion coatings</text>
    <text>780</text>
    <text>Lowsolids coatings</text>
    <text>120</text>
    <text>Magnesite cement coatings</text>
    <text>450</text>
    <text>Mastic texture coatings</text>
    <text>300</text>
    <text>Metallic pigmented coatings</text>
    <text>500</text>
    <text>Multicolor coatings</text>
    <text>250</text>
    <text>Nuclear coatings</text>
    <text>450</text>
    <text>Pretreatment wash primers</text>
    <text>420</text>
    <text>Primers, sealers, and undercoaters</text>
    <text>200</text>
    <text>Reactive penetrating carbonate stone sealer</text>
    <text>600</text>
    <text>Quickdry enamels</text>
    <text>250</text>
    <text>Quickdry primers, sealers and undercoaters</text>
    <text>200</text>
    <text>Recycled coatings</text>
    <text>250</text>
    <text>Roof coatings</text>
    <text>250</text>
    <text>Rust preventative coatings</text>
    <text>400</text>
    <text>Shellacs</text>
    <text>• Clear</text>
    <text>730</text>
    <text>• Opaque</text>
    <text>550</text>
    <text>Specialty primers, sealers, and undercoaters</text>
    <text>350</text>
    <text>Stains</text>
    <text>250</text>
    <text>Stone consolidants</text>
    <text>450</text>
    <text>Swimming pool coatings</text>
    <text>340</text>
    <text>Swimming pool repair and maintenance coatings</text>
    <text>340</text>
    <text>Temperatureindicator safety coatings</text>
    <text>550</text>
    <text>Thermoplastic rubber coatings and mastics</text>
    <text>550</text>
    <text>Traffic marking coatings</text>
    <text>150</text>
    <text>Waterproofing sealers</text>
    <text>250</text>
    <text>Waterproofing concrete/masonry sealers</text>
    <text>400</text>
    <text>Wood preservatives</text>
    <text>350</text>
    <text>Limits are expressed in grams of VOC per liter of coating thinned to the manufacturer&amp;#8217;s maximum recommendation, excluding the volume of any water, exempt compounds, or colorant added to tint bases. Manufacturer’s maximum recommendation means
      the maximum recommendation for thinning that is indicated on the label or lid of the coating container.</text>
    <text>Conversion factor: one pound VOC per gallon (U.S.) is equivalent to one hundred nineteen and ninety-five one hundredths grams per liter (119.95 g/L).</text>
    <text>Units for this coating are grams of VOC per liter (pounds of VOC/gallon) of coating, including water and exempt compounds</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 11286, 11397 (December 30, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>