<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-907</num>
  <heading>VEHICLE CONVERSIONS (§ 20-907)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>907.1.</num>
    <text>Covered fleet operators shall ensure that converted vehicles, conversion kits, and conversion installations shall conform to the requirements of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) for vehicle conversions as found in 40 CFR Parts 86 and 88.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>907.2.</num>
    <text>A vehicle converted to a clean-fuel vehicle shall be eligible to generate credits only if the conversion kit installer provides the covered fleet operator a clean-fuel vehicle certificate of conformity issued by EPA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>907.3.</num>
    <text>No person shall convert a gasoline or diesel-powered vehicle to a clean -fuel vehicle unless the conversion complies with the rules for conversions as promulgated in this chapter and pursuant to § 247 of the Clean Air Act and regulations promulgated
      by the Environmental Protection Agency under § 247. Any person performing conversions that do not comply with this chapter, § 247, or regulations promulgated pursuant to § 247, will be considered in violation of federal antitampering laws and subject
      to the penalties provided in the Clean Air Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>907.4.</num>
    <text>Any person who converts a vehicle to a clean-fuel vehicle shall issue a vehicle or engine warranty for any such conversion done by that person. The warranty and the warranty period shall meet the specifications stated in § 207(i) of the Clean Air
      Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>907.5.</num>
    <text>The person who converts to a clean-fuel vehicle is responsible for the recall and repair of the vehicles, as specified in § 207 of the Clean Air Act, if at any time there is found to be an inherent or developed problem associated with the conversion
      or installation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 3(a) of the Clean Fuel Fleet Vehicle Program and Alternative Fuels Incentives Amendment Act of 1994, D.C. Law 10-201, 41 DCR 7178, 7189 (November 4, 1994).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>