<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-905</num>
  <heading>FLEET REGISTRATION AND RECORDKEEPING (ยง 20-905)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>905.1.</num>
    <text>Operators of all covered fleets shall register with the Mayor within one hundred twenty (120) days after November 4, 1994, of the Clean Fuel Fleet Vehicle Program and Alternative Fuels Incentives Amendment Act of 1994. Fleets which become covered
      fleets after November 4, 1994, because of an increase in fleet size or central fueling capabilities shall register with the Mayor within ninety (90) days of becoming a covered fleet.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>905.2.</num>
    <text>Covered fleets shall register on a form to be prescribed by the Mayor, which shall require the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Name of fleet operator;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Address of fleet operator; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Number of fleet vehicles.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>905.3.</num>
    <text>Accurate records shall be maintained by covered fleets to verify compliance with this chapter. All records shall be maintained for the current model year plus the previous model year. For purposes of enforcement of this chapter, officers or employees
      duly designated by the Mayor, upon presenting appropriate credentials, are authorized to inspect the records of a covered fleet operator. All records provided by covered fleets to the Mayor or the Mayor&amp;#8217;s designee shall be treated as confidential
      and proprietary trade secrets.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>905.4.</num>
    <text>The records that must be maintained by covered fleet operators as provided in ยง 905.3 shall be limited to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The number of clean-fuel vehicles acquired for the applicable model years;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The make, model, weight classification, and fuel type of each fleet vehicle acquired pursuant to this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The type of clean-fuel vehicle (i.e., dedicated, flexible-fueled, bi-fueled, dual- fueled, original equipment manufacturer, converted);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The vehicle identification number; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Purchase records or clean fuel purchases on a monthly basis.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 3(a) of the Clean Fuel Fleet Vehicle Program and Alternative Fuels Incentives Amendment Act of 1994, D.C. Law 10-201, 41 DCR 7178, 7185 (November 4, 1994).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>