<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-915</num>
  <heading>NATIONAL LOW EMISSION VEHICLE PROGRAM (ยง 20-915)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>915.1.</num>
    <text>For the duration of the District of Columbia&amp;#8217;s (District) participation in the National Low Emission Vehicles Program (NLEV), automobile manufacturers may comply with NLEV or equally stringent mandatory federal standards in lieu of compliance
      with any program, including any mandates for sales of zero emissions vehicles (ZEV mandate), adopted by the District pursuant to the authority provided in section 177 of the Clean Air Act (Section 177 Program) applicable to passenger cars, light-duty
      trucks up through six thousand (6,000) pounds GVWR, and/or medium-duty vehicles from six thousand and one (6,001) to fourteen thousand (14,000) pounds GVWR if designed to operate on gasoline.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>915.2.</num>
    <text>The District&amp;#8217;s participation in NLEV extends until model year 2006, except as provided in 40 CFR 86.1707. If, no later than December 15, 2000, the U.S. EPA does not adopt standards at least as stringent as the NLEV standards provided in
      40 CFR part 86 subpart R that apply to new motor vehicles in model year 2004, 2005, or 2006, the District&amp;#8217;s participation in NLEV extends only until model year 2004, except as provided in 40 CFR 86.1707.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>915.3.</num>
    <text>If a covered manufacturer, as defined at 40 CFR 86.1702, opts out of NLEV pursuant to the NLEV regulations at 40 CFR 86.1707, the transition from NLEV requirements to any District section 177 program applicable to passenger cars, light-duty trucks
      up through six thousand (6,000) pounds GVWR, and/or medium-duty vehicles from six thousand and one (6,001) to fourteen thousand (14,000) pounds GVWR if designed to operate on gasoline will proceed in accordance with the EPA NLEV regulations at 40
      CFR 86.1707.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 886(February 11, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>