<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1507</num>
  <heading>WASTEWATER MONITORING (§ 21-1507)
    <text>WASA may require any Industrial User to construct monitoring facilities to allownspection, sampling, and flow measurement of the discharges from the buildingewer or internal drainage systems, and may also require sampling or meteringquipment to be
      provided, installed and operated, at the expense of thendustrial Users.</text>
    <text>The monitoring facility shall be situated on the Industrial User&amp;#8217;sremises and located so that it will not be obstructed by the landscape or byarked vehicles. There shall be ample room in or near such monitoring facilitieso allow accurate
      flow measurement, sampling and compositing of samples fornalysis.</text>
    <text>The monitoring facilities, sampling, and measuring equipment shall be approvedy WASA and maintained at all times in a safe and proper operating condition athe expense of the Industrial User.</text>
    <text>Sampling and analysis shall be done in accordance with the techniques prescribedn 40 C.F.R. Part 136 and amendments thereto and documented in accordance withhe requirements in § 1512.</text>
    <text>Where 40 C.F.R. Part 136 does not contain sampling or analytical techniques forhe pollutant in question, or where the EPA Administrator determines that the 40.F.R. Part 136 sampling and analytical techniques are inappropriate for theollutant in question,
      sampling and analysis shall be performed using validatednalytical methods or any other applicable sampling and analytical procedures,ncluding procedures suggested by WASA, and approved by the EPA Region IIIdministrator.</text>
    <text>Industrial Users shall collect and analyze all samples as follows:</text>
    <text>Collect grab samples for pH, cyanide, total phenols, oil and grease, sulfide,nd volatile organic compounds;</text>
    <text>Collect twenty-four (24) hour composite samples for all other pollutants,hrough flow-proportional composite sampling techniques, unless WASA authorizesime-proportional composite sampling or grab sampling;</text>
    <text>Where WASA authorizes time-proportional composite sampling or grab sampling, theamples shall be representative of the discharge and the decision to allow thelternative sampling shall be documented in the Industrial User file for thatacility or facilities;
      and</text>
    <text>Using protocols (including appropriate preservation) specified in 40 C.F.R. Part36 and appropriate EPA guidance, multiple grab samples collected during awenty-four (24) hour period may be composited prior to the analysis as follows:</text>
    <text>For cyanide, total phenols, and sulfides the samples may be composited in theaboratory or in the field;</text>
    <text>For volatile organic compounds and oil and grease the samples may be compositedn the laboratory; and</text>
    <text>Composite samples for other parameters unaffected by the compositing proceduress documented in approved EPA methodologies may be authorized by WASA, asppropriate.</text>
    <text>For sampling required in support of the Baseline Monitoring Report in § 1508.5nd ninety (90) day Compliance Report in § 1508.7, a minimum of four (4) grabamples shall be collected for pH, cyanide, total phenols, oil and grease,ulfide, and volatile
      organic compounds for facilities for which historicalampling data do not exist. For facilities for which historical sampling datare available, WASA may authorize a lower number of required grab samples.</text>
    <text>For sampling required in support of the Periodic Compliance Report in § 1508.3,ASA shall specify the number of grab samples necessary to assess and ensureompliance by Industrial Users with applicable pretreatment standards andequirements.</text>
    <text>For all Categorical Industrial Users, samples shall be collected immediatelyownstream from pretreatment facilities or from the regulated process if noretreatment exists. For all Industrial Users, sampling location(s) will bepecified in the permit
      and shall be representative of the normal dischargesccurring during the reporting period.</text>
    <text>Industrial Users shall maintain records of all information resulting from anyonitoring activities required by this chapter, including documentationssociated with Best Management Practices. The records shall include for allamples:</text>
    <text>Date, time, and place of sampling, method of sampling, preservation used, andhe names of the person or persons taking the samples;</text>
    <text>Date, time, and place where sample analyses were performed;</text>
    <text>Name of the person who performed the analyses;</text>
    <text>Analytical techniques or methods used; and</text>
    <text>Results of such analyses.</text>
    <text>Waivers to Sampling Requirements. WASA may authorize Industrial Users subject toategorical Pretreatment Standards to forego sampling of a pollutant if thendustrial User has submitted a request for a waiver and has demonstratedhrough sampling and other
      technical factors that the pollutant is neitherresent nor expected to be present in their discharge or is present only atackground levels (for example, due to the levels in their water intake) andithout any increase in the pollutant due to the activities
      of the Industrialser. All waiver requests are subject to the following conditions:</text>
    <text>A waiver may be granted if the pollutant is determined to be present solely dueo sanitary wastewater discharged from the facility provided that the sanitaryastewater is not regulated by an applicable Categorical Pretreatment Standardnd otherwise includes
      no process wastewater;</text>
    <text>The waiver shall be included in the Industrial User’s permit and is valid onlyuring the period of the permit, which in no case shall exceed five (5) years.he Industrial User shall submit a new waiver request for each permit issued;</text>
    <text>To justify the waiver request, the Industrial User shall sample their wastetream on at least two (2) separate occasions from a location that isepresentative of all wastewater from all processes prior to any treatment athe facility;</text>
    <text>All sampling shall follow the sampling and analysis requirements listed in thisection;</text>
    <text>Non-detect sample results may only be used as a determination that a pollutants not present if the EPA approved method from 40 C.F.R. Part 136 with theowest minimum detection level for that pollutant was used for the analysis;</text>
    <text>The waiver request shall include the certification statement in § 1508.10 andhall be signed in accordance with § 1508.11;</text>
    <text>Industrial Users who are granted a waiver shall certify on each Periodicompliance Report that there has been no increase in the pollutant in itsischarge using the following language:</text>
    <text>Based on my inquiry of the person or persons directly responsible for managingompliance with the Pretreatment Standard for 40 C.F.R. § __________ (specifypplicable National Pretreatment Standards), I certify that, to the best of mynowledge and belief,
      there has been no increase in the level of _________ (listhe pollutant) in the wastewater due to the activities at the facility sinceiling of the last periodic report as required under 21 DCMR § 1508;</text>
    <text>In the event that a waived pollutant is found to be present or is expected to beresent based on changes to the Industrial User’s operations, the Industrialser shall immediately notify WASA and comply with monitoring and reportingequirements listed
      in § 1508.3 or other more frequent monitoring imposed byASA; and</text>
    <text>The granting of a waiver does not supersede certification or other requirementsstablished in Categorical Pretreatment Standards.</text>
    <text>WASA may conduct sampling and analysis in lieu of or in addition to Industrialser sampling. Fees for sampling and laboratory analyses may be charged to thendustrial User.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 6194, 6200 (October 10, 1986); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 2948 (April 28, 2000); asmended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 1021, 1049 (February0, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>