<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1404</num>
  <heading>CRITERIA FOR APPROVAL (ยง 21-1404)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1404.1.</num>
    <text>A submerged aquatic vegetation removal plan may be approved by the Director only for projects which are necessary to do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Provide reasonable access to navigable waters;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Provide reasonable opportunities for water-based recreational activities; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Manage the living aquatic resources of the waters of the District.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1404.2.</num>
    <text>A submerged aquatic vegetation removal plan may be approved by the Director only if the following two (2) criteria are met to the Director&amp;#8217;s satisfaction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The duration of the proposed project is no longer than is necessary to achieve the purpose intended by this chapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The proposed project is consistent with acceptable natural resources and environmental management practices as determined by the Director.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1404.3.</num>
    <text>In determining the reasonableness of a plan submitted for approval, the Director may consider the following factors:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The purpose, timing, method and extent of the proposed removal action;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Potential impacts to the living aquatic resources in the project area such as anadromous fish, shellfish, and submerged aquatic vegetation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The method and location of disposal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The extent of overall benefit from the proposed project; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The opinions of affected property owners or others.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 1971, 1973 (April 15, 1994).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>