<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-109</num>
  <heading>REPORTS BY POLICE OFFICERS (ยง 21-109)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>109.1.</num>
    <text>It shall be the duty of all police officers to report in writing or otherwise to the Department any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Any leak, waste, or break in any water main, service pipe, meter, fire hydrant, public hydrant, drinking fountain, standpipe, horse trough, hose connection, valve, stopcock, or other water supply facility.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any valve casing, stopcock box, meter housing, lawn washer (hose connection), or similar device without a proper or secure cover or plate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any fire hydrant that has a missing operating nut or discharge outlet cap;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any accumulation of ice in public space caused by a leak or waste in the District water system;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any damage to any appurtenance or item of equipment connected to or used in connection with the District water system resulting from an accident or any other cause;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Any settlement or hazardous condition existing at any excavation or backfill in public space resulting from maintenance or repair work on the District water system;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The number and locations of buildings destroyed by fire if supplied with water; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Generally all violations of this title and such further information as may in their judgment be important.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 23, ยง8 of the Police Regulations of the District of Columbia; 12 DCRR ยง404.8 (October 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>