<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1150</num>
  <heading>GROUND WATER (ยง 21-1150)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1150.1.</num>
    <text>Sections 1150 through 1158 shall describe the following categories:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Classes of ground water within the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Establish criteria to protect the designated uses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Establish the concepts of Enforcement Standards and Early Warning Values; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Provide ground water monitoring requirements.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1150.2.</num>
    <text>Ground water in the District is not currently being used as a potable water source; however, where attainable, it shall be protected for beneficial uses, including surface water recharge, drinking water in other jurisdictions, and potential future
      use as a raw drinking water source in the District. Ground waters shall be protected from pollution because the lack of this protection might result in the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Large future cleanup costs of contaminated ground water;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Contaminated ground water becoming a potential health hazard to the public;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Contaminated ground water mixing with and contaminating adjacent surface waters;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Contaminated ground water mixing with and contaminating the ground waters of adjacent jurisdictions; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Harm to or loss of sensitive flora or fauna.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 4203 (July 2, 1993); renumbered by Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 1075 (March 4, 1994).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>