<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1508</num>
  <heading>REPORTING (§ 21-1508)
    <text>General Reporting Requirements. Industrial Users may be required to submit testesults from samples collected of their discharged wastewater or othernformation requested by WASA on a routine and continuing basis. The Industrialser shall bear the costs
      of such tests and reports.</text>
    <text>Baseline Monitoring Reports, ninety (90) Day Compliance Reports, and Periodicompliance Reports (for both Categorical and Non-Categorical Industrial Users),hall be based upon data obtained through appropriate sampling and analysiserformed during the
      period covered by the report and representative ofonditions occurring during the reporting period.</text>
    <text>Periodic Compliance Reports (applicable to all Industrial Users). The followingoverns the Periodic Compliance Reports applicable to all Industrial Users:</text>
    <text>Any Industrial User that is required to have a discharge permit and performself-monitoring shall submit Periodic Compliance Reports to WASA at a frequencypecified in the discharge permit, indicating the nature and concentration ofollutants in the
      discharge during that reporting period;</text>
    <text>At a minimum, Significant Industrial Users shall sample their discharge andubmit Periodic Compliance Reports once every six (6) months, or as WASAequires;</text>
    <text>Categorical Industrial Users (except for Non-Significant Categorical Industrialsers) shall submit reports during the months of June and December, unlessequired more frequently in the Pretreatment Standard or an alternative schedules established in
      writing by WASA; and</text>
    <text>All Periodic Compliance Reports shall include:</text>
    <text>A record of the concentrations (and mass if specified in the discharge permit)f the pollutants listed in the discharge permit that were measured and a recordf all flow measurements or the average and maximum daily flow for the reportingeriod;</text>
    <text>Documentation to demonstrate compliance with the Best Management Practices (BMP)r the average and maximum daily flow for the reporting period, in cases wherehe discharge standards are based on compliance with BMPs;</text>
    <text>Flow data, reported on the basis of actual measurement except when WASA mayllow for verifiable estimates of these flows if justified by cost oreasibility considerations;</text>
    <text>Sampling and analysis data collected at the permitted location when thendustrial User performs sampling and analysis more frequently than is requirednd follows the sampling and analysis procedures in this chapter; and</text>
    <text>The certification statement provided in § 1508.10 signed by an authorizedepresentative in accordance with § 1508.11.</text>
    <text>Reporting Violations (applicable to all Industrial Users). The followingpplies to reporting violations applicable to all Industrial Users:</text>
    <text>If sampling performed by an Industrial User exceeds an effluent limit, thendustrial User shall notify WASA within twenty-four (24) hours of becomingware of the exceedance;</text>
    <text>The Industrial User shall repeat the sampling and analysis for that parameternd submit the results of the repeat analysis to WASA within thirty (30) daysfter becoming aware of the violation; and</text>
    <text>If WASA performed the sampling and analysis in lieu of the Industrial User and aesult exceeds an effluent limit, then WASA shall perform the repeat samplingnd analysis for that parameter unless WASA requires the Industrial User toerform the repeat
      analysis.</text>
    <text>Baseline Monitoring Reports. All Categorical Industrial Users shall comply withhe following requirements for Baseline Monitoring Reports:</text>
    <text>Existing Categorical Industrial Users currently discharging to or scheduled toischarge to the District’s wastewater system shall be required to submit toASA a report which contains the information listed in paragraph (c) withinither one hundred eighty
      (180) days after the effective date of a Categoricalretreatment Standard or the final administrative decision on a categoryetermination under 40 C.F.R. § 403.6(a)(4), whichever is later;</text>
    <text>New sources and sources that become Categorical Industrial Users subsequent tohe promulgation of an applicable Categorical Pretreatment Standard shall beequired to submit to WASA a report which contains the information listed inaragraph (c) at least
      ninety (90) days prior to commencement of theirischarge. A new source shall also be required to report the methods ofretreatment it intends to use to meet applicable Categorical Pretreatmenttandards. New sources shall give estimates of anticipated
      flows and pollutantsischarged;</text>
    <text>Baseline Monitoring Reports shall include the following:</text>
    <text>The name and address of the facility, and the name of the operator and owner;</text>
    <text>A list of environmental control permits (including but limited to, hazardousaste generator permit, underground storage tank registration, and pesticideperator license) held by the facility;</text>
    <text>A brief description of the nature of the industrial processes or operations,verage rate of production, and North American Industrial Classification Systemr Standard Industrial Classification of the operation(s) carried out by thendustrial User. This
      description should include a schematic process diagramhich indicates points of discharge to the District’s wastewater system fromhe regulated processes;</text>
    <text>Measured average daily flow and the maximum daily flow in gallons per day forach of the regulated process streams and any other streams, as necessary, tollow use of the combined waste stream formula set out in 40 C.F.R. § 403.6(e).WASA may allow for
      verifiable estimates of these flows where justified by costr feasibility considerations;</text>
    <text>The Categorical Pretreatment Standards applicable to each regulated process, ifnown;</text>
    <text>The results of sampling and analysis of at least one (1) representative sampledentifying the nature and concentration (and/or mass where required by theretreatment Standard or WASA) of regulated pollutants in the discharge fromach regulated process,
      which shall comply with the following:</text>
    <text>Both daily maximum and daily average concentrations (or mass, where required)hall be reported; and</text>
    <text>The sample shall be representative of daily operations and collected andnalyzed in accordance with procedures listed in § 1507.6;</text>
    <text>The time, date, and place of sampling;</text>
    <text>Methods of analysis; and</text>
    <text>Certification that sampling and analysis is representative of normal work cyclesnd expected pollutant discharges to the District’s wastewater system;</text>
    <text>In cases where the Pretreatment Standard requires compliance with a Bestanagement Practice or pollution prevention alternative, the Industrial Userhall submit documentation as required by WASA or the applicable Standards toetermine compliance with
      the Standard;</text>
    <text>Certification. A statement reviewed by the Industrial User’s authorizedepresentative and certified to by a qualified professional, indicating whetherretreatment standards are being met on a consistent basis, and, if not, whetherdditional Operation
      and Maintenance (O&amp;#038;M) and/or additional pretreatment,s required to meet the pretreatment standards and requirements;</text>
    <text>Compliance schedule. If additional pretreatment and/or O&amp;#038;M is required toeet the pretreatment standards, the shortest schedule by which the Industrialser will provide such additional pretreatment and/or O&amp;#038;M. The completionate in
      this schedule shall not be later than the compliance date establishedor the applicable pretreatment standard. A compliance schedule pursuant tohis section shall meet the requirements set out in 40 C.F.R. § 403.12 (c); and</text>
    <text>All baseline monitoring reports shall include the certification statementrovided in § 1508.10 and shall be signed by an authorized representative inccordance with § 1508.11.</text>
    <text>Compliance Schedule Progress Reports (applicable to Industrial Users subject to compliance schedule). Not later than fourteen (14) days following each daten a schedule and the final date for compliance, the Industrial User shallubmit a progress report
      to WASA including, at a minimum, whether or not thendustrial User complied with the compliance deadlines and, if not, the date onhich the Industrial User expects to comply with the compliance deadlines, theeason for delay, and the steps being taken
      by the Industrial User to return tohe established compliance schedule. In no event shall more than nine (9)onths elapse between such progress reports to WASA.</text>
    <text>Ninety (90) Day Compliance Reports shall be submitted under the followingonditions:</text>
    <text>Final Compliance Reports shall be submitted by existing Industrial Users withininety (90) days following the date for final compliance with the applicableretreatment standards in a compliance schedule;</text>
    <text>Final Compliance Reports shall be submitted by Categorical Industrial Usersithin ninety (90) days following the date for final compliance with thepplicable Categorical Pretreatment Standards;</text>
    <text>Initial Compliance Reports shall be submitted by New Source Categoricalndustrial Users within ninety (90) days following commencement of the dischargeo the District’s wastewater system; and</text>
    <text>Both the ninety (90) Day Final and Initial Compliance Reports shall include thenformation described in § 1508.5(c)(4) – (11).</text>
    <text>Pretreatment Facilities Operation and Maintenance Certification. In addition tohe certification requirements associated with the discharge monitoring reports,ASA may request that Industrial Users submit a list of their pretreatmentacilities and a
      certification stating that their pretreatment facilities areeing properly operated and maintained. If WASA makes the request, theollowing certification statement shall be signed by an authorizedepresentative in accordance with § 1508.11 and submitted
      to WASA:</text>
    <text>Based on my inquiry of the person or persons directly responsible for operatingnd maintaining the pretreatment facilities, I certify under penalty of lawhat, to the best of my knowledge and belief that during the period fromspecify month, day, year]
      to [specify month, day, year], the facility describeds [specify facility name] located at [provide address] has properly operatednd maintained all pretreatment facilities in accordance with manufacturers’ecommendations and District and WASA regulations.
      This certification is basedn the following information: [provide supporting documentation that maynclude, but is not limited to, the following: operating logs; cleaning,nspection, and/or maintenance records; preventive maintenance work orders;quipment
      calibration records; and equipment repair or replacement records]. Im aware that there are significant penalties for submitting false information,ncluding the possibility of having to pay a fine and imprisonment for knowinglyoing so.</text>
    <text>Annual Certification by Non-Significant Categorical Industrial Users. Aacility determined to be a Non-Significant Categorical Industrial User pursuanto 40 C.F.R. § 403.3(v)(2) shall annually submit the following certificationtatement, signed by an
      authorized representative in accordance with § 1508.11:</text>
    <text>Based on my inquiry of the person or persons directly responsible for managingompliance with the Categorical Pretreatment Standards under 40 C.F.R. Parts05-471 [specify applicable section], I certify under penalty of law that, tohe best of my knowledge
      and belief that during the period from [specify month,ay, year] to [specify month, day, year]: (a) The facility described asspecify facility name] located at [provide address] met the definition of aon-Significant Categorical Industrial User as
      described in 40 C.F.R. §03.3(v)(2); (b) the facility complied with all applicable pretreatmenttandards and requirements during this period; and (c) the facility neverischarged more than 100 gallons of total categorical wastewater on any givenay
      during this reporting period. This compliance certification is based on theollowing information [provide supporting documentation]. I am aware that therere significant penalties for submitting false information, including theossibility of having
      to pay a fine and imprisonment for knowingly doing so.</text>
    <text>General Certification Statement. Industrial Users shall include the followingertification statement in the submission of all applications, reports, waiverequests, notices to WASA (except for Pretreatment Facilities Operation andaintenance Certification,
      and annual certification by Non-Significantategorical Industrial Users):</text>
    <text>I certify under penalty of law that this document and all attachments wererepared under my direction or supervision in accordance with a system designedo assure that qualified personnel properly gather and evaluate the informationubmitted. Based on
      my inquiry of the person or persons who manage the system,r those persons directly responsible for gathering the information, thenformation submitted is, to the best of my knowledge and belief, true,ccurate, and complete. I am aware that there are
      significant penalties forubmitting false information, including the possibility of having to pay a finend imprisonment for knowing violations.</text>
    <text>Signature Requirements. All applications, reports, certifications, and noticeshall be signed as follows:</text>
    <text>By a responsible corporate officer, if the Industrial User is a corporation;</text>
    <text>By a general partner or proprietor if the Industrial User is a partnership orole proprietorship, respectively;</text>
    <text>By a duly authorized representative of the individual designated in paragraphsa) and (b) of this subsection if:</text>
    <text>The authorization is made in writing by the individual described in paragraphsa) or (b);</text>
    <text>The authorization specifies either an individual or a position havingesponsibility for the overall operation of the facility from which thendustrial discharge originates, such as the position of plant manager, generalanager, facility manager, operator
      of a well, or well field superintendent, or position of equivalent responsibility, or having overall responsibility fornvironmental matters for the company; and</text>
    <text>The written authorization is submitted to WASA; and</text>
    <text>If an authorization under paragraph (c) of this subsection is no longer accurateecause a different individual or position has responsibility for the overallperation of the facility, or overall responsibility for environmental mattersor the company,
      a new authorization satisfying the requirements of paragraphc) of this subsection shall be submitted to WASA prior to or together with anyeports to be signed by an authorized representative.</text>
    <text>A written report or certification received by WASA after a specified due datehall be deemed a late report or certification and the Industrial User shall beubject to enforcement action in accordance with § 1513.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>WASA may allow historical data to be used if information is sufficient toetermine the need for industrial pretreatment measures. Submitted data shallnclude</heading>
      <text />
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 6194, 6201 (October 10, 1986); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 2948 (April 28, 2000); asmended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 1021, 1052 (February0, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>