<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1513</num>
  <heading>ADMINISTRATIVE ENFORCEMENT REMEDIES (§ 21-1513)
    <text>When WASA finds or suspects that a User’s discharge has a potential to violateny provision of the Act or this chapter, an individual wastewater dischargeermit, order issued hereunder, or any other Pretreatment Standard orequirement, WASA may issue
      that User a written Notice of Warning which shallnclude:</text>
    <text>Date and location of the potential violation, if applicable;</text>
    <text>Pretreatment standard or requirement potentially violated; and</text>
    <text>Recommended actions to prevent a violation.</text>
    <text>When WASA finds or suspects that a User’s discharge has a potential to violateny provision of the Act or this chapter, an individual wastewater dischargeermit, order issued hereunder, or any other Pretreatment Standard orequirement, WASA may issue
      that User a written Directive Letter which shallnclude:</text>
    <text>Date and location of the potential violation, if applicable;</text>
    <text>Pretreatment standard or requirement potentially violated; and</text>
    <text>Follow-up monitoring, corrective action, or other response requirements.</text>
    <text>When WASA finds that a User’s discharge violated, or continues to violate, anyrovision of the Act or this chapter, an individual wastewater discharge permit,r order issued hereunder, or any other Pretreatment Standard or requirement,ASA may issue
      that User a written Notice of Violation which shall include:</text>
    <text>Date and location of the violation;</text>
    <text>Pretreatment standard or requirement violated and the concentration in theastewater discharge, if applicable; and</text>
    <text>Follow-up monitoring, corrective action, or other response requirements.</text>
    <text>Within fourteen (14) calendar days of the receipt of the Notice of Violation ors specified by WASA, the User shall submit to WASA an explanation of theiolation and a corrective action plan for the satisfactory correction andrevention thereof, to include
      specific required actions. Submission of such aorrective action plan in no way relieves the User of liability for anyiolations occurring before or after receipt of the Notice of Violation. Nothingn this chapter shall limit the authority of WASA
      to take any action, includingmergency actions or any other enforcement action, without first issuing aotice of Violation.</text>
    <text>WASA may require any User to submit for approval a detailed time schedule forpecific actions which the User shall implement in order to either prevent aischarge, or to correct a source or cause of the violation. WASA may modifyuch time schedule as
      appropriate prior to approval. WASA may require suchotification as necessary to carry out the purposes of the Act and this chapter.</text>
    <text>Whenever WASA has reason to believe that a User is violating the Act, or thishapter, WASA may issue a Notice of Infraction and Proposed Order as set forthn §§ 1513 and 1514.</text>
    <text>The Notice of Infraction shall include the following:</text>
    <text>The nature, time, and place of the violation (with reasonable specificity);</text>
    <text>The corrective or remedial action to be taken and any fines imposed or othermounts sought in accordance with this chapter;</text>
    <text>The date upon which the Proposed Order shall become effective; and</text>
    <text>The procedure by which a User may answer a Notice of Infraction and Proposedrder and request a hearing, along with notification that failure to answer mayead to the adoption of some or all of the Proposed Order.</text>
    <text>The Proposed Order may direct the User to do the following:</text>
    <text>Eliminate the violation;</text>
    <text>Comply with the provisions of this chapter;</text>
    <text>Take specific actions to avoid future violations;</text>
    <text>Pay fines, costs, or other amounts, as authorized by this chapter; and</text>
    <text>Comply with the schedule for completion of any of the directives of the Proposedrder.</text>
    <text>The Proposed Order may provide for the suspension or revocation of any permitssued by WASA pursuant to this subchapter, or the suspension or revocation ofny contract or agreement between the User and WASA, to the extent that suchermit, contract, or
      agreement authorizes the User to discharge into theistrict&amp;#8217;s wastewater system.</text>
    <text>In the event of an actual or threatened discharge to the District&amp;#8217;sastewater system which, in the sole discretion of WASA, reasonably appears toresent an imminent danger to the health or welfare of persons, WASA may, afternformal notice
      to the discharger, suspend water service to any User who is oray be responsible for the discharge as is necessary to avoid or abate theanger. WASA is not required to conduct a hearing before taking such action.</text>
    <text>In the event of an actual or threatened discharge to the District&amp;#8217;sastewater system which, in the sole discretion of WASA, reasonably appears toresent an imminent danger to the environment or the operation or integrity ofhe District&amp;#8217;s
      wastewater system, WASA may, after providing notice and anpportunity to respond to the User, suspend water service to any User who is oray be responsible for the discharge as is necessary to avoid or abate theanger.</text>
    <text>A User notified of a suspension of its discharge shall immediately stop orliminate the discharge. In the event of a User’s failure to immediatelyomply voluntarily with the notice of suspension, WASA may, in addition touspending water service, take
      such steps as deemed necessary, includingmmediate severance of the sewer connection, to prevent or minimize damage tohe District’s wastewater system, its receiving stream, or endangerment to anyndividuals.</text>
    <text>Any notice or opportunity to respond to which WASA is required under the Unitedtates Constitution to provide to a User as a result of any action taken by WASAursuant to § 1513.9 or § 1513.10, is not required to be provided or conductedursuant to subchapter
      I of chapter 5 of title 2 of the District of Columbiafficial Code.</text>
    <text>WASA&amp;#8217;s decision to suspend service may be appealed as set forth in § 1519y filing a petition for an administrative hearing within fifteen (15) calendarays of the date of the notice of suspension as set forth in 21 DCMR § 412.3.</text>
    <text>The filing of an appeal of WASA&amp;#8217;s decision shall not stay suspension orermination of service.</text>
    <text>WASA shall restore the water service and allow the User to recommence itsischarge as soon as practical after the emergency situation has been correctednd the User has demonstrated to the satisfaction of WASA that the period ofndangerment has passed,
      unless WASA has terminated the Users permit.</text>
    <text>The permit of any User who violated the Act, any provision of this chapter orpplicable federal law or regulations may be revoked.</text>
    <text>WASA may immediately revoke any Wastewater Discharge Permit in any case in which violation of any provision of the Act or this chapter is known or found toxist or where a discharge or wastewater causes or threatens to cause aondition of interference,
      pollution, or nuisance as defined in this chapter.evocation of a permit alone is sufficient grounds for termination of waterervice.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 6194, 6202 (October 10, 1986); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 2948 (April 28, 2000); asmended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 1021, 1071 (February0, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>