<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1108</num>
  <heading>RIVERS (§ 21-1108)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1108.1.</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, primary contact recreation shall be prohibited in the Potomac and Anacostia Rivers and Rock Creek until such time as the standards in § 1104.8 for Class A beneficial use are consistently maintained.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.2.</num>
    <text>The Director may issue a decision that allows a special swimming event in the Potomac River, if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A study conducted by the special swimming event organizer shows that the numeric criteria for Class A listed in §1104.8 are being attained; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The other provisions of this section have been satisfied.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.3.</num>
    <text>The study required by § 1108.2 shall be conducted as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>At least twenty-eight (28) days before collecting samples, the special swimming event organizer shall submit to the District Department of the Environment (the Department) for review and approval a quality assurance project plan (QAPP) that shall
        be prepared and implemented by a qualified professional environmental monitoring firm in accordance with:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“EPA Requirements for Quality Management Plans (QA/R-2),” (EPA/240/B-01/002, March 2001 or subsequently issued guidance); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Equivalent documentation as determined by the United States Environmental Protection Agency (US EPA);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Samples shall not be collected before the QAPP is approved;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>All samples shall be collected as required in the approved QAPP;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Samples for Escherichia coli (E. coli), pH, and turbidity shall be collected and analyzed according to US EPA regulation 40 CFR Part 136;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The qualifications of each person undertaking the sample collection and analysis for the special swimming event organizer shall be subject to the Department&amp;#8217;s review, for verification that the person meets minimum technical background
        and experience requirements; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The laboratory conducting the sample analysis shall:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be capable of providing complete environmental analytical services, consistent with US EPA protocols, and according to a Laboratory Quality Management Plan; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Be accredited or certified to perform the analysis, including the specific methods identified in the QAPP.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.4.</num>
    <text>The study and report of the sample analysis shall be submitted to the Department at least forty-eight (48) hours before a scheduled special swimming event.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.5.</num>
    <text>Failure to submit the study and report by the deadline will result in the Director&amp;#8217;s denial of authorization for the special swimming event.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.6.</num>
    <text>The study and report shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Each completed chain of custody form and lab report;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An assessment of whether the water quality criteria for Class A in 21 DCMR § 1104 have been attained; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An evaluation of each relevant factor, including:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Rainfall;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Upstream sewage or chemical releases; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Other environmental conditions that may affect the water quality.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.7.</num>
    <text>The Director shall deny permission to swim in the Potomac River if the results of the study or the Director&amp;#8217;s independent investigation indicate:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The water quality standards are not being attained;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An emergency health hazard caused by a hazardous pollutant or condition has occurred; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>There may be a health risk from a known pollution source, including:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Combined sewer overflow;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Failing sewer infrastructure;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Chemical release; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Wastewater treatment discharge.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.8.</num>
    <text>At least twenty-eight (28) days before a special swimming event, the special swimming event organizer shall submit to the Director verification that a Certificate of Insurance, or other proof of coverage, that has been signed by an authorized representative
      of the insurer, has been provided to each appropriate permitting agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.9.</num>
    <text>The Director shall not authorize the special swimming event unless the verification is submitted to the Director in the time required by § 1108.8.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.10.</num>
    <text>The special swimming event organizer’s verification shall state in writing that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The special swimming event organizer has obtained the following coverage for the event period, and the amount of coverage, if any, for each of the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Comprehensive coverage;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Bodily injury liability coverage;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the owner of a vehicle, including a boat, liability coverage for use of the vehicle;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Workers&amp;#8217; compensation insurance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Coverage of the District as an additional insured;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Each insurance policy is written with a responsible company licensed by the District; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Each insurance policy provides for at least twenty-eight (28) days’ written notice to the District prior to termination or material alteration.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.11.</num>
    <text>If an approval required by this section is denied, canceled, not renewed, or materially altered, a special swimming event organizer shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Notify the Director immediately by phone and email; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Confirm to the Director by letter and fax within twenty-four (24) hours.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.12.</num>
    <text>Upon receiving notice of a material change in a required approval, the Director may rescind authorization for the special swimming event.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.13.</num>
    <text>As a condition of event authorization, the special swimming event organizer shall secure from each employee, contractor, and volunteer of the special swimming event organization and from each participant a signed, Department-approved statement that
      expressly:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Assumes the risk of event participation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Waives liability of the District Government, its officers, employees, and agents for any damage or injury arising out of the person’s participation in the event.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.14.</num>
    <text>The special swimming event organizer shall take each step which:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Director deems necessary to ensure that the requirements of this section are satisfied; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Shall include presenting each required report or form to the Director within twenty-eight (28) days after the event.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.15.</num>
    <text>The special swimming event organizer shall pay a fee of one thousand dollars ($1,000) per event for the costs the Department incurs, including review and approval or denial of the QAPP and other submittals.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.16.</num>
    <text>Payment of the fee shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Occur by the time the application is submitted; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be a precondition for review of the QAPP, related studies, and other submittals.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.17.</num>
    <text>The special swimming event organizer shall provide to the Director at least seven (7) days in advance of the special swimming event documentation showing:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Coordination with each relevant public safety agency; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A contingency plan for the special swimming event in the circumstance that either the Director or the special swimming event organizer determines that swimming would not be safe.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.18.</num>
    <text>The special swimming event organizer shall provide to the Director within fifty-six (56) days (eight weeks) after the special swimming event a report of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Each recorded incident from each relevant public safety agency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Each medical issue or incident involving an on-site first aid facility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Use of the contingency plan for unsafe swimming; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Sampling of each event day’s water at the event site, and the subsequent testing of each sample.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.19.</num>
    <text>With respect to this section, a person adversely affected or aggrieved by an action of the Department shall exhaust administrative remedies by timely filing an administrative appeal with, and requesting a hearing before, the Office of Administrative
      Hearings (OAH), in accordance with the Office of Administrative Hearings Establishment Act of 2001, effective March 6, 2002 (D.C. Law 14-76; D.C. Official Code, §§ 21831.01 et seq. (2007 Repl. &amp;#038; 2011 Supp.)), as amended, and OAH’s rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.20.</num>
    <text>The following general rules apply to this section:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A person who is regulated pursuant to this section may empower an agent to act for that person; however, empowering an agent does not change or eliminate that person’s duty, responsibility, or liability; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The special swimming event organizer shall, if not a natural person, be represented by an officer, chief executive, or other responsible natural person, who shall:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Sign and certify each application and report; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Take responsibility for the duties and conduct of the special swimming event organizer.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 9470, 9471 (August 10, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>