<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1002</num>
  <heading>DISPOSABLE CARRYOUT BAG MATERIAL AND LABELING REQUIREMENTS (§ 21-1002)
    <text>Starting on April 1, 2010, each disposable carryout bag provided by a retailstablishment shall meet the following requirements:</text>
    <text>All paper and plastic disposable carryout bags provided shall be one</text>
    <text>hundred percent (100%) recyclable;</text>
    <text>All paper and plastic disposable carryout bags shall display in a highly</text>
    <text>visible manner the phrase “Please Recycle This Bag”, or a substantiallyimilar phrase. The lettering of the phrase shall meet the followingequirements:</text>
    <text>The lettering of the phrase shall be at least one half of an inch (0.5″) ineight or at least seventy-five percent (75%) of the width of the front panel ofhe bag;</text>
    <text>The lettering of the recycling statement shall appear on the exterior of eitherhe front or back panel of the bag, and not on a gusset or the base of the bag;nd</text>
    <text>The lettering of the recycling statement shall be in a boldface font.</text>
    <text>A disposable carryout bag made of paper shall contain a minimum of forty</text>
    <text>percent (40%) post-consumer recycled content; and</text>
    <text>A disposable carryout bag made of plastic shall be made of high-density</text>
    <text>polyethylene film marked with the SPI resin identification code 2, orow-density polyethylene film marked with the SPI resin identification code 4.</text>
    <text>A disposable carryout bag shall meet the requirements of this section, even ifhe bag is biodegradable or compostable.</text>
    <text>A disposable carryout bag made of both plastic and paper shall meet the paperarryout bag requirements of this section for the paper components of the bag,nd shall meet the plastic carryout requirements of this section for the plasticomponents of the
      bag.</text>
    <text>Source: Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 7208, 7209 (August 13, 2010).</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>