<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1504</num>
  <heading>PERMIT APPLICATIONS FOR INDUSTRIAL USERS WITHIN THE DISTRICT (§ 21-1504)
    <text>WASA may require persons to complete and submit to WASA a questionnaire for theurpose of determining which Users need to submit a permit application. Thisuestionnaire shall be completed and returned within fifteen (15) days ofeceipt or as stated on
      the questionnaire. Based on the information provided inesponse to the questionnaire, WASA may request the User to submit a permitpplication.</text>
    <text>Each new Significant Industrial User located within the District proposing toirectly or indirectly discharge into the District’s wastewater system shallpply for a Wastewater Discharge Permit at least ninety (90) days beforeonnecting to, or discharging
      into, the wastewater system.</text>
    <text>Each new Non-Significant Non-Categorical Industrial User located within theistrict proposing to directly or indirectly discharge into the wastewaterystem of the District shall apply for a Wastewater Discharge Permit at leastinety (90) days before
      connecting to, or discharging into, the wastewaterystem if they know or have reason to know that their discharges exceed theistrict’s Pretreatment Standards.</text>
    <text>All existing Significant Industrial Users located within the District that doot have a current Wastewater Discharge Permit and are directly or indirectlyischarging into the wastewater system of the District shall immediately applyor a Wastewater Discharge
      Permit.</text>
    <text>All existing Non-Significant Non-Categorical Industrial Users located within theistrict that do not have a current Wastewater Discharge Permit and are directlyr indirectly discharging into the District’s wastewater system shallmmediately apply for
      a Wastewater Discharge Permit if they know or have reasono know that their discharges exceed the District’s Pretreatment Standards.</text>
    <text>Applications for Wastewater Discharge Permits shall contain at least theollowing:</text>
    <text>Name, address, office telephone number, and Standard Industrial Classificationr North American Industry Classification System number(s) of applicant;</text>
    <text>A list of any environmental permits held by or for the facility;</text>
    <text>Volume of wastewater to be discharged expressed in gallons per day. Forategorical Industrial Users, the volume of wastewater from each regulated oranufacturing process stream is required and other streams as necessary to allowse of the combined wastestream
      formula;</text>
    <text>Time and duration of discharge;</text>
    <text>Average and thirty (30) minute peak wastewater flow rates, including daily,onthly and seasonal variations, if any;</text>
    <text>The results of sampling and analysis identifying the nature and concentrationnd/or mass, where required by a Categorical Standard, of regulated pollutantsn the discharge from each regulated process, including the parameters listed inable I in § 1501.8,
      biochemical oxygen demand, total suspended solids, totalitrogen, total phosphorus, and pH. The sample shall be representative of dailyperations and shall be analyzed in accordance with procedures outlined in §507;</text>
    <text>For Categorical Industrial Users, the categorical pretreatment standardspplicable to each regulated process and any new categorically regulatedrocesses for Existing Sources;</text>
    <text>Ground plan or plat that indicates locations of building sewers, buildingrains, process waste sewers, monitoring and pretreatment facilities, buildings,roperty lines, adjacent streets and sewers, and industrial processacilities’</text>
    <text>Description of activities, facilities and plant processes on or proposed at theremises, including all materials and types of materials which are or could beischarged to the wastewater system;</text>
    <text>Each product produced or to be produced by type, amount, and chemicalomposition;</text>
    <text>Number of employees and hours of work;</text>
    <text>For a corporation, the State of incorporation, address of the corporate office,ames and titles of corporate officers and the name and address of theegistered agent in the District;</text>
    <text>Any other information which WASA deems to be necessary to evaluate the permitpplication including, but not limited to, any information required bypplicable federal laws and regulations;</text>
    <text>Any requests for a monitoring waiver (or a renewal of an approved monitoringaiver) for a pollutant neither present nor expected to be present in theischarge based on § 1507.11;</text>
    <text>Any request to be covered by a general permit based on § 1504.10; and</text>
    <text>Certification statement provided in § 1508.10 and with the signature of anuthorized representative in accordance with § 1508.11.</text>
    <text>Request any additional sampling and analytical testing of the wastewaterharacteristics;</text>
    <text>Perform a site inspection of the waste discharge system, pretreatment systems,r other systems;</text>
    <text>Request additional process or treatment system information or any othernformation as necessary for WASA to evaluate the permit application; or</text>
    <text>Return incomplete or inaccurate applications to the User for revision.</text>
    <text>After evaluation of the data furnished, WASA may:</text>
    <text>Determine that a Wastewater Discharge Permit is not required;</text>
    <text>Deny any application for a Wastewater Discharge Permit; or</text>
    <text>Determine that a permit is required and issue an invoice for the applicableastewater Discharge Permit fee as provided in chapter 1 of this title. Uponayment, WASA shall issue a Wastewater Discharge Permit subject to terms andonditions provided in
      the Wastewater Discharge Permit.</text>
    <text>Significant Categorical Industrial User Permits – Issued to Industrial Usershat are subject to Categorical Pretreatment Standards, and at any time</text>
    <text>discharge more than one hundred gallons per day (100 gal./day) of totalategorical wastewater excluding sanitary, non-contact cooling and boilerlowdown wastewater unless specifically included in the pretreatment standard;</text>
    <text>Significant Non-Categorical Industrial User Permits – Issued to Industrialsers that are not subject to Categorical Pretreatment Standards, and dischargen average of twenty-five thousand gallons per day (25,000 gal./day) or more ofrocess wastewater
      to the District’s wastewater system (excluding sanitary,on-contact cooling and boiler blowdown wastewater), or contribute more thanive percent (5%) of hydraulic or organic loading to the Blue Plains WWTP, orASA has determined that the industrial
      User has a reasonable potential todversely affect the operation of Blue Plains, violate any pretreatment standardr requirement, harm the environment, or cause a threat to wastewater utilityersonnel;</text>
    <text>Non-Significant Categorical Industrial User Permit – Issued to Industrialsers that are subject to Categorical Pretreatment Standards, never dischargeore than one hundred gallons per day (100 gal./day) of categorical wastewaterexcluding sanitary, non-contact
      cooling and boiler blowdown wastewater, unlesspecifically included in the pretreatment standard), and meet the three (3)onditions provided in the definition for Non-Significant Categorical Industrialser in § 1599;</text>
    <text>Non-Significant Non-Categorical Industrial User Permit – Issued to Industrialsers that are not subject to Categorical Pretreatment Standards, discharge lesshan twenty-five gallons per day (25,000 gal./day) of process wastewater, andpecifically designated
      by WASA due to type of business, characteristics of theischarge, or presence of pretreatment facilities; and</text>
    <text>General Permit – Industrial Users that have a process that is acceptable for aeneral permit, as established by WASA in accordance with 40 C.F.R. §03.8(f)(1)(iii)(A) and 21 DCMR § 1504.10.</text>
    <text>At the discretion of WASA, general permits may be used to control Significant oron-Significant Industrial User discharges if the following conditions are met.</text>
    <text>General permits shall cover facilities that:</text>
    <text>Involve the same or substantially similar types of operations;</text>
    <text>Discharge the same type of wastes;</text>
    <text>Require the same effluent limitations;</text>
    <text>Require the same or similar monitoring; and</text>
    <text>In the opinion of the General Manager, are more appropriately controlled under aeneral permit than under individual wastewater discharge permits.</text>
    <text>Industrial User’s seeking coverage under a general permit shall not be subjecto production-based Categorical Pretreatment Standards or Categoricalretreatment Standards expressed as mass of pollutant discharged per day or forndustrial Users whose limits
      are based on the Combined Wastestream Formula.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>WASA may, at any time</heading>
      <text />
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>WASA may issue the following types of Wastewater Discharge Permits</heading>
      <text />
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 6194, 6196 (October 10, 1986); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 2948 (April 28, 2000); asmended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 1021, 1040 (February0, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>