<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1300</num>
  <heading>PURPOSE AND SCOPE (§ 21-1300)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1300.1.</num>
    <text>This chapter shall establish the procedures for issuing grants to universities and institutions pursuant to §13 of D.C. Law 5-188, the &amp;#8220;Water Pollution Control Act of 1984.&amp;#8221;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1300.2.</num>
    <text>This chapter shall exclude commercial companies which operate on a profit basis. The Director may give preference to District of Columbia based universities and institutions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1300.3.</num>
    <text>The Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs (DCRA) may issue grants to universities and institutions for research, investigations or studies in the following areas:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Water quality surveys and assessments; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Living aquatic resources, including fish, shellfish and aquatic vegetation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1300.4.</num>
    <text>The Director of the Department of Public Works (DPW) may issue grants to universities and institutions for research, investigations or studies in the following areas:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Operation and maintenance of water and sewer systems;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Wastewater treatment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Water quality improvement; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Construction and monitoring of public facilities designed to improve water quality.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1300.5.</num>
    <text>The Director of DCRA shall maintain a list of universities and institutions which have expertise in the areas identified in § 1300.3.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1300.6.</num>
    <text>The Director of DPW shall maintain a list of universities and institutions which have expertise in the areas identified in §1300.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1300.7.</num>
    <text>The Director of DCRA or the Director of DPW may give written notice of the availability of grant funds directly to the institutions, or by publication in local papers. The notification shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A brief description of the project or projects for which funds may be available;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The estimated total funds available;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The deadline for submission of a preliminary proposal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A statement concerning the source of funds;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>An address within the appropriate Department where detailed information may be obtained; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The estimated time of availability of the funds.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is §13 of the Water Pollution Control Act of 1984, D.C. Law 5-188, D.C. Code §6-932 (1995 Repl. Vol.), and Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order No. 87-278 dated December 11, 1987.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3528 (May 13, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>