<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1512</num>
  <heading>RECORDKEEPING AND CONFIDENTIALITY (§ 21-1512)
    <text>All Users shall retain, preserve, and make available for inspection and copyingy the District, WASA, or EPA any records, books, documents, memoranda, reports,orrespondence, and any summaries of these materials relating to testing,nternal or external
      monitoring, sampling, investigative, and chemical analysesade by or on behalf of a User in connection with its discharge (whether suchonitoring is required by this chapter), and documentation associated with itsest Management Practices pursuant
      to this chapter, for no less than three (3)ears from the date of preparation, drafting, or memorialization. Permits shalle maintained for three (3) years from the date of expiration.</text>
    <text>Notwithstanding § 1512.1, the User shall retain and preserve all records whichertain or may pertain to matters which are the subject of enforcement oritigation activities or proceedings initiated by the District, WASA, or EPAntil such enforcement
      activities have concluded and all periods of appeal havexpired.</text>
    <text>Users shall make such records available for inspection and copying by theistrict, WASA or EPA and shall submit any or all of the information describedn § 1512.1 and 1512.2 to WASA, the District or EPA upon demand and as requiredn the Wastewater Discharge
      Permit.</text>
    <text>User information and data provided to WASA shall be available to the public oro any government agencies in accordance with section 10 of the Wastewaterystem Regulation Amendment Act of 1985 (D.C. Law 6-95; D.C. Official Code §-105.09 (2008 Repl. &amp;#038;
      2011 Supp.)).</text>
    <text>Information and data, which would disclose trade secrets or secret processes,hall be withheld from public inspection as provided in section 10 of the Act,.C. Official Code § 8-105.09 (2008 Repl. &amp;#038; 2011 Supp.)).</text>
    <text>In accordance with 40 C.F.R. Part 2, any information submitted to WASA may belaimed as confidential by the submitter.</text>
    <text>The claim for confidentiality shall be asserted at the time of submission in theanner prescribed on the application form or instructions, or, in the case ofther submissions, by stamping the words “confidential business information”n each page containing
      such information.</text>
    <text>If no claim of confidentiality is made at the time of submission, WASA may makehe information available to the public without further notice.</text>
    <text>If a claim is asserted, the information will be treated in accordance with therocedures in 40 C.F.R. Part 2.</text>
    <text>Effluent data, as defined in 40 C.F.R. § 2.302, which is provided to WASA shalle available to the public without restriction.</text>
    <text>All other information which is submitted to WASA shall be available to theublic at least to the extent provided by 40 C.F.R. § 2.302.</text>
    <text>Information accepted by the Mayor or WASA as confidential shall not beransmitted to any governmental agency, except EPA as provided in D.C. Officialode § 8-105.09 (2008 Repl. &amp;#038; 2011 Supp.), unless written notification isent to the User at
      least ten (10) days before transmitting the information.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 6194, 6202 (October 10, 1986); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 2948 (April 28, 2000); asmended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 1021, 1069 (February4, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>