<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1501</num>
  <heading>DISCHARGE STANDARDS AND SEWER USE REQUIREMENTS (§ 21-1501)
    <text>It shall be unlawful to discharge into the wastewater system of the Districtxcept in accordance with this chapter.</text>
    <text>General Prohibitions. A User shall not introduce into the District’sastewater system any pollutant which causes pass through or interference. Theseeneral prohibitions and the specific prohibitions in § 1501.4 apply to anyser introducing pollutants
      into the District’s wastewater system whether orot the User is subject to National Pretreatment Standards or National, State,istrict or local pretreatment standards or requirements.</text>
    <text>Affirmative Defenses. A User shall have an affirmative defense in any actionrought against it alleging a violation of the general prohibitions establishedn § 1501.2 and the specific prohibitions in § 1501.4(c)-(g) where the Useran demonstrate that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>It did not know or have reason to know that its discharge, alone or inonjunction with a discharge or discharges from other sources, would cause passhrough or interference; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>One (1) of the following conditions:</text>
    </level>
    <text>A local limit designed to prevent pass through and/or interference, as the caseay be, was developed in accordance with paragraph 40 C.F.R. § 403.5(c) forach pollutant in the User&amp;#8217;s discharge that caused pass through ornterference, and the
      User was in compliance with each such local limit directlyrior to and during the pass through or interference; or</text>
    <text>If a local limit designed to prevent pass through and/or interference, as thease may be, has not been developed in accordance with 40 C.F.R. § 403.5(c) forhe pollutant(s) that caused the pass through or interference, the User&amp;#8217;sischarge directly
      prior to and during the pass through or interference did nothange substantially in nature or constituents from the User&amp;#8217;s priorischarge activity when WASA was regularly in compliance with WASA&amp;#8217;sational Pollutant Discharge Elimination
      System (NPDES) permit requirements and,n the case of interference, applicable requirements for beneficial reuse ofiosolids.</text>
    <text>Specific Prohibitions: No User shall introduce the following pollutants into theistrict’s wastewater system:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Pollutants which create a fire or explosion hazard in the District&amp;#8217;sastewater system, including, but not limited to:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Waste streams with a closed-cup flashpoint of less than one hundred fortyegrees Fahrenheit (140° F) or sixty degrees Centigrade (60° C) using testethods specified in 40 C.F.R. Chapter I, Subchapter N, Part 261.21;</text>
    <text>Waste streams causing two (2) readings on an explosion hazard meter at the pointf discharge into the District’s wastewater system, or at any point in theistrict’s wastewater system, of more than five percent (5%) or any singleeading over ten percent
      (10%) of the Lower Explosive Limit of the meter;</text>
    <text>Any liquids, solids, or gases, which by reason of their nature or quantity are,r may be, sufficient either alone or by interaction with other substances toreate fire or explosion or to injure in any other way the wastewater system orhe process or
      operation and maintenance of the wastewater system;</text>
    <text>Gasoline;</text>
    <text>Kerosene;</text>
    <text>Naphtha;</text>
    <text>Ethers;</text>
    <text>Alcohols;</text>
    <text>Ketones;</text>
    <text>Aldehydes;</text>
    <text>Peroxides;</text>
    <text>Chlorates;</text>
    <text>Perchlorates;</text>
    <text>Bromates;</text>
    <text>Carbides;</text>
    <text>Hydrides; and</text>
    <text>Sulfides;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Pollutants which have a pH of less than five (5.0) or more than ten (10.0),xcept when a waiver to the upper pH limit is authorized in writing by WASA, orhich have any corrosive property capable of damaging or creating a hazard totructures, equipment,
        processes, or personnel of the District&amp;#8217;sastewater system, including, but not limited to, acids, sulfides, concentratedhloride and fluoride compounds, and substances which will react with water toorm acidic or alkaline products;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Solid or viscous substances in amounts which may cause, or contribute tobstruction of the flow in a sewer or otherwise interfere with the operation ofhe District’s wastewater system, including, but not limited to:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Substances which may solidify or become viscous at temperatures above thirty-twoegrees Fahrenheit (32° F) or zero degrees Centigrade (0° C);</text>
    <text>Solids having any linear dimensions greater than one inch (1 in.);</text>
    <text>Fats, oils, and grease;</text>
    <text>Incompletely shredded garbage;</text>
    <text>Animal remains;</text>
    <text>Blood;</text>
    <text>Feathers;</text>
    <text>Ashes;</text>
    <text>Cinders;</text>
    <text>Sand;</text>
    <text>Spent lime;</text>
    <text>Stone or marble dust;</text>
    <text>Metal;</text>
    <text>Glass;</text>
    <text>Straw;</text>
    <text>Shavings;</text>
    <text>Grass clippings;</text>
    <text>Rags;</text>
    <text>Spent grains;</text>
    <text>Spent hops;</text>
    <text>Waste paper;</text>
    <text>Wood;</text>
    <text>Plastic;</text>
    <text>Tar;</text>
    <text>Asphalt residues;</text>
    <text>Residues from refining or processing of fuel or lubricating oil;</text>
    <text>Mud;</text>
    <text>Glass grinding; and</text>
    <text>Polishing wastes;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any pollutant, including, but not limited to oxygen demanding pollutants,eleased in the discharge at a flow rate, or concentration, or a combination ofoth, which causes interference with or compromises the structural integrity of</text>
    </level>
    <text>the District&amp;#8217;s wastewater system;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any wastewater with heat in such amounts as will inhibit the biologicalctivity of processes in the District&amp;#8217;s wastewater system resulting innterference. In no case shall wastewater be discharged by a User inemperatures in excess of one
        hundred forty degrees Fahrenheit (140° F) orixty degrees Centigrade (60° C), nor shall wastewater be discharged whichauses individually or in combination with other wastewater, the influent at theistrict&amp;#8217;s wastewater treatment plant
        to have a temperature exceeding oneundred four degrees Fahrenheit (104° F) or forty degrees Centigrade (40° C),xcept where a variance from the one hundred forty degrees Fahrenheit (140° F)r sixty degrees Centigrade (60° C) discharge limit is authorized
        in writing byASA;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Any wastewater containing petroleum oil, non-biodegradable cutting oil, orroducts of mineral oil origin in amounts that will cause pass through ornterference;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Any wastewater containing pollutants which result in the presence of toxic,oxious or malodorous liquids, solids, gases, vapors, or fumes within theistrict’s wastewater system which alone or in interaction with other wastes,re capable of creating
        a public nuisance or hazard to humans or animals, areufficient to cause acute worker health and safety problems, or are sufficiento cause interference or pass through;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Any wastewater of objectionable color or tint not removed in the treatmentrocess, including, but not limited to, dye wastes and vegetable tanning wastes;</text>
    </level>
    <text>Any trucked or hauled pollutants, except at discharge points that WASAesignates;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Wastewater containing any radioactive wastes or isotopes of such half-lifer concentration as may exceed limits that WASA establishes or applicable Stater National standards, cause pass through or interference or otherwise adverselympact the District’s
        wastewater system or cause or contribute to pollution;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Unless WASA specifically authorizes any substance including, but not limitedo:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Septic tank sludge;</text>
    <text>Restaurant grease;</text>
    <text>Waste from a fuel service station;</text>
    <text>Waste from a marine holding tank; and</text>
    <text>Waste from a portable toilet;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Sludges, screenings, or other residues from the pretreatment of industrialastes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Medical or infectious wastes except as WASA specifically authorizes inriting;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>Wastewater causing, alone or in conjunction with other sources, the effluentrom Blue Plains to fail toxicity tests;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>Detergents, surface-active agents, or other substances which might causexcessive foaming in the District’s wastewater system;</text>
    </level>
    <text>Any waste that if otherwise disposed of would be a hazardous waste, unlesspecifically authorized in writing by WASA; or</text>
    <text>Any substance which, alone or in conjunction with a discharge or discharges fromther sources, causes or may cause, or contributes to, a violation of anyequirement of the Blue Plains Title V permit issued pursuant to the Clean Airct.</text>
    <text>Pharmaceutical waste shall not be discharged to the District’s wastewaterystem if they contain materials in amounts that will contribute to or result inastewater concentrations that cause or contribute to pass through ornterference.</text>
    <text>Health care facilities located in the District of Columbia shall not dischargeharmaceutical products or pharmaceutical wastes into the District’sastewater system except in accordance with District laws and regulations.</text>
    <text>Excreta from individuals undergoing medical diagnosis or therapy withadioactive material shall be exempt from any limitations contained in thishapter.</text>
    <text>The following shall apply to discharges into the wastewater system:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>No User shall discharge into the wastewater system arsenic, cadmium,opper, lead, mercury, molybdenum, nickel, silver, zinc, cyanide, oil andrease, or Polychlorinated Biphenyls (PCBs) in concentrations greater than thoseisted in Table I of this subsection;</text>
    </level>
    <text>TABLE I</text>
    <text>SUBSTANCE</text>
    <text>DAILY MAXIMUM CONCENTRATION, mg/L</text>
    <text>Arsenic (T)</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <num>0.23</num>
    <text>0.23</text>
    <text>Cadmium (T)</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>0.07</num>
    <text>0.07</text>
    <text>Copper (T)</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2.3</num>
    <text>2.3</text>
    <text>Lead (T)</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1.0</num>
    <text>1.0</text>
    <text>Mercury (T)</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>