<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1303</num>
  <heading>GRANT AWARD (ยง 21-1303)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1303.1.</num>
    <text>The procedure for awarding grants shall be applicable to both DCRA and DPW. The Director of the appropriate Department shall review the applications and make a determination of those to be funded based upon the following criteria:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Availability of funds;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Completeness of the application and responsiveness to the grant notice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Priority of the work;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Reasonableness of the costs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Expertise to perform the work;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Whether the university or institution is District based;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Submission of all required documents in a timely manner;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Any federal requirements associated with the funds; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Other factors, as identified in writing by the Director of the appropriate Department prior to grant award.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1303.2.</num>
    <text>All grants shall be made pursuant to a written agreement. The Director shall send a grant agreement to the designated representative of the institution. The agreement shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The purpose of the project;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The amount of the grant award;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The term of the project and any conditions, statutes, rules or regulations with which the grant recipient must comply;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The scope of work for the grant, a description of all deliverables required under the grant, and a schedule specifying when all deliverables are to be provided to the Department;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The name of the grant administrator for the appropriate Department and the name of the agent for the grant recipient;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The names of all personnel assigned to perform the work required by the grant agreement, including the names of the subcontractor&amp;#8217;s employees;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A payment schedule; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The address to which all written communications from the Department to the grant recipient may be sent, including, but not limited to, the periodic payments due under the grant.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1303.3.</num>
    <text>The Director may consider unsolicited proposals, but may give preference to solicited proposals for grant award.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3528, 3531 (May 13, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>