<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-104</num>
  <heading>ABANDONED SERVICE (§ 21-104)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>104.1.</num>
    <text>No permit for a water supply to any property shall be installed until all outstanding charges for water consumed at the premises have been paid, and the applicant has made satisfactory arrangement with the Department for removal from the public main
      of all abandoned taps or connections formerly supplying all or any part of the property, including those taps or connections which will become abandoned after the installation of a new supply.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.2.</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, an applicant shall have the option to do either of the following, subject to compliance with existing rules and regulations:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Excavating and exposing the tap or connection (for removal by the Department) and backfilling the excavation; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Depositing (with the D.C. Treasurer) the amount of the fee fixed by the Director for the performance of all work in connection with the removal of the tap or connection.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.3.</num>
    <text>In all cases where the connections are larger than two inches (2 in.), removal shall be accomplished by the Department in accordance with the option set forth in §104.2(b).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.4.</num>
    <text>Under the option set forth in §104.2(a), the applicant shall be responsible for securing all required permits and for repairs to pavements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.5.</num>
    <text>No permit shall be issued for a temporary or special use of water through a tap or connection until the applicant (in addition to complying with the requirements of § 104.1) has deposited with the D.C. Treasurer the amount of the established fee for
      tap removal to cover the estimated cost of removal of the connection to be applied upon termination of that use. If the applicant has the tap removed under the option set forth in § 104.2(a), the applicant may apply for and receive a refund of the
      deposit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.6.</num>
    <text>No permit for razing a building shall be issued until the applicant has paid all outstanding charges for water consumed at the premises and has deposited with the D.C. Treasurer the amount of the established fee or the estimated cost of removal of
      all taps or connections formerly supplying the premises.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.7.</num>
    <text>If the service pipe is definitely recorded as being of a type currently permitted by- the D.C. Plumbing Code and the applicant anticipates reusing it to supply new construction on the property, the deposit may be noted &amp;#8220;Subject to approval
      of the Chief, Plumbing Inspection&amp;#8221; and removal of the tap or connection deferred until completion of the new construction, at which time the deposit will be refunded if the old service is re-used.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.8.</num>
    <text>If two (2) or more lots are integrated into one property, no razing permit for any building on that property shall be used until deposit is made by the applicant to cover removal of all abandoned taps and connections formerly supplying any portion
      of that property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.9.</num>
    <text>If an abandoned service is found to be leaking or defective, the owner of the property which was supplied by the service shall, within five (5) days of notice from the Department, arrange for tap or connection removal as provided in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.10.</num>
    <text>Written notice addressed to the owner of record as shown in the records of the Property Tax Division of the D.C. Department of Finance and Revenue, shall be deemed sufficient for the purpose of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.11.</num>
    <text>The Director may authorize removal of a tap or connection without notice to the property owner when, in his or her judgment, the condition of the service pipe constitutes a hazard to life, health, or property. The cost of removal of the tap or connection
      by the Department shall be charged to and collected from the owner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.12.</num>
    <text>The owner of property supplied by any service may be required by the Director to disconnect the service in accordance with the option set forth in this section, if either of the following apply:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The service pipe has not been used for a period of one (1) year and no imminent use is apparent; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The service pipe is not definitely recorded as being of the type currently permitted by the D.C. Plumbing Code.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>12 DCRR §401.5 (October 1981).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR&amp;#8217;S NOTE</heading>
      <text>The D.C. Plumbing Code referred to in this section has been superseded by D.C. Law 6-216. Construction Codes Approval and Amendments Act of 1986, effective March 21, 1987. Section 12 of D.C. Law 6-216 provides that the construction regulations existing
        prior to March 21, 1987, remain in effect for projects having reached specified stages of completion. D.C. Law 6-216 adopted the 1984 National BOCA Codes, and the 1985 D.C. Supplement to the National BOCA Codes. Effective November 27, 1992 (39
        DCR 8665), the 1984 BOCA Codes, and the 1985 D.C. Supplement to the National BOCA Codes were superseded by the adoption of the 1990 BOCA Codes, and the 1992 D.C. Supplement to the BOCA Codes.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>