<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1403</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION, LETTER OF NOTIFICATION AND PLAN CONTENTS (ยง 21-1403)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1403.1.</num>
    <text>This section prescribes the information which shall be included in a plan submitted for approval. Applications and plans submitted to the Director for approval shall be made on forms provided by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1403.2.</num>
    <text>Application forms submitted to the Director shall, at a minimum, contain the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Name and address of the applicant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Project location, the name of the waterway, and a description of how to reach the site;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Purpose and justification of the project and the proposed method of removal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Location of off-loading site;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Method and location of disposal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Name and address of the contractor, if applicable; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Proposed starting date and dates on which the proposed actions will be undertaken.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1403.3.</num>
    <text>Each application form shall contain the signature of the applicant certifying that the information provided is accurate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1403.4.</num>
    <text>Each plan (diagram) submitted to the Director shall include, but not be limited to, the following information or documentation:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A vicinity map which identifies the relative location of the project site, off-loading site and disposal site;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The area and extent of the proposed harvesting, cutting, or otherwise removing or eradicating of the submerged aquatic vegetation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The areas of existing submerged aquatic vegetation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Water depths on the project site;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Location of major landside structures (houses and boathouses) and water based structures including buoys, and mooring areas, in the project area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The names and current mailing addresses of adjoining property owners impacted;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The scale to which the plan is drawn; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The dates of the drawing or diagrams submitted.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1403.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant submitting a plan for approval to the Director shall notify property owners who may be affected the proposed action through a letter of notification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1403.6.</num>
    <text>A letter of notification shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A copy of the application and proposed plan; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A statement directing the affected property owner(s) to contact the Director for additional information or provide comments concerning the project.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1403.7.</num>
    <text>A copy of each letter of notification shall accompany the application and plan submitted to the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 1971, 1972 (April 15, 1994).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>