<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1509</num>
  <heading>TEMPORARY DISCHARGE AUTHORIZATION (§ 21-1509)
    <text>Temporary Discharge Authorization (TDA) Permits are issued for a limited periodf time to Users who have a need to discharge directly or indirectly into aatch basin, manhole or other conduit that is connected to the combined sewer oranitary sewer.</text>
    <text>All Users who are issued a TDA Permit shall comply with the requirements of thisubchapter and the requirements of §§ 1501-1503, 1506-1508, 1512, and514-1516.</text>
    <text>In an emergency situation, WASA may, upon request, authorize a User to dischargeirectly to a catch basin or manhole connected to the combined sewer or sanitaryewer for a limited period of time, provided the User submits a TDA Permitpplication within
      seventy-two (72) hours of the emergency situation.</text>
    <text>A TDA Permit may be issued to Users to permit the discharge of treated orntreated groundwater, surface water, storm water, or other discharges includingut not limited to, swimming pool drainage, wash water, and hydrodemolitionaters. TDA Permit’s may
      be issued to permit the discharge of groundwaterrom remediation sites, dewatering at construction or restoration sites, andther sources.</text>
    <text>The TDA Permit may be issued under the following conditions:</text>
    <text>The discharge consists entirely of treated or untreated non-wastewater flows orther approved wastewater discharges and is being discharged to the combinedewer system or consists of contaminated non-wastewater flows or approvedastewater discharges
      to the sanitary sewer system in conformance to §501.14(a);</text>
    <text>The Users have no other reasonable means for disposal; and</text>
    <text>The average daily volume of discharge for treated or untreated non-wastewaterlows or other approved wastewater is:</text>
    <text>Less than twenty-five thousand gallons per day (25,000 gal./day);</text>
    <text>Greater than twenty-five thousand gallons per day (25,000 gal./day) and theischarge (prior to treatment) does not exceed the District’s Pretreatmenttandards; or</text>
    <text>Greater than twenty-five thousand gallons per day (25,000 gal./day), theischarge (prior to treatment) exceeds the District’s Pretreatment Standards,nd WASA grants the User an exemption to discharge based on the duration, naturend location of the discharge.
      If WASA does not grant the User an exemption, theser shall apply for a Significant Non-Categorical Industrial User permit.</text>
    <text>TDA Permits shall have a maximum term of two (2) years and may be reissued asuthorized by WASA, following submittal of a new application at least fourteen14) days prior to the expiration of the TDA permit.</text>
    <text>The TDA Permit application shall include the following information:</text>
    <text>Name, address, and contact information;</text>
    <text>Project address (including square and lot number);</text>
    <text>Permit information, including, but not limited to, WASA’s sheeting and shoringermit, and the District’s sediment and erosion control permit, as applicable;</text>
    <text>Project description, including, but not limited to, a description of theroposed pretreatment facilities for contaminated sites;</text>
    <text>Description of discharge to include daily maximum flow and rate of discharge;</text>
    <text>Results from laboratory analysis of a representative sample of the water to beischarged (if applicable);</text>
    <text>Discharge location map;</text>
    <text>Design plan (for remediation projects), dewatering plan and geotechnical reportfor construction projects), and site assessment report, if available; and</text>
    <text>Certification statement (included on the application) signed by an authorizedepresentative of the applicant in accordance with § 1508.11.</text>
    <text>After evaluation of the information submitted, WASA may:</text>
    <text>Deny any application for a TDA Permit; or</text>
    <text>Issue an invoice for the applicable TDA Permit fees as provided in chapter 1 ofhis title. Upon payment, WASA shall issue a TDA Permit subject to terms andonditions provided in the TDA Permit.</text>
    <text>Upon review of the TDA Permit application or subsequent monitoring data, WASAay require the User to provide pretreatment of the wastewater prior toischarge to the District’s wastewater system in accordance with § 1502.</text>
    <text>Any User that is issued a TDA Permit shall comply with all permit conditions asstablished by WASA. Discharge of wastewater without a permit shall berohibited, unless authorized by WASA.</text>
    <text>Any User that is issued a TDA Permit shall monitor the volume of discharge anderform sampling and analysis of the wastewater discharged as required by theDA Permit.</text>
    <text>Reports shall be submitted to WASA as required by the TDA Permit and shallnclude, but not be limited to, average daily flow, analytical data, andhain-of-custody documentation. All reports shall include the certificationtatement provided in § 1508.10
      and shall be signed by an authorizedepresentative in accordance with § 1508.11.</text>
    <text>A sanitary sewer service charge shall apply based on the measured quantity ofater discharged to the wastewater system under the TDA Permit in accordanceith D.C. Official Code § 34-2107 (2008 Repl.) and 21 DCMR § 207.</text>
    <text>Unless otherwise permitted under District law, the temporary discharge ofroundwater or surface water to the District’s wastewater system without a TDAermit or in violation of a TDA Permit as provided in this section shall beubject to enforcement action
      as provided in § 15 of the Act and as provided in§ 1513 and 1517.</text>
    <text>A TDA Permit may be suspended, terminated, or denied for good cause including,ut not limited to, the following:</text>
    <text>Information indicating that the permitted discharge poses a threat to theistrict’s wastewater system, WASA personnel, or the public;</text>
    <text>Violation of any terms or conditions of the TDA Permit;</text>
    <text>Obtaining a TDA Permit by misrepresentation or failure to disclose fully, allelevant facts;</text>
    <text>The unauthorized discharge of wastewater from non-domestic sources;</text>
    <text>Denying WASA personnel access to a facility for purposes of collecting a samplend/or obtaining instrument readings; and</text>
    <text>Failure to pay applicable fees.</text>
    <text>Users may petition the General Manager to reconsider the issuance, suspension,ermination or denial of a TDA Permit or the terms or conditions of a TDA Permitithin fifteen (15) calendar days of the effective date of the TDA Permit byubmission of a
      Permit Appeal form. The submission of a Permit Appeal foreconsideration shall not stay compliance with TDA Permit conditions.</text>
    <text>Failure to submit a timely Permit Appeal for review shall be deemed to be aaiver of administrative appeal unless the General Manager grants a timextension.</text>
    <text>In the Permit Appeal, the User shall indicate the discharge permit provisionsbjected to, the reasons for the objection, and the alternative condition, ifny, it seeks to place in the TDA Permit.</text>
    <text>The General Manager will review and make a final decision on the Permit Appeal.</text>
    <text>The General Manager will send the User the final decision.</text>
    <text>If the General Manager denies the Permit Appeal or the User is not satisfiedith the General Manager’s final decision, the Permittee may appeal the Permitppeal decision as set forth in § 1519 by filing a petition for andministrative hearing within
      fifteen (15) calendar days of the date of theeneral Manager’s final decision. The petition for an administrative hearinghall be filed in accordance with the requirements set forth in 21 DCMR § 412.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 6194, 6201 (October 10, 1986); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 2948 (April 28, 2000); asmended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 1021, 1059 (February0, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>