<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-102</num>
  <heading>TAPS AND CONNECTIONS (§ 21-102)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>102.1.</num>
    <text>No public watermain shall be tapped or connections made to a public watermain under any circumstances, except by the regular tappers or construction forces of the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.2.</num>
    <text>The provision of taps or connections to the public watermain shall be at the expense of the applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.3.</num>
    <text>Upon application, approval, deposit of cost by the applicant, and the submission of an executed &amp;#8220;Authority Card&amp;#8221; for each service, the Department will install taps (sizes 3/4 in. through 2 in.), or connections (3 in. in diameter
      and larger) including tees, sleeves, valves, valve casings, or valve boxes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.4.</num>
    <text>Each water service larger than one and one-half inch (11/2 in.) shall have stop valve with approved valvebox as close as practicable to the public water main.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.5.</num>
    <text>Taps or connections to watermains larger than twelve inches (12 in.) in diameter will not be permitted with-out specific written approval of the Director or his or her duly authorized representative.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.6.</num>
    <text>No tap or connection shall be nearer than two feet (2 ft.) to a bell or coupling of a watermain.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.7.</num>
    <text>No two (2) taps shall be nearer together than two feet (2 ft.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.8.</num>
    <text>In no case shall a water service pipe from the tap in the main to the building line be less than three-quarters of an inch (3/4 in.) in size.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.9.</num>
    <text>In no case shall the valves of the service pipe be smaller in size than the supply pipe.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>12 DCRR §§401.2 and 401.3 (October 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>