<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-106</num>
  <heading>PERMITS FOR USE OF WATER FROM FIRE HYDRANTS (§ 21-106)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>106.1.</num>
    <text>Each person desiring the use of one or more fire hydrants for the purposes set forth in §105 and this section (except § 105.4) shall apply for a permit on the form provided by the Director. The proper forms are available from the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>106.2.</num>
    <text>Permission for use of hydrants for community recreational purposes shall be requested through the Department of Recreation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>106.3.</num>
    <text>The Department representative shall ensure that water from another source is not available before processing the permit application. If water from another source is available, the applicant shall be required to file for a permit to use a temporary
      tap or a connection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>106.4.</num>
    <text>The following fees shall be charged for use of fire hydrant water:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>For construction, demolition, dust control, or other similar purposes, the fee shall be based on usage for each fire hydrant.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For swimming pools without meters, baptismal pools, tank trucks, storage tanks, and similar uses where the amount of water used can be determined, the fee shall be determined using the prevailing water rate.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Fire Hydrant Charges</text>
    <text>Fire Hydrant Use Based on usage</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>106.5.</num>
    <text>Approved users of fire hydrants shall be responsible for the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Damage that they may cause to the fire hydrant(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The disconnection of all hoses and other appurtenances from the fire hydrant when the hydrant is not in use; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Obtaining permission from the Department of Public Works for laying hose in public space.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>106.6.</num>
    <text>Hose or pipe connections shall be equipped with an approved back flow preventer (such as an air gap or check valve) if there is any possibility of potential contamination of the water supply.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>106.7.</num>
    <text>In cases where flow regulation valves are placed on the outlets of fire hydrants, those hydrants shall be turned on full when in use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>106.8.</num>
    <text>The use of any implement or tool, except the authorized fire hydrant key to turn the water from the hydrant on or off is prohibited.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking (DES Order No. 40-42-01) published at 25 DCR 7223 (February 2, 1979), incorporating text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 24 DCR 5407 (December 15, 1978); 12 DCRR §§404.21(a), 404.22, 404.23, 404.25(a)-(f) (October 1981); as
        amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 5943 (July 16, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 6448 (August 8, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>