<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-2010</num>
  <heading>PREMISES TO RECEIVE DPW RECYCLING COLLECTION SERVICES (ยง 21-2010)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2010.1.</num>
    <text>Premises authorized to receive District collection of recyclables shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Single family dwellings and buildings containing three (3) or fewer dwelling units used exclusively for residential purposes.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>[Repealed] D.C. Law 10-178, 41 DCR 5205, 5207 (August 5, 1994).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2010.2.</num>
    <text>The Director shall not collect recyclables from the following buildings or structures:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Any building or structure containing four (4) or more dwelling units;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any building or connected group of buildings which is used, maintained, advertised, or held out as a place where, for a consideration, sleeping accommodations are furnished to five (5) or more persons who are not members of the immediate family
        of the owner or lessee of the building and in which the accommodations are not under the exclusive control of the occupants;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any building or connected group of buildings which is used, maintained, advertised, or held out as a place where for a consideration, meals or lunches are furnished to five (5) or more boarders or to five (5) or more transients who have sleeping
        accommodations on the premises;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any dwelling unit which does not abut public space; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Hotels.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2010.3.</num>
    <text>[Repealed]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 7470, 7474 (October 2, 1992); as amended by ยง4 of the District of Columbia Solid Waste Management and Mutti-Material Recycling Act of 1988 Amendment Act of 1994, D.C.Law 10-178, 41 DCR 5205, 5207 (August 5, 1994).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>