<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-200</num>
  <heading>ACCESS TO SEWERS (§ 21-200)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>200.1.</num>
    <text>No person other than those employed in the Bureau of Sewer Services of the Department, while on duty, shall enter any public sewer or appurtenance of a public sewer without a written permit from the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>200.2.</num>
    <text>No person shall turn, lift, remove, raise, or tamper with any cover of any manhole, basin, inlet, or other appurtenance of any public sewer without a written permit from the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>200.3.</num>
    <text>No person shall cut, break, pierce, or tap any public sewer or appurtenance of a public sewer, or introduce any tube, pipe, trough, or conduit into any public sewer or public sewer appurtenance without a written permit from the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>200.4.</num>
    <text>Violation of any provision of this section shall be punishable, upon conviction, by a fine not to exceed three hundred dollars ($300).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is the District of Columbia Public Works Act of 1954, approved May 18, 1954 (68 Stat. 101; D.C. Code §43-1607 et seq.); §§401 and 402 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967, effective August 11,
        1967, filed August 11, 1967, D.C. Code Vol. 1 at 126 (1981 Ed.); §2(g) of the Water and Sewer Repair and Compensation Act of 1976, D.C. Law 1.98, D.C. Code §6-405, 23 DCR 4933 (January 21, 1977), Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 77-82 dated May 6, 1977;
        §§IV(A) and V of Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1983, 30 DCR 6428, effective March 2, 1984; Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 91-176, 38 DCR 6821, dated October 24, 1991; the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Operations Amendment Act of 1990, effective
        June 13, 1990 (D.C. Law 8-136, D.C. Code §§43-1527 et seq.).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 3, §§14 through 16; and Article 30, §4 of the Police Regulations; 12 DCRR §§502.1, 502.2 (October 1981); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 5358 (June 18, 1999).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR&amp;#8217;S NOTE</heading>
      <text>Transfer of functions §219 of the &amp;#8220;Water and Sewer Authority Establishment and Department of Public Works Reorganization Act of 1996,&amp;#8221; D.C. Law 11-111, effective April 18, 1996, transferred the functions of the Water and Sewer
        Utility Administration of the Department of Public Works to the independent District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>