<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-204</num>
  <heading>SEWER STOPPAGES (§ 21-204)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>204.1.</num>
    <text>If there is a complaint regarding a sewer stoppage, the Director shall first ascertain if the main sewer is clear. If the main sewer is clear, the complaining party shall be so informed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>204.2.</num>
    <text>Any stoppage in the main sewer shall be relieved within a reasonable period of time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>204.3.</num>
    <text>If the main sewer is clear, the complaining party shall, at his or her own expense, employ a registered master plumber or sewer cleaner to clear the stoppage from the building to the main sewer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>204.4.</num>
    <text>A registered master plumber or sewer cleaner employed under §204.3 shall not excavate in public ways beyond the property line.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>204.5.</num>
    <text>If the registered master plumber or sewer cleaner finds that the stoppage is located between the main sewer and property line, and that it cannot be cleared by power rodding or snaking, he or she shall inform the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>204.6.</num>
    <text>If the Director finds that the stoppage is in the building connection between the property line and the main sewer, and that the stoppage could not have been cleared by power rodding or snaking, the condition shall be corrected by the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>204.7.</num>
    <text>If the Director finds that the stoppage is not due to the faulty condition of the building sewer connection between the property line and the main sewer, the property owner shall pay the D.C. Treasurer the amount of expense incurred by the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>204.8.</num>
    <text>All stoppages in public space outside of the property line, whether relieved or not, shall be reported to the Director by the registered master plumber or sewer cleaner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 24 DCR 4651 (December 2, 1977), incorporating text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 24 DCR 3060, 3061 (October 21, 1977); 12 DCRR §§503.4(c) and (d) (October 1981); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46
        DCR 5358 (June 18, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>