<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-2021</num>
  <heading>RECYCLING REQUIREMENTS FOR PREMISES NOT ELIGIBLE FOR DPW COLLECTION SERVICES (§1-2021)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2021.2.</num>
    <text>Each owner of a commercial property shall be responsible for the separate removal of recyclable material by a registered recycling hauler or pursuant to an approved self-implementation plan. The owner may provide through a lease agreement for an occupant
      to be responsible for its own solid waste removal, in which case the occupant shall also be responsible for the separate removal of recylable material, unless otherwise provided for in the lease agreement. Notwithstanding the existence of such a
      lease agreement, the owner is responsible for complying with these regulations except where the Director determines that there are circumstances that warrant holding an occupant liable for compliance. The Director may issue a notice of violation
      to an occupant or to the owner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2021.3.</num>
    <text>Each owner of commercial property shall, at least once a year, notify any tenants or occupants of the property of the legal requirement that certain materials be separated for recycling, the types of materials to be separated, how and where recyclables
      shall be taken in order to be collected for recycling, and the name and contact information of any recycling coordinator for the property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2021.4.</num>
    <text>Each owner of commercial property shall post and maintain at least one (1) sign where solid waste is collected or stored that sets forth what materials are required to be source separated and states the collection procedures for such materials, and
      shall post at least one (1) sign at containers where recyclables are collected stating what materials may properly be placed in them. The owner may provide through the lease agreement that an occupant shall also be responsible for posting and maintaining
      such signs, in which case the occupant shall also be responsible for meeting the requirements of this subsection. Notwithstanding the existence of such a lease agreement, the owner is responsible for complying with this regulation except where the
      Director determines that there are circumstances that warrant holding an occupant liable for compliance.  The Director may issue a notice of violation to an occupant or to the owner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2021.5.</num>
    <text>REPEALED</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2021.6.</num>
    <text>REPEALED</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2021.7.</num>
    <text>REPEALED</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2021.8.</num>
    <text>REPEALED</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 7470, 7477 (October 2, 1992); as amended by §4 of the District of Columbia Solid Waste Management and Multi-Material Recycling Act of 1988 Amendment Act of 1994, D.C. Law 10-178, 41 DCR 5205, 5207 ( August 5,
        1994); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11962, 11964 (December 17, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>