<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-2099</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 21-2099)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2099.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the words and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Collector &amp;#8211; any person who is engaged in the collection or transportation of recyclable goods.</text>
    <text>Commercial Property &amp;#8211; as defined in D.C. Law 7-226, the District of Columbia Solid Waste Management and Multi-Material Recycling Act of 1988, D.C. Code §6-3403 (1995 Repl. Vol.).</text>
    <text>Contaminants &amp;#8211; any substance or waste material other than the desired recyclable product. For the purpose of §2002, newspaper contaminants shall include paint (and other chemical substance), animal wastes and garbage. (39 DCR 7470 &amp;#038;
      D.C. Law 10-178)</text>
    <text>Designated Point of Collection &amp;#8211; a location, designated by the Department of Public Works, as the point for recyclable collection.</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; the Director of the Department of Public Works (or its successor agencies) or his or her designee.</text>
    <text>Household waste &amp;#8211; any substance, liquid or solid, placed in containers for non-recycling purposes (i.e. collection and disposal at a residential property). (39 DCR 7970 &amp;#038; D.C. Law 10-178)</text>
    <text>Occupant &amp;#8211; any person who has a leasehold right, ownership interest, management responsibility, or direct or indirect control over the maintenance or affairs of any space within a residential or commercial building.</text>
    <text>Office Building &amp;#8211; as defined in D.C. Law 7-226, the District of Columbia Solid Waste</text>
    <text>Management and Multi &amp;#8211; Material Recycling Act of 1988, D.C. Code §6-3403 (1995 Repl. Vol.).</text>
    <text>Office Paper &amp;#8211; all fine paper, bond paper, offset paper, xerographic paper, memo paper, duplication paper, continuous form paper, envelopes, printed material, or related cellulosic material containing not more than ten percent (10%) by weight
      or volume of non-cellulosic material such as laminates, binders, coatings, or saturants.</text>
    <text>Other Commercial Business &amp;#8211; any form of commercial activity taking place in a commercial property other than an apartment or office building. Commercial activity includes retail, governments warehouse, manufacturing, industrial, service,
      storage, production, and wholesale activities.</text>
    <text>Owner &amp;#8211; the record owner of a property except that, for a condominium, the owner shall be the condominium association for that property.</text>
    <text>Paper- newspapers, glossy magazines, coupons, office paper, advertisements, telephone</text>
    <text>directories, books, envelopes that do not have plastic address windows, brochures and other similar paper items.</text>
    <text>Plastic- narrow necked plastic bottles.</text>
    <text>Processor &amp;#8211; any person who is engaged in the marketing, preparing, or processing of recyclables.</text>
    <text>Recyclable &amp;#8211; as defined in D.C. Law 7-226, the District of Columbia Solid Waste Management and Multi-Material Recycling Act of 1988, D.C. Code §6-3403 (1995 Repl. Vol.).</text>
    <text>Recycling &amp;#8211; as defined in D.C. Law 7-226, the District of Columbia Solid Waste Management and Multi-Material Recycling Act of 1988, D.C. Code §6-3403 (1995 Repl. Vol.).</text>
    <text>Registration Packet &amp;#8211; [Repealed] (D.C. Law 10-178)</text>
    <text>Residential Property &amp;#8211; as defined in D.C. Law 7-226, the District of Columbia Solid Waste Management and Multi-Material Recycling Act of 1988, D.C. Code §6-3403 (1995 Repl. Vol.).</text>
    <text>Undue Hardship &amp;#8211; a rare or unusual circumstance, but does not typically pertain to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Inconvenience in locating space for materials collection;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Necessity to hire additional personnel or the encountering of other expenses; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Concern over vermin.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Yard Waste &amp;#8211; as defined in D.C. Law 7-226, the District of Columbia Solid Waste Management and Multi-Material Recycling Act of 1988, D.C. Code §6-3403 (1995 Repl. Vol.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 7470, 7490 (October 2, 1992); as amended by §4 of the District of Columbia Solid Waste Management and Multi-Material Recycling Act of 1988 Amendment Act of 1994, D.C. Law 10-178, 5205, 5206 (August 5, 1994);
        as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11962, 11970 (December 17, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>