<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-2052</num>
  <heading>HAULING ENFORCEMENT (§ 21-2052)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2052.1.</num>
    <text>Recyclables, as defined in this chapter, shall not be deposited at any District solid waste disposal facility, unless otherwise approved by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2052.2.</num>
    <text>The contents of vehicles hauling solid waste to any District of Columbia disposal facility shall be subject to visual inspection for evidence of recyclables, as defined in this chapter. If recyclables are detected, the driver of the vehicle shall
      be required to dump the load in an area away from regular dumping activities. If, upon separation and inspection of the vehicle&amp;#8217;s contents, a substantial amount of the load (approximately 30%) is determined to be recyclable, the inspector
      shall issue a Notice of Violation in accordance with §2061.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2052.3.</num>
    <text>If the Director finds that any recycling collector, solid waste hauler, or an agent of either, violates any provision of this section, the Director may (in addition to any other remedy available) deny the hauler or its agent access to the District
      of Columbia’s solid waste facilities for a period not to exceed thirty (30) days for each violation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2052.4.</num>
    <text>If the Director finds that a recycling collector has committed three (3) or more violations of this chapter within a twelve (12) month period, the Director may (in addition to any other remedy available) suspend the collector’s registration for up
      to twelve (12) months.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2052.5.</num>
    <text>If the Director finds that a recycling collector has committed six (6) or more violations of this chapter within a twelve (12) month period, the Director may (in addition to any other remedy available) revoke the recycling collector’s registration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2052.6.</num>
    <text>A recycling collector shall maintain a copy of each day’s recycling collection route and a list of customers served, and provide a copy to the Director within two (2) business days after the Director requests the list.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 7470, 7480 (October 2, 1992); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published 57 DCR 11962, 11966 (December 17, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>