<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-399</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 21-399)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>399.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following words and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Authority &amp;#8211; The District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority.</text>
    <text>Dwelling unit &amp;#8211; A habitable room with kitchen and bathroom facilities exclusively under the control of and for the use of the occupant.</text>
    <text>General Manager &amp;#8211; The General Manager of the Authority, or his or her designee.</text>
    <text>Meter Ready &amp;#8211; The circumstance that pertains after the property owner has created, built and installed the vault, meter risers and appurtenances so that the premises is ready for the installation of the meter.</text>
    <text>Meters &amp;#8211; Includes any device which is used to measure the amount of water utilized by consumers.</text>
    <text>Consumer &amp;#8211; Individuals or Businesses which use water provided by the Water and Sewer Authority.</text>
    <text>Commercial Water Meter &amp;#8211; For purposes of this chapter, a &amp;#8220;commercial water meter&amp;#8221; is a meter which serves a premises used as other than a single family dwelling or a two-family flat, whether the premises is served directly
      from a District-owned water main or from an un-metered privately owned water main.</text>
    <text>Residential Meters &amp;#8211; In general, are meters on water services that supply residential users that range in size from five-eighths inch (5/8 in.) through two inches (2 in.).</text>
    <text>Preventive Maintenance &amp;#8211; For purposes of this chapter, the term &amp;#8220;preventive maintenance&amp;#8221; means maintenance, including testing and repair (if necessary and when possible) performed in accordance with the current American
      Water Works Association (AWWA) schedule based on meter size and recorded consumption, or as otherwise determined by the General Manager.</text>
    <text>(</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 1300, 1306 (February 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 782(January 24, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>