<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-4101</num>
  <heading>RATES FOR SEWER SERVICE (§ 21-4101)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4101.1</num>
    <text>4101.1 Effective October 1, 2013, the rates for sanitary sewer service shall be:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The retail sanitary sewer service rate shall be increased from four dollars and eighteen cents ($4.18) for each one hundred cubic feet (1 Ccf) (or five dollars and fifty-nine cents ($5.59) for each one thousand gallons (1,000 gals.) (one hundred
        cubic feet (1 Ccf) equals seven hundred forty-eight and five hundredths gallons (748.05 gals.)) of water used to:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Residential Customers: four dollars and forty-one cents ($4.41) per Ccf (or the equivalent of five dollars and eighty-nine cents ($5.89) for each one thousand gallons (1,000 gals.)) of water used;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Multi-Family Customers: four dollars and forty-one cents ($4.41) per Ccf (or the equivalent of five dollars and eighty-nine cents ($5.89) for each one thousand gallons (1,000 gals.)) of water used; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Non-Residential Customers: four dollars and forty-one cents ($4.41) per Ccf (or the equivalent of five dollars and eighty-nine cents ($5.89)) for each one thousand gallons (1,000 gals.)) of water used; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The annual Clean Rivers Impervious Surface Area Charge (IAC) shall be increased from one hundred fourteen dollars and eighty-four cents ($114.84), billed monthly at nine dollars and fifty-seven cents ($9.57), per Equivalent Residential Unit (ERU),
        to one hundred forty-two dollars and twenty cents ($142.20) per ERU, billed monthly as follows:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Residential Customers: eleven dollars and eighty-five cents ($11.85) per month for each ERU;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Multi-Family Customers: eleven dollars and eighty-five cents ($11.85) per month for each ERU; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Non-Residential Customers: eleven dollars and eighty-five cents ($11.85) per month for each ERU.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The retail groundwater sewer charge for an unimproved real property under construction shall be two dollars and thirty-three cents ($2.33) per CCF (one hundred cubic feet (1 CCF) equals seven hundred forty-eight and five hundredths gallons (748.05
        gals.)) for groundwater discharged into the District’s wastewater sewer system;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The retail cooling water sewer charge shall be the retail sanitary sewer service rate set forth in Section 4101.1(a) for cooling water discharged into the District&amp;#8217;s wastewater sewer system; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The retail non-potable water source sewer charge shall be the retail sanitary sewer service rate set forth in Section 4101.1(a) for non-potable water discharged into the District&amp;#8217;s wastewater sewer system.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4101.2.</num>
    <text>The IAC shall be based upon the Equivalent Residential Unit (ERU). An ERU is defined as one thousand square feet (1,000 sq. ft.) of impervious surface area, taking account of a statistical median of residential properties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4101.3</num>
    <text>4101.3 All residential customers shall be assessed an IAC based on the following Six-Tier Residential Rate Structure for the IAC:</text>
    <text>Tier</text>
    <text>Size of Impervious Area (Square Feet)</text>
    <text>Equivalent Residential Unit (ERU)</text>
    <text>Tier 1</text>
    <text>100 &amp;#8211; 600</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>0.6</num>
    <text>0.6</text>
    <text>Tier 2</text>
    <text>700 &amp;#8211; 2000</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1.0</num>
    <text>1.0</text>
    <text>Tier 3</text>
    <text>2,100 &amp;#8211; 3,000</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2.4</num>
    <text>2.4</text>
    <text>Tier 4</text>
    <text>3,100 &amp;#8211; 7,000</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3.8</num>
    <text>3.8</text>
    <text>Tier 5</text>
    <text>7,100 &amp;#8211; 11000</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8.6</num>
    <text>8.6</text>
    <text>Tier 6</text>
    <text>11,100 and more</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>13.5</num>
    <text>13.5</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4101.4</num>
    <text>4101.4 All non-residential and multi-family customers shall be assessed ERU(s) based upon the total amount of impervious surface area on each lot. This total amount of impervious surface shall be converted into ERU(s), truncated to the nearest one-hundred
      (100) square feet.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4101.5</num>
    <text>4101.5 Impervious Only Properties are defined and subject to the follow requirements:</text>
    <text>Impervious Only Properties are properties that do not currently have metered water/sewer service (for example, parking lots) and may require the creation of new accounts; and</text>
    <text>Effective October 1, 2012, Impervious Only Properties shall be billed as follows:</text>
    <text>Impervious Only Properties with three (3) or more ERU’s shall be billed monthly;</text>
    <text>Impervious Only Properties with less than three (3) ERU’s shall be billed every six (6) months; and</text>
    <text>Customers who are billed for more than one (1) property and who participate in District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority’s group billing program shall be billed monthly for all properties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 1993, 1994 (April 4, 1997); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 320 (January 21, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 5977 (June 28, 2002); as amended by Final Rulemaking published
        at 50 DCR 6452 (August 8, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 8849 (September 10, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 8528 (September 16, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 7655
        (September 22, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 9178 (September 21, 2007); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 9845 (September 19, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 2728 (April 10,
        2009); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 2739 (April 10, 2009); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 7534 (September 18, 2009); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 8419, 8420 (September 17, 2010);
        as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 6941, 6942 (August 12, 2011); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8820, 8821 (July 27, 2012); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11239 (August 2, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>