<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-416</num>
  <heading>DISMISSAL OF HEARINGS (ยง 21-416)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>416.1.</num>
    <text>A petitioner may request a dismissal by filing a written petition with the hearing officer or orally requesting dismissal at the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>416.2.</num>
    <text>The hearing officer may, on his or her own motion, dismiss a hearing demand, either entirely or as to any stated issue, under any of the following circumstances:</text>
    <text>a) Where the matter has previously been the subject of a hearing or the petitioner has previously been afforded an opportunity for a hearing on the same matter, and the owner or occupant has failed to preserve his or her right to a hearing;</text>
    <text>b) Where the owner or occupant demanding a hearing is not a lawful owner or occupant or does not otherwise have a right to a hearing. This would include, but is not limited to, cases in which the individual is not the owner or occupant as defined
      in D.C. Law 8-136;</text>
    <text>c) Where the petitioner has failed to file a timely hearing demand pursuant to the provisions of this chapter; and</text>
    <text>d) Where the hearing officer, in his or her opinion, finds that a petition filed in any proceeding does not raise a question of fact or law or the claim is frivolous.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>416.3.</num>
    <text>The dismissal shall be in the form of an order by the hearing officer, which shall contain a statement of facts and law and the reason for the dismissal. No such order shall be necessary where all the parties have expressly requested the dismissal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>416.4.</num>
    <text>The dismissal order shall be given to the parties or mailed to them at their last known address.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 1300, 1314 (February 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 5358 (June 18, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 1743(February 23, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>