<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-4000</num>
  <heading>NOTICE OF PROPOSED RATE CHANGE AND PUBLIC HEARING (§ 21-4000)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4000.1.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in §6(c) of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 5006; D.C. Code §1-1506(c)), before establishing or changing a retail rate for the provision of potable water or sewage services
      in the District of Columbia, the Board shall first publish notice of its intention to do so in the D.C. Register. The notice may also be published in a newspaper of general circulation in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4000.2.</num>
    <text>The notice shall state as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The rate under consideration by the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The date, time, and location of a public hearing to be held by the Board on the proposed rate, or an indication that the date, time and location will be specified in a forthcoming notice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The time period during which written comments may be submitted for consideration by the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The requirements of §4001.5 of this chapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Whether the Board is considering adopting the new rate at a meeting of the Board immediately following the public hearing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is §216 of the Water and Sewer Authority Establishment and Department of Public Works Reorganization Act of 1996, D.C. Law 11-111, D.C. Code §43-1686 (1990 Repl. Vol.).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 2633 (May 2, 1997).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR&amp;#8217;S NOTE</heading>
      <text>Chapter 50, Retail Rulemaking was renumbered Chapter 40.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>