<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-419</num>
  <heading>STYLE OF PLEADINGS AND PETITIONS (ยง 21-419)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>419.1.</num>
    <text>All pleadings, notices, orders and other papers filed under the provisions of this chapter shall be captioned &amp;#8220;Before the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority.&amp;#8221;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>419.2.</num>
    <text>A document shall contain the WASA Docket Number if assigned.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>419.3.</num>
    <text>Each petition filed under this chapter shall be notarized and shall be styled in the manner of pleadings as provided in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>419.4.</num>
    <text>Each document shall contain a title appropriate to the proceedings which describe generally the type of document, such as one of the following:</text>
    <text>In the Matter of the _________________ (Charges, Interest, Penalties, and Fees) for the water and sewer services rendered to ___________________________ (Property Address) owned by ________________________ (Name of Owner of Record) and occupied by
      _____________ (Name of Occupant)</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>419.5.</num>
    <text>Upon filing, each petition shall be given a docket number and shall become a matter of public record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>419.6.</num>
    <text>Each petition shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Facts related to the water and sewer service account including the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The account number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The service address;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The name of the party who holds the account;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The type of property and number of units;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The date of the last bill; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The number of people residing at the service address during the period of the disputed bill.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A concise statement of the facts concerning the disputed charges;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Supporting data, facts, or evidence upon which petitioner relies as justification for disputing the water and sewer service charges; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A request for adjustment of the water and sewer service charges.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 1300, 1315 (February 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 5358 (June 18, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>