<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-499</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 21-499)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>499.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following words and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Comparable periods -</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>No change in occupancy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The same or like seasons; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The same or like number of days and billing periods.</text>
    </level>
    <text>General Manager &amp;#8211; The chief administrative officer of the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority or his or her designee.</text>
    <text>Occupant &amp;#8211; any individual, corporation, association or partnership who holds or possesses a premises in subordination to the title of the owner of the premises, with the consent of the owner.</text>
    <text>Owner &amp;#8211; any individual, corporation, association or partnership listed as the legal title holder of record.</text>
    <text>Petitioner &amp;#8211; an owner, occupant, owner&amp;#8217;s agent, applicant for certification to test backflow preventers or a holder of a certificate to test backflow preventers.</text>
    <text>Practicable &amp;#8211; For purposes of Section 430, a finding made by the General Manager that it is feasible to individually meter each apartment on the premises, or that there exists a tenant group or association that meets the Department&amp;#8217;s
      requirements.</text>
    <text>Privately owned water meters &amp;#8211; meters required to be installed, at no cost to the District, for the measurement of water supplied and used by commercial and industrial users or by premises with three (3) or more separate dwelling units.</text>
    <text>Residential tenants &amp;#8211; a tenant as defined by the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Operations Amendment Act of 1990 (D.C. Law 8-136), D.C. Code ยง 43-1651(3) (1990 Repl. Vol.).</text>
    <text>WASA &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority or its lawful agent, successor in interest or designee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 1300, 1329 (February 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 5358 (June 18, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 1743 (February 23, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>