<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-5213</num>
  <heading>CONFLICT OF INTEREST (ยง 21-5213)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5213.1.</num>
    <text>Authority employees shall not participate in transactions that may result in a conflict of interest or the apparent conflict of interest between the private interests of the employee and the public interests of the Authority. Specifically:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>No employee may have a direct or indirect financial interest in any transaction that directly conflicts with the employee&amp;#8217;s responsibilities for the Authority.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>No employee may solicit or accept, directly or indirectly, on their own behalf or on behalf of a relative, any gift, gratuity, favor, compensation, offer of employment, or any other thing having more than a nominal monetary value from any person,
        corporation, or other entity having or seeking to have contractual, business, or financial relationship with the Authority.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5213.2.</num>
    <text>Political activities of employees of the Authority are subject to provisions of the Hatch Act Reform Amendment Act of 1993. This Act and the regulations which implement it govern employee political activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5213.3.</num>
    <text>Authority employees may engage in outside employment or private business provided they meet the following conditions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An Authority employee may not engage in any outside employment or other activity which interferes with the full and proper discharge of his or her duties and responsibilities as an Authority employee.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Each independent outside professional activity shall be conducted on the employee&amp;#8217;s own time without the use of Authority facilities, funds, supplies, staff or resources unless the activities are authorized and approved by the Authority
        in writing before they are initiated.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Each outside professional activity is not in conflict with any activity or policy of the Authority.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any outside employment, private business activity or other interest shall not impair an employee&amp;#8217;s mental or physical capacity to such an extent that he or she can no longer carry out his or her duties and responsibilities as an Authority
        employee in a proper and efficient manner</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5213.4.</num>
    <text>An employee of the Authority who worked for a contractor or was a contractor doing business with the Authority is prohibited from supervising, directing or reviewing the work of such contractor. The General Manager may, under circumstance deemed to
      be in the best interests of the Authority, waive this prohibition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5213.5.</num>
    <text>The relative of an Authority employee as defined in ยง 5202.6 may not work for a contractor on a project at the Authority for which the Authority employee has any direct responsibility or supervision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5213.6.</num>
    <text>No Authority employee or authorized representative shall disclose proprietary or confidential information belonging to the Authority to any person other than Authority employees and authorized representatives who need access to the information as
      part of their duties for the Authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5213.7.</num>
    <text>Conflicts of Interest for Former Employees</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A former employee, who voluntarily leaves their employment with the Authority in good standing, is prohibited for 18 months after leaving their employment with the Authority, from working for a contractor on an Authority project on which the employee
        directly worked. The General Manager may reduce this limitation period if it is determined that it is in the best interests of the Authority after a review and recommendation by the General Counsel.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any person whose employment is terminated by the Authority other than pursuant to a reduction in force, is permanently barred from working on any Authority contract or project.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 6868 (June 20, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>