<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-528</num>
  <heading>STORMWATER MANAGEMENT[COLON] MAINTENANCE (§ 21-528)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>528.1.</num>
    <text>Each owner or designee of each lot and parcel that is part of a site that undertook a major regulated project shall be responsible for maintenance required by the Stormwater Management Plan (SWMP) approved by the Department and shall record that responsibility
      in a declaration of covenants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>528.2.</num>
    <text>The Department may assign maintenance responsibility for a Shared Best Management Practice (S-BMP) in an approved SWMP after considering:</text>
    <text>How maintenance will be achieved;</text>
    <text>Each lot and parcel’s responsibility relative to its reliance on each S-BMP and land cover to comply with this chapter;</text>
    <text>Administrative feasibility; and</text>
    <text>Accountability and enforceability.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>528.3.</num>
    <text>The owner, governmental agency, or other person with maintenance responsibility shall ensure that a Best Management Practice (BMP) and a land cover on a lot or parcel is maintained in good working order if:</text>
    <text>The BMP or land cover was installed to meet the requirements of this chapter for a major regulated project; or</text>
    <text>The Department certified a Stormwater Retention Credit for a gallon of retention capacity created by the BMP or land cover.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>528.4.</num>
    <text>Natural land cover employed to comply with a retention requirement in this chapter shall not be converted to compacted or impervious land cover, unless the loss of retention capacity associated with the land conversion will be:</text>
    <text>Offset by a corresponding increase in retention capacity elsewhere on the site that complies with the requirements of this chapter; or</text>
    <text>Offset by a corresponding increase in use of off-site retention that complies with the requirements of this chapter; and</text>
    <text>The Department approves a change to the previously approved SWMP for the site, showing how the loss of retention capacity will be offset.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>528.5.</num>
    <text>Compacted land cover employed to comply with a retention requirement in this chapter shall not be converted to impervious land cover, unless the loss of retention capacity associated with the land conversion will be:</text>
    <text>Offset by a corresponding increase in retention capacity elsewhere on the site that complies with the requirements of this chapter; or</text>
    <text>Offset by a corresponding increase in use of off-site retention that complies with the requirements of this chapter; and</text>
    <text>The Department approves a change to the previously approved SWMP for the site, showing how the loss of retention capacity will be offset.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>528.6.</num>
    <text>Maintenance of each BMP and land cover shall comply with the applicable Department-approved SWMP, including promptly repairing and restoring each:</text>
    <text>Grade surface;</text>
    <text>Wall;</text>
    <text>Drain;</text>
    <text>Structure;</text>
    <text>Foundation;</text>
    <text>Sign;</text>
    <text>Plant; and</text>
    <text>Erosion or sediment control measure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>528.7.</num>
    <text>If the Department finds that a BMP or land cover is not being properly maintained:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Department may require that the condition be corrected; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The governmental agency, owner, or other person charged with maintenance responsibility shall correct the condition.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>528.8.</num>
    <text>If an owner or other person charged with maintenance responsibility fails or refuses to correct a condition as the Department directs, the Department may:</text>
    <text>Declare the owner or person out of compliance;</text>
    <text>Take corrective action itself or through its contractor;</text>
    <text>Assess the cost incurred and fees; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Assess a fine or penalty.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>528.9.</num>
    <text>If the Department determines that the condition of a BMP or land cover presents an actual or imminent harm to the environment or the public health, the Department may:</text>
    <text>Declare the owner or other person charged with maintenance responsibility to be out of compliance;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Take protective and corrective action itself or through its contractor without prior notice to the owner;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Assess the cost incurred and fees; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Assess a fine or penalty.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>528.10.</num>
    <text>Used soil media removed from a BMP receiving drainage from an area intended for use or storage of motor vehicles shall not be re-used for planting or as fill material and shall be disposed of in a landfill or at a transfer station for transport to
      a landfill.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>528.11.</num>
    <text>Non-vegetative waste material from cleaning, maintaining, repairing, and replacing a BMP shall be disposed of in a landfill, trash transfer station, or other facility for processing these materials in accordance with District and Federal law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 21 (January 1, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10640 (July 19, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>