<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-5499</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 21-5499)
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following words and phrases shall have theeanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Backflow &amp;#8211; a reversal of the flow of water caused by a loss in waterressure. This reversal may allow other liquids, gases or mixtures of substanceso enter into the potable water supply.</text>
    <text>Backflow Preventer &amp;#8211; a device approved by the General Manager or his orer designee for a water supply pipe to prevent the backflow of water into theater supply system from the connections on its outlet end.</text>
    <text>Contaminant &amp;#8211; any substance in the Potable Water Supply that creates aazard to human health when its level exceeds the standards established underhe Safe Drinking Water Act, 42 U.S.C. ยง 300(f) et. seq..</text>
    <text>Cross-connection &amp;#8211; an actual or potential link between any part of aotable water system and any other environment of liquid, gas, solid or mixturef substances in a manner that, under any circumstances, would allow suchubstances to enter
      the potable water system.</text>
    <text>General Manager &amp;#8211; the chief administrative officer of the District ofolumbia Water and Sewer Authority or his or her designee.</text>
    <text>Interior Plumbing &amp;#8211; part of plumbing system that includes the water supplyo the building and distribution pipes within the building or premises; plumbingixtures and traps; soil, waste and vent pipes; and sanitary and storm sewersnd building
      drains; including their respective connections, devices andppurtenances within a building or premises.</text>
    <text>Owner &amp;#8211; any individual, corporation, association or partnership listed ashe legal titleholder of record or his or her agent, including whereppropriate, agents and agencies of the government of the United States ofmerica.</text>
    <text>Pollutant &amp;#8211; any substance in the water supply that renders it to bensuitable or unacceptable for drinking.</text>
    <text>Potable Water Supply &amp;#8211; water distributed by WASA that meets theequirements of the Safe Drinking Water Act (42 U.S.C. ยง 300(f) et seq.) and istherwise suitable and acceptable for drinking.</text>
    <text>Private Water System &amp;#8211; the water service pipe, water distribution pipes,ny necessary connecting pipes, fittings, control valves, hydrants, and allppurtenances in or adjacent to the building(s) or premises.</text>
    <text>WASA &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority or its lawfulgent, representative, successor in interest, assign or designee.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 1743 (February 23, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>