<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-530</num>
  <heading>STORMWATER MANAGEMENT[COLON] IN-LIEU FEE (ยง 21-530)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>530.1.</num>
    <text>The base in-lieu fee established by the Department for a purpose of this chapter shall represent the full life-cycle cost for the Department to retain one gallon (1 gal.) of stormwater for one (1) year, including the following costs:</text>
    <text>Project planning;</text>
    <text>Project design;</text>
    <text>Project management;</text>
    <text>Construction and installation;</text>
    <text>Operations and maintenance;</text>
    <text>Project financing;</text>
    <text>Land acquisition;</text>
    <text>Administration of the in-lieu fee program; and</text>
    <text>Legal support for the in-lieu fee program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>530.2</num>
    <text>530.2 The Department shall annually adjust the base in-lieu fee to account for inflation, using the Urban Consumer Price Index published by the United States Bureau of Labor Statistics.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>530.3.</num>
    <text>The Department may re-evaluate the costs underlying the in-lieu fee and re-base the in-lieu fee as the Department determines necessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>530.4.</num>
    <text>The Department shall provide notice in the D.C. Register prior to re-basing the in-lieu fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>530.5.</num>
    <text>An in-lieu fee payment shall be based on the in-lieu fee in effect at the time payment is made.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>530.6.</num>
    <text>An in-lieu fee payment shall:</text>
    <text>Be used solely to achieve increased retention in the District of Columbia;</text>
    <text>Be used to achieve increased retention in the Anacostia watershed, if the payment achieves Off-Site Retention Volume for an Anacostia Waterfront Development Zone site.</text>
    <text>Be deposited in the Stormwater In-Lieu Fee Payment Special Purpose Revenue Fund, established by The Water Pollution Control Act of 1984, effective March 16, 1985, as amended (D.C. Law 5-188; D.C. Official Code ยง 8-103.01 et seq.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 21 (January 1, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10640 (July 19, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>