<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-519</num>
  <heading>STORMWATER MANAGEMENT[COLON] PLAN (§ 21-519)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>519.1</num>
    <text>519.1 A Department-approved stormwater management plan (SWMP) shall:</text>
    <text>Govern all construction for which stormwater management is required;</text>
    <text>Govern all applicable maintenance activities; and</text>
    <text>Demonstrate compliance with this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>519.2.</num>
    <text>A submitted SWMP and supporting documentation shall contain information sufficient for the Department to determine whether the SWMP complies with this chapter including:</text>
    <text>Existing site conditions, including the identification and location of each existing Best Management Practice (BMP) and whether it will remain on the site and in use or will be removed;</text>
    <text>Proposed site design;</text>
    <text>Each land use proposed for the site;</text>
    <text>Identification and location of each proposed BMP, including geographic coordinates;</text>
    <text>Design and performance of each BMP for stormwater retention, detention, and treatment;</text>
    <text>Conveyance capacity of stormwater infrastructure;</text>
    <text>Environmental characteristics of the site;</text>
    <text>Pre- and post-development hydrologic computations, including:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Calculation of required stormwater management volume for:</text>
    </level>
    <text>The entire site; and</text>
    <text>Each individual drainage area; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>On-site and off-site retention volumes;</text>
    </level>
    <text>Maintenance plan and schedule for each proposed BMP;</text>
    <text>Monitoring plan for each BMP that captures stormwater for use;</text>
    <text>For each proposed BMP not included in the Department’s Stormwater Management Guidebook (SWMG):</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Separate identification and description; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Documentation of performance and effectiveness;</text>
    </level>
    <text>Construction sequence for:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Each BMP; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The related development or improvement project, if any.</text>
    </level>
    <text>A list of the construction and waste material to be stored on site and a description of the material and each pollution control measure that will be implemented to minimize exposure to stormwater discharge, including:</text>
    <text>Each storage practice;</text>
    <text>A spill prevention response;</text>
    <text>The United States Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) identification number, or copy of application to EPA for identification number, for each hazardous waste that will be stored on site; and</text>
    <text>Proof of payment of each applicable fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>519.3.</num>
    <text>The retention capacity of each BMP in a SWMP shall be calculated using the applicable equations for calculating retention value in Chapter three (3) of the Department’s Stormwater Management Guidebook.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>519.4.</num>
    <text>The pollutant removal efficiency of each BMP in a SWMP shall be calculated using the applicable equation in Chapter three (3) of the Department’s SWMG.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>519.5.</num>
    <text>The Department may require for each area that a project proposes for use to meet the requirements of this chapter, including a contiguous area or an area with a shared BMP:</text>
    <text>Information listed in this section; or</text>
    <text>A SWMP.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>519.6.</num>
    <text>A submitted SWMP shall use:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A standard drawing size of twenty-four inches by thirty-six inches (24 in. x 36 in);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>One (1) of the following horizontal scales of profile, unless otherwise approved:</text>
    </level>
    <text>One inch equals ten feet (1 in. = 10 ft.);</text>
    <text>One inch equals twenty feet (1 in. = 20 ft.);</text>
    <text>One inch equals thirty feet (1 in. = 30 ft.);</text>
    <text>One inch equals forty feet (1 in. = 40 ft.);</text>
    <text>One inch equals fifty feet (1 in. = 50 ft.); or</text>
    <text>One inch equals eighty feet (1 in. = 80 ft.);</text>
    <text>One (1) of the following vertical scales of profile, unless otherwise approved:</text>
    <text>One inch equals two feet (1 in. = 2 ft.);</text>
    <text>One inch equals four feet (1 in. = 4 ft.);</text>
    <text>One inch equals five feet (1 in. = 5 ft.); or</text>
    <text>One inch equals ten feet (1 in = 10 ft.); and</text>
    <text>Drafting media that yield first or second generation reproducible drawings with a minimum letter size of No. 4 (1/8 inch).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>519.7.</num>
    <text>A SWMP shall not be approved without the signature and seal of the Director or the Director’s designee on the plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>519.8.</num>
    <text>For each as-built SWMP that an applicant submits to the Department, an applicant shall provide that a professional engineer licensed in the District of Columbia, certifies with seal and signature that:</text>
    <text>The design, and installation for an as-built plan:</text>
    <text>Conforms to engineering principles applicable to stormwater management; and</text>
    <text>Complies with the requirements of this chapter; and</text>
    <text>A set of instructions for operation and maintenance of each BMP has been provided to the applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>519.9.</num>
    <text>A SWMP for a project shall be consistent with each other project submittal, including:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An erosion and sediment control plan; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A floodplain management plan.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>519.10.</num>
    <text>The approved SWMP for a major regulated project shall be available on site for Department review for the entire period of construction during ordinary business hours.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10640 (July 19, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>