<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-516</num>
  <heading>STORMWATER MANAGEMENT[COLON] APPLICABILITY (§ 21-516)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>516.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall engage in a major regulated project unless the Department has issued an approved stormwater management plan (SWMP) for the project.</text>
    <text>Application for Department approval of a SWMP for a major regulated project shall be made by at least one (1) of the following persons:</text>
    <text>The owner of a property on which a major regulated project is planned;</text>
    <text>The lessee who undertakes a major regulated project, with the owner’s permission, on a property that the lessee has leased; or</text>
    <text>The agent of the owner or lessee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>516.3.</num>
    <text>In preparing and implementing a SWMP, or a part of a SWMP, a person must comply with:</text>
    <text>This chapter;</text>
    <text>The terms and conditions of the SWMP once approved; and</text>
    <text>The Department’s orders and directions to achieve compliance with the approved SWMP.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>516.4.</num>
    <text>A major regulated project shall comply with the requirements and procedures of this chapter unless a provision exempts compliance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>516.5.</num>
    <text>The owner of a site on which a major regulated project occurs and each person to whom the owner has designated responsibility for management of the site shall ensure that the site complies with the approved SWMP for the site until site redevelopment
      that follows a Department-approved SWMP occurs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>516.6.</num>
    <text>Responsibility for compliance with an approved SWMP for a site shall pass to a subsequent owner of the site and each person to whom that owner designates responsibility for the management of the site until site redevelopment that follows a Department-approved
      SWMP occurs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>516.7.</num>
    <text>No person shall engage in a project for the generation of a Stormwater Retention Credit unless the Department has issued an approved SWMP for the project, except as otherwise provided in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10640 (July 19, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>