<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-5408</num>
  <heading>GROUNDS AND PROCEDURE FOR DENIAL, SUPSENSION, OR REVOCATION OF CERTIFICATION (ยง1-5408)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5408.1.</num>
    <text>A backflow preventer tester certification shall be subject to denial, suspension, or revocation for the following causes:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Material misstatement in application for certification;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Willful failure or refusal to comply with any provision of statute or regulation relating to plumbing or water and sanitation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Fraud;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Willful misrepresentation or concealment through any subterfuge or device of any matter or the nature of any matter required by the chapter to be stated or furnished;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Willful employment of any fraudulent or misleading device, method, or practice in connection with the testing of backflow preventers; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Incompetence.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5408.2.</num>
    <text>Whenever the General Manager finds that an applicant for a certificate under this chapter is deficient in one or more of the certificate qualifications or whenever the General Manager has reasonable grounds to believe that there has been a violation
      of any statute or regulation applicable to plumbing or water and sanitation for which the tester is subject to suspension or revocation, the General Manager shall give written notice to the applicant or certificate holder in accordance with the
      provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5408.3.</num>
    <text>The notice required by ยง 5408.2 shall state with specificity the grounds for the suspension, revocation or denial.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5408.4.</num>
    <text>Any person who has received a notice of denial, suspension or revocation may file a written notice of appeal pursuant to chapter 400 of this Title. The notice of appeal shall be filed no later than fifteen (15) days after the date of the notice of
      denial.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 1743 (February 23, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>