<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-503</num>
  <heading>INSPECTIONS, NOTICES OF WORK, AND APPROVALS OF CHANGES (§ 21-503)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>503.1.</num>
    <text>The Department may conduct an inspection of an activity regulated under this chapter, including emergency work that may otherwise be exempt, to ensure compliance with this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>503.2.</num>
    <text>The Department may require a change to an approved plan if the Department determines that a discrepancy between site conditions and the approved plan makes the plan inadequate to comply with the requirements of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>503.3.</num>
    <text>A person may not change an approved plan or its implementation without Department approval, as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If the change is substantial, the person shall resubmit the revised plan to the Department for approval in accordance with this chapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the change is not substantial, the person may secure written approval from the Department in the field or at the Department’s office.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>503.4.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this chapter, a substantial change in an approved plan is a change in design, specification, construction, operation, or maintenance that the Department determines:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>May result in a failure to comply with a requirement of this chapter; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Has a significant effect on the discharge of pollutants to the District’s waters.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>503.5.</num>
    <text>The Department may require an additional inspection at a particular stage of construction by specifying that requirement in:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The approved plan;</text>
    </level>
    <text>The preconstruction inspection report; or</text>
    <text>The Department’s report of the preconstruction meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>503.6.</num>
    <text>No person may proceed with work past a stage of construction that the Department has identified as requiring an inspection unless:</text>
    <text>The Department’s inspector has issued an “approved” or “passed” report;</text>
    <text>The Department has approved a plan modification that eliminates the inspection requirement; or</text>
    <text>The Department otherwise eliminates or modifies the inspection requirement in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>503.7.</num>
    <text>A person shall communicate with the Department:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>In order to schedule a preconstruction meeting or field visit before commencement of a land-disturbing activity, contact the Department at least three (3) business days before the start of the land-disturbing activity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>In order to schedule a preconstruction inspection before beginning construction of a Best Management Practice (BMP), contact the Department at least three (3) business days before the start of the construction;</text>
    </level>
    <text>In order to schedule an inspection required for a stage of construction or other construction event, contact the Department at least three (3) business days before the anticipated inspection;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>For the completion of a land-disturbing activity, give notice to the Department within two (2) weeks of completion of the activity; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>For the completion of a BMP, and to request a final construction inspection, give the Department one (1) week’s notice.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>503.8.</num>
    <text>The Department shall make reasonable efforts to accommodate a request for inspection outside of the Department’s normal business hours if the request:</text>
    <text>Is made during the Department’s normal business hours;</text>
    <text>Includes the information the Department requires, including the matters to be inspected, the location of the site work to be inspected, and details for site access; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Includes payment or proof of payment of the after-hours inspection fee.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>503.9.</num>
    <text>The Department shall determine whether work, construction, and maintenance complies with each approved plan, including conducting a final construction inspection and ongoing maintenance inspections of each BMP, land cover, and the site.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>503.10.</num>
    <text>The Department may require inspections, on a periodic or as-needed basis, of a BMP, land cover, and the site to ensure that maintenance is sufficient to achieve performance or eligibility requirements and to avoid harm to the environment or public
      health.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>503.11.</num>
    <text>A person shall allow the Department, upon presentation of Department credentials, to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Enter premises where a practice, measure, or activity subject to this chapter is located or conducted, or where required records are kept, including locations where a retention BMP or land cover is voluntarily installed to generate a Stormwater
        Retention Credit or receive a stormwater fee discount;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Access and copy a required record;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Inspect a site, practice, measure, or activity subject to this chapter, including to verify sufficient maintenance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Conduct sampling, testing, monitoring, or analysis.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>503.12.</num>
    <text>The Department may require as a precondition to its approval of an inspection that the applicant:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Make available to the Department for the purposes of the inspection on site, or at the Department’s offices, the professional engineer responsible for certifying the &amp;#8220;as-built&amp;#8221; plans; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Secure the seal and signature of this professional engineer certifying that the as-built plans comply with this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>503.13.</num>
    <text>Upon notice, a person shall promptly correct work which the Department has found fails to comply with an approved plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>503.14.</num>
    <text>The Department shall not approve the issuance of a certificate of occupancy for a building until the Department has determined that the approved stormwater management plan for the building site has been implemented for:</text>
    <text>On-site stormwater management; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Required off-site retention.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE Section 2 of the Soil Erosion and Sedimentation Control Act of 1977 (D.C. Law 2-23; 24 DCR 792 (July 22, 1977)), 8 DCRR §8-2:</heading>
      <text>804, Health Regulations (1965 Edition); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10640 (July 19, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>