<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-523</num>
  <heading>STORMWATER MANAGEMENT[COLON] RESTRICTIONS (§ 21-523)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>523.1.</num>
    <text>The Department may restrict use of an infiltration Best Management Practice (BMP) to prevent contamination of soil or groundwater and require submittal of and compliance with a Stormwater Pollution Prevention Plan if:</text>
    <text>An applicant proposes to engage in a land use activity that has the potential to pollute stormwater runoff, as specified in the Department’s Stormwater Management Guidebook (SWMG); or</text>
    <text>Surface contamination is present at the site.</text>
    <text>To prevent stormwater migration in underlying soil or groundwater in an area determined to have sub-surface contamination of soil or groundwater, the Department may:</text>
    <text>Prohibit use of an infiltration BMP; or</text>
    <text>Limit use of an infiltration BMP, including by requiring that an impermeable liner be used.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>523.3.</num>
    <text>The Department may require a BMP that receives runoff from a stormwater hotspot designated in the Department’s SWMG to include pollution control measures, including, as applicable, a baffle, skimmer, oil separator, grease trap, or other mechanism
      which prevents release of oil and grease in concentrations exceeding ten milligrams per Liter (10 mg/L).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>523.4.</num>
    <text>The Department may require a BMP that receives runoff from an animal confinement area to:</text>
    <text>Connect to a combined sewer, if DC Water approves the connection as not exceeding available capacity; or</text>
    <text>Include pollution control measures necessary to protect water quality standards of the receiving waterbody, if the runoff discharges directly to a waterbody or through the separate sewer system.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>523.5.</num>
    <text>No person shall use a coal tar product, or other toxic material, to seal a BMP.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10640 (July 19, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>