<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-525</num>
  <heading>STORMWATER MANAGEMENT[COLON] SHARED BEST MANAGEMENT PRACTICE (§ 21-525)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>525.1.</num>
    <text>A Shared Best Management Practice (S-BMP) may, upon approval by the Department:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Provide stormwater management for a major regulated project in satisfaction of an on-site stormwater management requirement of that project; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be eligible for Department certification of a Stormwater Retention Credit (SRC).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>525.2.</num>
    <text>A Department-approved S-BMP may provide stormwater management for a nearby property if:</text>
    <text>Stormwater flow from the nearby property is directly conveyed to the S-BMP; and</text>
    <text>The S-BMP has sufficient capacity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>525.3.</num>
    <text>To obtain Department approval of the use of an existing S-BMP, a major regulated project shall show how each requirement of the project will be met by the S-BMP, including:</text>
    <text>Submit an as-built Stormwater Management Plan (SWMP) for the S-BMP that is accurate as of the time of submittal;</text>
    <text>Prove sufficient capacity of the S-BMP;</text>
    <text>Demonstrate the adequacy of each stormwater conveyance from the major regulated project to the S-BMP; and</text>
    <text>Show each drainage area conveying stormwater into the S-BMP from the major regulated project.</text>
    <text>To obtain Department approval of the use of a proposed S-BMP, a major regulated project shall show how each requirement of the project will be met by the S-BMP, including:</text>
    <text>Submit a Department-approved SWMP for the S-BMP;</text>
    <text>Prove sufficient capacity of the S-BMP;</text>
    <text>Demonstrate the adequacy of each stormwater conveyance from the major regulated project to the S-BMP; and</text>
    <text>Show each drainage area conveying stormwater into the S-BMP from the major regulated project.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>525.5.</num>
    <text>A major regulated project that uses a S-BMP to meet a requirement shall not pass the Department’s final inspection until the S-BMP passes the Department’s final inspection and is operational.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>525.6.</num>
    <text>After an alteration to a S-BMP to provide stormwater management for another site, the site with the S-BMP shall:</text>
    <text>Pass the Department’s inspection; and</text>
    <text>Submit an as-built SWMP, showing each area draining into the S-BMP and the means of conveyance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>525.7.</num>
    <text>The Department may certify a SRC for a S-BMP if the S-BMP meets each requirement for certification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>525.8.</num>
    <text>A site with a S-BMP that provides a volume of stormwater management to satisfy an on-site requirement of a major regulated project shall be responsible for maintenance of the S-BMP capacity to manage that volume and shall record that responsibility
      in a declaration of covenants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>525.9.</num>
    <text>If the Department determines that a S-BMP has ceased satisfying an on-site retention requirement for a site that underwent a major regulated project, the site shall be responsible for retaining the required volume on site or via use of off-site retention.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10640 (July 19, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>