<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-540</num>
  <heading>SOIL EROSION AND SEDIMENT CONTROL[COLON] APPLICABILITY (§ 21-540)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>540.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall engage in razing or land-disturbing activity, including stripping, clearing, grading, grubbing, excavating, and filling of land, without obtaining the Department’s approval of a soil erosion and sediment control plan, unless exempted
      in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>540.2.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any exemptions provided in this chapter, a person who engages in a demolition project that results in debris, dust, or sediment leaving the site shall apply each necessary control measure, upon receiving instruction to do so by the
      Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>540.3</num>
    <text>540.3 Notwithstanding any exemptions provided in this chapter, a person who exposes erodible material and causes erosion shall apply each necessary control measure, upon receiving instruction to do so by the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>540.4.</num>
    <text>A person who applies for Department approval of a soil erosion and sediment control plan shall be the owner of the property where the activity is to take place.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>540.5.</num>
    <text>The approved soil erosion and sediment control plan shall govern all construction work requiring the control of soil erosion and sediment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>540.6.</num>
    <text>At the Director’s discretion, the Department may establish conditions for a general or blanket approval of soil erosion and sediment control plans that are solely covering specified activities carried out under and complying with specifications approved
      by the Department. These conditions may include requirements for an applicant to provide notice to the Department and comply with inspections as would normally be required under this chapter. The Department shall establish and revise any such conditions
      as necessary and publish them on its website as updates to the District of Columbia Standards and Specifications for Soil Erosion and Sediment Control.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 1033 (July 28, 1978); incorporating text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 24 DCR 10522 (June 9, 1978); 8 DCRR, Health Regulations (1965 Edition); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10640 (July
        19, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>