<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-604</num>
  <heading>RIPARIAN RIGHTS AND WATER PRIVILEGES PETITIONS (ยง 21-604)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>604.1.</num>
    <text>Any person, corporation, association or other entity owning land, with riparian rights or water privileges appurtenant to that land, bordering any waters or having the right to possession of that land and appurtenances, or having riparian rights or
      water privileges in those waters, may file a petition in writing, to the Department seeking any or all of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Fixation of the boundaries of riparian or water privileges in which the petitioner is interested within the pierhead line in those waters; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A permit to deposit artificial fill within the bulkhead line in those waters.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>604.2.</num>
    <text>Each petition shall consist of an original and four copies, addressed to the Mayor, and duly verified by the petitioner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>604.3.</num>
    <text>A filing fee of twenty-five dollars ($25), payable to the order of the D.C. Treasurer, shall be paid upon the filing of each petition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>604.4.</num>
    <text>Each petition (and copy of a petition) filed under this section shall have attached to it a blueprint showing the area involved.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>604.5.</num>
    <text>Each petition shall name as respondents all persons, corporations, and associations whose interests will be affected by the prayers for relief in the petition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>604.6.</num>
    <text>Within ten (10) days (unless the Mayor shall for cause extend that time) after the filing of the petition, each petitioner shall file with the Mayor an affidavit showing that a copy of the petition was served upon each party named as respondent in
      the petition personally or by mail, postage prepaid, to the last known address of the respondent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>604.7.</num>
    <text>If the petitioner fails to name and serve all interested parties, the Mayor shall have the right to defer any hearing in the matter until the petitioner establishes by affidavit that all interested parties have been served as provided for in this
      chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>604.8.</num>
    <text>Each party served shall have ten (10) days from the date of service upon that party to file a response setting forth any objections or consent to the relief, action, or permit sought in the petition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order No. 54-576, dated March 16, 1954, 5T DCRR ยง3.1 (September 21, 1970).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>