<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-732</num>
  <heading>SOLID WASTE FACILITY PERMIT TERMS AND CONDITIONS (ยง 21-732)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>732.1.</num>
    <text>If the Director concludes that an application for a solid waste facility permit should be granted, the Director shall issue a solid waste facility permit which shall specify, as the Director determines, the following operating requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The types of solid waste which can be delivered to the solid waste facility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The solid waste processing and disposal procedures to be followed by the solid waste facility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The annual and, if appropriate, daily, weekly or monthly tonnage limits of solid waste which may be delivered to the solid waste facility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The solid waste facility&amp;#8217;s approved days and hours of operation. Except as provided in subparagraph (d)(4) of this subsection, or as may be modified by the Zoning Commission or the Board of Zoning Adjustment, the days and hours of operation
        in accordance with subparagraphs (d)(1) through (d)(3) as follows:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Solid waste facilities located within three hundred feet (300 ft.) of a residential property line shall be precluded from operating between the hours of 7:00 p.m. and 6:00 a.m. Monday through Saturday;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Solid waste facilities located more than three hundred feet (300 ft.) of a residential property line shall be precluded from operating between the hours of 10:00 p.m. and 6:00 a.m. Monday through Saturday;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Solid waste facilities shall be precluded from operating on Sundays; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Authorization of a solid waste facility to operate on a Sunday, or during hours otherwise prohibited by subparagraphs (d)(1) and (d)(2) may be granted by the Director if the expanded hours of operation do not exceed the limits set by the Zoning
        Commission or the Board of Zoning Adjustment and the applicant proves to the Director&amp;#8217;s satisfaction that the additional hours of operation will not adversely affect the reasonable enjoyment of life and property of persons residing within
        a one-quarter (1/4) mile radius of the facility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any additional insurance required beyond the minimum established by ยง730.3(v); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Other terms and conditions as are necessary to safeguard human health, the public welfare, and the environment, and to assure compliance with the Act and all environmental, health, safety, and zoning laws, rules, and regulations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>732.2.</num>
    <text>Each interim operating permit and solid waste facility permit shall indicate that the terms and conditions of the permit include the obligation of the permittee to abide by all the laws, rules and regulations of the District of Columbia which are
      applicable to solid waste facilities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 43 DCR 6816, 6825 (December 20, 1996).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>