<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-719</num>
  <heading>SOLID WASTE DISPOSAL FEE-SETTING FORMULAS (§ 21-719)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>719.1.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section shall apply to the disposal of each ton of solid waste at the waste-handling facilities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>719.2.</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall establish fee-setting formulas to govern the imposition of solid waste disposal fees. The Mayor may modify the fee-setting formulas on an annual basis.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>719.3</num>
    <text>719.3 The solid waste disposal fee-setting formulas shall be based upon the District government’s expenses for solid waste disposal operations. The Mayor shall take into account the costs of operating the disposal facilities, including the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Maintenance and administrative costs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Engineering services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Debt retirement or debt reserves;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Landfill replacement costs; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Other expenses attributable to operating the District government’s solid waste disposal facilities.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>719.4.</num>
    <text>The solid waste disposal fee-setting formulas may take into account the cost differences that arise from the types of waste disposed, the method of disposal, and the site of disposal. The solid waste disposal fee-setting formulas may be derived by
      averaging total system costs, prorating the costs of disposal at a specific facility, or prorating the cost of disposal for a specific type of waste, whichever, is determined to be most cost effective by the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>719.5.</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall impose a surcharge to be included in the solid waste disposal fee for the purpose of offsetting the cost of implementing and operating the Mayor&amp;#8217;s solid waste reduction and multi-material recycling program. The amount of
      the surcharge shall be included in the solid waste disposal fee-setting formulas.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>719.6.</num>
    <text>The following fee-setting formula is established for the disposal of each ton of construction and demolition debris:</text>
    <text>Solid Waste Disposal Fee for Construction and Demolition Debris + Solid Waste Disposal Fee + Special Handling Costs + Recycling Surcharge</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>719.7.</num>
    <text>The following fee-setting formula is established for the disposal of each ton of vehicle tires:</text>
    <text>Solid Waste Disposal Fee for Vehicle Tires = I-95 Complex Fee = Recycling Surcharge</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>719.8.</num>
    <text>The following fee-setting formula is established for the disposal of each ton of the various recyclable commodities included in the District&amp;#8217;s solid waste reduction and multi-material recycling program:</text>
    <text>Solid Waste Disposal Fee for Recyclable Commodities = Recycling Surcharge</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>719.9.</num>
    <text>The following fee-setting formula is established for the disposal of each ton of solid waste, excluding those wastes specified in §§ 719.6, 719.7 and 719.8:</text>
    <text>Solid Waste Disposal Fee = [Estimated Material Processing Costs ÷ Projected Tonnage] + Recycling Surcharge</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>719.10</num>
    <text>719.10 The following fee-setting formula is established for the disposal of each ton of food waste:</text>
    <text>Solid Waste Disposal Fee for Recyclable Food Waste=Processing cost of recyclable food waste + Recycling Surcharge</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 4238, 4239 (June 29, 1990); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 10959 (December 16, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 2303 (March 19, 2010); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 60 DCR 4833 (March 29, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>