<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-803</num>
  <heading>GALVANIZED METAL CANS FOR UNCOMPACTED SOLID WASTE (§ 21-803)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>803.1.</num>
    <text>The sizes and minimum weight per dozen of the can covered shall be as prescribed in Table 1:</text>
    <text>Tabel 1 &amp;#8211; Galvanized Mental Can (Hot-dipped)</text>
    <text>Used For Containment of Solid Waste (Refuse)</text>
    <text>Nominal Size*</text>
    <text>Minimum Weight Per</text>
    <text>Dozen Finished**</text>
    <text>Standard No</text>
    <text>0020</text>
    <text>0026</text>
    <text>0032</text>
    <text>Gallons</text>
    <text>20</text>
    <text>26</text>
    <text>32</text>
    <text>Lb./Avdp.</text>
    <text>140</text>
    <text>160</text>
    <text>170</text>
    <text>* The capacity or dimension of cans shall not be less than ninety-five percent (95%) of the nominal size.</text>
    <text>** Weight includes cover when finished with items.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.2.</num>
    <text>The basic metal of bodies, bottoms, bands, covers stamped handles, and clips shall be of a good grade of sheet steel having the strength, rigidity, and quality necessary for the production of hot-dipped galvanized ware conforming to these specifications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.3.</num>
    <text>Top wires and size handles shall be of drawn-steel wire.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.4.</num>
    <text>Rivets shall be of high-grade soft steel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.5.</num>
    <text>Top-wire shall be full length (not spliced) with ends separated not more than one-half inch (1/2 in.) and fully enclosed except where exposed for forming ears.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.6.</num>
    <text>Handles and handle clips shall be of ample strength and so attached that no permanent deformation shall occur when samples of cans are tested as prescribed in §803.14.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.7.</num>
    <text>All cans shall be water tight when tested as prescribed in §803.13.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.8.</num>
    <text>After fabrication and cleaning, each can shall be completely zinc-coated by the hot-dip process. The coating shall be smooth, continuous and thorough. It shall be free from such imperfections as lumps, slivers, blisters, gritty areas, uncoated spots,
      acid and black spots, dross and flux.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.9.</num>
    <text>As per A-123, §3, the grade of zinc used in the coating shall be at least equal to Prime Western and conform to ASTM B6, for zinc metal (slab zinc).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.10.</num>
    <text>The weight of coating on the finished cans shall not be less than one and one-half ounces per square foot (1.5 oz./ft.2), as determined by the method prescribed in §803.16. The weight of the coating is the total amount on both sides of the steel sheet,
      expressed in ounces per square foot (oz. /ft.2: total for both sides). The coating shall be sufficiently tight to withstand the test prescribed in §803.15.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.11.</num>
    <text>Workmanship shall ensure production of cans free from defects impairing their water-tightness, serviceability, or durability. All rivets shall be securely set and all welds shall be sound and smooth.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.12.</num>
    <text>Sufficient samples of galvanized ware shall be selected at random from each lot of each container produced during the process of manufacture as are needed to maintain quality of the product so as to be consistently in conformance with these specifications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.13.</num>
    <text>Samples of containers intended to hold liquid shall be taken at random. Each sample selected shall be filled with water and allowed to stand for twenty-four (24) hours. To be acceptable under this test, there shall be no indications of leakage during
      this period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.14.</num>
    <text>Samples taken at random shall be filled with dry sand to half capacity and suspended from the handles for a period of five (5) minutes. Measurements shall be made before and after test to determine whether any permanent deformation of handles or handle
      clips, or top diameter has occurred.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.15.</num>
    <text>After inspection, the samples selected for tests shall be struck a blow with a half pound (1/2 lb.) ball-pein hammer with sufficient force to dent the metal. The coating shall be adherent and no peeling shall result.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.16.</num>
    <text>The weight of coating shall be determined by the standard spot test method as described in ASTM A-90, Methods of Test for Weight of Coating on Zinc Coated (galvanized) Iron or Steel Articles.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.17.</num>
    <text>All approved galvanized metal cans distributed, sold or used for the containment of solid waste (refuse) in the District shall contain the following printed statement on a pressure sensitive backed label affixed to the container in a conspicuous location:</text>
    <text>This container ware meets all requirements of the applicable D.C. Standard (D.C.1-1-GI) issued by the Department of Public Works by:</text>
    <text>(Name of Manufacturer)</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.18.</num>
    <text>The display of the statement of approval on a galvanized metal can shall be considered the manufacturer&amp;#8217;s certification that the container conforms to the specification and testing procedures prescribed in this section. Each galvanized metal
      can shall have marked on it the name and address of the principal place of business of the manufacturer or distributor of the can, and a code identifying the date and location of the container&amp;#8217;s manufacture and the number issued by the
      District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Pinal Rulemaking published at 26 DCR 6221 (January 5, 1979), incorporating text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 359 (November 3, 1978); 5T DCRR §§8(a)-(1) (September 21, 1970).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>