<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-801</num>
  <heading>PAPER BAGS FOR UNCOMPACTED SOLID WASTE (ยง 21-801)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>801.1.</num>
    <text>Paper bags shall be fabricated from new and unused wet-strength kraft paper, wholly extensible or wholly non-extensible or equivalent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.2.</num>
    <text>All wet-strength paper shall be distinctly marked on the outer surface for identification by longitudinal stripes spaced not less than two inches (2 in.) nor more than ten inches (10 in.) apart across the paper width, and each stripe shall be not
      less than one eighth inch (1/8 in.) in width. No other grade of paper used in the bags shall be striped in this manner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.3.</num>
    <text>For multi-ply bags, the identification marking shall appear on the external surface of the bag.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.4.</num>
    <text>The non-extensible paper used to construct single-ply or multi-ply bags shall be a nominal basis weight of one hundred pounds (100 lbs.) per five hundred (500) sheets, and a minimum basis weight of ninety-five pounds (95 lbs.) per five hundred (500)
      sheets. The size of each sheet is twenty-four inches by thirty-six inches (24 in. x 36 in.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.5.</num>
    <text>The extensible or equivalent paper used to construct single-ply or multi-ply bags shall have a nominal basis weight of ninety pounds (90 lbs.) per five hundred (500) sheets, and a minimum basis of eighty-five and one-half pounds (85.5 lbs.) per five
      hundred (500) sheets. The size of each sheet is twenty-four inches by thirty-six inches (24 in. x 36 in.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>801.6.</num>
    <text>Minimum tensile energy absorptions for dry and wet extensible or equivalent paper used in single and multi-ply bags are set forth in Table I:</text>
    <text>Table I &amp;#8211; Minimum Tensile</text>
    <text>Energy Absorption &amp;#8211; Extensible</text>
    <text>Single-ply or Multiply Bags</text>
    <text>Cross direction or paper</text>
    <text>Cross direction plus machine direction of paper</text>
    <text>Dry</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9.3</num>
    <text>9.3 ft. lb./ft.2</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>30.8</num>
    <text>30.8 ft. lb./ft.2</text>
    <text>Wet</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2.7</num>
    <text>2.7 ft. lb./ft.2</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>