<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-904</num>
  <heading>PERMITS FOR OTHER METHODS OF DISPOSAL (ยง 21-904)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>904.1.</num>
    <text>Each application for the construction and maintenance of a method for the disposal of human excreta or body wastes other than by an earth-pit privy or a septic tank and subsoil sewage disposal system shall be made in writing on a blank form furnished
      by and filed with the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>904.2.</num>
    <text>The application form shall specify the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The parcel or lot and square numbers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The house number and street; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The type and occupancy of the building or premises to be served.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>904.3.</num>
    <text>The form shall be executed in duplicate, and each copy shall be accompanied by a complete set of detailed working plans of the method proposed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>904.4.</num>
    <text>The Director shall determine whether the method proposed is to be upon an original lot or a subdivisional lot situated on a street where there is a public sewer and watermain available for the use of that lot.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>904.5.</num>
    <text>No permit shall be issued until the Director is satisfied that the method can be maintained without endangering the public health or otherwise creating a nuisance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>904.6.</num>
    <text>The permit for the maintenance of the disposal method shall be issued without cost.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>904.7.</num>
    <text>The permit shall be affixed in a conspicuous place on the inside of the privy, outhouse building, or other place designated by the Director, and shall remain in that place.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order No. 300,417/2, dated August 3, 1944, 8 DCRR C-3312. Health Regulations Supplement.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>