<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-905</num>
  <heading>ADDITIONAL REQUIREMENTS FOR DISPOSAL SYSTEMS (§ 21-905)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>905.1.</num>
    <text>Nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed as relieving the applicant of a duty to comply with the provisions of the D.C. Building Code.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>905.2.</num>
    <text>Every method or system for the reception, disposition, or storage of human excreta or body wastes (either temporarily or permanently) shall be constructed and maintained in a manner which conforms at all times with the requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>905.3.</num>
    <text>The receptacle for receiving and storing human excreta or body wastes shall be fly-tight, and shall be constructed in a manner and of material which will afford reasonable assurance of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That the receptacle will remain fly-tight under ordinary conditions of use;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That the receptacle will not deteriorate rapidly;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>That the receptacle will provide adequate capacity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>That the receptacle will facilitate maintenance in a satisfactory manner under ordinary conditions of use; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>That the receptacle will be convenient and accessible to use.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>905.4.</num>
    <text>The receptacle shall be located to prevent the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Pollution of a public or private water supply;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Pollution of a pond, pool, bathing place, lake, or stream;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Overflow of the contents to the surrounding ground; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Flow of surface water into the receptacle.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>905.5.</num>
    <text>If scavenger service is necessary, the receptacle shall be convenient and accessible for the rendering of that service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order No. 300 417/2, dated August 3, 1944, 8 DCRR §§C-340, C-3310, C-3311 and C-3312, Health Regulations Supplement.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR&amp;#8217;S NOTE</heading>
      <text>The Building Code referred to in this section has been superseded by D.C. Law 6-216, Construction Codes Approval and Amendments Act of 1986, effective March 21, 1987. Section 12 of D.C. Law 6-216 provides that the construction regulations existing
        prior to March 21, 1987, remain in effect for projects having reached specified stages of completion. D.C. Law 6-216 adopted the 1984 National BOCA Codes, and the 1985 D.C. Supplement to the National BOCA Codes. Effective November 27, 1992 (39
        DCR 8665), the 1984 BOCA Codes, and the 1985 D.C. Supplement to the National BOCA Codes were superseded by the adoption of the 1990 BOCA Codes, and the 1992 D.C. Supplement to the BOCA Codes.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>