<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-1204</num>
  <heading>RETAILER&amp;#8217;S BOOKS AND RECORDS (ยง 23-1204)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1204.1</num>
    <text>1204.1 Each holder of a Retailer&amp;#8217;s license shall keep and maintain available upon the licensed premises, either physically or electronically, records which include invoices and delivery slips and which adequately and fully reflect all purchases,
      sales, and deliveries of all alcoholic beverages, except beer, made to it.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1204.2.</num>
    <text>Records shall include and distinctly show the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The quantity in gallons of each kind of beverage purchased in each purchase;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The date of each purchase;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The name and business address of the person from whom purchased with the license number of the vendor, if licensed under the Act;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The price of each kind of beverage purchased with the total price; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The character and brand and quantity in gallons of all beverages, except beer, acquired other than by purchase.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1204.3.</num>
    <text>All invoices and delivery slips required by ยง 1204.1 and all importation permits after cancellation as required by D.C. Official Code ยง 25-119, shall be systematically filed and maintained for a period of three (3) years from date of delivery and
      shall show a true, accurate and complete statement of terms and conditions on which each purchase was made.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11580 (August 9, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>