<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-1208</num>
  <heading>RETENTION AND INSPECTION OF BOOKS AND RECORDS (ยง 23-1208)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1208.1.</num>
    <text>The books and records referred to in this chapter, including the original and duplicate invoices, shall be open to inspection by the Board or its designated agent, and the OTR, during the establishment&amp;#8217;s approved hours of operation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1208.2.</num>
    <text>The holders of Manufacturer&amp;#8217;s and Wholesaler&amp;#8217;s licenses shall keep and maintain all books and records referred to in this chapter on the licensed premises for a period of four (4) years after the latest transaction recorded in
      those books and records.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1208.3.</num>
    <text>The holder of a Retailer&amp;#8217;s license shall keep and maintain all book and records referred to in this chapter on the licensed premises for a period of three (3) years after the latest transaction recorded in those books and records.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1208.4.</num>
    <text>The holder of a Retailer&amp;#8217;s, Manufacturer&amp;#8217;s, or Wholesaler&amp;#8217;s license may maintain its records at a location in the District of Columbia other than the licensed premises with the approval of the Board. Any requested location
      must: (1) maintain both the original and duplicate invoices; and (2) be available for inspection by ABRA investigators at any time during business hours.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1208.5.</num>
    <text>The holder of a Retailer&amp;#8217;s license may maintain its original invoices outside of the District of Columbia upon a determination by the Board that good cause exists. However, duplicate invoices must be maintained in the District of Columbia
      at either the licensed premises or a location approved by the Board and the applicant is responsible for providing the original invoices to the Board within three (3) days of receiving a written request from the Board. Failure to make the original
      invoices available to the Board within three (3) days of its written request shall constitute a violation of ยง 1208.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>