<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-1801</num>
  <heading>PROTEST PETITIONS (ยง 23-1801)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1801.1.</num>
    <text>Petitions in support of or in opposition to a license application for the issuance of a new license, the renewal of an existing license, the transfer of a license to a new location, substantial changes to the nature of the operations of a licensed
      establishment, or a change in license class shall be filed with the Board by the final day of the protest period for the license application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1801.2.</num>
    <text>Petitions filed under ยง 1801.1 shall set forth the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name of the applicant or licensee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The address for which the license is sought;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The class of license requested;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The application number or license number, as appropriate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A brief summary of the reasons for support of or opposition to the granting of the license; provided, that participation in Board proceedings shall not be limited by this summary; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The printed name and address of each petitioner, accompanied by his or her handwritten signature.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1801.3.</num>
    <text>Forms for the filing of Protest Petitions shall be available from ABRA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1801.4.</num>
    <text>Petitions filed pursuant to this section shall not be withdrawn after the date of the protest hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1801.5.</num>
    <text>Protest Petitions which are received by the Board after the fifteen (15) calendar day period specified in ยง 1801.1 shall not be considered by the Board in reaching a decision on any matter and shall be promptly returned to the party or individual
      submitting the petitions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1801.6.</num>
    <text>The Board shall permit any party to a protested case to challenge the validity of signatures on Protest Petitions submitted by the opposing party.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>