<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-1701</num>
  <heading>PARTIES, INTERVENTION, AND RIGHT TO BE HEARD (ยง 23-1701)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1701.1.</num>
    <text>The parties to a show cause hearing shall be the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The respondent, licensee, permittee, or applicant, and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1701.2.</num>
    <text>The parties to a protest hearing shall be the applicant and the protestants and their designated representatives, if any.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1701.3.</num>
    <text>The parties to a fact-finding hearing shall be the licensee, permittee, or applicant for a license, and such other persons whose appearance the Board deems necessary and who are designated by the Board as parties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1701.4.</num>
    <text>The Board may, in its discretion, permit interested persons other than parties, as defined in this chapter, to intervene in a proceeding for such general or limited purpose as the Board may specify.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1701.5.</num>
    <text>A person permitted to intervene under this section shall comply with all conditions fixed by the Board and shall not be considered a party to the proceedings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1701.6.</num>
    <text>At any proceeding before the Board on an application for issuance or renewal of a license, or transfer of a license to a new person or location, the Board shall hear as witnesses all persons residing within and without the neighborhood who desire
      to be heard; provided that such testimony is not irrelevant or duly repetitious.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>