<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-1706</num>
  <heading>APPEARANCE AND REPRESENTATION (ยง 23-1706)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1706.1.</num>
    <text>In any proceeding before the Board, an individual may appear on his or her own behalf.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1706.2.</num>
    <text>In any proceeding before the Board, a general partner of a partnership may represent the partnership, if properly authorized.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1706.3.</num>
    <text>In any proceeding before the Board, an officer of a corporation or association may represent the corporation or association, if authorized to do so by the Board of Directors of the corporation or association.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1706.4.</num>
    <text>A partner or officer appearing pursuant to ยง 1706.2 or 1706.3 may be required to establish his or her authority to act in that capacity;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1706.5.</num>
    <text>Any party appearing or having the right to appear before the Board in any proceeding shall have the right to representation by an attorney or designated representative of his or her choice. Any party appearing before the Board in any proceeding may
      also bring an interpreter of his or her choice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1706.6.</num>
    <text>The provisions of ยง 1706.5 shall not infringe upon the authority of the Board under ยง 1706.7 to require representation of a party.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1706.7.</num>
    <text>If it appears to the Board that the facts or issues in a matter before it are so intricate or involved that, in the interests of justice, of conserving time, or of facilitating preparation of an adequate record, a party ought to be represented by
      an attorney, the Board may urge the party to obtain counsel and shall allow the party a reasonable time in which to do so, as long as the rights of other parties to the hearing are not substantially and adversely affected.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1706.8.</num>
    <text>Any person authorized to appear pursuant to this section may sign any paper required or permitted by statute, regulation, or this chapter to be filed with the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>