<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-1703</num>
  <heading>SERVICE OF PAPERS (ยง 23-1703)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1703.1.</num>
    <text>Any papers filed with the Board in a contested case shall be served by personal delivery, first class U.S. mail, registered or certified mail, or facsimile. An original and six (6) copies of all papers filed with the Board are required, and proof
      of service shall be shown as required in ยง 1703.7.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1703.2.</num>
    <text>Any papers required to be served upon a party may be served upon the party or the party&amp;#8217;s designated representative.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1703.3.</num>
    <text>When a party has appeared through a representative, service shall be made upon the representative of record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1703.4.</num>
    <text>Service upon a party may be made in the following manner:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>By personal delivery;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>By use of a process server;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>By registered or certified mail;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>By telegram; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>As otherwise authorized by law.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1703.5.</num>
    <text>Service upon a party shall be completed upon any of the following acts:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Handing the paper to the person to be served;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Leaving the paper at the licensed premises with a Board-approved manager;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Leaving the paper at the party&amp;#8217;s usual place of residence with some individual of suitable age and discretion residing therein;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Deposit of the paper in the U.S. Mail, by registered or certified mail, properly stamped and addressed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Deposit of the paper with a telegraph company, properly addressed and with charges prepaid;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Deposit of the paper in the U.S. Mail, by first class mail, properly stamped and addressed, by an attorney of record; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>By an action in conformity with an Order of the Board in any proceeding.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1703.6.</num>
    <text>Proof of service shall state the name and address of the person served, the manner of service, and the date of service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1703.7.</num>
    <text>Proof of service shall be shown by one of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Written acknowledgement of the person served or that person&amp;#8217;s representative;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The certificate of the person making the service;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A return receipt, if served by registered or certified mail; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A receipt, if served by telegram.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1703.8.</num>
    <text>Failure to serve all parties of record, or their designated representatives, may result in the Board delaying action on the matter at issue until such time as service is properly accomplished.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>