<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-1708</num>
  <heading>INSPECTION OF BOARD FILES (§ 23-1708)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1708.1.</num>
    <text>The records of the Board shall be available for inspection and copying during normal business hours without appointment at the request of any interested party or member of the public, except as otherwise provided in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1708.2.</num>
    <text>The records of the Board that shall be available for inspection and copying include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Written decisions and orders of the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Regulatory inspection reports;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>License applications and related documentation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any other records not specifically excepted from disclosure by the Freedom of Information Act of 1976 (D.C. Official Code §§ 2-531 et seq.).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1708.3.</num>
    <text>The Board shall withhold from its files those documents and other information which are exempted from public disclosure under the Freedom of Information Act of 1976. However, all documents and other information which is relied upon by the Board in
      reaching a decision on a contested case shall be made available to all parties and shall be entered into the record of the proceedings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1708.4.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § 1708.3, all petitions filed under this chapter shall be considered part of the record and shall be available for public inspection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>