<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-2000</num>
  <heading>CATERER&amp;#8217;S LICENSE (§ 23-2000)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2000.1.</num>
    <text>A Caterer&amp;#8217;s license, issued under D.C. Official Code § 25-113(i), shall authorize the licensee to sell, deliver, and serve alcoholic beverages for consumption on the premises of a catered event at which the licensee is also serving prepared
      food. A Caterer is a business entity engaged principally in the processing, preparation, and service of food products which it has prepared especially for the customer for an event, and the service of alcoholic beverages is incidental to the food
      preparation and service. A Caterer&amp;#8217;s license shall not be granted to or maintained by entities which only serve snack items. Snack items shall include, but not limited to, potato chips, popcorn, pretzels, nuts, cookies, and candy. A violation
      of this subsection shall be grounds for the Board to order the licensee to show cause why the license should not be suspended or revoked, or a civil fine imposed based upon the primary tier schedule set forth in D.C. Official Code § 25-830(c).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2000.2.</num>
    <text>The licensee under a Caterer&amp;#8217;s license or its designated manager shall remain on the premises of a catered event for the period during which alcoholic beverages are sold, served, and consumed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2000.3</num>
    <text>2000.3 Holders of a caterer’s license may purchase alcoholic beverages from Wholesalers and holders of an off-premises license, class A, for catered events of one hundred (100) persons or less. Holders of a caterer’s license shall purchase alcoholic
      beverages from an off-premises license, class A, for catered events in excess of one hundred (100) persons except that holders of a caterer’s license may also purchase alcoholic beverages from Wholesalers for catered events in excess of one hundred
      (100) persons when the licensed caterer also holds another type of on-premise, retailer’s license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by D.C. Act 15-442, published at 51 DCR 6525 (July 2, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11580 (August 9, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>