<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-208</num>
  <heading>LICENSE FEES (ยง 23-208)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>208.1.</num>
    <text>All license fees shall be paid by credit card, certified check, money order, business check, attorney&amp;#8217;s check, or personal check payable to ABRA. Applicants and licensees shall pay the annual fees specified by the Board in the following
      manner:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The fee for the first year shall be paid at the time an application is filed, but shall be returned to an applicant, minus the prescribed processing fee, if the application is denied; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The fees for the second and third year shall be paid no later than one (1) and two (2) years, respectively, from the date of the issuance of the license; provided, that a licensee may pay the second and third year fees when the first year fee is
        paid. The payment of the second and third year license fees shall not require the filing of a clean-hands certificate by the applicant.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.2.</num>
    <text>The Board may impose a late fee upon a licensee for failure to timely remit the second or third year fee, or the renewal fee, in the amount of fifty dollars ($50) for each day after the due date of payment. The total amount of the late fee to be paid
      to ABRA shall not exceed the annual cost of the license. The Board may suspend a license until the licensee pays the second or third year fee and any additional fee imposed by the Board for late payment. A licensee who has not renewed timely shall
      not be permitted to sell or serve alcoholic beverages with an expired license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.3.</num>
    <text>The Board may suspend a license, permit, or endorsement where payment was made by the applicant to ABRA with a check returned unpaid. The applicant, in addition to any late fees imposed by the Board pursuant to ยง 208.2, shall also be charged by ABRA
      with a one hundred dollar ($100) returned check fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.4.</num>
    <text>The annual fees for a Manufacturer&amp;#8217;s license Class A shall be as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Rectifying Plant $6,000;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Distillery $6,000;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Distillery selling more than fifty percent (50%) of alcohol for non-beverage purposes $3,000; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Winery $1,500.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.5.</num>
    <text>The annual fee for a Manufacturer&amp;#8217;s license Class B (brewery) shall be five thousand dollars ($5,000).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.6.</num>
    <text>The annual fee for a Wholesaler&amp;#8217;s license Class A shall be five thousand two hundred dollars ($5,200).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.7.</num>
    <text>The annual fee for a Wholesaler&amp;#8217;s license Class B shall be two thousand six hundred dollars ($2,600).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.8.</num>
    <text>The annual fee for a Retailer&amp;#8217;s license Class A shall be two thousand six hundred dollars ($2,600).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.9.</num>
    <text>The annual fee for a Retailer&amp;#8217;s license Class B shall be one thousand three hundred dollars ($1,300).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>208.10.</num>
    <text>The annual license fees for all Class C licenses, except the Washington Convention Center and the DC Arena, shall be based on its capacity load, which shall be defined as the maximum number of patrons that may be in the establishment at any one time.
      The holder of a Class C license shall submit both its capacity placards identifying the maximum number of patrons and certificate of occupancy identifying the number of seats from the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs with both its initial
      and renewal license applications. The annual license fees are as follows:</text>
    <text>Class</text>
    <text>Capacity</text>
    <text>Fee</text>
    <text>CR restaurant</text>
    <text>99 or fewer</text>
    <text>$1,000</text>
    <text>CR restaurant</text>
    <text>100 to 199</text>
    <text>$1,300</text>
    <text>CR restaurant</text>
    <text>200 to 499</text>
    <text>$1,950</text>
    <text>CR restaurant</text>
    <text>500 or more</text>
    <text>$2,600</text>
    <text>CT tavern</text>
    <text>99 or fewer</text>
    <text>$1,300</text>
    <text>CT tavern</text>
    <text>100 to 199</text>
    <text>$2,080</text>
    <text>CT tavern</text>
    <text>200 or more</text>
    <text>$3,120</text>
    <text>CN nightclub</text>
    <text>99 or fewer</text>
    <text>$1,950</text>
    <text>CN nightclub</text>
    <text>100 to 199</text>
    <text>$2,600</text>
    <text>CN nightclub</text>
    <text>200 to 499</text>
    <text>$3,250</text>
    <text>CN nightclub</text>
    <text>500 to 999</text>
    <text>$4,550</text>
    <text>CN nightclub</text>
    <text>1,000 or more</text>
    <text>$5,850</text>
    <text>CH hotel</text>
    <text>99 or fewer guest rooms</text>
    <text>$2,600</text>
    <text>CH hotel</text>
    <text>100 or more guest rooms</text>
    <text>$5,200</text>
    <text>CX club</text>
    <text>$1,950</text>
    <text>CX multipurpose facility</text>
    <text>$1,950</text>
    <text>CX marine vessel, single vessel</text>
    <text>$1,950</text>
    <text>CX marine vessel line, for 3 or fewer vessels and dockside waiting areas</text>
    <text>$3,250</text>
    <text>For each additional vessel or dockside waiting area</text>
    <text>$1,950</text>
    <text>CX railroad dining or club car, single car</text>
    <text>$650</text>
    <text>CX railroad company, all dining or club cars</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>