<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-2001</num>
  <heading>CATERER&amp;#8217;S APPLICATION (§ 23-2001)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2001.1.</num>
    <text>Application for a Caterer&amp;#8217;s license shall be made on a form prescribed by the Board that shall include, at a minimum, the name, address, and federal and D.C. tax identification numbers of the catering business, the date of application, and
      a notarized statement that the applicant for the Caterer&amp;#8217;s license is informed of and agrees to abide by Title 25 of the D.C. Official Code and this title. Caterers without a place of business within the District of Columbia shall also
      designate a registered agent upon whom service of process may be served. The Board may require documentation evidencing the applicant&amp;#8217;s qualification to transact business in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.2.</num>
    <text>The Board may issue a Caterer&amp;#8217;s license to an applicant who meets the criteria set forth in D.C. Official Code §§ 25-301 and 25-303(a)(2). An applicant for a Caterer&amp;#8217;s license shall not be subject to the appropriateness standards
      set forth in D.C. Official Code §§ 25-313 and 25-314 and § 400 to qualify for the issuance or renewal of a Caterer&amp;#8217;s license; provided, that the licensee under a Caterer&amp;#8217;s license shall be subject to the appropriateness standards
      se forth in D.C. Official Code § 25-313 for purposes of the catered site protest hearing set forth in § 2008.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.3.</num>
    <text>The licensee under a Caterer&amp;#8217;s license shall be eligible to sell, deliver, and serve alcoholic beverages for consumption on premises designated by its customers in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.4.</num>
    <text>The licensee under an on-premises license, class C or class D, shall be required to file a separate application for the issuance or renewal of a Caterer&amp;#8217;s license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.5.</num>
    <text>The Board in its discretion may grant temporary licenses to a caterer pending approval of its catering license application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by D.C. ACT 15-442 published at 51 DCR 6525 (July 2, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>