<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-403</num>
  <heading>PROHIBITED BUSINESS INTERESTS (ยง 23-403)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>403.1.</num>
    <text>The spouse of an ABC license holder may apply for a separate ABC license if he or she can establish that the conflict provisions of D.C. Official Code ยง 25-303 will not be violated. Specifically, in applying for a license the spouse not holding an
      ABC license must submit a signed and notarized affidavit which states that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>the applicant has no present or future ownership interest in any other ABC establishment that the applicant is prohibited from owning under D.C. Official Code ยง 25-303;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>the applicant&amp;#8217;s spouse will have no ownership interest in the license being sought by the applicant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>the applicant or another corporation (in which the spouse is not an officer, shareholder or member) is solely liable for the business rather than the spouse or spouse&amp;#8217;s business;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>the other spouse will not have any operational control over the establishment and will not serve in a management capacity for the ABC establishment or apply for an ABC Manager&amp;#8217;s license for that establishment; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>the applicant will not transfer any alcoholic beverage inventory to or receive any alcoholic beverage inventory from their spouse&amp;#8217;s ABC licensed establishment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>403.2.</num>
    <text>The applicant shall provide documentation, upon request of the Board, necessary to validate the applicant&amp;#8217;s sworn affidavit. Failure to submit the necessary documentation within ten (10) business days of the Board&amp;#8217;s request may
      result in the suspension or revocation of the applicant&amp;#8217;s license, unless an extension is granted by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>