<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-705</num>
  <heading>HOURS OF SALE AND DELIVERY FOR OFF-PREMISES RETAIL LICENSEES (§ 23-705)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>705.1.</num>
    <text>The new hours for Class A and Class B off-premises retail licensees set forth in D.C. Official Code § 25-722 took effect on August 1, 2001.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.2.</num>
    <text>The Board may, by written Order, further limit the hours of sale and delivery set forth in D.C. Official Code § 25-722 on a case-by-case basis upon conclusion of a protest hearing or through Board approval of a cooperative/voluntary agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.3.</num>
    <text>Any licensee, who held a Retailer&amp;#8217;s license Class B, as of May 3, 2001, and who was authorized under its license to sell alcoholic beverages on Sundays, may continue such sales unless the Board, after a hearing, finds that such authority
      should be discontinued. In determining whether to allow the holder of a Retailer&amp;#8217;s license Class B to sell on Sundays, the Board shall determine whether Sunday sales are appropriate applying the criteria set forth in D.C. Official Code
      § 25-313.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.4.</num>
    <text>The holder of a Retailer&amp;#8217;s license Class A or Class B shall not sell or deliver alcoholic beverages during any hour or on any day other than during those days and during those hours stated in D.C. Official Code § 25-722 and § 705.2 of this
      title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.5.</num>
    <text>The holder of a Retailer&amp;#8217;s license Class A may sell and deliver, during the hours of sale set forth in D.C. Official Code § 25-722 and § 705.2 of this title, no less than six (6) miniatures of spirits or wine per purchase.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.6.</num>
    <text>The holder of a Retailer&amp;#8217;s license Class A or B may not provide &amp;#8220;go-cups&amp;#8221; to patrons. A &amp;#8220;go-cup&amp;#8221; means a drinking utensil provided at no charge or a nominal charge to a patron for the purpose of consuming
      alcoholic beverages off the premises of an establishment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.7.</num>
    <text>A hotel holding a Retailer&amp;#8217;s license Class CH or Class DH may make available in the room of a registered adult guest, and charge to the registered guest if consumed, closed miniature containers of spirits, wines, and beer at all hours on
      any day of the week.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.8.</num>
    <text>The holder of a Retailer&amp;#8217;s license Class C, D, F, or G, or a Catering license issued under D.C. Official Code § 25-113, may sell, dispense, serve, or give away any beverages for consumption on the premises during any hour or on any day other
      than during those hours prohibited by D.C. Official Code § 25-723.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.9.</num>
    <text>The holder of a Retailer&amp;#8217;s license Class C, D, F, or G, or a Caterer&amp;#8217;s license may sell, serve, or permit the consumption of alcoholic beverages on the licensed premises at any time except between the hours of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>2:00 a.m. and 8:00 a.m., Monday through Friday;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>3:00 a.m. and 8:00 a.m., on Saturday; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>3:00 a.m. and 10:00 a.m., on Sunday.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.10.</num>
    <text>The hours of operation set forth in § 705.9 for an ABC establishment may be further reduced by hour restrictions that have been approved as conditions of the establishment&amp;#8217;s ABC license by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.11.</num>
    <text>On each January 1st, service shall be lawful until 4:00 a.m. by the holder of any license listed in § 705.9. Licensee&amp;#8217;s listed in § 705.9 shall not be required to obtain Board approval to stay open until 4:00 a.m. on January 1st.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.12.</num>
    <text>The holder of a Retailer&amp;#8217;s license Class C or D may not serve &amp;#8220;back-up&amp;#8221; drinks.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>705.13.</num>
    <text>The holder of a brew pub permit shall be permitted to sell beer in growlers to patrons for off-premise consumption between the hours of 7:00 a.m. and midnight. The holder of a wine pub permit shall be permitted to sell wine to patrons in sealed bottles
      or other closed containers for off-premise consumption between the hours of 7:00 a.m. and midnight.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11586 (August 9, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>