<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-718</num>
  <heading>REIMBURSABLE DETAIL SUBSIDY PROGRAM (§ 23-718)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>718.1.</num>
    <text>This section sets forth the procedures for receiving reimbursement from ABRA under the subsidy program for monies paid to the Metropolitan Police Department (&amp;#8220;MPD&amp;#8221;) by licensees for the hiring of MPD officers to work a reimbursable
      detail. A licensee, a group of licensees, or a Business Improvement District on behalf of licensees (&amp;#8220;licensees&amp;#8221;), may enter into an agreement with MPD to provide for reimbursable detail and are eligible for reimbursement under
      the subsidy program. This section shall apply only to the extent that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Council funds the subsidy program; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>ABRA has sufficient funds earmarked for this program remaining to reimburse MPD for costs incurred by licensees for MPD officers working reimbursable details.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>718.2</num>
    <text>718.2 ABRA will reimburse MPD fifty percent (50%) of the total cost of invoices submitted by MPD to cover the costs incurred by licensees for MPD officers working reimbursable details on Friday and Saturday nights and District or federal Holidays.
      The hours eligible for reimbursement shall be 11:30 p.m. to 5:00 a.m. MPD shall submit to ABRA on a monthly basis invoices documenting the fifty percent (50%) amount owed by each licensee. Invoices will be paid by ABRA to MPD within thirty (30)
      days of receipt in the order that they are received until the subsidy program’s funds are depleted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>718.3.</num>
    <text>ABRA shall notify MPD when funds in the subsidy program fall below two hundred and fifty thousand dollars ($250,000).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>718.4.</num>
    <text>Any invoices unpaid by ABRA either for good cause or a lack of sufficient funds left in the subsidy program shall remain the responsibility of the licensee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>718.5.</num>
    <text>ABRA shall not be involved in determining the number of MPD officers needed to work a reimbursable detail.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 4199 (March 22, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>