<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-707</num>
  <heading>MANAGER&amp;#8217;S LICENSE (§ 23-707)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>707.1.</num>
    <text>In the absence of a licensee, a Board approved manager shall be present at the licensed premises during the hours that alcoholic beverages are permitted to be sold, served, or consumed on the licensed premises.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a Manager&amp;#8217;s license shall submit an application to the Board on the prescribed form and pay the required fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.3.</num>
    <text>If a licensee has designated a person to manage the licensed business, each manager shall be the holder of a valid Manager&amp;#8217;s license which shall be renewable every two years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.4.</num>
    <text>A Manager&amp;#8217;s license shall remain valid until surrendered, expired, suspended, or revoked.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a Manager&amp;#8217;s license shall be investigated and shall be subject to the approval of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.6.</num>
    <text>Prior to issuance of a Manager&amp;#8217;s license, an applicant shall certify that he or she has obtained and read a copy of the Act (D.C. Official Code §§ 25-101 et seq.) and this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.7.</num>
    <text>A manager holding a valid license according to the provisions of this section may be employed by one (1) or more licensees without further investigation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.8.</num>
    <text>All licensees shall notify the Board within seven (7) calendar days of discovering any manager&amp;#8217;s arrest or conviction for other than minor traffic violations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.9.</num>
    <text>Failure by the applicant to comply with § 707.8, may, in the discretion of the Board, cause the applicant&amp;#8217;s license to be suspended or revoked.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.10.</num>
    <text>A licensee may file a written request with the Board that an applicant for a Manager&amp;#8217;s license who has not completed an alcohol training and education certification program be issued a temporary Manager&amp;#8217;s license subject to the
      requirements of § 212.2. The written request shall set forth the name of the licensed establishment, the trade name, the address of the establishment, the name of the applicant for the Manager&amp;#8217;s license, and the reason why the issuance
      of the temporary Manager&amp;#8217;s license is necessary. Such temporary authority shall cease after thirty (30) days or upon the approval or denial of the Manager&amp;#8217;s license application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>