<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-713</num>
  <heading>STREET FESTIVALS (ยง 23-713)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>713.1.</num>
    <text>The holder of a Retailer&amp;#8217;s license Class CR or Class DR who is participating in a street festival may apply to the Board for a one-day substantial change on a form provided by the Board to serve alcoholic beverages on public space rented
      by the licensee if the establishment abuts the closed street.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>713.2.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section &amp;#8220;street festival&amp;#8221; means any event for which a temporary street closing permit has been issued and which meets the following conditions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The licensee to whom the street closing permit was issued is a nonprofit organization;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The street closed is zoned for primarily retail use; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The festival uses the street closed primarily to rent to retail vendors.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>713.3.</num>
    <text>Business associations or citizens associations incorporated under the laws of the District of Columbia shall be allowed to obtain approval from the Board on behalf of multiple festival permit participants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>713.4.</num>
    <text>The holder of a Class CR or Class DR Retailer&amp;#8217;s license who rents public space shall not permit patrons to take alcoholic beverages off the licensed premises or any public space rented by that establishment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>713.5.</num>
    <text>The cost of filing a one-day substantial change application shall be the same as the cost of a Temporary license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>