<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-1613</num>
  <heading>SUSPENSION AND REVOCATION (ยง 24-1613)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1613.1</num>
    <text>1613.1 [REPEALED]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1613.2.</num>
    <text>Upon providing fifteen (15) days written notice to the Permittee, the Department may suspend or revoke a Valet Parking permit for any of the following reasons:</text>
    <text>The Valet Parking operation adversely impacts vehicular or pedestrian traffic;</text>
    <text>The Permittee violates a provision of this chapter or any condition or requirement of the Valet Parking permit;</text>
    <text>The Valet Parking Operator violates a provision of this chapter or the Valet Parking permit;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Permittee fails to submit timely payment of the applicable public space rental fees;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The Permittee fails to inform the Department of any changes as required by section 1606.3 or 1612.4 of this chapter; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The peace, order, or quiet in the immediate environs of a Valet Parking zone is negatively impacted.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1613.3.</num>
    <text>The Department may immediately suspend or revoke a Valet Parking permit if the Valet Parking operations pose a threat to public safety or welfare. The Department must provide notice in writing to the Permittee specifying the reasons for the immediate
      suspension or revocation no more than fifteen (15) days after the suspension or revocation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5019, 5032 (June 28, 2009); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 5059 (June 11, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 8024, 8027 (September
        3, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>