<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-1106</num>
  <heading>STANDARDS FOR TREES AND LANDSCAPING (ยง 24-1106)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1106.1.</num>
    <text>Where a conflict exists between the standards set forth in this section and standards set forth in sections 1105 and 1109, the standards set forth in this section shall take precedence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1106.2.</num>
    <text>One (1) row of trees shall be required on each side of the street.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1106.3.</num>
    <text>Repealed</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1106.4.</num>
    <text>Except as provided for in subsection 1106.5, the species of the required trees shall be in conformance with the Master Street Tree Plan as approved by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1106.5.</num>
    <text>Subject to approval by the Director, the second row of trees on Indiana Avenue, and K Street east of 12th Street, NW and any other additional rows of trees proposed by the applicant, may be of a species selected by the applicant and approved by the
      Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1106.6.</num>
    <text>The trees shall be planted to conform to the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Trees shall be planted a minimum of forty feet (40&amp;#8242;) from the intersection of the radius tangent line and the curb and shall allow motorists and pedestrians to clearly view traffic control devices;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Trees shall be planted a minimum of thirty feet (30&amp;#8242;) to forty feet (40&amp;#8242;) apart;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Where necessary to avoid other fixed elements in the public space, trees may be planted a minimum of thirty feet (30&amp;#8242;) apart or a maximum of fifty feet (50&amp;#8242;) apart;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>On Massachusetts Avenue, trees shall be planted forty feet (40&amp;#8242;) apart with the second row of trees set back twenty feet (20&amp;#8242;) from the curb and staggered at even forty feet (40&amp;#8242;) intervals between curb trees;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Trees shall be at least eight feet (8&amp;#8242;) from any building or utility vault;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Trees shall be at least fifteen feet (15&amp;#8242;) from a streetlight;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Trees shall be at least twelve feet (12&amp;#8242;) from any above grade building projection;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Trees shall be at least ten feet (10&amp;#8242;) from a driveway or an alley;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Trees shall be planted in the center of the tree space;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>When planted, the size (caliper) of the tree shall be at least three inches (3&amp;#8243;) to three and one half inches (3 1/2&amp;#8243;);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Trees shall be nursery grown and planted balled and burlapped; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>When planted, trees shall be supported by three wood stakes.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1106.7.</num>
    <text>Trees shall be spaced and planted to conform to planting details as approved by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1106.8.</num>
    <text>The tree space shall satisfy the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>On those streets which are not listed in subsection 1105.4 and which are south of Massachusetts Avenue, the dimension of the tree space shall be four feet (4&amp;#8242;) by ten feet (10&amp;#8242;) with a minimum depth of three feet (3&amp;#8242;);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>With the exception of Massachusetts Avenue, streets listed in subsection 1105.4, and on all other streets north of Massachusetts Avenue, the tree space adjacent to the curb shall be four feet (4&amp;#8242;) wide and continuous and shall have a minimum
        depth of three feet (3&amp;#8242;);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The tree space on Massachusetts Avenue shall be six feet (6&amp;#8242;) wide and continuous.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The tree space shall be back filled with a planting mix specifically approved by the Director;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The tree space shall be protected by the installation of plantings with ground cover to be maintained by the adjacent property owner. The types of ground cover and plantings in a tree space shall be specified by the applicant and are subject to
        Committee approval;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Crushed rock or gravel shall not be used for ground cover;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The tree space shall be open to soil on all sides; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Where an enclosed tree space is required due to the below grade restrictions, drainage shall be provided from beneath the tree space.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1106.9.</num>
    <text>Where public space exists between the edge of the sidewalk and the property line, a landscape plan for this area shall be required as part of the submitted streetscape plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1106.10.</num>
    <text>Subject to approval by the Committee, raised planter boxes shall be permitted at the edge of the public space between the sidewalk and the property line or at the building line, provided that the following requirements are fulfilled:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Raised planter boxes shall be a minimum of ten feet (10&amp;#8242;) from the curb;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Raised planter boxes shall be clear of other sidewalk streetscape elements, including, but not limited to, trees and tree spaces, signs, meters and streetlight poles; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Where planter boxes are accessible to pedestrians, the planter boxes may be designed to serve as seating.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1106.11.</num>
    <text>Installation of electrical service within the tree box shall be subject to the approval of the Committee. Electrical service shall be metered to the owner&amp;#8217;s building.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7117 (September 1, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>