<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-112</num>
  <heading>RETAIL BUSINESS USE OF ADJOINING PUBLIC SPACE (§ 24-112)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>112.1.</num>
    <text>The owner or occupant of a store located in a residential-use district (as designated under the zoning regulations) may, during the time the store is open for business, use the space outside the front of the store to the extent of four feet (4 ft.)
      from the building line for the display of goods, wares, and merchandise directly connected with the business transacted within the store; Provided, that the use is conducted in compliance with the zoning regulations and in accordance with the provisions
      of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>112.2.</num>
    <text>The owner or occupant of a store located in the first or second commercial or industrial-use districts (as designated under the zoning regulations) may use the space outside the front of the store to the extent of three feet (3 ft.) from the building
      line for the display, in show cases or otherwise, of goods, wares, or merchandise directly connected with the business transacted within the store; Provided, that the use is conducted in accordance with the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>112.3.</num>
    <text>. No meat, fish, or fowl shall be displayed outside of a store on any street or avenue.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>112.4.</num>
    <text>No permit shall be issued for a bootblack stand on public space.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>112.5.</num>
    <text>No permit shall be granted for a fruit stand on public space, except for the purpose of displaying fruit under the conditions set forth in §§112.1 and 112.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>112.6.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section shall not apply to the owners of occupants of stores or places of business located on business streets designated under §113.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 4, §§6 &amp;#038; 7 of the Police Regulations (May 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>