<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-1511</num>
  <heading>RETURN OF ANIMAL ON CONDITION OF PROTECTIVE ACTION (§ 24-1511)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1511.1.</num>
    <text>The President or his or her designee may condition the return of an animal on the owner’s agreement to undertake specified actions to protect the animal against ongoing neglect and cruelty.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1511.2.</num>
    <text>The President or his or her designee may reach agreement with the owner on the conditions for return outside of the formal hearing process or may impose conditions for return in its final decision pursuant to § 1509.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1511.3.</num>
    <text>WHS may enforce the conditions of return by:</text>
    <text>Requiring that the owner comply with the conditions after the return of the animal. The President or his or her designee may specify a time period, lasting no fewer than fifteen (15) and no more than thirty (30) days, during which the owner must demonstrate
      compliance with the conditions of the return; or</text>
    <text>Requiring that the owner comply with the conditions prior to the return of the animal. The President or his or her designee may specify a time period, lasting no fewer than fifteen (15) and no more than thirty (30) days, during which the owner must
      demonstrate compliance with the conditions of return.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1511.4.</num>
    <text>If the owner has failed to comply with the requirements of release, the President or his or her designee may make a written determination that the owner has failed to comply with the conditions of the animal’s release pursuant to § 1511.3, which shall
      be mailed or delivered to the owner within three (3) days. Such a determination authorizes WHS to retake or maintain custody of the animal pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 22-1004(b)(1.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 316 (January 9, 2009)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published 56 DCR 2374, 2383 (March 27, 2009).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>