<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-1602</num>
  <heading>STANDARD VALET PARKING PERMIT APPLICATION PROCEDURE (§ 24-1602)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1602.1.</num>
    <text>An Applicant shall submit an application to the Department to rent public space for a Standard Valet Staging Zone in the District of Columbia to offer Valet Parking services at the same location on an on-going basis. The application form shall be
      furnished by the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1602.2.</num>
    <text>Each completed Standard Valet Parking permit application shall be accompanied by a Valet Parking Plan that shall include, but not be limited to, the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name, mailing address, email address and telephone number of the Applicant(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A copy of the Applicant’s business license(s) issued by the DCRA, if the Applicant is required to have a business license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A copy of the Applicant’s Certificate of Occupancy issued by DCRA for the facility used by the Applicant for the business for which the Valet Parking service will be provided, if the Applicant is required to have one;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The name, mailing address, email address, and telephone number of the Valet Parking Operator;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A copy of the Valet Parking license issued by DCRA or other District agency, if the Applicant is required to have such a license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A copy of the Valet Parking Operator’s liability insurance certificate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>One (1) original and five (5) copies each of three (3) eight inch by ten inch (8 in. x 10 in.) glossy photographs of the public space, including the curb space and road way, of the proposed Valet Staging Zone. The photographs shall show the following
        views of the proposed Valet Staging Zone:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Frontal view;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Sharp angle right side view; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Sharp angle left side view;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Six (6) copies of a traffic flow plan, including a map, that provides all proposed routes from the Valet Staging area to the off-street parking facility location(s) where the motor vehicles will be parked;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and telephone number of the off-street parking facility where motor vehicles will be parked during Valet Parking hours;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Verification of access to off-street parking spaces in the off-street parking facility described in subsection (i); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Verification that adjacent property owners, i.e. property owners to the immediate left, right, under, and on top of the property, have been provided thirty (30) days advance notice of the Valet Parking application and Valet Parking Plan.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1602.3.</num>
    <text>The Applicant shall post a notice of its intent to obtain a Valet Parking permit in a conspicuous site at the street frontage near the proposed Valet Staging Zone and on the entrance to the building for thirty (30) days.</text>
    <text>The Applicant shall make the Standard Valet Parking application and Valet Parking Plan available for public viewing during the thirty (30) day notice period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5019, 5021 (June 28, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>