<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-1199</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 24-1199)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1199.1.</num>
    <text>The terms and phrases used in this chapter shall have the meanings set forth in this section.</text>
    <text>Committee &amp;#8211; the Downtown Streetscape Review Committee</text>
    <text>Department &amp;#8211; The District of Columbia Department of Public Works</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; The Director of the Department or the Director&amp;#8217;s designee</text>
    <text>The Downtown Streetscape Area &amp;#8211; The Downtown Urban Renewal Area, as defined in the Zoning Regulations, Title 11 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations, and the west side of North Capitol Street and both sides of all other boundary
      streets of the Downtown Urban Renewal Area.</text>
    <text>Downtown Business Improvement District &amp;#8211; The area defined pursuant to section 4(c) of the Business Improvement District Act of 1996, effective May 29, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-134; D.C. Code section 1-2274(c)).</text>
    <text>Manhole &amp;#8211; Vaults which house the equipment of any private or public utility company or agency.</text>
    <text>Property Line &amp;#8211; The line of demarcation between privately owned property fronting or abutting a street and the publicly owned property in such street.</text>
    <text>Public space &amp;#8211; All the publicly owned property between the property lines on a street, as such property lines are shown on the Department&amp;#8217;s records, and includes, but is not limited to, the roadway, tree spaces and sidewalks.</text>
    <text>Redevelopment &amp;#8211; The construction of a new building or a new structure.</text>
    <text>Rehabilitation &amp;#8211; The repair of an existing, reusable structure or building which provides a satisfactory improved physical condition for the intended use of the structure or building.</text>
    <text>Standard Specifications &amp;#8211; The District of Columbia Department of Public Works, Standard Specifications for Highways and Structures, 1996.</text>
    <text>Street &amp;#8211; A public highway as shown on the records of the District, whether designated as a street, alley, avenue, freeway, road, drive, lane, place, boulevard, parkway, circle, or by any other term.</text>
    <text>Substantial Rehabilitation &amp;#8211; The rehabilitation of an existing structure or an existing building when the estimated cost of the rehabilitation, as determined for a building permit, is (50%) percent or more of the value of the structure.</text>
    <text>Vault &amp;#8211; A structure or an enclosure of space beneath the surface of the public space, including, but not limited to tanks for petroleum products, utility vaults and building vaults. If the structure or enclosure of space is divided horizontally
      into two (2) or more levels, the term &amp;#8220;vault&amp;#8221; shall be considered as applying to one (1) level only, and each level shall be considered as a separate vault.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7117 (September 1, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>