<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-1102</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION PROCEDURE (ยง 24-1102)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1102.1.</num>
    <text>To obtain a Step 1 streetscape review of a streetscape plan, an applicant shall submit an application on a form provided by the Director and ten (10) copies of the streetscape plan as part of the public space permit application process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1102.2.</num>
    <text>The streetscape plan submitted for the Step 1 streetscape review should show, if known, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Sidewalk treatment including proposed materials and paving patterns;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The location and type of all existing and proposed streetlights, traffic signals, parking signs, other traffic control devices and parking meters;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The location of existing and proposed tree spaces, tree species and proposed tree planting details;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The location, design and dimension of all existing and proposed driveways and curb cuts, sewer and water connections, utility lines, and oil tank openings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The length of the radii for all driveways, alleys, and street corners;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Vaults or any other underground projection below public space, sidewalks or alleys;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Metrobus stops, bus shelters, and Metrorail station entrances;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The location and size of pedestrian entrances, including, but not limited to, store entrances and through-building passageways;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The size and location of shop windows;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>The location and design of loading berths, taxi, bus, and other vehicle queuing, waiting areas, or other drop-off or pick-up areas and facilities. The plans for loading berths shall include the number of berths and details of access to the berths;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Top of curb profiles, alley profiles, sidewalk cross slopes, and final street grades;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>The location of street amenities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Elevation of any portion of the building facing a street; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>Handicap ramp locations and details.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1102.3.</num>
    <text>To obtain a Step 2 Streetscape review of a streetscape plan, an applicant shall submit ten (10) copies of the streetscape plan as part of the public space permit application process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1102.4.</num>
    <text>The streetscape plan submitted for the Step 2 Streetscape review shall show the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The actual paving materials, their design and support details, landscaping treatment and planting details, final sidewalk grades and any streetscape amenities with necessary details for installation, and drainage details;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Design and location of the sidewalk level streetscape elements, including but not limited to, the designated tree species, tree box plantings, specific designs, number and location of any streetscape hardware, pedestrian amenities, and decorative
        fixtures; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The treatment of vault covers.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1102.5.</num>
    <text>Applicant may, subject to approval by the Director, submit a combined streetscape plan that shows the elements required by subsections 1102.2 and 1102.4. A combined streetscape plan shall be submitted pursuant to the time period set for a Step 1 Streetscape
      plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1102.6.</num>
    <text>The applicant shall clearly indicate on the submitted streetscape plan any variation or exception to the standards set forth in this chapter and the applicant shall provide a letter describing the variation or the exception and its underlying rationale.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1102.7.</num>
    <text>All drawings for a Step 1 or a Step 2 Streetscape review shall be submitted to the Executive Secretary, Downtown Streetscape Review Committee, Department of Public Works, seventh floor, 2000 14th Street, NW, Washington, D.C.</text>
    <text>Source: Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7117 (September 1, 2000).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>