<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-1110</num>
  <heading>STANDARDS FOR STREET ACCESS (ยง 24-1110)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1110.1.</num>
    <text>The location of curb cuts and driveways shall be approved when the following conditions are fulfilled:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The land use, traffic and pedestrian patterns, and transit operation in the area have been considered;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Where feasible, access to loading and parking facilities shall be from an alley;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Where feasible, loading facilities shall be located below grade;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>On the following streets, curb cuts and driveways shall be approved only if the applicant demonstrates that there is no other means or method of providing vehicular access to the property:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>F Street, NW between 7th Street and 15th Street;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>G Street, NW between 7th Street and 15th Street;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>7th Street, NW between Pennsylvania Avenue and Massachusetts Avenue;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>8th Street, NW between Pennsylvania Avenue and Massachusetts Avenue;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>10th Street, NW between Pennsylvania Avenue and H Street; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Circular driveways, building entrance driveways, porte cocheres, and laybys shall not be permitted in the Downtown Streetscape Area, unless approved by the Director.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1110.2.</num>
    <text>The design of a driveway shall fulfill the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Driveways and their aprons shall be poured concrete and flush with grade of sidewalk;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Driveway shall be a minimum width of twelve feet (12&amp;#8242;) and a maximum width of twenty-five feet (25&amp;#8242;);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The radius for curb returns for driveways shall be six feet (6&amp;#8242;);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>There must be a minimum six feet (6&amp;#8242;) wide pedestrian safety island between two driveways that are more than twenty four feet (24&amp;#8242;) wide. This pedestrian island shall match the same material used for the sidewalk. It shall have
        a three feet (3&amp;#8242;) radius at the curb of the street;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>All alleys are required to have a minimum width of twenty feet (20&amp;#8242;) and radius at curb shall be ten feet (10&amp;#8242;). Driveway shall not be located within sixteen feet (16&amp;#8242;) of another driveway or alley;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Driveway shall be at least eight feet (8&amp;#8242;) from the adjacent interior property line;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Driveway shall be at least forty feet (40&amp;#8242;) from the point of the intersection of the two (2) street curbs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Driveways shall be designed to avoid vehicle backing and vehicle waiting within the street;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Where the driveway provides access to a parking facility, the driveway shall provide a sufficient off-street storage area for vehicles waiting to enter the parking facility; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Driveway shall have a maximum grade of twelve percent (12%) within the public space.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1110.3.</num>
    <text>Driveways shall be located according to the Driveway Location Standards approved by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1110.4.</num>
    <text>The use of shared driveways for more than one (1) property or building and the shared use of parking and loading facilities by more than one (1) property or building shall be permitted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7117 (September 1, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>