<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-1310</num>
  <heading>HEARING EXAMINERS (ยง 24-1310)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1310.1.</num>
    <text>Any hearing required by D.C. Law 6-100, the &amp;#8220;Litter Control Administration Act of 1985&amp;#8243; (D.C. Code ยง6-2901 et seq.) or this chapter shall be held before a Hearing Examiner or the Chief, Office of Public Space Adjudication. No other
      person shall have the authority to adjudicate the solid waste or public space violations specified by the &amp;#8220;Litter Control Administration Act of 1985&amp;#8243; or to dismiss a Notice that has been returned to the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1310.2.</num>
    <text>A Hearing Examiner shall have the following powers, in addition to any other powers specified in this chapter:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>To give appropriate notices;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>To administer oaths and affirmations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>To examine witnesses and to take testimony;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>To request the Superior Court of the District of Columbia to issue subpoena;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>To permit depositions or interrogatories;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>To rule upon offers of proof and to receive relevant evidence;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>To regulate the course and conduct of hearings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>To hold conferences before, during, or after a hearing to settle or simplify issues;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>To make final determinations as provided herein or by law;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>To take any other action authorized by this chapter, the Administrative Procedure Act, or by any other applicable statute, rule or regulation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Upon application, to reopen the record to receive additional evidence; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>To review charges for abatement activities performed by the Mayor.</text>
    </level>
    <text>1310 3 A Hearing Examiner shall not hear any case in which he or she has any interest with either a party or the matter pending.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 7807, 7816 (December 4, 1987); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 1099, 1100 (February 3, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>