<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-105</num>
  <heading>TEMPORARY COVERED WALKWAYS (ยง 24-105)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>105.1.</num>
    <text>Temporary covered ways across sidewalks or parkings may be permitted by the Chief of Police for periods not to exceed forty-eight (48) hours.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.2.</num>
    <text>Temporary covered ways shall afford a free passage of at least six feet (6 ft.) in width along the middle of the sidewalk.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.3.</num>
    <text>Each applicant for a temporary covered way shall communicate to the Chief of Police by telephone, stating the time when the applicant desires to erect the covered way. The Chief of Police shall note the desired time and communicate this to the commanding
      officer of the police districts involved.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.4.</num>
    <text>The commanding officer shall require the removal of a covered way within forty-eight (48) hours. If the inclement weather continues beyond forty-eight (48) hours, the commanding officer may extend the time for removal an additional forty-eight (48)
      hours.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.5.</num>
    <text>Once a covered way is removed, it shall not be erected against without further permission from the Chief of Police.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.6.</num>
    <text>Permits for sockets in the sidewalk, in connection with temporary covered ways across sidewalks or parkings, shall be issued by the Director of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs upon approval of the Director of the Department of Public Works.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.7.</num>
    <text>Permits for sockets confer no authority to erect temporary covered ways across the sidewalks or parking areas. Once sockets have been installed, the Police Department shall issue forty-eight (48) hour permits to allow the use of the temporary covered
      way in inclement weather.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 4, ยง10 of the Police Regulations (May 1981); as amended by ยง4 of the District of Columbia Solid Waste Regulations Amendment Act of 1989, D.C. Law 8-31, 36 DCR 4750, 4753 (July 7, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>