<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-1608</num>
  <heading>EVENT VENUE VALET PARKING APPLICATION PROCEDURE (§ 24-1608)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1608.1.</num>
    <text>An Applicant shall submit an application to the Department to rent public space for an Event Venue Valet Parking permit to offer Valet Parking services at the same location on an occasional basis. The application form shall be furnished by the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1608.2.</num>
    <text>Each completed Event Venue Valet Parking permit application shall include, but not be limited to, the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name, mailing address, email address and telephone number of the Applicant(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A copy of the Applicant’s business license(s) issued by the DCRA, if the Applicant is required to have a business license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A copy of the Applicant’s Certificate of Occupancy issued by DCRA for the facility used by the Applicant for the business for which the Valet Parking service will be provided, if the Applicant is required to have one;</text>
    </level>
    <text>and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Six (6) eight inch by ten inch (8 in. x 10 in.) glossy photographs of the public space, including the curb space and road way, of the proposed Valet Staging Zone(s). The photographs shall show the following views of the proposed Valet Staging Zone:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Frontal view;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Sharp angle right side view; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Sharp angle left side view.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5019, 5027 (June 28, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>