<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-116</num>
  <heading>INSTALLATION OF PERSONALIZED MARKERS IN THE PUBLIC SPACE BY THE MAKE AIFFERENCE FOUNDATION (§ 24-116)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>116.1.</num>
    <text>The Make a Difference Foundation may install personalized markers made of granite or other material approved by the Director according to specifications approved by the Director, consistent with the Make a Difference Selection Committee Establishment
      Act of 1998, Establishment Act of 1998, effective April 30, 1998 (D.C. Law 12-98; D.C. Code §§ 9-1215.01 (2001) (formerly codified at D.C. Code §§ 7-231 et seq. (1999 Supp.)).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>116.2.</num>
    <text>Prior to the installation of any personalized marker, the Make a Difference Foundation shall obtain the approval of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>the Downtown Streetscape Committee, if a personalized marker is to be installed in the Downtown Streetscape Area, or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>the Public Space Committee, if a personalized marker is to be installed outside the Downtown Streetscape Area.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>116.3.</num>
    <text>The Make a Difference Foundation shall submit the following documents to the Downtown Streetscape Committee or Public Space Committee, as appropriate, with each request for approval of the installation of a personalized marker:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A drawing of the proposed personalized marker;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A construction drawing of the site of the proposed marker;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A drawing of the proposed location indicating all other personalized markers currently planned or already installed within 50 feet of the proposed location;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Certification that the specifications of the personalized marker have been approved by the Director;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Certification that the Make a Difference Foundation is currently registered as a foreign corporation in the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Certification that the Make a Difference Foundation currently maintains liability insurance for personalized markers, as provided for in the Make Difference Selection Committee Establishment Act of 1998, as amended.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>116.4.</num>
    <text>Once affixed to the sidewalk, a personalized marker may not be removed or altered, except for maintenance and repair, without the written consent of the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 4099 (May 3, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>