<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-108</num>
  <heading>SIGNS, POSTERS, AND PLACARDS (§ 24-108)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>108.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall affix a sign, advertisement, or poster to any public lamppost or appurtenances of a lamppost, except as provided in accordance with this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>108.2.</num>
    <text>The placing of any advertisement on any tree in public space is prohibited.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>108.3.</num>
    <text>No poster or placard shall be publicly displayed or exhibited if it is lewd, indecent, or vulgar, or if it pictorially represents the commission of or the attempt to commit any crime.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>108.4.</num>
    <text>Any sign, advertisement, or poster that does not relate to the sale of goods or services may be affixed on public lampposts or appurtenances of a lamppost, subject to the restrictions set forth in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>108.5.</num>
    <text>A sign, advertisement, or poster shall be affixed for no more than one hundred eighty (180) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>108.6.</num>
    <text>A sign, advertisement, or poster related to a specific event shall be removed no later than thirty (30) days following the event to which it is related. This subsection does not extend the time limit in subsection 108.5.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>108.7.</num>
    <text>Each sign, advertisement, or poster shall contain the date upon which it was initially affixed to a lamppost.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>108.8.</num>
    <text>Each sign, advertisement, or poster shall be affixed securely to avoid being torn or disengaged by normal weather conditions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>108.9.</num>
    <text>Signs, advertisements, and posters shall not be affixed by adhesives that prevent their complete removal from the fixture, or that do damage to the fixture.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>108.10.</num>
    <text>No more than three (3) versions or copies of each sign, advertisement, or poster shall be affixed on one (1) side of a street within one (1) block.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>108.11.</num>
    <text>Within twenty-four (24) hours of posting each sign, advertisement, or poster, two (2) copies of the material shall be filed with an agent of the District of Columbia so designated by the Mayor. The filing shall include the name, address, and telephone
      number of the originator of the sign, advertisement, or poster, and if the sign is for an event, the date of the event.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>108.12.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, a &amp;#8220;public lamppost&amp;#8221; is any public post erected for the purpose of supporting electric wires.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>108.13.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, the term “event” refers to an occurrence, happening, activity or series of activities, specific to an identifiable time and place, if referenced on the poster itself or reasonably determined from all circumstances by
      the inspector.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 20, §2, Article 22, §3, Article 25, §12 of the Police Regulations (May 1981); as amended by §2 of the Street Sign Regulation Amendment Act of 1979, D.C. Law 3-50, 26 DCR 2733 (December 21, 1979); by §2 of the Crime Prevention Sign Posting
        Act of 1980, D.C. Law 3-148, 27 DCR 4883 (November 7, 1980); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 528 (January 8, 2010); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 7688 (August 26, 2011)[EXPIRED];
        as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 8410 (September 30, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 273 (January 20, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>