<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2399</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 24-2399)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2399.1</num>
    <text>2399.1 When used in this chapter, and in forms prescribed under this chapter,here not otherwise distinctly expressed or manifestly incompatible with thentent of the Act or this chapter, the following terms shall have the meaningsscribed:</text>
    <text>Act – the Firearms Control Regulations Act of 1975, effective September 24,976 (D.C. Law 1-85; D.C. Official Code §§ 7-2501.01 et seq. (2012 Repl. and013 Supp.)).</text>
    <text>Chief – the Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
    <text>Dealer – any person engaged in the business of buying, selling, or otherwiseealing in firearms, ammunition, or destructive devices at wholesale or retail;ny person engaged in the business of repairing, testing, or analyzing firearms;ny person engaged
      in the business of making or fitting special barrels, stocks,r trigger mechanisms for firearms or destructive devices; or any personepairing, testing, analyzing, or making any destructive device or ammunition.</text>
    <text>Director – the commanding officer or acting commanding officer of the Policeusiness Services Division of the Metropolitan Police Department or theirelegates.</text>
    <text>Explosive or explosives – any chemical compound or mechanical mixture thatontains any oxidizing and combustible units, or other ingredients, in suchroportion, quantities, or packing that an ignition by fire, friction,oncussion, percussion, or detonator,
      or any part of the compound or mixture,ay cause a sudden generation of highly heated gasses that results in gaseousressures capable of producing destructive effects on contiguous objects or ofestroying life or limb. (Art. 9, § 3 of the Police Regulations).</text>
    <text>Firearms Registration Section – a part of the Police Business Servicesivision of the Metropolitan Police Department, located in 300 Indiana Avenue,.W., Washington, D.C. 20001.</text>
    <text>Home – the principal place of residence of an individual in the District andimited to the interior of a house, condominium unit, cooperative unit,partment, houseboat, or a mobile home, so long as that structure is not capablef unassisted movement.
      The term home does not include any common areas of anyondominium unit, cooperative unit, or apartment.</text>
    <text>Intrafamily offense – shall have the same meaning as provided in D.C. Officialode § 16-1001(8) (2012 Repl.).</text>
    <text>Licensed dealer – a deadly weapons dealer licensed under the Act and thishapter.</text>
    <text>Machine gun – means any firearm which shoots, is designed to shoot, or can beeadily restored to shoot, automatically more than one shot, without manualeloading, by a single function of the trigger. The term “machine gun” shalllso include the frame
      or receiver of any such firearm, any part designed andntended solely and exclusively, or combination of parts designed and intended,or use in converting a firearm into a machine gun, and any combination of partsrom which a machine gun can be assembled
      if such parts are in the possession ornder the control of a person.</text>
    <text>Pistol – any firearm originally designed to be fired by use of a single handr with a barrel less than 12 inches in length.</text>
    <text>Supervisor – the person in charge of the Firearms Registration Section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 23 DCR 8942 (May 6, 1977), incorporatingext of the Proposed Rulemaking published at 23 DCR 7061 (March 4, 1977), 35CRR §301, November 1980, Special Edition; as amended by Article 9, §3 of theolice Regulations (May 1981);
        as amended by Emergency and Proposed Rulemakingublished at 56 DCR 624 (January 16, 2009)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Finalulemaking published at 56 DCR 4380, 4386 (June 5, 2009); as amended by Finalulemaking published at 60 DCR 17215 (December 27,
        2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>