<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2104</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (ยง 24-2104)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2104.1.</num>
    <text>A media representative displaying a press pass is authorized to enter designated areas, set aside by members of the Metropolitan Police Department, for the purpose of gathering, photographing or reporting news events. The holder of a press pass is
      not required to remain in any such designated area and may not be restricted from any area open to the general public or any area open to participants in a First Amendment assembly.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2104.2.</num>
    <text>The holder of a press pass is authorized to cross a police or fire line, unless, in the judgment of a Metropolitan Police Department officer or official, to do so would interfere with the management of a police or fire scene or would endanger the
      public safety.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2104.3.</num>
    <text>Possession of a press pass does not authorize the holder to enter a private building or private property that may be located within a police or fire line.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2104.4.</num>
    <text>MPD officers shall allow media representatives reasonable access to all areas where a First Amendment assembly is occurring. At a minimum, officers shall allow media representatives no less access than that enjoyed by members of the general public.
      Unless inconsistent with public safety considerations, officers shall allow media representatives access to areas closed to the general public in order to assist their ability to report on such an event. Officers shall also make reasonable accommodations
      to allow media representatives effectively to use photographic, video, or other equipment relating to their reporting of a First Amendment assembly.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2104.5.</num>
    <text>The Chief of Police or his or her designee shall accept or honor a press pass issued to a media representative by a local, state or federal governmental body within or outside the District of Columbia. The holder of such a press pass shall enjoy the
      same rights and privileges as if the pass were issued directly by the Chief of Police.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2104.6.</num>
    <text>It is the policy of the Metropolitan Police Department that media representatives shall have maximum access to First Amendment assemblies, fires, crime scenes, weather-related events, accidents and other news events, consistent with maintaining public
      safety and the management of a police or fire scene.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2104.7.</num>
    <text>The commanding officer at the scene of a First Amendment assembly or other news event, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Public Information, shall ensure that the policy set forth in subsection 2104.6 and the applicable provisions
      of these regulations are carried out.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2104.8.</num>
    <text>Press passes and credentials shall be plainly exposed to view whenever the persons to whom they are issued are using them.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2104.9.</num>
    <text>The Chief of Police shall appoint an advisory committee composed of representatives of the media, universities and colleges, which may make recommendations concerning the implementation of these rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 7086 (June 27, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>