<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2201</num>
  <heading>EMERGENCY REGULATIONS (§ 24-2201)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2201.1.</num>
    <text>Whenever the Mayor has proclaimed the existence of an emergency pursuant to §2200, and until that state of emergency is terminated as provided for in §2202, the Mayor may order and promulgate, as he or she may deem necessary for the protection of
      the public and the welfare of the city, any or all of the emergency regulations provided for in §§2201.3 through 2201.7, in whole or in part, and with such limitations and conditions as the Mayor may deem appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2201.2.</num>
    <text>Any emergency regulations ordered under this section shall be in effect only during the period of the emergency and in the area or areas of the District that the Mayor orders.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2201.3.</num>
    <text>The Mayor may order the imposition of a curfew in all of the District of Columbia commencing and ending at the times as the Mayor may specify.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2201.4.</num>
    <text>During the hours of a curfew, no person, other than persons officially designated by the Mayor, shall walk, run, loiter, stand, or motor upon any street, alley, or other public place within the designated area.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2201.5.</num>
    <text>The Mayor may order the prohibition of the sale or dispensing of alcoholic beverages, including beer and wine, altogether or by the bottle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2201.6.</num>
    <text>The Mayor may order the prohibition of the sale or dispensing of gasoline or other inflammable materials or liquids, altogether or except by delivery into a tank permanently affixed to an operable motor-driven vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2201.7.</num>
    <text>The Mayor may order the prohibition of the sale, gift, or exchange of any firearm, ammunition, explosive, incendiary device, or other dangerous weapon.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2201.8.</num>
    <text>The Mayor may order the prohibition of the possessing or carrying upon any street, alley, or other public place, or in any vehicle upon any street, alley, or other public place, any firearm, ammunition, explosive, incendiary device, or other dangerous
      weapon; except by law enforcement officers and military personnel in the official exercise of their duty.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2201.9.</num>
    <text>The Mayor is authorized, whenever he or she has proclaimed the existence of an emergency situation pursuant to §2200, to perform the function of making regulations under D.C. Code §1-319 (1981), in addition to the regulations specifically authorized
      under this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2201.10.</num>
    <text>Emergency regulations shall continue in effect until terminated by proclamation of the Mayor; Provided, that no emergency regulation shall continue in effect beyond the termination of the state of emergency in connection with which it was issued.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order No. 68-432, effective June 19, 1968, Article 48, §§2, 5(c), (6) of the Police Regulations (May 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>