<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2010</num>
  <heading>CONTAINERS CAPABLE OF CONFINING CHILDREN (ยง 24-2010)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2010.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall leave or cause to be left unattanded [unattended] in any place accessible to any child any unused or discarded refrigerator, ice box, freezer locker, or other box or container that has a capacity of one and one-half cubic feet (1 1/2
      ft.) or more, if it is equipped with a lock, latch, or other fastening device that permits the door or lid of the container to be securely fastened.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2010.2.</num>
    <text>The requirements of ยง2010.1 shall be applicable to owners, lessees, and managers with respect to the premises under their control.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2010.3.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section shall not apply to containers that have been securely padlocked or otherwise securely fastened in a manner that will prevent the door or lid being opened.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2010.4.</num>
    <text>Any person violating the provisions of this section shall be subject to civil sanctions provided in the Litter Control Administration Act of 1985.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2010.5.</num>
    <text>Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this article which involve any container that has been left unattended within a residential building or structure or which is not in plain
      view from public space pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory/Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication of any infraction of this article which in not in plain view from public space shall be pursuant to
      titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 39 of the Police Regulations (May 1981); as amended by ยง3 of the Litter Control Administration Act of 1985, D.C. Law 6-100, 33 DCR 781 (February 7, 1986); and by ยง14 of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions
        Act of 1985 Technical and Clarifying Amendments Act of 1990, D.C. Law 8-237, 38 DCR 314, 322 (January 11, 1991).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>