<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2006</num>
  <heading>FUEL OIL TANKS IN PUBLIC SPACE[COLON] PUBLIC ACCESS (ยง 24-2006)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2006.1.</num>
    <text>The permit issued under ยง2005 shall be granted on condition that the District has the right at any time to construct water pipes, gas pipes, sewers, conduits, or other pipes, or any underground construction that the Mayor may deem necessary to install
      under, over, around, or adjacent to the fuel oil tank</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2006.2.</num>
    <text>The permit shall be issued and accepted with the understanding that the occupation of the tank space is permitted merely as an accommodation to the owner of the abutting premises, and that no right, title, or interest of the public is in any way waived
      or abridged by the issuance of the permit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2006.3.</num>
    <text>If the street, roadway, or sidewalk is widened, the fuel oil tank shall be changed to correspond with the widened street, roadway, or sidewalk, without expense to the District, as directed by the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2006.4.</num>
    <text>The permit shall be granted on the further condition that the owner or owners, their heirs, executors, administrators, or assigns, shall remove entirely the tank and its appurtenances, immediately upon notice from the Mayor that water pipes, gas pipes,
      sewers, conduits, or other pipe or underground construction are to be installed in the space occupied by the tank. The tank shall be removed from the public space or to a new location to be designed by the Mayor without cost to the District, so
      as to leave a space clear and sufficient in the judgement of the Mayor for the introduction and maintenance of any underground construction that the Mayor deems is necessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2006.5.</num>
    <text>The owner or owners, their heirs, executors, administrators, or assigns shall agree to pay rental to the District in the amount prescribed by law or regulation for vault space.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2006.6.</num>
    <text>In the event of failure to pay the vault space rental, or any part of the rental, the permit shall be voided within thirty (30) days from the date the rental is demanded by the Mayor; and the tank and its appurtenances shall be removed immediately
      upon an order from the Mayor that they be removed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 12, ยง13 of the Police Regulations (May 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>