<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2001</num>
  <heading>HAZARDOUS OBSTRUCTIONS IN PUBLIC SPACE (§ 24-2001)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2001.1.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, the term &amp;#8220;public space&amp;#8221; includes any street, avenue, alley, highway, footway, sidewalk, parking, or other public space in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.2.</num>
    <text>No person shall construct, place, leave, or cause to be constructed, placed, or left on any public space any obstruction to travel, without first obtaining a permit from the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.3.</num>
    <text>No person, without a permit from the District, shall permit any bush, shrub, or tree to extend from private property onto public space in any manner that interferes with the free use of the public space.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.4.</num>
    <text>No person shall occupy with, place, leave, or cause to be placed or left on public space, any obstruction to travel that is dangerous to life and limb, without protecting and guarding that public space.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.5.</num>
    <text>The protection of public space required under §2001.4 shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Display of red flags or other danger signals during the time of the occupancy of the public space; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>At night, the display of a red light (or a sufficient number of red lights) in a manner that sufficiently warns the public of the obstruction, and that shows distinctly the clear passageway left in the highway, alley, street, or other public space.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.6.</num>
    <text>When the space occupied under §2001.4 extends a distance of five feet (5 ft.) or more, at least one (1) light shall be exhibited at each end of the obstruction. The light shall be hung so that it is clearly visible for a distance of at least one hundred
      feet (100 ft.) in any direction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.7.</num>
    <text>Whenever any permit issued by the District for the performance of work in either public or private space also includes permission to occupy public space, that permit shall be in place of the permit required by this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.8.</num>
    <text>No proprietor of any automobile or bicycle store, garage, or automobile filling station or service station shall place or leave any hose or pipe on the curb, sidewalk, or parking at any time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.9.</num>
    <text>Nothing in §2001.8 shall be construed as prohibiting the installation of any readily movable fixture authorized under a permit issued in conformity with the provisions of chapter 2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 3, §7(a), Article 4, §12 of the Police Regulations (May 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>