<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2320</num>
  <heading>PROCEDURES AND REQUIREMENTS FOR REGISTRATION OF A PISTOL FOR THE PURPOSE OFELF-DEFENSE WITHIN APPLICANT&amp;#8217;S HOME (§ 24-2320)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2320.1</num>
    <text>2320.1 In addition to satisfying all other firearms registration requirementsn this chapter, an applicant for a registration certificate for a pistol to besed for the purpose of self-defense within that person’s home shall complyith all the procedures
      and requirements of this section. In the event of anyrreconcilable conflict between this section and any other regulations regardinghe registration of a pistol, this section shall control.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2320.2</num>
    <text>2320.2 The Director may register a pistol so long as the pistol is not anssault weapon, or a machine gun as those terms are defined in § 101(3A) and10) of the Act (D.C. Official Code § 7-2501.01(3A) &amp;#038; (10) (2013 Supp.)),r an unsafe firearm
      prohibited under § 504 of the Act (D.C. Official Code §-2504.04 (2012 Repl.)).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2320.3</num>
    <text>2320.3 An applicant seeking to register a pistol he or she will purchase from airearms dealer pursuant to this section shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Acquire the firearm registration application (P.D. 219) either from anyicensed firearms dealer in the District of Columbia, or in person at theirearms Registration Section at the Metropolitan Police Department</text>
    </level>
    <text>headquarters, or by mailing a request with a self-addressed, stamped envelope toirearms Registration Section, Metropolitan Police Department, 300 Indianavenue, NW, Washington, D.C. 20001;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Obtain assistance necessary to complete the application by presenting theirearm registration application to a firearms dealer licensed under federal lawither:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Located inside the District if the firearm is purchased within theistrict; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Located outside the District if the firearm is purchased outside theistrict;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Appear in person at MPD headquarters to take these steps:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Report to the Firearms Registration Section with the completed firearmegistration application and provide the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>[RESERVED];</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A valid driver’s license or a letter from a physician attesting that thepplicant has vision at least as good as that required for a driver’s license;nd</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Residency verification, such as a District of Columbia driver’s licenser identification card, a current rental agreement, or a deed to property thatncludes a home;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Complete a firearm registration test;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If successful on the test, pay all applicable fees at the MPD cashier,ncluding thirty-five dollars ($35) for fingerprinting and thirteen dollars$13) for a firearm registration; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Present a fee receipt and submit to fingerprinting.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Await notification from the Firearms Registration Section via mail,elephone, or other electronic communication on whether all statutory andegulatory requirements for registration have been satisfied;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Upon notification that all statutory and regulatory requirements foregistration have been satisfied, an applicant shall either:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Return to the Firearms Registration Section to complete the registrationrocess and obtain the approved firearms registration certificate; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Choose to receive the completed firearms registration certificate by mail;nd</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Present the approved firearm registration application to the dealericensed under federal law or, if federal law such as 18 U.S.C. § 922 prohibitshe dealer from delivering the pistol to the applicant because the dealer is notithin the District of
        Columbia, have that firearms dealer transport the pistolo a dealer located within the District, where the applicant will take deliveryf the pistol.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2320.4</num>
    <text>2320.4 [RESERVED].</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2320.5</num>
    <text>2320.5 An applicant seeking to register a pistol legally possessed in anotherurisdiction pursuant to this section shall follow the procedure laid out inaragraphs (a), (c), (d), and (e) of § 2320.3, in that order. If the applicantoes not transport
      the pistol immediately to the Firearms Registration Sectionpon bringing it into the District, the applicant shall contact the Firearmsegistration Section by calling 202-727-4275, providing notification that aistol from another jurisdiction has been
      brought into the District, and thenegin the application process within forty-eight (48) hours of suchotification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2320.6</num>
    <text>2320.6 [RESERVED].</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2320.7</num>
    <text>2320.7 In the event of the loss, theft, or destruction of the registrationertificate or of a registered pistol, a registrant shall immediately file aolice report and shall also:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Immediately notify the Firearms Registration Section in writing of theoss, theft, or destruction of the registration certificate or of the registeredistol (including the circumstances, if known) upon discovery of such loss,heft, or destruction;
        and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Immediately return to the Firearms Registration Section the registrationertificate for any pistol which is lost, stolen, or destroyed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2320.8</num>
    <text>2320.8 [RESERVED].</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2320.9</num>
    <text>2320.9 When permitted under this section to transport a pistol, the pistolhall be unloaded, and neither the pistol nor any ammunition being transportedhall be readily accessible or directly accessible from the passengerompartment of the transporting
      vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2320.10</num>
    <text>2320.10 If the transporting vehicle does not have a compartment separate fromhe driver’s compartment, the pistol or ammunition shall be contained in aocked container other than the glove compartment or console, and the pistolhall be unloaded.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2320.11</num>
    <text>2320.11 If the transportation is in a manner other than in a vehicle, theistol shall be:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Unloaded;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Inside a locked container; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Separate from any ammunition.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 624 (January 16,009)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 4380, 4382June 5, 2009); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 8240September 23, 2011); as corrected
        by Errata Notice published at 58 DCR 8577October 7, 2011); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 17215December 27, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>