<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2401</num>
  <heading>REWARD ADVISORY PANEL (ยง 24-2401)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2401.1.</num>
    <text>The Chief of Police shall establish a Reward Advisory Panel which will consist at a minimum of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Support Services Officer, who shall chair the panel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Director, Criminal Investigations Division; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A representative from the law enforcement agency which made the arrest based on information provided if other than the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2401.2.</num>
    <text>The Reward Advisory Panel shall review each case upon the adjudication or conviction of a defendant arrested based on information provided under this chapter in order to determine the recommended amount of the award to be paid.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2401.3.</num>
    <text>If information was provided by more than one source, the Reward Advisory Panel shall determine the share of the reward to be awarded to each citizen based on the value of the information to the investigation and prosecution of the case.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2401.4.</num>
    <text>If the candidate for a reward from this Fund was nominated by a law enforcement agency other than the Metropolitan Police Department, the Chairman of the Reward Advisory Panel shall request a representative from the arresting agency to sit on the
      Panel when it reviews that case.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2401.5.</num>
    <text>The Reward Advisory Panel shall forward its recommendations to the Chief of Police for approval.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 6037, 6038 (August 26, 1994).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>