<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2315</num>
  <heading>APPROVAL PERIOD (§ 24-2315)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2315.1</num>
    <text>2315.1 The sixty- (60-) day period for issuance of a certificate under § 207f the Act (D.C. Official Code § 7-2502.07(b) (2012 Repl.)) may be extended forood cause in the event that the investigation into the applicant’sualifications has not been
      completed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2315.2</num>
    <text>2315.2 Reasons that an extension may be granted for good cause shall includehe following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Non-receipt of the results of an F.B.I. fingerprint check;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Non-receipt of responses from other law enforcement agencies queried abouthe applicant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Lost, mutilated, or destroyed records requiring reproduction oreplacement; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A substantial question concerning the applicant’s eligibility thatequires further inquiry.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2315.3</num>
    <text>2315.3 Any extension taken shall not exceed thirty (30) calendar days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2315.4</num>
    <text>2315.4 The applicant shall be notified of the extension by letter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2315.5</num>
    <text>2315.5 An application shall be automatically held in abeyance if the applicantas any other certificate pending, or becomes liable to revocation on any otherertificate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2315.6</num>
    <text>2315.6 An application that has been held under § 2315.5 shall be approved orenied in accordance with the time limits set forth in this section, after theermination of the revocation proceeding.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2315.7</num>
    <text>2315.7 Except as provided in § 2315.5, any application not expressly approvedr denied within the following periods shall be deemed to be denied for theurpose of appealing to the Director:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Within the sixty- (60-) day period required in the Act, unless the periods extended for good cause shown in accordance with this section; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>At the end of the thirty- (30-) day extension period under this section.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 23 DCR 8942 (May 6, 1977), incorporatingext of the Proposed Rulemaking published at 23 DCR 7061, 7074 (March 4, 1977);5 DCRR §314, November 1980, Special Edition; as amended by Final Rulemakingublished at 60 DCR 17215
        (December 27, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>