<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2316</num>
  <heading>CORRECTION OF CERTIFICATES (ยง 24-2316)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2316.1.</num>
    <text>Each applicant receiving a registration certificate shall immediately examine it to determine if it contains any incorrect information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2316.2.</num>
    <text>If any error is found in the registration certificate, the applicant shall return it either by mail or in person to the Firearms Registration Section, together with a statement showing the error and the correct information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2316.3.</num>
    <text>If the error occurred as a result of information supplied by the applicant, the applicant shall submit with the statement and certificate a fee equal to the fee paid at the time of the initial filing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2316.4.</num>
    <text>If a certificate is returned without the payment of the additional fee, and it is determined to include erroneous data supplied by the applicant, the certificate shall be held at the Firearms Registration Section until the fee is paid. The applicant
      shall be notified of this action by mail.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2316.5.</num>
    <text>If the applicant fails to pay the additional fee within fifteen (15) calendar days of the notice, the certificate shall be revoked. A notice of revocation shall be sent to the applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2316.6.</num>
    <text>Errors appearing on the certificate through inadvertence or error on the part of the Firearms Registration Section shall be corrected without charge to the applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2316.7.</num>
    <text>If the Firearms Registration Section discovers an error, it shall notify the holder of the certificate and require the holder to return it to the Section. The procedures set forth in this section shall apply, as appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 23 DCR 8942 (May 6, 1977), incorporating text of the Proposed Rulemaking published at 23 DCR 7061, 7075 (March 4, 1977); 35 DCRR ยง315, November 1980, Special Edition.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>