<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2105</num>
  <heading>EMERGENCY COMMUNICATIONS AND SERVICES (§ 24-2105)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2105.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall break the doors or locks of, or interfere in any way with, the signal boxes of the fire alarm or police patrol system.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2105.2.</num>
    <text>No person shall meddle or tamper with any bells, gongs, telephones, or other instruments or apparatus connected with or constituting any part of the telegraph or telephone service of the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2105.3.</num>
    <text>No person shall cut, break, injure, remove, or disturb any wire or wires connected with or forming a part of the services listed in §2105.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2105.4.</num>
    <text>No person shall place any billboard, sign, or other article or thing in front of or upon any fire alarm, patrol box, or fire hydrant so as to obstruct the view or ready access to it.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2105.5.</num>
    <text>No person shall fasten, tie, or hitch any horse, mule, or other animal to any fire alarm or patrol box, or to any pole or post used for the support of that box.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2105.6.</num>
    <text>No person shall leave any animal standing, without being tied, hitched, or fastened, near enough to any fire alarm or patrol box that injury might ensue by the animal rubbing against or coming in contact with the box, pole, or post.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2105.7.</num>
    <text>No person shall ride or drive any horse, mule, or other animal or cart, wagon, or other vehicle against any box, pole, or post upon which a fire alarm or police patrol box is supported.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2105.8.</num>
    <text>No person shall hang or swing upon the iron rods or pipes attached to any signal box; or climb upon, or in any manner tamper with, any fire alarm or patrol box within the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2105.9.</num>
    <text>Each lineman, repairman, or other employee of any telegraph, telephone, messenger, signal, or electric lighting company shall wear a conspicuously numbered badge indicating the name of the company by which he or she is employed while doing the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>While engaged in stringing, repairing, or replacing any overhead wire;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>While engaged in erecting, restoring, or repairing any pole of the company; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>While doing other work in connection with poles or wires.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 19, §§1, 2, 3 of the Police Regulations (May 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>