<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2319</num>
  <heading>EXECUTORS AND ADMINISTRATORS (§ 24-2319)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2319.1</num>
    <text>2319.1 The executor or administrator of an estate in the District of Columbia containing a firearm shall notify the Firearm Registration Section of his or her appointment or qualification, as the case may be, not later than thirty (30) days after
      the appointment or qualification and, until the lawful distribution of any such firearm, shall be subject to § 301(b) of the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2319.2</num>
    <text>2319.2 The notice required under § 2319.1 shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name, mailing address, and telephone number of the executor or administrator;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The registration number of the firearm, if available, or a description of the firearm including, the make, model, and serial number; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the decedent.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2319.3</num>
    <text>2319.3 Persons qualified to file a petition for distribution or for waiver of administration under Chapter 7 of Title 20 of the D.C. Official Code shall be considered to be executor or administrator of the small estate for the purposes of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2319.4</num>
    <text>2319.4 If the Director determines that the firearm was not registered or was otherwise possessed in violation of the Act, the Director shall so notify the executor or administration in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2319.5</num>
    <text>2319.5 If the executor or administrator receives a notification issued under § 2319.4, he or she shall, within seven (7) days of receiving the notification:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Surrender the firearm to the Firearm Registration Section;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Lawfully remove the firearm from the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Lawfully dispose of the firearm; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Submit a written appeal to the Director of the determination issued under § 2319.4.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2319.6</num>
    <text>2319.6 The executor or administrator shall not distribute any firearm in an estate to an heir or legatee that resides in the District unless the person to inherit or receive the firearm has first obtained a valid registration certification for the
      firearm. The registration application shall include a statement by the applicant that he or she seeks to gain possession of a firearm which is part of an estate and shall include the information required under § 2319.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2319.7.</num>
    <text>For an heir or legatee that resides outside the District, the executor or administrator shall notify the Firearm Registration Section, in writing, that the firearm in the estate has been distributed to a person living outside the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 24 DCR 2607 (September 30, 1977); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 17215 (December 27, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>