<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-299</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 24-299)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>299.1.</num>
    <text>In addition to the terms and phrases defined in the Act (D.C. Code §7-1001 (1981)), when used in this chapter, the following words and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed, except in those instances where the context clearly indicates a different
      meaning:</text>
    <text>Committee &amp;#8211; the Public Space Committee of the District of Columbia as constituted by Commissioner&amp;#8217;s Order No. 69-502, September 3, 1969.</text>
    <text>Department &amp;#8211; the D.C. Department of Public Works (D.C. Law 8-31).</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; the Director of the Department of Public Works, or the Director&amp;#8217;s agent, representative, or designee.</text>
    <text>Enclosed sidewalk cafe &amp;#8211; any authorized enclosure of public space as a temporary structure adjacent to a restaurant that consists of no more than one (1) story constructed primarily of light, incombustible, or fire-resistant materials; that
      does not restrict egress from the properties abutting the restaurant adjacent to the cafe; and that can be removed within a twenty-four (24) hour period.</text>
    <text>Unenclosed sidewalk cafe &amp;#8211; any authorized use of public space adjacent to a restaurant that contains tables, chairs, railings, or planters, that is open to the sky and at the sides, but may include awnings or umbrellas, and that can be removed
      within a twenty-four (24) hour period.</text>
    <text>Street right-of-way frontage – the section of the public space abutting the affected private property.</text>
    <text>Surface space &amp;#8211; all the space between the building line and the curb, regardless of whether the space is paved or unpaved.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 43, §§2(b), 3(e) the Police Regulations (May 1981); as amended by §4 of the District of Columbia Solid Waste Regulations Amendments Act of 1989, D.C. Law 8-31, 36 DCR 4750, 4753 (July 7, 1989); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published
        at 58 DCR 1118, 1132 (February 4, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>