<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2311</num>
  <heading>KNOWLEDGE OF FIREARMS AND TRAINING REQUIREMENTS (ยง 24-2311)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2311.1</num>
    <text>2311.1 Knowledge of the laws of the District pertaining to firearms, andnowledge of the safe and responsible use of firearms, shall be tested through aritten examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2311.2</num>
    <text>2311.2 Under compelling circumstances, an oral test may be administered inlace of the written test.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2311.3</num>
    <text>2311.3 The type of test and its content shall be at the sole discretion of theirector.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2311.4</num>
    <text>2311.4 [RESERVED].</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2311.5</num>
    <text>2311.5 [RESERVED].</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2311.6</num>
    <text>2311.6 Rifles and shotguns shall be considered the same type of firearm for theurposes of testing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2311.7</num>
    <text>2311.7 If an applicant fails an examination, he or she shall be allowed one (1)etest without charge.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2311.8</num>
    <text>2311.8 A fee equal to that submitted with the original application may, at theiscretion of the Director, be assessed for the second retest and for eachubsequent retest.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2311.9</num>
    <text>2311.9 An applicant shall complete a firearms training and safety classrovided by the Chief or submit evidence of compliance with ยง 203(a)(13)(B) ofhe Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 23 DCR 8942 (May 6, 1977), incorporatingext of the Proposed Rulemaking published at 23 DCR 7061, 7069 (March 4, 1977);5 DCRR ยง306, November 1980, Special Edition; as amended by Emergency androposed Rulemaking published
        at 56 DCR 624 (January 16, 2009)[EXPIRED]; asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 4380, 4381 (June 5, 2009); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 17215 (December 27, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>