<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-3313</num>
  <heading>RESERVED ON-STREET CAR SHARING (§ 24-3313)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3313.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall use the public right-of-way for the parking of its car-sharing vehicles in designated spaces in the public space without a public space permit issued by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3313.2.</num>
    <text>The Director shall issue an annual public space permit for a reserved on-street car sharing program only to a reserved on-street car-sharing company (“company”).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3313.3.</num>
    <text>A public space permit issued pursuant to this section shall be subject to the following conditions, in addition to such other conditions as may be imposed by law, regulation, or the Director:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The company must indemnify the District against legal liabilities associated with the use of public space for car-sharing operations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>All company car-sharing vehicles parked in the District, regardless of whether they are located on private or public space, must be registered in the District and display District license plates;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The company must reserve at least one (1) on-street space in each ward;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The company must have at least as many vehicles available to members in private parking locations as in public parking locations, including at least one (1) in each ward; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The company shall provide DDOT with data to help evaluate the impact of the reserved on-street car-sharing program.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3313.4.</num>
    <text>The fee for a permit issued pursuant to this section shall be assessed, for each parking space covered by the permit, at an annual cost of two thousand eight hundred and ninety dollars ($2,890).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3313.5.</num>
    <text>The fee may be increased annually by the lesser of the Consumer Price Index or five percent (5%).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3313.6.</num>
    <text>The permit may be renewed annually.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11236 (August 2, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>