<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-3506</num>
  <heading>CHANGES IN INFORMATION (§ 24-3506)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3506.1.</num>
    <text>An intercity bus service public space permit holder shall inform the Department in writing at least fifteen (15) days before any of the following changes:</text>
    <text>A change in the intercity bus owner if different from the intercity bus service operator; or</text>
    <text>A modification in the intercity bus service operator’s liability insurance; provided the modified insurance still meets requirements specified in § 3509.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3506.2.</num>
    <text>Upon receiving information described in § 3506.1, the Director, without review by the Public Space Committee, may approve and issue a new public space permit, and the prior permit shall be void. Within five (5) days after issuance of a new public
      space permit, the bus service operator shall ensure that copies of the new permit are displayed as required by § 3505.5.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3506.3.</num>
    <text>Prior to the occurrence of any of the following changes, an intercity bus service public space permit holder shall submit a new application to the Department requesting a new public space permit:</text>
    <text>A proposed change in the location of the approved passenger loading zone;</text>
    <text>A proposed increase in the size of the approved passenger loading zone; or</text>
    <text>A proposed increase in the hours of operation beyond the approved schedule.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3506.4.</num>
    <text>An application received under § 3506.3 shall be reviewed and approved by the Public Space Committee in accordance with the process outlined in this chapter for a new intercity bus passenger loading zone application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3506.5.</num>
    <text>Upon approval by the Public Space Committee of any changes outlined in § 3506.3 of this section, the Department shall issue a new permit reflecting the approved change(s), and the prior permit shall be void. Within five (5) days after issuance of
      a new permit, the bus service operator shall ensure that copies of the new permit are displayed as required by § 3505.5.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 5323, 5332 (June 24, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>