<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-3499</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 24-3499)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3499.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed below:</text>
    <text>Applicant &amp;#8211; an Owner or duly authorized agent of such Owner, who has submitted an application for a Permit to Excavate.</text>
    <text>Block &amp;#8211; that part of the Public Right-of-Way that includes the street area from the property line to the parallel property line in width and extending from the property line of an intersecting street to the nearest property line of the next
      intersecting street in length. For purposes of this definition, an intersection shall also be consider a Block&amp;#8221;.</text>
    <text>Days &amp;#8211; Calendar days, unless expressly stated otherwise.</text>
    <text>Department &amp;#8211; Department of Public Works.</text>
    <text>Excavation &amp;#8211; any work in the surface or subsurface of the Public Right-of-Way, including opening the Public Right-of-Way; installing, servicing, repairing, or modifying any Facility(ies) in or under the surface or subsurface of the Public
      Right-of-Way; and restoring the surface and subsurface of the Public Right-of-Way.</text>
    <text>Facility or Facilities &amp;#8211; any and all cables, cabinets, ducts, conduits, converters, equipment, drains, handholds, manholes, pipes, pipelines, splice boxes, surface location markers, tracks, tunnels, utilities, and other appurtenances or
      tangible things owned, leased, operated, or licensed by an Owner or Person, that are located or are proposed to be located in the Public Right-of-Way.</text>
    <text>Major Work &amp;#8211; any reasonably foreseeable Excavation that will affect the Public Right-of-Way for 15 or more consecutive calendar days.</text>
    <text>Moratorium Street &amp;#8211; any Block that has been reconstructed, repaved, or resurfaced by the department or any other Owner or Person in the preceding five year period.</text>
    <text>Owner &amp;#8211; any Person, including the District of Columbia, who owns any Facility or Facilities that are proposed to be installed or maintained in the Public Right-of-Way.</text>
    <text>Permit or Permit to Excavate &amp;#8211; an authorization to perform an Excavation as it has been approved, amended, or renewed by the Department.</text>
    <text>Permittee &amp;#8211; the Applicant to whom a Permit to Excavate has been granted by the Department in accordance with this Chapter.</text>
    <text>Person &amp;#8211; any natural Person, utility, firm, partnership, association, corporation, company or governmental agency, including the District of Columbia or United States of America.</text>
    <text>Public Right-of-Way &amp;#8211; the surface, the air space above the surface (including air space immediately adjacent to a private structure located on Public Space or in a Public Right-of-Way), and the area below the surface of any public street,
      bridge, tunnel, highway, lane, path, alley, sidewalk or boulevard</text>
    <text>Public Space &amp;#8211; all the publicly-owned property between the property lines on a street, park, or other public property as such property lines are shown on the records of the District, and includes any roadway, tree space, sidewalk, or parking
      between such property lines.</text>
    <text>Standard Specifications &amp;#8211; The District of Columbia Department of Public Works Standard Specifications for Highways and Structures (1996), as such may be amended from time to time.</text>
    <text>Winter Months &amp;#8211; The months of December through March.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 2360 (March 31, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9505 (December 1, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>