<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-3502</num>
  <heading>PUBLIC NOTICE OF APPLICATION (ยง 24-3502)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3502.1.</num>
    <text>Within five (5) calendar days after filing an application, the applicant shall give notice of the application to the adjacent property owner(s) and to the property owners on either side of the adjacent property owner(s). Notice shall be provided by
      certified mail or other similar method that ensures date of delivery. The notice shall include a full copy of the submitted public space permit application, provided, that only one (1) copy of each photographic that is part of the application need
      be provided, and the contact information provided by the Department for acceptance of comments on the application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3502.2.</num>
    <text>Within five (5) calendar days after filing an application, the applicant shall deliver notice of the application by hand to the operator of each business in a building that is located on property that is immediately adjacent to the proposed passenger
      loading zone, if the business can be accessed directly from the sidewalk without entry into a common area of the building. The notice shall include a full copy of the submitted public space permit application, provided, that only one (1) copy of
      each photograph that is part of the application need be provided, and the contact information provided by the Department for acceptance of comments on the application.</text>
    <text>Notice need not be provided to any business that cannot be accessed directly from the sidewalk.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3502.3.</num>
    <text>Within five (5) calendar days after filing an application, the operator shall post signs provided by the Department on at least one (1) sign pole or streetlight that is immediately adjacent to the curb where the intercity bus service passenger loading
      zone will be located. If no sign pole or streetlight is directly adjacent to the curb where the intercity bus service passenger loading zone will be located, the intercity bus operator may post the sign on the nearest sign pole or streetlight. The
      operator shall laminate the signs or protect the signs in another manner from the weather.</text>
    <text>The operator shall take all reasonable steps necessary to ensure the signs are posted for thirty (30) consecutive calendar days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3502.4.</num>
    <text>Within five (5) calendar days after providing the required notice as specified in this section, the applicant shall file with the Department an affidavit verifying that the applicant provided each notice required in this section.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 5323, 5327 (June 24, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>