<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-3599</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 24-3599)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3599.1.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the following words and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed, except in those instances where the context clearly indicates a different meaning:</text>
    <text>Adjacent property owner – a person who owns the private property nearest the curb where the intercity bus operator plans to establish an intercity bus passenger loading zone. The adjacent property owner is on the same side of the street as the intercity
      bus passenger loading zone.</text>
    <text>Bus – a motor vehicle with a seating capacity of more than twenty-five (25) passengers, exclusive of the driver, that is used for the transportation of passengers;</text>
    <text>Department &amp;#8211; District Department of Transportation</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; Director of the District Department of Transportation.</text>
    <text>Intercity bus – a bus used for intercity bus service.</text>
    <text>Intercity bus service operator – a company that operates intercity buses.</text>
    <text>Intercity bus service – regularly scheduled bus service for the general public which operates with limited stops over fixed routes connecting two (2) or more areas not in close proximity, and which has the capacity for transporting baggage carried
      by passengers.</text>
    <text>Intercity bus service passenger loading zone or intercity bus passenger loading zone – a segment of a curb lane designated by signs prohibiting general purpose parking or standing to facilitate loading and unloading of passengers for intercity bus
      service.</text>
    <text>Occupy – the parking, as that term is defined in 18 DCMR § 9901, of an intercity bus in a public right-of-way under the jurisdiction of the District of Columbia Government for any purpose.</text>
    <text>Person &amp;#8211; a person, utility, firm, partnership, association, corporation, company or organization of any kind.</text>
    <text>Public right-of-way – all the publicly owned property between the property lines on a street as such property lines are shown on the records of the District of Columbia, including the roadways, tree spaces, sidewalks, and alleys.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 5323, 5336 (June 24, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>