<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-3402</num>
  <heading>NOTICE OF EXCAVATIONS (ยง 24-3402)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3402.1.</num>
    <text>Any Permittee who excavates or causes to be made an Excavation in the Public Right-of-Way shall provide notice in accordance with this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3402.2.</num>
    <text>Notice for Non-Major Work. For Excavations that will be completed and restored in a period exceeding twenty-four (24) hours but within fourteen (14) calendar days of commencement, the Permittee shall post and maintain a notice at the site of Excavation.
      The notice shall include the name; telephone number of a Person who will be available during normal business hours to provide information to and receive complaints from any member of the public concerning the Excavation; the address of the Owner
      and Permittee; a description of the Excavation to be performed; and the duration of the Excavation. The notice shall be posted at each end of the block where Excavation is to take place at least seventy-two (72) hours prior to commencement of the
      Excavation. The Excavation project signs shall be in a format, and size specified by the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3402.3.</num>
    <text>Notice for Major Work. Prior to the commencement of all non-emergency Major Work, the Permittee shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>At least five (5) calendar days in advance, provide written notice delivered to each property Owner, resident, building manager, or tenant association on the block(s) affected by the Major Work and each affected advisory neighborhood commission
        and business improvement district. The notice shall include the same information that is required for the posted notice pursuant to subsection ยง3402.2; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Post and maintain notice at the site of the Excavation at least five (5) calendar days prior to commencement of the Excavation in the same manner and with the same information as required for posted notice pursuant to subsection ยง3402.2.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3402.4.</num>
    <text>Notice for emergency Excavation. For emergency Excavation, the Permittee, or the Applicant if a Permit has not been issued, shall post and maintain notice at the site of the Excavation during the construction period. The notice shall include the name,
      telephone number, and address of the Owner and Permittee, a description of the Excavation to be performed, and the duration of the Excavation. The notice shall be posted at least every 100&amp;#8242; along any Block where the Excavation is to take
      place.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 2360 (March 31, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>