<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-301</num>
  <heading>GENERAL REQUIREMENTS (§ 24-301)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>301.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall construct or operate a sidewalk cafe except when authorized by the Public Space Committee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.2.</num>
    <text>No person shall operate a sidewalk cafe until issued a Sidewalk Cafe Permit and a Certificate of Use, except as otherwise provided in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.3.</num>
    <text>No applicant shall be issued a Sidewalk Cafe Permit unless the adjacent property is zoned for restaurant or grocery store use or a variance to operate a restaurant or grocery store has been granted to the adjacent property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.4.</num>
    <text>No applicant shall be issued a Sidewalk Cafe Permit unless the applicant saves harmless and indemnifies the District, and its officers, agents, and employees from all suits, claims, charges, and judgments to which the District, its officers, agents,
      and employees may be subject on account of the issuance of a Sidewalk Cafe Permit, the operation of the sidewalk cafe, or the injury to any person or damage to any property, including the property of the District and the property of the applicant,
      where the applicant&amp;#8217;s or the District&amp;#8217;s property may be damaged or destroyed by the Fire Department or any other agency of the District pursuant to a public emergency or fire.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.5.</num>
    <text>No person permitted to operate a sidewalk cafe adjacent to a grocery store shall be permitted to obtain an alcoholic beverage license for that sidewalk café.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 30 DCR 4346, 4347 (August 26, 1983); as amended by D.C.ACT 17-665 published at 56 DCR 969 (January 30, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>