<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-400</num>
  <heading>FARMERS&amp;#8217; MARKETS (§ 24-400)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>400.1.</num>
    <text>The following sidewalks and parking spaces are designated as farmers&amp;#8217; street markets, and may be used by farmers for the temporary display and sale of farm products in accordance with the applicable provisions of this chapter:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That portion of the sidewalk on the north side of O Street, N.W., between Seventh and Eighth Streets, N.W., and that portion of the sidewalk on the west side of Seventh Street, N.W., between O and P Streets, N.W., adjacent to the market house owned
        by the Northern Market Company;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That portion of the sidewalk and parking space on the northside of K Street, N.W., between Fourth and Fifth Streets, N.W., and that portion of the sidewalk on the east side of Fifth Street, N.W., between K and L Streets, N.W., adjacent to the market
        house known as &amp;#8220;New Center Market&amp;#8221; (formerly Convention Hall Market);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>That portion of the sidewalk and northeast corner of Lot 824 in Square 2551, which is a square that is bordered by the south side of Columbia Road between Belmont Road, N.W., and 18th Street, N.W., and the west side of 18th Street, N.W., between
        Columbia Road and Belmont Road, N.W., adjacent to the Perpetual American Federal Savings and Loan Association; Provided, that prior written consent of the owner of the property has been obtained for the display and sale of farm products; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>That portion of the sidewalk and parking space on the west side of Wisconsin Avenue, N.W., that extends southward from Grace Street, N.W., for fifty feet (50 ft.), adjacent to Lot 811 in Square 1188.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>400.2.</num>
    <text>Spaces on each of the sidewalks and parking spaces listed in §400.1 for display and sale of farm produce by farmers shall be laid off and numbered in accordance with plats that shall have been submitted to, and approved by, the Department of Consumer
      and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>400.3.</num>
    <text>Spaces for display and sale of farm produce shall be not more than eight feet (8 ft.) long and not more than four feet (4 ft.) wide.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>400.4.</num>
    <text>Farm products may be displayed for sale on temporary removable stands not more than four feet (4 ft.) high on each of the numbered spaces.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>400.5.</num>
    <text>All stands shall be removed from the spaces when not in use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>400.6.</num>
    <text>Farm products may be displayed and sold at the farmers&amp;#8217; markets between the hours of 6:00 a.m. and 3:00 p.m. daily. On Saturdays and days before holidays, the time may extend until 8:30 p.m.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>400.7.</num>
    <text>No owner of any market house, or any other person, shall rent or lease to any person, either directly or indirectly, or occupy for gain, any public sidewalk, parking space, or other public space adjacent to any of the listed market houses, except
      as provided in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is §1 of the Commissioner&amp;#8217;s Order No. 273,040/128, effective May 10, 1932; §412 of the District.of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, as amended, 87 Stat.
        790, Pub. L. No. 93-198, D.C. Code §1-227(a) (1992 Repl. Vol.).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 5, §§1(a) &amp;#038; (b), 2(a), (b), &amp;#038; (d) of the Police Regulations (May 1981); as amended by §2 of the Police Regulations Amendment Act of 1981, D.C. Law 4-65, 28 DCR 5038 (November 27, 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>