<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-508</num>
  <heading>VENDING SITE PERMIT[COLON] GENERAL REQUIREMENTS AND FEES (§ 24-508)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>508.1.</num>
    <text>No person may vend from the public space in the District of Columbia without a Vending Site Permit issued by the DCRA Director pursuant to this chapter; provided, that a holder of a Class C Vending License may manage vendors from public space upon
      the issuance of a public space permit to the holder by DDOT and Mobile Roadway Vending vehicles may vend pursuant to § 533.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>508.2.</num>
    <text>A Vending Site Permit shall not be required for:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Persons authorized to sell products, merchandise, food, or services at a licensed Public Market or;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Persons authorized to sell products, merchandise, food, or services at a licensed or permitted Special Event.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>508.3.</num>
    <text>The Vending Site Permit shall authorize the permittee to occupy a specific Vending Location for the purpose of vending.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>508.4.</num>
    <text>A vendor may vend only at the assigned Vending Location stated on his or her Vending Site Permit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>508.5.</num>
    <text>In addition to the authorities cited in § 524, the DCRA Director, the DDOT Director, or MPD may eliminate a Vending Location without prior notice for public safety or transportation reasons, construction requirements, or Special Event operations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>508.6.</num>
    <text>The DCRA Director may revoke a Vending Site Permit and require the previously permitted vendor to vacate his or her Vending Location or relocate to another Vending Location pursuant to § 512.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>508.7.</num>
    <text>The annual fee for a Vending Site Permit for sidewalk vending locations shall be six hundred dollars ($600).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>508.8.</num>
    <text>The fee for a monthly Vending Site Permit in the Nationals Park Vending Zone shall be one hundred twenty-five dollars ($125) per monthly lottery, as described in § 529.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>508.9.</num>
    <text>The fee for a monthly Vending Site Permit for stationary roadway vending at Vending Locations designated by § 530 shall be four hundred and fifty dollars ($450) per monthly lottery.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>508.10.</num>
    <text>The annual fee for a Mobile Roadway Vending site permit shall be three hundred dollars ($300) as described in § 533.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 502 of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1984, effective September 26, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-113; 31 DCR 3974, 3981 (August 10, 1984)); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 32 DCR 5746, 5747 (October 11, 1985) ; as amended by D.C.
        Act published at 45 DCR 1172 (March 6, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 13055 (September 20, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>