<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-532</num>
  <heading>VENDING LOCATIONS[COLON] STATIONARY ROADWAY VENDING LOCATIONS[COLON] ADDITIONALOCATIONS (§ 24-532)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>532.1.</num>
    <text>The DDOT Director, in consultation with the DCRA Director, may designate or modify Stationary Roadway Vending Locations in addition to those authorized in § 531.1; provided, that no additional Stationary Roadway Vending Location shall be designated:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Within areas under the exclusive jurisdiction of the United States Park Police, the United States Capitol Police, or any other agency of the United States government;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Within a loading zone, entrance zone, parking space designated for diplomatic parking, or other curbside zone restricted for certain vehicles or uses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>On a snow emergency route designated under § 4024 of Chapter 40 (Traffic Signs and Restrictions at Specific Locations) of Title 18 (Vehicles and Traffic) of the DCMR;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Within forty feet (40 ft.) of an intersection;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Along the length of a Metrobus Stop Zone, a commuter bus zone, an intercity bus zone, or other curbside zone specifically designated and demarcated as being for transit use;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Within forty feet (40 ft.) of the driveway entrance to a police or fire station, or within twenty feet (20 ft.) of any other driveway;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Within twenty feet (20 ft.) of an alley;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Within forty feet (40 ft.) of any crosswalk;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Between the south side of Independence Avenue and the north side of Constitution Avenue, bounded by Rock Creek Parkway on the west and 4th Street NE/SE on the east; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Five feet (5 ft) from a building’s marked fire control room.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>532.2.</num>
    <text>Upon the designation of additional Stationary Roadway Vending locations, a lottery shall be conducted by the DCRA Director to assign these Stationary Roadway Vending locations. Any Stationary Roadway Vending Locations not assigned during this lottery
      shall be included in the lottery conducted pursuant to § 539.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 13055 (September 20, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>