<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-540</num>
  <heading>ASSIGNMENT OF MOBILE ROADWAY VENDING LOCATIONS (§ 24-540)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>540.1.</num>
    <text>MRV location permits for each MRV vehicle shall initially be determined by a monthly lottery with each lottery assigning a MRV vehicle to a specific MRV location and for a specific day of the month.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>540.2.</num>
    <text>The DCRA Director shall establish the format of the MRV location permit lottery program and may modify the format, as necessary, to improve efficiency or to incorporate technological advancements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>540.3.</num>
    <text>The lottery shall be conducted monthly, with MRV locations allocated to MRV vehicles by the following days of the week:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Monday;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Tuesday;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Wednesday;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Thursday; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Friday.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>540.4.</num>
    <text>A MRV vehicle shall register for the MRV location permit lottery by the MRV vehicle’s vehicle registration number and Vending Business license number. No vendors will be eligible for MRV location permit lottery in months when their Vending Business
      license will expire without renewal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>540.5.</num>
    <text>There shall be only one (1) MRV location permit lottery entry per MRV vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>540.6.</num>
    <text>Prior to each monthly lottery, MRV vendors shall have the option to list the available MRV locations in order of their preference; this information will serve as the MRV vendor’s lottery preference request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>540.7.</num>
    <text>In addition to the standard MRV location permit lottery entry, the DCRA Director may create a lottery program for MRV vehicles to vend from multiple established MRV locations for specific hours on specific days of the week during each month.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>540.8.</num>
    <text>The non-refundable lottery application fee for the monthly MRV location permit lottery shall be $25 per MRV vehicle and shall be paid prior to a MRV vehicle submitting monthly MRV location preferences.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>540.9.</num>
    <text>The monthly MRV location permit fee shall be $150 per MRV vehicle and shall be paid in full prior to the MRV vehicle being authorized to vend from the designated MRV location assigned via the monthly lottery.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>540.10.</num>
    <text>A MRV vendor not participating in the monthly MRV location permit program may vend from any legal parking space, in compliance with its Vending Site Permit and §§ 534 and 535.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 13055 (September 20, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>