<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-533</num>
  <heading>VENDING LOCATIONS[COLON] MOBILE ROADWAY VENDING LOCATIONS[COLON] GENERAL (§4-533)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>533.1.</num>
    <text>A Mobile Roadway Vending (MRV) vehicle operating in public space under this section shall have either an individual holding a valid Class A, Class B, or Class D Vending Business License or an individual holding a valid Vendor Employee Identification
      Badge, issued pursuant to § 564, inside the vehicle at all times while the vehicle is in operation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>533.2.</num>
    <text>A MRV Site Permit shall be required for each MRV vehicle, whether vending from a designated MRV location or any legal parking space in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>533.3.</num>
    <text>A MRV vehicle must be legally parked and pay all appropriate meter fees in order to vend from public space.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>533.4.</num>
    <text>A MRV vehicle shall not include an ice cream vending vehicle, as defined in § 599.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>533.5.</num>
    <text>A MRV shall not vend on any residential block designated as Residential Permit Parking unless specifically authorized by a Special Event permit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>533.6.</num>
    <text>To vend in a designated MRV location during the designated hours pursuant to § 534, a MRV vehicle shall be required to participate in a monthly MRV location permit lottery. If a MRV vehicle, with a valid MRV Site Permit, does not participate in the
      monthly MRV location permit lottery, the MRV shall still be authorized to vend from public space pursuant to § 535.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>533.7.</num>
    <text>No mobile roadway vending shall be authorized within two hundred feet (200 ft.) or directly across the street of a designated MRV location during the designated hours, except within another designated MRV location or with written approval from DCRA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 13055 (September 20, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>