<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-564</num>
  <heading>EMPLOYEES OF LICENSED VENDORS (§ 24-564)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>564.1.</num>
    <text>No individual shall work at a vending business unless the individual is the licensed vendor of the vending business or is an employee of the vendor holding a valid Vendor Employee Identification Badge.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>564.2.</num>
    <text>The employing vendor shall follow all applicable District and federal employment laws and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>564.3.</num>
    <text>An employee of a vendor may operate the vendor’s Class A or Class D vending business without the vendor being present; provided, that the employee holds a valid:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Food Protection Manager Certificate issued by the Conference of Food Protection Standards for Accreditation of Food Protection Manager Certification Programs in accordance with § 203 of Subtitle A (Food and Food Operations) of Title 25 of the DCMR;
        and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>DOH-issued a Certified Food Protection Manager Identification Card in accordance with § 203 of Subtitle A (Food and Food Operations) of Title 25 of the DCMR.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>564.4.</num>
    <text>No individual may act as an employee of a vendor unless that individual holds a valid Vendor Employee Identification Badge issued by the DCRA Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>564.5.</num>
    <text>An individual shall apply for a Vendor Employee Identification Badge by submitting an application to the DCRA Director, on a form prescribed by the DCRA Director, which shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name, address, photograph, and telephone number of the individual;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name and license number of the vendor for whom the individual will act as an employee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The signature of the individual;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The notarized signature of the vendor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The application fee, which shall be fifty-five dollars ($55); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Any additional information or documentation required by the DCRA Director.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>564.6.</num>
    <text>The Vendor Employee Identification Badge shall include the name of the employee of the vendor, a badge number, the name of the licensed vendor, and the Vending Business License number of the vendor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>564.7.</num>
    <text>An employee shall conspicuously wear his or her Vendor Employee Identification Badge when the employee is operating the vendor’s vending business.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>564.8.</num>
    <text>An individual may represent more than one (1) licensed vendor; provided, that the individual:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Has a Vendor Employee Identification Badge for each licensed vendor that employs the individual; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Displays the Vendor Employee Identification Badge for the respective licensed vendor while working at that vendor’s vending business.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>564.9.</num>
    <text>A licensed vendor shall be held responsible for the actions of his or her employees and independent contractors, where such actions are related to the operation of the vending business and, either singularly or in combination, the Vending Business
      License, Vending Site Permit, Vendor Employee Identification Badge, and health inspection certificate of the vendor may be suspended or revoked based on those actions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 13055 (September 20, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>