<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-505</num>
  <heading>VENDING BUSINESS LICENSE[COLON] ISSUANCE (§ 24-505)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>505.1.</num>
    <text>Within forty-five (45) days of filing a complete application for a Vending Business License, the applicant shall be notified by the DCRA Director of the issuance or denial of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>505.2.</num>
    <text>If the application is approved, the DCRA Director shall issue a Vending Business License to the applicant; provided, that if the applicant has applied for a Class A or Class C Vending Business License, no license shall be issued by the DCRA Director
      until the applicant has received all necessary licenses, permits, and authorizations from DOH and any other District agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>505.3.</num>
    <text>The Vending Business License shall include the vendor’s name, the class of license, and the date of expiration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>505.4.</num>
    <text>All Vending Business Licenses shall be valid for two (2) years from the date of issuance, unless the DCRA Director designates another time period in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>505.5.</num>
    <text>If the application is denied, the DCRA Director shall follow the procedures set forth in § 507.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>505.6.</num>
    <text>The DCRA Director and DOH Director shall return an incomplete application to the applicant without either approving or denying the application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>505.7.</num>
    <text>A Vending Business License will not be issued until a Vending Location has been designated pursuant to §§ 538-540.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 2 of the Vendors Regulation Amendments Act of 1978, effective June 30, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-82; 24 DCR 9293 (May 5, 1978)); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 32 DCR 1347 (March 8, 1985); as amended by D.C. Act published at 45 DCR 1172
        (March 6, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 372 (January 20, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 13055 (September 20, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>