<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-612</num>
  <heading>NON-DRIVING PARKING FACILITY ATTENDANTS (§ 24-612)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>612.1</num>
    <text>612.1 Notwithstanding the requirements of § 610.9 of this section, the Director may waive the requirement that the applicant possess a valid motor vehicle operator’s license when an application is accompanied by the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An affidavit from the owner or operator of the parking facility at which the applicant is to be employed stating that the applicant will, under no circumstances, be required or allowed to operate a motor vehicle while he or she is employed as a
        parking attendant in that establishment; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An affidavit from the applicant stating that the applicant will not operate any motor vehicle while he or she is employed as a parking attendant.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>612.2</num>
    <text>612.2 Any parking facility attendant subject to § 612.1 shall have clearly indicated on his or her license information identifying the attendant as a person not authorized to operate a motor vehicle in the course of his or her employment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>612.3</num>
    <text>612.3 The operation of a motor vehicle in the course of employment by a parking facility attendant subject to § 612.1 shall constitute a violation of this chapter. Conviction of this violation shall constitute grounds for the revocation of the license
      issued to the attendant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>612.4.</num>
    <text>A parking facility attendant subject to § 612.1 shall submit a new application for a parking facility attendant’s license if the terms of employment of the parking facility attendant require him or her to operate a motor vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 28, §5(b) of the Police Regulations (1981) (as section 617); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 7303 (September 4, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>