<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-811</num>
  <heading>FLOATS AND VEHICLES (§ 24-811)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>811.1.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section shall apply during the inaugural period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>811.2.</num>
    <text>All decorations used on floats shall be made of flame-resistant material approved by the Fire Chief.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>811.3.</num>
    <text>Heating devices or smoke effects used on floats shall not be installed unless written permission of the Fire Chief has been obtained in advance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>811.4.</num>
    <text>All electrical wiring used in floats, including that in the propelling equipment of floats, shall be installed in a safe manner and shall be clean and free from defects.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>811.5.</num>
    <text>Fire extinguishers of such number, type, and size as may be required by the Fire Chief shall be carried on each float.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>811.6.</num>
    <text>A list of all float entries, giving the location where each float is being built, shall be furnished to the Fire Chief by the Inaugural Committee no later than the final date for the entries, so that inspections can be made during construction of
      those floats that are being built within the Washington Metropolitan Area.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>811.7.</num>
    <text>Floats that are constructed at locations outside the Washington Metropolitan Area shall be inspected in accordance with the provisions of §811.8.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>811.8.</num>
    <text>Floats shall be completed and made available for inspection by the Fire Chief at least eight (8) hours prior to the inaugural parade.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>811.9.</num>
    <text>Floats that do not meet the requirements of §811.8 shall not be permitted to participate in the inaugural parade.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>811.10.</num>
    <text>All vehicles and floats exceeding the following size and weight limitations, specified in 18 DCMR §§2501, 2502, and 2505, require special hauling permits prior to being moved within the District, in accordance with the provisions of 18 DCMR §2508:</text>
    <text>Combined Vehicles</text>
    <text>Single Unit Vehicles</text>
    <text>Gross weight</text>
    <text>80,000 lbs.</text>
    <text>50,000 lbs.</text>
    <text>Total height</text>
    <text>13&amp;#8242; 6&amp;#8243;</text>
    <text>13&amp;#8242; 6&amp;#8243;</text>
    <text>Total length (including tractor)</text>
    <text>55&amp;#8242; 0&amp;#8243;</text>
    <text>40&amp;#8242; 0&amp;#8243;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>811.11.</num>
    <text>Special hauling permits shall be issued upon application to the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs, and upon payment to the D.C. Treasurer of a fee for each permit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>811.12.</num>
    <text>The engines and all other mechanical equipment of each float shall be in good working order and shall be free of excess grease.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>811.13.</num>
    <text>The mechanical condition of any motor vehicle used for the transportation or propulsion of a float shall be subject to the approval of the Director of Public Works, and no vehicle shall be operated in the inaugural parade until it has been approved
      by the Director of Public Works.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Sections 30 &amp;#038; 31 of the Presidential Inauguration Special Regulations and Rule of Interpretation Concerning Nonrevival of Statutes Act of 1982, D.C. Law 4-125, 29 DCR 2093 (May 21, 1982).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>