<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-812</num>
  <heading>STABLING OF ANIMALS (§ 24-812)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>812.1.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of §§3 and 18 of the Ordinance to Revise, Consolidate, and Amend the Ordinances of the Board of Health (DCMR Title 22), temporary places for stabling animals may be established during the inaugural period within the
      District if the Director of Environmental Services finds the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That the places have adequate and sufficient water supplies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That adequate receptacles for manure have been furnished;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>That adequate services for the removal of manure are available; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>That no animals are to be quartered within fifty feet (50 ft.) of any dwelling unit, railroad sleeping car, or other place used for habitation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>812.2.</num>
    <text>Each stabling area shall be maintained in a sanitary condition at all times.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>812.3.</num>
    <text>The Director of Environmental Services shall be authorized and directed to make any inspections and to take any necessary steps to obtain compliance with the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>812.4.</num>
    <text>A license issued by the Director of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs shall be required for each area where animals are stabled.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>812.5.</num>
    <text>Each building, structure, tent, shelter, or premises in which animals may be stabled shall be subject to the approval of the Fire Chief and the Director of Environmental Services, and shall comply with the requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>812.6.</num>
    <text>Non-fire-resistant buildings and structures may be used for the stabling of animals only if specifically approved for this use by the Fire Chief and the Director of Housing and Community Development.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>812.7.</num>
    <text>Canvas and other fabrics used in the construction of tents or shelters for animals shall be flame-resistant as directed by the Fire Chief.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>812.8.</num>
    <text>Where canvas or other fabric has been used in the construction of a tent or shelter for animals, the tent or shelter shall not be erected within fifty feet (50 ft.) of any building.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>812.9.</num>
    <text>No internal combustion engine shall be used within twenty-five feet (25 ft.) of any tent or shelter for animals.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>812.10.</num>
    <text>No person shall smoke in any building or premises in which hay, straw, wood shavings, dried grass, or similar combustible material is stored or used.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>812.11.</num>
    <text>&amp;#8220;NO SMOKING&amp;#8221; signs shall be conspicuously displayed at close intervals in each building or premises in which hay, straw, wood shavings, dried grass, or similar combustible material is stored or used.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>812.12.</num>
    <text>No open fires, flame appliance, or flame device shall be permitted or used in any area in which animals may be stabled.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>812.13.</num>
    <text>No internal combustion engine shall be permitted or used in any area in which animals may be stabled.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>812.14.</num>
    <text>All trash, refuse, manure, discarded bedding for animals, and other waste shall be removed daily, or more often if so ordered by either the Fire Chief or the Director of Environmental Services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>812.15.</num>
    <text>Firefighting appliances of the type and in the number as the Fire Chief may require shall be provided by the person using any building or premises for the stabling of animals.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Sections 32 &amp;#038; 33 of the Presidential Inauguration Special Regulations and Rule of Interpretation Concerning Nonrevival of Statutes Act of 1982, D.C. Law 4-125, 29 DCR 2093 (May 21, 1982).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>