<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-903</num>
  <heading>PIGEONS (ยง 24-903)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>903.1.</num>
    <text>No person or persons shall keep or cause to be kept any pigeons within the District, without a permit from the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>903.2.</num>
    <text>A permit shall be issued only upon the approval of the Director of the Department of Human Services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>903.3.</num>
    <text>Before a permit is issued to any person or persons, signatures of fifty-one percent (51%) of the householders within the radius of one hundred feet (100 ft.) from the loft shall first be obtained.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>903.4.</num>
    <text>The permit shall be dated when issued.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>903.5.</num>
    <text>Each permit shall be renewed annually on the anniversary date of issuance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>903.6.</num>
    <text>In any case where there have been no complaints during the previous year, the permit may be renewed for a corresponding period by endorsement on the back of the permit by the Director of the Department of Human Services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>903.7.</num>
    <text>Lofts, aviaries, nests, and other places where pigeons are kept shall be kept dry, well ventilated, clean, and sanitary at all times.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>903.8.</num>
    <text>Lofts, aviaries, nests, and other places where pigeons are kept shall be open at all reasonable times to inspectors of the Department of Human Services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>903.9.</num>
    <text>The permit shall be issued at a fee of two hundred dollars ($200).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 18, ยง12 of the Police Regulations (May 1981); as amended by ยง3 Animal Control Amendment Act of 1992, D.C. Law 9-236, 40 DCR 614, 616 (January 22, 1993).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>