<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-900</num>
  <heading>DOGS (§ 24-900)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>900.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall own or keep a dog that, by barking or in any other manner, disturbs the quiet of any neighborhood or any person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>900.2.</num>
    <text>No dog shall be allowed to go at large without a collar or tag, as prescribed by law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>900.3.</num>
    <text>No person owning, keeping, or having custody of a dog in the District shall permit the dog to be on any public space in the District, other than a dog park established by section 9a of the Animal Control Act of 1979, passed on 2 nd reading on September
      20, 2005 (Enrolled version of Bill 16-28), unless the dog is firmly secured by a substantial lease. The leash shall be held by a person capable of managing the dog.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>900.4.</num>
    <text>The length of the leash required under §900.3 shall not exceed four feet (4 ft.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>900.5.</num>
    <text>No person owning, keeping, or having custody of a dog in the District shall permit the dog to go on private property without the consent of the owner or occupant of the property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>900.6.</num>
    <text>No person owning, keeping, or having custody of a dog in the District shall permit the dog to be confined in any yard or other enclosure, or on any private property, or in any automobile or other vehicle, in a manner that allows the dog to bite or
      menace persons lawfully using any public street, highway, or public space.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>900.7.</num>
    <text>No person owning, keeping, or having custody of a dog, except a seeing eye dog, shall allow or permit the dog to defecate or urinate on public parking or any sidewalk or in any and each such person shall immediately remove dog excrement from any curb,
      gutter, alley or street.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>900.8.</num>
    <text>No person owning, keeping, or having custody of a dog, except a seeing eye dog, shall permit the dog&amp;#8217;s excrement to remain on private property without the consent of the owner or occupant of the property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>900.9.</num>
    <text>Any person violating any provision of §§900.1 through 900.6 shall be punished by a fine of not more than three hundred dollars ($300), or by imprisonment not exceeding ten (10) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>900.10.</num>
    <text>Any person violating §§900.7 or 900.8 shall be subject to civil sanctions provided in the Litter Control Administration Act of 1985.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>D.C. Code § 8-1908; Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 2000-98.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order 61-1734 effective October 12, 1961, as amended by Regulation No. 72-20, effective August 25, 1972; by §3 of the Animal Control Act Amendment Act of 1980, D.C. Law 3-97, 27 DCR 3523 (August 15, 1980); Article 18, 551-6
        and 8 of the Police Regulations (May 1981); by §3 of the Litter Control Administration Act of 1985, D.C. Law 6-100, 33 DCR 781, 783 (February 7, 1986); and by §2 of the Litter Control Fine Increase Amendment Act of 1995, D.C. Law 11-13, 42 DCR
        1268 (March 17, 1995); as amended by D.C. Act at 52 DCR 9087 (October 14, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>