<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-1528</num>
  <heading>POSTPONEMENT OF BID OPENING (ยง 27-1528)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1528.1.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer may postpone a bid opening until after the time scheduled for bid opening under the following circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If the contracting officer has reason to believe that the bids of an important segment of bidders have been delayed in the mail or in the electronic system specified for transmission of bids, for causes beyond the control of bidders and without
        their fault or negligence, such as flood, fire, accident, weather conditions, strikes, or District equipment blackout or malfunction when bids are due; or</text>
    </level>
    <text>If an emergency or unanticipated event interrupts normal governmental processes so that the conduct of bid openings as scheduled is impractical.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1528.2.</num>
    <text>At the time of a determination to postpone a bid opening, an announcement of the determination shall be publicly posted. If practical, before issuance of a formal amendment to the IFB, the determination shall be otherwise communicated to prospective
      bidders.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1528.3.</num>
    <text>When a bid opening is postponed, the time of the rescheduled bid opening shall be communicated to prospective bidders.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1528.4.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer may proceed with bid opening as soon as practical after the original scheduled bid opening time without amendment to the IFB or notice to bidders whenever any delay incident to the issuance of the amendment or notice would
      not be in the best interest of the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1431 (February 26, 1988); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 3714 (March 6, 2012)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 6290, 6299 (June 1, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>