<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-1609</num>
  <heading>EVALUATION OF UNSOLICITED PROPOSALS (ยง 27-1609)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1609.1.</num>
    <text>The agency shall consider the following factors when evaluating a valid unsolicited proposal:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Unique or innovative methods, approaches, or concepts demonstrated by the proposal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Overall scientific, technical, or socio-economic merits of the proposal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Potential contribution of the effort to the agency&amp;#8217;s specific mission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The offeror&amp;#8217;s capabilities, related experience, facilities, techniques, or unique combinations of these which are integral factors for achieving the proposal objectives; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Qualifications, capabilities, and experience of the proposed team leader or key personnel who are critical to achieving the proposal objective.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1609.2.</num>
    <text>An agency shall return an unsolicited proposal to an offeror, citing reasons, when its substance meets any of the following criteria:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>It is available to the District without restriction from another source;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>It closely resembles a pending competitive requirement; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>It does not demonstrate an innovative or unique method, approach, or concept.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1609.3.</num>
    <text>A favorable evaluation of an unsolicited proposal shall not, by itself, justify awarding a contract without full and open competition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1609.4.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer may commence negotiations only when all of the following conditions are met:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The unsolicited proposal has received a favorable comprehensive evaluation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The unsolicited proposal is not disqualified under the provisions of ยง 1609.2;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The agency supports its recommendations with facts and circumstances that preclude competition, and has the necessary funds;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The agency has obtained written approval from the Director; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The contracting officer has publicized the requirement in accordance with Chapter 13 of this title.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1450 (February 26, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 1136 (February 1, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>