<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-1524</num>
  <heading>LATE BIDS, LATE WITHDRAWALS, AND LATE MODIFICATIONS (ยง 27-1524)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1524.1</num>
    <text>1524.1 Any bid received at the location designated in the solicitation after the time and date set for receipt of bids shall be considered a &amp;#8220;late&amp;#8221; bid unless it was received prior to the contract award and any of the following
      applies:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>It was sent by registered or certified mail not later than five (5) calendar days before the bid receipt date specified;</text>
    </level>
    <text>It was sent by mail and the contracting officer determines that the late receipt was due solely to mishandling by the District after receipt at the location specified in the IFB; or</text>
    <text>It was sent electronically by the bidder prior to the time and date specified and there is objective evidence in electronic form confirming that the bid was received prior to the bid receipt time and date specified.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1524.2</num>
    <text>1524.2 Any request for withdrawal or request for modification of a bid received after the bid receipt time and date is late.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1524.3.</num>
    <text>A late bid, late request for modification, or late request for withdrawal shall not be considered, except as provided in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1524.4.</num>
    <text>A late modification of a successful bid which makes its terms more favorable to the District shall be considered at any time it is received and may be accepted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1524.5.</num>
    <text>A late bid, late modification of bid, or late withdrawal of bid that is not considered shall be held unopened, unless opened for identification, until after award and then retained with unsuccessful bids.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1430 (February 26, 1988); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed published at 59 DCR 3714 (March 6, 2012)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 6290, 6297 (June 1, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>