<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-1003</num>
  <heading>APPOINTMENT OF CONTRACTING OFFICERS (ยง 27-1003)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1003.1.</num>
    <text>Each delegation of contracting authority under the Act shall be in writing and shall include clear instructions on the limitations of the contracting authority being delegated.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1003.2.</num>
    <text>The Director may delegate contracting authority to any District employee; however, the chief procurement officer of an agency which is not subject to the authority of the Director may only delegate authority to a District employee within his or her
      agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1003.3.</num>
    <text>The Director shall use a form approved for each written delegation or modification of contracting authority. The executed form shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The limitations on the scope of delegated authority to be exercised;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The limitations on the authority set forth in applicable laws and regulations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The signature of the Director.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1003.4.</num>
    <text>In no instance shall the individual being delegated contracting authority presume any greater contracting authority than what has been given.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1003.5.</num>
    <text>Termination of a contracting officer&amp;#8217;s appointment shall be in writing unless the written delegation or modification of authority contains a provision for automatic termination or expiration. No termination shall operate retroactively.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1003.6.</num>
    <text>The Director shall publish and regularly update on the OCP Internet an updated list of authorized contracting officers and their authority limits.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1386 (February 26, 1988); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 9071 (September 27, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 11071,
        11072 (December 23, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>