<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-114</num>
  <heading>SUBPOENAS (ยง 27-114)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>114.1.</num>
    <text>A party is expected to cooperate in good faith by making available witnesses and evidence under the party&amp;#8217;s control, when requested by another party, without issuance of a subpoena and by securing the voluntary attendance of third-party
      witnesses and the production of evidence by third parties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>114.2.</num>
    <text>The presiding judge may issue, on his or her initiative or upon written motion of a party, a subpoena that commands the person to whom it is directed to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Attend and give testimony at a deposition;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Attend and give testimony at a hearing; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Produce the books, papers, documents, and other tangible things designated in the subpoena.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>114.3.</num>
    <text>A request for subpoena shall state the relevancy, materiality, and scope of the testimony or documentary evidence sought, including, as to documentary evidence, the identification of all documents desired and the facts to be proved by them in sufficient
      detail to indicate materiality and relevancy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>114.4.</num>
    <text>The party requesting a subpoena shall arrange for its service. The service shall be made as soon as practicable after the subpoena has been issued.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>114.5.</num>
    <text>A subpoena requiring the attendance of a witness at a deposition or hearing may be served at any place consistent with the rules of the D.C. Superior Court. A subpoena may be served by registered or certified mail, by a United States Marshal or his
      or her deputy, or by any other person who is not a party and is not less than 18 years of age.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>114.6.</num>
    <text>The service of a subpoena upon a person named in the subpoena shall be made by personally delivering a copy to that person and tendering the fees for one day&amp;#8217;s attendance and the mileage allowed by law. However, where the subpoena is issued
      on behalf of the District government, the fees and mileage allowance need not be tendered in advance of attendance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>114.7.</num>
    <text>The person serving the subpoena shall make proof of the service to the Board promptly, and, in any event, before the date on which the person served must respond to the subpoena. The proof of service shall be made by completing and executing the &amp;#8220;Return
      on Service&amp;#8221; portion of a duplicate copy of the subpoena issued by an administrative judge and returning it to the Board. If service is made by a person other than a United States Marshal or his or her deputy, that person shall make an
      affidavit as proof by executing the &amp;#8220;Return on Service&amp;#8221; in the presence of a notary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>114.8.</num>
    <text>Upon written motion by the person subpoenaed or by a party, made within ten (10) days after service, but in any event not later than the time specified in the subpoena for compliance, the Board may:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Quash or modify the subpoena if it is unreasonable and oppressive or for other good cause shown; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Require the party in whose behalf the subpoena was issued to advance the reasonable cost of producing subpoenaed documentary evidence.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>114.9.</num>
    <text>In a case of contumacy or refusal to obey a subpoena by a person who resides, is found, or transacts business within the jurisdiction of the D.C. Superior Court, the Board shall apply to the D.C. Superior Court for an order requiring the person to
      appear before the Board to give testimony, produce evidence, or both. If a person fails to obey the order, without adequate excuse, the Board may apply for an order that the person be held in contempt by the Court.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 2078 (March 8, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>