<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-1608</num>
  <heading>UNSOLICITED PROPOSALS (ยง 27-1608)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1608.1.</num>
    <text>Unsolicited proposals may be considered by agencies in order to obtain innovative or unique methods or approaches to accomplishing their missions from sources outside the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1608.2.</num>
    <text>A valid unsolicited proposal shall meet all of the following criteria:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be innovative or unique;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be independently originated and developed by the offeror;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Be prepared without District supervision;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Include sufficient detail to permit a determination that District support would be worthwhile; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Show that the proposed work could benefit the mission of the agency.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1608.3.</num>
    <text>Unsolicited proposals shall contain the following information to permit consideration in an objective and timely manner:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Offeror&amp;#8217;s name, address, and type of organization, such as profit, non- profit, educational or certified business enterprise;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Names of and contact information for technical and business personnel to be contacted for evaluation or negotiation purposes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Identification of proprietary data to be used only for evaluation purposes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Signature of a person authorized to represent and contractually obligate the offeror;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Proposed price or total estimated cost for the effort in sufficient detail for meaningful evaluation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The period of time for which the proposal is valid;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The type of contract preferred; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The proposed duration of effort.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1449 (February 26, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 1136 (February 1, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>