<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-1009</num>
  <heading>PROCUREMENT PLANNING (ยง 27-1009)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1009.1.</num>
    <text>Agencies shall perform procurement planning and conduct market surveys to promote and provide for full and open competition with due regard to the nature of the goods and services to be acquired.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1009.2.</num>
    <text>When full and open competition is not required by law, agencies shall perform procurement planning and conduct market surveys to obtain competition to the maximum extent practicable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1009.3.</num>
    <text>The Director shall prescribe procurement planning procedures for the following purposes:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>To ensure that contracts are awarded after full and open competition with adequate procurement planning and availability of funds;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>To ensure that procurement planning addresses the requirement to specify needs, develop specifications, and to solicit offers in a manner that promotes and provides for full and open competition;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>To establish criteria and thresholds at which increasingly greater detail and formality in the procurement planning process is required in those cases in which a written procurement plan must be prepared;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>To ensure that the principles of this section are applied, as appropriate, for all procurements whether or not a written plan is required;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>To review and approve procurement plans and revisions to those plans; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>To authorize the waiver of standard procurement planning formats in cases of emergency.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1009.4.</num>
    <text>Procurement planning shall begin as soon as an agency need is identified and preferably well in advance of the fiscal year in which the contract award is necessary. In developing the plan, the planner may form a team consisting of all those who will
      be responsible for significant aspects of the procurement, such as contracting, fiscal, legal, and technical personnel and, when applicable, the Department of Small and Local Business Development.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1394 (February 26, 1988); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 9071 (September 27, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 11071,
        11076 (December 23, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>