<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-1008</num>
  <heading>PROHIBITION AGAINST CONTINGENT FEES (§ 27-1008)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1008.1</num>
    <text>1008.1 The contracting officer shall ensure that each solicitation, other thanhose for small purchases, contains language approved by the Director givingotice to prospective contractors of the prohibition against contingent feerrangements set forth
      in § 416 of the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1008.2</num>
    <text>1008.2 The contracting officer shall ensure that the language required by §16(b) of the Act is inserted into each contract, except contracts for smallurchases.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1008.3</num>
    <text>1008.3 Except as permitted in § 416(b) of the Act, the contracting officerhall not award any contract to a contractor that has made arrangements to pay aontingent fee or other consideration for soliciting or obtaining the contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1008.4</num>
    <text>1008.4 If the contracting officer has reason to believe that a prospectiveontractor or contractor is or has been involved in a contingent fee arrangementrohibited under § 416 of the Act, the contracting officer shall inform theirector in writing,
      which shall include any evidence or documentation of thelleged prohibited arrangement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1008.5</num>
    <text>1008.5 If the Director determines that a prohibited contingent fee has beenaid or that a contractor has entered into an arrangement to pay a prohibitedontingent fee under an existing contract, the Director shall have the right toerminate an existing
      contract or take any other remedial action authorizednder § 416(b) of the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1008.6</num>
    <text>1008.6 If the Director determines that a prospective contractor has enterednto an arrangement to pay a prohibited contingent fee, he or she shall directhe contracting officer to notify the prospective contractor that it is noonger eligible for contract
      award.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1391 (February 26, 1988); asmended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 9071September 27, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemakingublished at 58 DCR 11071, 11076
        (December 23, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>