<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-1610</num>
  <heading>PRICES FOR SERVICES PROVIDED UNDER THE DISTRICT&amp;#8217;S TEMPORARY ASSISTANCE TOEEDY FAMILIES PROGRAM (§ 27-1610)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1610.1.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the requirements of § 1612.1, for services provided under the District’s Temporary Assistance to Needy Families (TANF) Program, implementing the Self-sufficiency Promotion Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Law 12-241), the Director sets
      the following prices to be paid to contractors selected through the solicitation, and no price evaluation factor will be required for procurement of these services:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Work Readiness and Placement Services</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Base compensation &amp;#8211; The District shall make the monthly base payments set out in the table below depending on the contractor’s number of not-employed Point-In-Time (PIT) caseload:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Not-employed PIT</text>
    <text>Monthly Base Compensation</text>
    <text>150</text>
    <text>$34,000</text>
    <text>300</text>
    <text>$54,000</text>
    <text>450</text>
    <text>$75,000</text>
    <text>600</text>
    <text>$82,000</text>
    <text>750</text>
    <text>$103,000</text>
    <text>900</text>
    <text>$110,000</text>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Outcome-based compensation &amp;#8211; The District shall pay the outcome-based compensation set out in the following table based on the contractor’s achievement of specific outcomes:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Outcomes</text>
    <text>Performance Standard</text>
    <text>Incentive</text>
    <text>Payment Point 1: Education or training program completion payment</text>
    <text>A not-employed customer completes the education or training program(s) specified in the customer’s Individual Responsibility Plan (IRP). Upon verification of the successful completion of the education or training program(s), the contractor determines
      that the customer is employable and is eligible to receive Job Placement Services.</text>
    <text>$400 per customer who meets the performance standard for Payment Point 1.</text>
    <text>The District shall pay the contractor a maximum of one education or training program completion payment per customer who meets the performance standard per 12-month calendar period.</text>
    <text>Payment Point 2: Participation payment</text>
    <text>A not-employed customer meets his or her full monthly participation requirements, through a combination of approved core and non-core TANF activities.</text>
    <text>$200 per month per customer who meets the performance standard for Payment Point 2.</text>
    <text>Payment Point 3: Work placement payment</text>
    <text>The contractor places a customer in unsubsidized employment.</text>
    <text>Payment shall be made to the contractor when the customer successfully completes two weeks of work and has fully met his or her work participation requirements for those two weeks.</text>
    <text>Participation weeks do not have to be consecutive.</text>
    <text>$400 per customer who obtains unsubsidized work either within four months of the education and work slot completion date or while still engaged in an education or work slot.</text>
    <text>$200 per customer who obtains unsubsidized work more than four months after the education and work slot completion date.</text>
    <text>The District shall pay the contractor a maximum of two work placement payments per customer per 12-month calendar period; however, should the contractor be eligible for two work placement payments of $400 each in a 12-month calendar period, the contractor
      shall be limited to only one $400 payment, with the second one being a $200 payment.</text>
    <text>Outcomes</text>
    <text>Performance Standard</text>
    <text>Incentive</text>
    <text>Payment Point 4: Higher wage payment</text>
    <text>The contractor places a customer in unsubsidized employment, where the customer’s wages exceed an amount equal to $2.50 per hour less than the District’s Living Wage rate.</text>
    <text>Payment shall be made to the contractor when the customer successfully completes two weeks of work and has fully met his or her work participation requirements for those two weeks.</text>
    <text>Participation weeks do not have to be consecutive.</text>
    <text>$300 per customer who meets the performance standard for Payment Point 4.</text>
    <text>The District shall pay the contractor a maximum of two higher wage payments per customer per 12-month calendar period.</text>
    <text>Payment Point 5: Employment retention payment</text>
    <text>A customer who is placed in unsubsidized employment by the contractor meets his or her full monthly participation requirements through a combination of core and non-core TANF activities.</text>
    <text>$400 per month per customer who meets performance standard for Payment Point 5.</text>
    <text>The District shall pay the contractor a maximum of six employment retention payments (six months of full participation) per customer per 12-month calendar period. Participation months do not have to be consecutive.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Reimbursable costs &amp;#8211; The District shall reimburse the contractor the following amounts for allowable incentives, stipends and discrete work-related expenses for which the contractor can provide documentation:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Education or training program(s) completion incentives: Three hundred dollars ($300) per customer who completes the education or training program(s) specified in the customer’s IRP, is subsequently determined employable by the contractor, and becomes
        eligible to receive Job Placement Services; limited to one (1) such incentive per customer per twelve (12)-month calendar period.</text>
    </level>
    <text>(ii) Employment retention incentives: A total incentive payment not to exceed one thousand two hundred fifty dollars ($1,250) per customer per twelve (12)-month calendar period; for a customer who enters unsubsidized employment, and retains the unsubsidized
      job for six (6) months. The employment retention incentives shall be calculated as follows:</text>
    <text>a. Two (2)-week employment retention incentive: One hundred fifty dollars ($150) when the customer enters an unsubsidized job and works for at least two (2) weeks and has met his or her full work participation requirements over these two (2) weeks.
      Participation weeks do not have to be consecutive.</text>
    <text>b. One (1)-month employment retention incentive: One hundred twenty dollars ($120) when the customer retains the unsubsidized job and has met his or her full work participation requirements for one (1) month.</text>
    <text>c. Two (2)-month employment retention incentive: One hundred twenty dollars ($120) when the customer retains the unsubsidized job and has met his or her full work participation requirements for two (2) months. Participation months do not have to be
      consecutive.</text>
    <text>d. Three (3)-month employment retention incentive: One hundred twenty dollars ($120) when the customer retains the unsubsidized job and has met his or her full work participation requirements for three (3) months. Participation months do not have
      to be consecutive.</text>
    <text>e. Four (4)-month employment retention incentive: One hundred twenty dollars ($120) when the customer retains the unsubsidized job and has met his or her full work participation requirements for four (4) months. Participation months do not have to
      be consecutive.</text>
    <text>f. Five (5)-month employment retention incentive: One hundred twenty dollars ($120) when the customer retains the unsubsidized job and has met his or her full work participation requirements for five (5) months. Participation months do not have to
      be consecutive.</text>
    <text>g. Six (6)-month employment retention incentive: Five hundred dollars ($500) when the customer retains the unsubsidized job and has met his or her full work participation requirements for six (6) months. Participation months do not have to be consecutive.</text>
    <text>(iii) Stipends: Fifteen dollars ($15) per day per customer who participates in approved core and non-core TANF activities for at least four (4) hours per day. Stipends shall not be reimbursed for a customer once he or she enters unsubsidized employment
      and has received his or her first paycheck.</text>
    <text>(iv) Discrete work-related expenses: No more than two hundred fifty dollars ($250) per customer per twelve (12)-month calendar period for actual allowable costs to enable the customer to defray significant, discrete customer work-related expenses
      such as obtaining a medical test not covered by Medicaid or purchasing uniforms for customers who have a firm job offer. The total discrete work-related expense shall not exceed two hundred fifty dollars ($250) per customer per twelve (12)-month
      calendar period, unless pre-approved in writing by DHS.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Job Placement Services</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Base compensation &amp;#8211; The District shall make the monthly base payments set out in the table below depending on the contractor’s not-employed PIT:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Not-employed PIT</text>
    <text>Monthly Base Compensation</text>
    <text>150</text>
    <text>$18,000</text>
    <text>300</text>
    <text>$19,000</text>
    <text>450</text>
    <text>$19,000</text>
    <text>600</text>
    <text>$12,000</text>
    <text>750</text>
    <text>$12,000</text>
    <text>900</text>
    <text>$6,000</text>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Outcome-based compensation &amp;#8211; The District shall pay the outcome-based compensation set out in following table based on the contractor’s achievement of specific outcomes:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Outcomes</text>
    <text>Performance Standard</text>
    <text>Incentive</text>
    <text>Payment Point 1: Education or training program completion payment</text>
    <text>This payment point is not applicable to the Job Placement Services solicitation.</text>
    <text>This payment point is not applicable to the Job Placement Services solicitation.</text>
    <text>Payment Point 2: Participation payment</text>
    <text>A not-employed customer meets his or her full monthly participation requirements, through a combination of approved core and non-core TANF activities.</text>
    <text>$150 per month per customer who meets the performance standard for payment point 2.</text>
    <text>Payment Point 3: Work placement payment</text>
    <text>The contractor places a customer in unsubsidized employment.</text>
    <text>Payment shall be made to the contractor when the customer successfully completes two weeks of work and has fully met his or her work participation requirements for those two weeks.</text>
    <text>Participation weeks do not have to be consecutive.</text>
    <text>$400 per customer who obtains unsubsidized work within three months of the date DHS referred the customer to the contractor.</text>
    <text>$200 per customer who obtains unsubsidized work more than three months after the date DHS referred the customer to the contractor.</text>
    <text>The District shall pay the contractor a maximum of two work placement payments per customer per 12-month calendar period; however, should the contractor be eligible for two work placement payments of $400 each in a 12-month calendar period, the contractor
      shall be limited to only one $400 payment, with the second one being a $200 payment.</text>
    <text>Outcomes</text>
    <text>Performance Standard</text>
    <text>Incentive</text>
    <text>Payment Point 4: Higher wage payment</text>
    <text>The contractor places a customer in unsubsidized employment, where the customer’s wages exceed an amount equal to the District’s Living Wage rate.</text>
    <text>Payment shall be made to the contractor when the customer successfully completes two weeks of work and has fully met his or her work participation requirements for those two weeks.</text>
    <text>Participation weeks do not have to be consecutive.</text>
    <text>$300 per customer who meets the performance standard for Payment Point 4.</text>
    <text>The District shall pay the Contractor a maximum of two higher wage payments per customer per 12-month calendar period.</text>
    <text>Payment Point 5: Employment retention payment</text>
    <text>A customer who is placed in unsubsidized employment by the contractor meets his or her full monthly participation requirements through a combination of core and non-core TANF activities.</text>
    <text>$300 per month per customer who meets the performance standard for Payment Point 5.</text>
    <text>The District shall pay the Contractor a maximum of six employment retention payments (six months of full participation) per customer per 12-month calendar period. Participation months do not have to be consecutive.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Reimbursable costs &amp;#8211; The District shall reimburse the contractor the following amounts for allowable incentives, stipends and discrete work-related expenses for which the contractor can provide documentation:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Employment retention incentives: A total incentive payment not to exceed one thousand two hundred fifty dollars ($1,250) per customer per twelve (12)-month calendar period; for each customer who enters unsubsidized employment, and retains the unsubsidized
        job for six (6) months. The employment retention incentives shall be calculated as follows:</text>
    </level>
    <text>a. Two (2)-week employment retention incentive: one hundred fifty dollars ($150) when the customer enters an unsubsidized job and works for at least two (2) weeks and has met his or her full work participation requirements over these two (2) weeks.
      Participation weeks do not have to be consecutive.</text>
    <text>b. One (1)-month employment retention incentive: one hundred twenty dollars ($120) when the customer retains the unsubsidized job and has met his or her full work participation requirements for one (1) month.</text>
    <text>c. Two (2)-month employment retention incentive: one hundred twenty dollars ($120) when the customer retains the unsubsidized job and has met his or her full work participation requirements for two (2) months. Participation months do not have to be
      consecutive.</text>
    <text>d. Three (3)-month employment retention incentive: one hundred twenty dollars ($120) when the customer retains the unsubsidized job and has met his or her full work participation requirements for three (3) months. Participation months do not have
      to be consecutive.</text>
    <text>e. Four (4)-month employment retention incentive: one hundred twenty dollars ($120) when the customer retains the unsubsidized job and has met his or her full work participation requirements for four (4) months. Participation months do not have to
      be consecutive.</text>
    <text>f. Five (5)-month employment retention incentive: one hundred twenty dollars ($120) when the customer retains the unsubsidized job and has met his or her full work participation requirements for five (5) months. Participation months do not have to
      be consecutive.</text>
    <text>g. Six (6)-month employment retention incentive: five hundred dollars ($500) when the customer retains the unsubsidized job and has met his or her full work participation requirements for six (6) months. Participation months do not have to be consecutive.</text>
    <text>(ii) Stipends: Fifteen dollars ($15) per day per customer who participates in approved core and non-core TANF activities for at least four (4) hours per day. Stipends shall not be reimbursed for customers once he or she enters unsubsidized employment
      and has received his or her first paycheck.</text>
    <text>(iii) Discrete work-related expenses: No more than two hundred fifty dollars ($250) per customer per twelve (12)-month calendar period for actual allowable costs to enable the customer to defray significant, discrete customer work-related expenses
      such as obtaining a medical test not covered by Medicaid or purchasing uniforms for customers who have a firm job offer. The total discrete work-related expense shall not exceed two hundred fifty dollars ($250) per customer per twelve (12)-month
      calendar period, unless pre-approved in writing by DHS.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1451 (February 26, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 1136 (February 1, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>