<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-1400</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 27-1400)
    <text>The District shall accomplish the purposes of this title by using electronicommerce whenever practicable.</text>
    <text>The use of the terms in this title commonly associated with paper transactionsfor example, “typewritten”, “copy”, “document”, “signed innk”, “written legibly”, “page”, “postmark”, “envelope”) shalle deemed to include their electronic analogues and
      shall not be interpreted toiscourage the use of electronic commerce.</text>
    <text>As a condition of participation in an electronic transaction, the Director mayequire potential bidders and offerors to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Register with the District, and any other entity designated by the District,efore participating in an electronic transaction; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Agree to the terms, conditions, or other requirements of an electronicransaction, or to agree to terms and conditions governing the electronicransaction, such as procedures that the District may use to attribute,uthenticate, or verify the accuracy
        of an electronic offer or the actions thatonstitute an electronic signature.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Contracting officers may allow the use of other media, including but notimited to hard copies of drawings, specifications, or bid samples, toupplement electronic submissions to meet the requirements of the electronicransaction.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 10224October 29, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposedulemaking published at 58 DCR 1658 (March 4, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended byotice of Emergency and
      Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 6100 (July 22,011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR978 (September 9, 2011).</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>