<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-113</num>
  <heading>FAILURE TO MAKE OR COOPERATE IN DISCOVERY; SANCTIONS (ยง 27-113)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>113.1.</num>
    <text>Before any motion to compel discovery is filed, the affected parties or counsel must meet for a reasonable period of time in an effort to resolve the disputed matter. The movant shall include in any motion to compel discovery with a certification
      that despite a good faith effort to secure it, the discovery material sought has not been provided. This certification shall set forth specific facts describing the good faith effort, including a statement of the date, time, and place of the meeting
      required by this rule.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>113.2.</num>
    <text>If a party fails to obey an order to provide or permit discovery, the Board may make:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An order that certain facts shall be taken to be established in accordance with the claim of the moving party;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An order refusing to allow the disobedient party to support or oppose designated claims or defenses, or prohibiting that party from introducing designated matters in evidence;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An order striking pleadings, staying further proceedings until the order is obeyed, dismissing the case or proceeding or any part thereof, or rendering a judgment by default against the disobedient party; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>An order imposing such other sanctions as the Board deems appropriate.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>113.3.</num>
    <text>When the Board believes that the circumstances warrant either dismissing the case or rendering a default judgment against the disobedient party as a discovery sanction, it will issue an order to show cause pursuant to Rule 121.3.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 2078 (March 8, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>