<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-117</num>
  <heading>RECONSIDERATION (ยง 27-117)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>117.1.</num>
    <text>A party to an appeal or a protest may by motion request the Board to reconsider its decision or order for the reasons stated below:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>To clarify the decision;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>To present newly discovered evidence which by due diligence could not have been presented to the Board prior to the rendering of its decision;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If the decision contains typographical, numerical, technical or other clear errors that are evidence on their face; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>If the decision contains errors of fact or law, except that parties shall not present arguments substantially identical to those already considered and rejected by the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>117.2.</num>
    <text>For appeals, a motion for reconsideration shall be filed within (30) thirty days after the Board&amp;#8217;s decision or order is transmitted to a party. For protests, a motion for reconsideration shall be filed within the time period set forth in
      Rule 313.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>117.3.</num>
    <text>A motion for reconsideration shall set forth the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The particular points of fact or law which the moving party believes the Board has overlooked or misapprehended;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any argument the moving party wishes to make in support of the motion; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The relief sought and the reasons for seeking the relief.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>117.4.</num>
    <text>For appeals, a party may file an opposition to a motion for reconsideration no later than fifteen (15) days after the motion is served. For protests, a party may file an opposition within the time period set forth in Rule 313.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>117.5.</num>
    <text>If a motion for reconsideration is granted, the Board may make a final disposition of the case without reargument, permit reargument, or issue an appropriate order regarding further proceedings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>117.6.</num>
    <text>A motion of reconsideration does not affect the finality of the Board&amp;#8217;s decision or suspend its operation except that the Board may stay its decision for good cause shown.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 2078 (March 8, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>