<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-1527</num>
  <heading>OPENING OF BIDS (ยง 27-1527)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1527.1.</num>
    <text>Bids and modifications shall be opened publicly, in the presence of one (1) or more witnesses, at the time, date, and location designated in the IFB.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1527.2.</num>
    <text>The name of each bidder, the bid price and such other information as the contracting officer deems appropriate, shall be read aloud or otherwise made available. Such information also shall be recorded at the time of bid opening; that is, the bids
      shall be tabulated or a bid abstract made.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1527.3.</num>
    <text>The names and addresses of required witnesses shall be recorded at the bid opening.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1527.4.</num>
    <text>The opened bids shall be available for public inspection except to the extent the bidder designates trade secrets or other proprietary data to be confidential as set forth in ยง 1527.7. Material so designated shall accompany the bid and shall be readily
      separable from the bid in order to facilitate public inspection of the nonconfidential portion of the bid.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1527.5.</num>
    <text>Prices, makes and models, or a catalogue of the items offered, deliveries, and terms of payment shall be publicly available at the time of bid opening regardless of any designation to the contrary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1527.6.</num>
    <text>If bids are submitted through electronic means, a bid abstract containing the requirements of this section shall be published on the Internet as soon as practicable after bid opening.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1527.7</num>
    <text>1527.7 The contracting officer shall examine the bids to determine the validity of any requests for nondisclosure of trade secrets and other proprietary data identified in writing. The contracting officer may request that a bidder provide the justification
      for withholding information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1431 (February 26, 1988); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 3714 (March 6, 2012)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 6290, 6299 (June
        1, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>