<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-1500</num>
  <heading>INVITATION FOR BIDS (ยง 27-1500)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1500.1.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall solicit goods and services for contracts exceeding one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000) using the competitive sealed bidding process unless the Director determines that use of competitive sealed bidding is not practicable
      or in the best interest of the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1500.2.</num>
    <text>An invitation for bids (IFB) shall be used to solicit goods or services under competitive sealed bidding procedures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1500.3.</num>
    <text>Each IFB shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Instructions and information to bidders concerning bid submission requirements, including the time and date set for receipt of bids and the location where bids are to be delivered;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The purchase description, delivery, or performance schedule, and any special instructions necessary; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A statement indicating whether contract award will be made on the basis of the lowest bid price or the lowest evaluated bid price, whichever is applicable.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1500.4.</num>
    <text>If the lowest evaluated bid price is the basis of contract award, the objective measurable criteria to be used shall be set forth in the IFB. The objective measurable criteria must be related to price.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1500.5.</num>
    <text>The IFB shall require acknowledgement by each bidder of the receipt of all issued amendments, addenda, and changes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1500.6.</num>
    <text>The District shall evaluate bids without discussions with bidders.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1500.7.</num>
    <text>Information concerning proposed acquisitions shall not be released outside the District before solicitation, except for pre-solicitation notices.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1420 (February 26, 1988); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 3714 (March 6, 2012)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 6290 (June 1,
        2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>