<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-1627</num>
  <heading>LATE PROPOSALS, LATE MODIFICATIONS, AND LATE WITHDRAWALS (ยง 27-1627)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1627.1.</num>
    <text>Any proposal or modification to proposal received at the location designated in the RFP after the time and date set for receipt of proposals shall be considered &amp;#8220;late&amp;#8221; unless it was received prior to the contract award and any
      of the following applies:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>It was sent by registered or certified mail not later than five (5) calendar days before the date and time specified for receipt of offers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>It was sent by mail and the contracting officer determines that the late receipt was due solely to mishandling by the District after receipt at the location specified in the RFP;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>It was sent electronically by the offeror prior to the time and date specified and there is objective evidence in electronic form confirming that the offer was received prior to the date and time specified for receipt; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>It was the only proposal received.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1627.2</num>
    <text>1627.2 Any request for withdrawal or request for modification of an offer received after the time and date set for receipt of proposals is late.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1627.3.</num>
    <text>A late proposal, late request for modification, or late request for withdrawal shall not be considered, except as provided in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1627.4.</num>
    <text>A late modification of a successful proposal which makes its terms more favorable to the District shall be considered at any time it is received and may be accepted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1627.5.</num>
    <text>A late proposal, late modification of offer, or late withdrawal of offer that is not considered shall be held unopened, unless opened for identification, until after award and then retained with unsuccessful offers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1627.6.</num>
    <text>If any information received electronically is unreadable, the contracting officer immediately shall notify the offeror and permit the offeror to resubmit the unreadable portion of the information. The method and time for resubmission shall be prescribed
      by the contracting officer after consultation with the offeror, and documented in the contract file. The resubmission shall be considered as if it were received at the date and time of the original unreadable submission for the purpose of determining
      timeliness, provided the offeror complies with the time and format requirements for resubmission prescribed by the contracting officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1463 (February 26, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 1136 (February 1, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>