<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2116</num>
  <heading>LEASING OF MOTOR VEHICLES (ยง 27-2116)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2116.1.</num>
    <text>Each motor vehicle leased by and for the District shall comply with all Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standards and applicable District motor vehicle safety regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2116.2.</num>
    <text>Before preparing a solicitation for leasing of motor vehicles, the contracting officer shall obtain from the requesting agency written certification of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That the vehicles requested are of maximum fuel efficiency and minimum body size, engine size, and equipment necessary to fulfill operational needs, and meet prescribed fuel economy standards; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That the head of the requesting agency has certified that any requested passenger automobiles (sedans and station wagons) that are larger than compact size are essential to the agency&amp;#8217;s mission.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2116.3.</num>
    <text>The solicitation shall not be limited to current-year production models. However, with the prior approval of the head of the using agency, the solicitation may be limited to current models on the basis of overall economy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2116.4.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall include the following items in each solicitation for leasing motor vehicles:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The scope of the contract;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The method of computing payments;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A listing of the number and type of vehicles required, and the equipment and accessories to be provided with each vehicle;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The responsibilities of the contractor or the District for furnishing gasoline, motor oils, antifreeze, and similar items;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A statement that the contractor shall perform all maintenance on the vehicles, unless the contracting officer determines that it will be more economical for the District to perform the work;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A statement regarding the applicability of pertinent District laws and regulations, and the responsibility of each party for compliance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The responsibilities of the contractor and the District for emergency repairs and services.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2116.5.</num>
    <text>In each solicitation and contract for leasing of motor vehicles, the contracting officer shall insert clauses, approved by the Director, pertaining to vehicle lease payments, condition of leased vehicles, marking of leased vehicles, and other pertinent
      clauses approved by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1522 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>