<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2611</num>
  <heading>NOTICE OF INTENT TO AWARD (ยง 27-2611)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2611.1.</num>
    <text>Each notice of intent to award shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The identity of the IFB;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The prospective contractor&amp;#8217;s bid;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The award price;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A statement notifying the prospective contractor that all required performance and payment bonds must be properly executed by the prospective contractor and sureties and returned to the contracting officer by the prospective contractor within the
        time period specified in the IFB, or, if no time period is specified in the IFB, within ten (10) days after the bond forms are presented by the District to the prospective contractor for signature;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A statement notifying the prospective contractor that the required contract form must be properly executed by the prospective contractor and returned to the contracting officer by the prospective contractor within the time period specified in the
        IFB, or, if no time period is specified in the IFB, within ten (10) days after the District government contract form is presented by the District to the prospective contractor for signature; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A statement that a notice to proceed will be issued, contingent upon the contracting officer&amp;#8217;s receipt of executed performance and payment bonds and executed contract form that is in compliance with the requirements of the IFB and this
        title.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2611.2.</num>
    <text>The District may, without any liability upon the District, rescind the notice of intent to award at any time prior to approval of a formal written contract signed by the prospective contractor and the contracting officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1584 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>