<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2708</num>
  <heading>SURETIES (ยง 27-2708)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2708.1.</num>
    <text>Agencies shall obtain adequate security for bonds (including coinsurance and reinsurance agreements), required or used with a contractor for goods or services, including construction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2708.2.</num>
    <text>A bond security may be obtained from a corporate or individual surety, provided that an individual surety shall not be used for any construction contract in excess of one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2708.3.</num>
    <text>Each corporate surety shall be a company authorized to do business in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2708.4.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall determine the acceptability of all individuals proposed as sureties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2708.5.</num>
    <text>At least two (2) individual sureties shall be required to execute a security. The net worth of each individual surety shall equal or exceed the amount of the security.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2708.6.</num>
    <text>When determining the acceptability of an individual surety, the contracting officer shall consider the number and amounts of other bonds upon which a proposed individual surety is bound, and the status of the contracts for which those securities were
      furnished.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2708.7.</num>
    <text>Each individual surety shall execute an affidavit of financial responsibility on a form prescribed by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2708.8.</num>
    <text>In accordance with ยง2 of the Act of June 11, 1878, D.C. Code ยง1-301 (1981), no person, corporation, partnership, or other entity shall act as a surety under this chapter at any time during the period when that person, corporation, partnership, or
      other entity is a party to a contract with the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1602 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>