<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-211</num>
  <heading>HEARINGS (ยง 27-211)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>211.1.</num>
    <text>The Board shall provide the parties at least seven (7) business days notice of the time and place of a hearing, but the notice may be waived by the parties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>211.2.</num>
    <text>All hearings on the merits shall be open to the public. The Board may limit access to testimony covered by a protective order entered in the case pursuant to Rule 104.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>211.3.</num>
    <text>Questions concerning the admissibility of evidence and other matters that may arise in the course of the hearing shall be ruled upon by the presiding administrative judge, or, if necessary, by a majority vote of the designated panel. A decision upon
      the merits, or a final disposition of any appeal or part thereof, shall be by majority vote of the designated panel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>211.4.</num>
    <text>Witnesses at hearings shall be examined orally under oath or affirmation, which shall be administered by the presiding administrative judge or any member of the assigned panel. Any member of the panel may question any witness at any time during or
      after examination or cross-examination by the parties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>211.5.</num>
    <text>An official reporter selected by the District shall make an official transcript of the proceedings at hearings on the merits. After the close of a hearing this transcript, together with any exhibits, briefs, or other documents filed in the proceeding,
      shall be filed with the Board and become a part of the record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>211.6.</num>
    <text>The official reporter shall transmit copies of the transcript to the Board and the contracting agency. Copies of the official transcript shall be supplied to other parties by the official reporter at rates determined between the official reporter
      and the parties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>211.7.</num>
    <text>Motions to correct an official transcript shall be filed with the Board within fifteen (15) days after the receipt of the last portion of the transcript, and shall certify the date when the last portion of the transcript was received by the maker
      of the motion.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 2078 (March 8, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>