<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2801</num>
  <heading>CONTRACTING OFFICER&amp;#8217;S RESPONSIBILITIES (ยง 27-2801)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2801.1.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall ensure that any requirements for consent to subcontract are included in the solicitation for the prime contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2801.2.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer&amp;#8217;s consent to subcontract shall not constitute a determination of the acceptability of the subcontract terms, price, or allowability of costs, unless the consent to subcontract specifies otherwise.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2801.3.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall not consent to subcontract in any of the following instances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>When the fee in a cost-reimbursement subcontract exceeds any applicable fee limitations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>When a payment under the subcontract is on a cost-plus-a-percentage-of- cost basis;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>When the contracting officer is obligated to deal directly with the subcontractor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>When the results of arbitration, judicial determination, or voluntary settlement between the prime contractor and subcontractor are made binding on the District; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>When there is a repetitive or unduly protracted use of cost-reimbursement, time-and-materials, or labor-hour subcontracts.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2801.4.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall not refuse consent to subcontract merely because the subcontract contains a clause giving the subcontractor the right of indirect appeal to the Contract Appeals Board if the subcontractor is affected by a dispute between
      the District and the prime contractor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1610 (February 26, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 7493 (June 22, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>