<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2500</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (ยง 27-2500)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2500.1.</num>
    <text>The District shall specify procurement needs in a manner designed to promote competition to the maximum extent possible.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.2.</num>
    <text>The District shall develop specifications and purchase descriptions using market research in a manner designed to promote competition to the maximum extent possible, with due regard to the nature of the goods or services to be procured.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.3.</num>
    <text>Solicitations shall contain specifications and purchase descriptions that include restrictive provisions or conditions only to the extent necessary to satisfy the minimum needs of the District, or as authorized or required by law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.4.</num>
    <text>Plans, drawings, specifications, standards, or purchase descriptions for procurements shall state only the District&amp;#8217;s actual minimum needs and describe the goods or services in a manner designed to promote competition to the maximum extent
      possible.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.5.</num>
    <text>Specifications and purchase descriptions shall reflect the minimum needs of the District and the market available to meet those needs. Specifications and purchase descriptions may be stated in terms of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Function, so that a variety of products or services may qualify;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Performance, including specifications of the range of acceptance characteristics or the minimum acceptable standards; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Design requirements.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.6.</num>
    <text>Responsibility for the preparation and issuance of standard specifications shall be in accordance with ยง401 of the Procurement Practices Act of 1985 (the &amp;#8220;Act&amp;#8221;), D.C. Code ยง 1-1184.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, D.C. Law 6-85, as amended, D.C. Code ยง 1-1181.1 et seq. (1981).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1572 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>