<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2110</num>
  <heading>PROCUREMENT FROM THE BLIND AND SEVERELY HANDICAPPED (§ 27-2110)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2110.1.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall be responsible for implementing the procurement requirements of §6 of the Employment Opportunities Act of 1978, D.C. Law 2-128, D.C. Code §36-605 (1981).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2110.2.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in §2100, the contracting officer, when procuring goods and services, shall use the procurement lists established by the Committee for the Purchase of Products and Services of the Blind and Other Severely Handicapped (the &amp;#8220;Committee&amp;#8221;).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2110.3.</num>
    <text>The use of procurement lists of workshops representing the blind and other severely handicapped is mandatory for the procurement of listed goods and services, except as provided in §2112 or where the use would be contrary to the priorities established
      in §2100.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2110.4.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall obtain goods and services on the procurement list from the Committee or directly from a workshop authorized by the Committee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2110.5.</num>
    <text>When the Committee authorizes the contracting officer to transmit orders for specific goods or services directly to a workshop, the authorization shall be in writing and shall remain valid until it is revoked by the Committee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2110.6.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall purchase goods or services on the procurement list, at prices established by the Committee, from a qualified workshop if they are available within the required period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2110.7.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer may procure goods and services not included on the procurement list from a workshop under a solicitation issued by any other procurement method authorized by this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2110.8.</num>
    <text>Prior to initiating a procurement from commercial sources, the contracting officer shall document, in writing, that the supply or service is not available from a procurement list or that an exception has been granted by the Committee in accordance
      with §2112. The document shall be maintained in the contract file.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1519 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>