<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2605</num>
  <heading>PRICING CONSTRUCTION CONTRACTS (ยง 27-2605)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2605.1.</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise authorized under this chapter, a contracting officer shall use firm-fixed-price contracts to procure construction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2605.2.</num>
    <text>A contract may be priced on a lump-sum basis (when a lump sum is paid for the total work or defined parts of the work), on a unit-price basis (when a unit price is paid for a specified quantity of work units), or a combination of both methods.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2605.3.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall use lump-sum pricing in preference to unit pricing except when any one (1) of the following circumstances exists:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Large quantities of work (such as excavation, grading, paving, building outside utilities, or site preparation) are involved which cannot be estimated with sufficient confidence to permit a lump-sum offer without a substantial contingency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Estimated quantities of work required may change significantly during construction; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Bidders would have to expend unusual effort to develop adequate estimates.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2605.4.</num>
    <text>If an economic price adjustment provision is customary in contracts for the type of work being procured, or when omission of an adjustment provision would preclude a significant number of firms from submitting bids or would result in bidders including
      unwarranted contingencies in proposed prices, fixed-price contracts with economic price adjustments may be used in accordance with the applicable provisions of chapters 15 and 24 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1581 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>