<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2199</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 27-2199)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2199.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have the meaning ascribed:</text>
    <text>Committee &amp;#8211; the Committee for Purchase of Products and Services of the Blind and Other Severely Handicapped.</text>
    <text>Commercial sources &amp;#8211; sources available in the open market or sheltered market under the Minority Contracting Act of 1976, D.C. Law 1-95, D.C. Code ยง1-1141 et seq. (1981), including educational and non-profit institutions.</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; the Director of the Office of Contracting and Procurement or the District of Columbia Chief Procurement Officer.</text>
    <text>Excess personal property &amp;#8211; any personal property under the control of a District agency that the agency head or a designee determines is not required for its needs and for the discharge of its responsibilities.</text>
    <text>Leasing &amp;#8211; the acquisition, hiring, or renting of motor vehicles other than by purchase from private or commercial sources.</text>
    <text>Maximum order limitation &amp;#8211; the dollar amount or unit quantity above which a contracting officer may not submit orders and a contractor may not accept orders. The limitation is generally specified in the schedule contract.</text>
    <text>Minimum order &amp;#8211; the dollar amount or unit quantity below which a contracting officer may not submit orders and a contractor is not obligated to accept orders. It is generally specified in each schedule contract. Orders below established
      minimums are generally subject to the contractor&amp;#8217;s acceptance.</text>
    <text>Motor vehicle &amp;#8211; an item of equipment, mounted on wheels and designed for highway or land use that derives power from a self-contained power unit or is designed to be towed by and used in conjunction with self-propelled equipment.</text>
    <text>Multiple award schedule &amp;#8211; a contract made with more than one (1) supplier for comparable goods and services at varying prices for delivery within the same geographic area.</text>
    <text>Printing &amp;#8211; the product of duplication, binding, blank-book, and microform work (including any items requiring the process of composition, platemaking, presswork, or binding) for use by a District agency.</text>
    <text>Procurement list &amp;#8211; a list of goods and services that the Committee has determined are suitable by the District.</text>
    <text>Related goods &amp;#8211; goods that are used and equipment that is usable in printing and binding operations.</text>
    <text>Single award schedule &amp;#8211; a contract made with one (1) supplier at a stated price for specific items and for delivery to a geographic area defined in the schedule.</text>
    <text>Term contract &amp;#8211; a requirements contract or an indefinite quantity contract as defined in chapter 24 of this title.</text>
    <text>Utility service &amp;#8211; electricity, gas, telecommunications, water, sewerage, and steam that are available to the general public, and the provision of those services by governmental entities or private companies.</text>
    <text>Workshop &amp;#8211; a qualified non-profit agency for the blind or other severely handicapped approved by the Committee to produce a supply or provide a service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1523 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>