<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2205</num>
  <heading>DETERMINATIONS AND DOCUMENTATION (ยง 27-2205)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2205.1.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer&amp;#8217;s execution of a contract shall constitute a determination that the prospective contractor is responsible with respect to that contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2205.2.</num>
    <text>When an offer on which an award would otherwise be made is rejected because the prospective contractor is found to be nonresponsible, the contracting officer shall make, sign, and place in the contract file a determination of nonresponsibility, which
      shall state the basis for the determination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2205.3.</num>
    <text>If the contracting officer determines and documents that a responsive certified minority business lacks certain elements of responsibility, the contracting officer shall comply with the provisions of ยง2202.6.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2205.4.</num>
    <text>Documents and reports supporting a determination of responsibility or nonresponsibility, including any preaward survey reports and any applicable information from the District of Columbia Local Business Opportunity Commission, shall be included in
      the contract file.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2205.5.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in chapter 42 of this title (regarding the Freedom of Information Act) and ยง2205.6, information, including the preaward survey report, accumulated for purposes of determining the responsibility of a prospective contractor shall
      not be released or disclosed outside the District government.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2205.6.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer may discuss preaward survey information with the prospective contractor before determining responsibility. At any time after award, the contracting officer may discuss the findings of the preaward survey with the company surveyed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1529 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>