<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2506</num>
  <heading>USED OR RECONDITIONED MATERIAL, SURPLUS PROPERTY, AND RESIDUAL INVENTORY (ยง7-2506)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2506.1.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer may procure used or reconditioned material, former government surplus property, or residual inventory conforming to the requirements of a solicitation if the contracting officer determines that it is in the best interests of
      the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2506.2.</num>
    <text>When the contracting officer determines that procurement of used or reconditioned material, former government surplus property, or residual inventory is acceptable, the solicitation shall clearly identify which goods or components do not have to be
      new and the necessary requirements for acceptability.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2506.3.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall consider the following when determining whether used or reconditioned materials, former government surplus property, or residual inventory are acceptable:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The safety of persons or property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The total cost to the District, including maintenance, inspection, testing, and useful life;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Performance requirements; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The availability and cost of new materials and components.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2506.4.</num>
    <text>When procuring former government surplus property, the contracting officer shall ensure that the prices paid for the items are reasonable considering the overall cost to the District, as determined under ยง2506.3(b).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2506.5.</num>
    <text>When a contract calls for material to be furnished at cost, the allowable charge for former government surplus property shall not exceed the cost at which the contractor acquired the property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1577 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>