<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2504</num>
  <heading>DEVIATIONS FROM SPECIFICATIONS AND STANDARDS (ยง 27-2504)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2504.1.</num>
    <text>When the exceptions set forth in ยง 2503 are not applicable, and an existing specification does not meet an agency&amp;#8217;s minimum needs, the agency head may authorize deviations in accordance with this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2504.2.</num>
    <text>Each contracting officer shall be responsible for ensuring the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That District specifications are normally used, and requirements for exceptions and deviations are complied with;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That written justifications for each exception and deviation are subject to prior review and approval by the agency head, and that each justification can be fully substantiated if post audit is required;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>That major or repeated deviations are not taken except as prescribed in this chapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>That notification of each deviation or recommendation for change in specification is sent promptly in duplicate to the Director.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2504.3.</num>
    <text>Deviations reported by the contracting officer in accordance with ยง 2504.2(d) shall not be continued except as authorized by the Director in accordance with this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2504.4.</num>
    <text>When an agency submits notification to the Director of major or repeated deviations that have been taken but makes no recommendation for change in the specification, the Director shall notify the agency whether those deviations may be continued in
      subsequent contracting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2504.5.</num>
    <text>In cases where continued deviations are not approved by the Director, and the contracting agency has progressed to a point where it would be impracticable to amend or cancel the procurement, the procurement may be completed, but the deviation shall
      not be continued by the agency in subsequent procurements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2504.6.</num>
    <text>When an agency has recommended changing the specifications consistent with the deviations it has taken and reported, those deviations may be continued until the recommended change is incorporated in the specifications or the agency is notified otherwise
      in accordance with ยง2504.7.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2504.7.</num>
    <text>When coordination with other agencies and industry does not result in acceptance of the change, the deviations shall not be continued by the agency in subsequent contracts after notification by the Director that the request for change of specifications
      has been denied.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1575 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>