<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-301</num>
  <heading>FORM AND CONTENT OF PROTEST (ยง 27-301)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>301.1.</num>
    <text>All protests shall be in writing, addressed to the Board, and shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and telephone and facsimile numbers of the protester;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The identity of the contracting agency, the number and date of the solicitation, and if a contract has been awarded, the number and date of the contract and to whom the contract was awarded, if known;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A clear and concise statement of the legal and factual grounds of the protest, including copies of relevant documents, and citations to statutes, regulations, or solicitation provisions claimed to be violated;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Information establishing the timeliness of the protest (see Rule 302);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Information establishing that the protester is an aggrieved person for the purpose of filing the protest (see Rule 100.2(a)); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The relief sought by the protester. In addition, a protest may request a protective order, request specific documents relevant to the protest grounds, and request a hearing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.2.</num>
    <text>Protests shall be signed by the protester or by an authorized representative or attorney.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.3.</num>
    <text>Protests are not required to be formal or technical but shall be logically arranged and legally sufficient.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 2078 (March 8, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>