<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-3601</num>
  <heading>TYPES OF CONTRACT MODIFICATIONS (ยง 27-3601)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3601.1.</num>
    <text>A contract modification may either be bilateral or unilateral.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3601.2.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall use a bilateral contract modification (also known as a &amp;#8220;supplemental agreement&amp;#8221;) to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Make negotiated equitable adjustments resulting from the issuance of a change order;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Formalize a letter contract; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Reflect other agreements of the parties to modify the terms of the contract.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3601.3.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall use a unilateral contract modification to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Make administrative changes, such as correction of typographical errors or appropriations information;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Issue change orders;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Make changes authorized by a provision of the contract other than a changes clause, such as an option; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Issue a termination notice.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3601.4.</num>
    <text>When a contractor considers that the District has effected or may effect a change in the contract that has not been identified as such in writing and signed by the contracting officer, the contractor shall notify the District in writing as soon as
      possible. The District shall evaluate the alleged change and:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Confirm that it is a change, direct the mode of further performance, and plan for its funding;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Countermand the alleged change; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Notify the contractor that the District considers no change to have occurred.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1685 (February 26, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 014956 (December 21, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>