<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-3207</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION FOR ADVANCE PAYMENTS (ยง 27-3207)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3207.1.</num>
    <text>An eligible contractor may apply for advance payments before or after the award of a contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3207.2.</num>
    <text>The contractor or prospective contractor shall submit an advance payment request to the contracting officer in writing which provides the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A reference to the contract if the request concerns an existing contract, or a reference to the solicitation if the request concerns a proposed contract;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A cash flow forecast showing estimated disbursements and receipts for the period of contract performance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The proposed total amount of advance payments;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the bank at which the contractor expects to establish a special depository account for the advance payments;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A description of the contractor&amp;#8217;s efforts to obtain private financing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Whether the contractor is receiving or has applied to receive advance payments under any other current District contracts or solicitations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Other information appropriate to an understanding of the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The contractor&amp;#8217;s financial condition and need;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The contractor&amp;#8217;s ability to perform the contract without loss to the District; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Financial safeguards that will be used to protect the District&amp;#8217;s interests.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1628 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>