<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-3355</num>
  <heading>LOBBYING COSTS (ยง 27-3355)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3355.1.</num>
    <text>Costs associated with activities that involve attempts to influence the outcome of any District, federal, state, or local election, referendum, initiative, or similar procedure, including in-kind or cash contributions, endorsements, publicity, or
      similar activities, shall not be allowable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3355.2.</num>
    <text>Costs associated with establishing, administering, contributing to, or paying the expenses of a political party, campaign, political action committee, or other organization established for the purpose of influencing the outcomes of elections shall
      not be allowable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3355.3.</num>
    <text>Costs associated with any attempt to influence the introduction of District, federal, state, or local legislation, or the enactment or modification of any pending District, federal, state, or local legislation through communication with any member
      or employee of the Council, the Congress, or any state or local legislature, or any government official or employee in connection with a decision to sign or veto enrolled legislation shall not allowable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3355.4.</num>
    <text>Costs associated with any attempt to influence the introduction of District, federal, state or local legislation, or the enactment or modification of any pending District, federal, state, or local legislation by preparing, distributing, or using publicity
      or propaganda, or by urging any member of the public to contribute to or participate in any mass demonstration, march, rally, fundraising drive, lobbying campaign, or letter writing or telephone campaign shall not be allowable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3355.5.</num>
    <text>Costs associated with legislative liaison activities, including attendance at legislative sessions or committee hearings, gathering information regarding legislation, and analyzing the effect of legislation, when those activities are carried on in
      support of or in preparation for an effort to engage in other activities for which costs are not allowed under this section, shall not be allowable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3355.6.</num>
    <text>The costs of providing a technical and factual presentation of information on a topic directly related to the performance of a contract through hearing testimony, statements or letters to the Council or the Congress, including any committee, subdivision,
      member, or staff member, in response to a documented request made by or on behalf of the recipient member or legislative body shall be allowable if the information is readily obtainable and can be readily put in deliverable form.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3355.7.</num>
    <text>Costs for transportation, lodging, or meals in connection with the activities authorized under ยง3355.6 shall not be allowable unless incurred for the purpose of offering testimony at a regularly scheduled Council or congressional hearing pursuant
      to a written request for the presentation from the committee or subcommittee conducting the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3355.8.</num>
    <text>The costs of an activity specifically authorized by statute to be undertaken with funds from the contract shall be allowable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3355.9.</num>
    <text>When a contractor seeks reimbursement for indirect costs, total costs for the activities set forth in this section shall be separately identified in the indirect cost rate proposal, and shall be treated as unallowable activity costs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1676 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>