<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-3345</num>
  <heading>RECRUITMENT COSTS (ยง 27-3345)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3345.1.</num>
    <text>If the size of the staff recruited and maintained is in keeping with District contract workload requirements, the following costs shall be allowable:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Costs of help-wanted advertising;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Costs of operating an employment office needed to secure and maintain an adequate labor force;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Costs of operating an aptitude and educational testing program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Travel costs of employees engaged in recruiting personnel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Travel costs of applicants for interviews; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Costs of employment agencies not in excess of standard commercial rates.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3345.2.</num>
    <text>Recruitment and advertising costs shall not be allowable when any of the following apply:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The advertising or recruitment is for personnel other than those required to perform obligations under a District contract;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The advertising does not describe specific positions or classes of positions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The advertising or recruitment is excessive relative to the number and importance of the positions or to the industry practices;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The advertising includes material that is not relevant for recruitment purposes, such as extensive illustrations, the use of color, or descriptions of the company&amp;#8217;s products or capabilities; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The advertising or recruitment is designed to hire personnel from another District contractor.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1674 (February 26, 1988),</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>