<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-4110</num>
  <heading>DISTRICT RECORDS[COLON] GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 27-4110)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4110.1.</num>
    <text>The contractor&amp;#8217;s property control records shall constitute the District&amp;#8217;s official property records unless an exception has been authorized by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4110.2.</num>
    <text>The contractor shall establish and maintain adequate control records for all District property, including property provided to, and in the possession or control of, a subcontractor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4110.3.</num>
    <text>The property control records specified in §§4110 and 4111 shall be the minimum required by the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4110.4.</num>
    <text>Unless the contracting officer directs otherwise, when a subcontractor has an approved property control system for District property provided under its own prime contracts, the contractor shall use the records created and maintained under that system.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4110.5.</num>
    <text>The contractor&amp;#8217;s property control system shall provide financial accounts for District owned property in the contractor&amp;#8217;s possession or control.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4110.6.</num>
    <text>The property control system shall be subject to internal control standards and shall be supported by property records for all property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4110.7.</num>
    <text>The records shall be safeguarded from tampering or destruction and shall be accessible to authorized District personnel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4110.8.</num>
    <text>The contractor shall maintain separate property records for each contract. However, the contractor may maintain a consolidated property record if it provides the required information and is specifically authorized by the contracting officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4110.9.</num>
    <text>The contractor&amp;#8217;s property control system shall contain a system or technique to locate any item of District property within a reasonable period of time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1741 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>