<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-499</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 27-499)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>499.1.</num>
    <text>E Filing-Electronic transmission of an original document (pleading) to the Board via the Vendor&amp;#8217;s system. An E File consists of a document, an image, or both.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>499.2.</num>
    <text>E Service-Electronic transmission of an original document (pleading) to all other designated recipients via the Vendor&amp;#8217;s system. Upon the completion of any transmission to the Vendor&amp;#8217;s system, a certified receipt is issued to the
      sender acknowledging receipt by the Vendor system.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>499.3.</num>
    <text>E Document-An electronic file of a word processing document that contains almost exclusively text.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>499.4.</num>
    <text>E Image-An electronic file of a document that has been scanned or converted to a graphical or image format.</text>
    <text>Appendix &amp;#8211; CourtLink Pricing</text>
    <text>Fees are based on the size and number of transactions. A transaction is a filing to the Board and/or service of electronic documents to one or more parties.</text>
    <text>Filing with the Board ($2.00 minimum)</text>
    <text>10￠ a page</text>
    <text>Official Service ($2.00 minimum)</text>
    <text>To other CourtLink subscribers: 10￠ a page</text>
    <text>To non-subscribers: 20￠ a page via fax</text>
    <text>Courtesy Notification (optional)</text>
    <text>50￠ per attorney notified</text>
    <text>Provides e-mail or fax notification that documents have been filed with the Board and/or served to other parties</text>
    <text>Accessing Documents</text>
    <text>For documents officially served on or filed by you: No charge to view, print and or download</text>
    <text>All other documents: No charge to view, 10￠ a page to print and/or download ($1 minimum)</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 2078 (March 8, 2002); as amended by Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 4782 (May 20, 2005) [EXPIRED].</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>