<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-4631</num>
  <heading>PROTESTS (§ 27-4631)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4631.1.</num>
    <text>All protests to the award of a contract by the Contracting Officer shall be resolved in accordance with this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4631.2.</num>
    <text>A protest shall be submitted to the Contracting Officer in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4631.3.</num>
    <text>A protest shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name of the protestor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name of the protestor’s counsel or other representative;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A detailed description of the basis for the protest; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A description of the relief requested.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4631.4.</num>
    <text>The Contracting Officer shall promptly issue a decision with regard to a protest.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4631.5.</num>
    <text>If the Contracting Officer is someone other than the CCO, the protestor may appeal the Contracting Officer’s decision to the CCO.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4631.6.</num>
    <text>An appeal of the Contracting Officer’s decision shall be submitted to the CCO within three (3) business days after the protestor receives the Contracting Officer’s decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4631.7.</num>
    <text>The decision of the CCO shall be the Hospital’s final decision with regard to the protest.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4631.8.</num>
    <text>A protest must be filed within the timeframes established in this subsection to be considered by the Hospital.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4631.9.</num>
    <text>A protest that is not filed within these timelines will not be considered by the Hospital, and the protestor shall be deemed to have waived the right to protest.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4631.10.</num>
    <text>A protest that is based on the language or requirements of a solicitation or is otherwise based on facts which are apparent on the face of the solicitation shall be filed with the Contracting Officer no later than five (5) business days before the
      date responses to the solicitation are due.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4631.11.</num>
    <text>A protest that is not based on the language or requirements of a solicitation or otherwise based on facts which are apparent on the face of a solicitation must be submitted within five (5) business days after the protestor knows or should have known
      of the facts that serve as the basis for the protest.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 8507 (October 8, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 3086 (April 18, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking
      published at 58 DCR 4565, 4595 (May 27, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>