<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-4720</num>
  <heading>SEALED BIDDING (§ 27-4720)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4720.1.</num>
    <text>The solicitation used to initiate a procurement conducted by competitive sealed bidding is known as an Invitation for Bids (IFB).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4720.2.</num>
    <text>If the Department issues an IFB, the Department shall allow prospective bidders a reasonable time to prepare and submit bids. Except in the event of an emergency, this time period shall be no less than ten (10) business days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4720.3.</num>
    <text>The evaluation factors used in sealed bid procurements are limited to price and price-related factors, including price evaluation preferences for CBEs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4720.4.</num>
    <text>The IFB shall specify:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Any information necessary to explain how the Department will evaluate price (for example, whether option prices will be evaluated);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any price-related factors that will be evaluated and their relative importance in the overall evaluation scheme (for example, escalators);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A description of the goods or services sought, including quantity requirements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The contract delivery schedule;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A description of any special qualification requirements the contractor must satisfy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Instructions for submitting bids, including:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The deadline for bid submission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The method(s) for submitting bids;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any representations or certifications bidders must submit; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>any requirements for the submission of items such as bid samples, subcontracting plans, or payment or performance bond;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The period during which bids must remain open for acceptance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The contract’s terms and conditions.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4720.5.</num>
    <text>Any changes in the information set forth in an IFB must be made by an amendment to the IFB.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4720.6.</num>
    <text>Bids shall be submitted by a method specifically permitted by the IFB (for example, hand delivery, mailing, electronic transmission, or fax).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4720.7.</num>
    <text>A bid may be withdrawn or modified at any time before bid opening by any of the methods permitted for submitting bids.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4720.8.</num>
    <text>A late bid, late modification, or withdrawal shall not be considered, except that the Department may accept a late modification to an otherwise successful bid that makes the bid more favorable to the Department. A late bid is any bid received after
      the bid date, unless such delay is caused by the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4720.9.</num>
    <text>The Contracting Officer shall prepare and maintain in the contract file an abstract listing the bid prices.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4720.10.</num>
    <text>The contract shall be awarded to the qualified bidder whose bid is responsible and responsive to the IFB and is most advantageous to the Department considering only price and the price-related evaluation factors identified in the IFB.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4720.11.</num>
    <text>To be considered responsive, a bid must comply in all material respects with the IFB. Responsiveness involves matters that relate to the bid itself as opposed to the responsibility or other qualifications of the bidder. In determining whether a bid
      is responsive, the Contracting Officer has the discretion to permit correction of minor informalities or irregularities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4720.12.</num>
    <text>The Contracting Officer shall endeavor to include with every IFB solicitation the form of the contract that the contractor will be required to enter into. To the greatest extent possible, the Department should endeavor to provide clear, concise contract
      documents. Contracts which consist of the solicitation, the proposal, and other documents attached together but not integrated into a single contract document are discouraged.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4720.13.</num>
    <text>Bids shall be opened publicly at a time and place provided for in the IFB and shall be open for public inspection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DC 8805 (October 14, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 985, 1005 (February 10, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>