<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-4731</num>
  <heading>TRANSFER OF CONTRACTS (§ 27-4731)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4731.1.</num>
    <text>Procurements pending on October 1, 2011, and transferred to the Department on that date shall be completed, including the award of contracts pursuant thereto, in accordance with the procurement rules and regulations pursuant to which those procurements
      were commenced.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4731.2.</num>
    <text>Following the transfer of duties, responsibilities, contracts and procurements to the Department upon its creation, contracts or pending procurements related to facilities maintenance and/or capital projects held by other District agencies may be
      assigned to the Department in accordance with the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4731.3.</num>
    <text>The CCO shall review the proposed procurement or contract and determine whether it is in the best interest of the Department to accept the assignment of the procurement or contract or to terminate the procurement or contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4731.4.</num>
    <text>If the Department determines it is in its best interest to accept the assignment of a contract or procurement, the Department shall have the authority to modify the contract or procurement so as to conform with the best practices and procedures employed
      by the Department on its own procurements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4731.5.</num>
    <text>Assignment of contracts or procurements to the Department shall not confer on the Department any authority not otherwise granted to it by law or regulation. Acceptance of an assignment by the Department shall be predicated on the Department’s statutory
      authority to conduct the work contemplated by the assigned contract or procurement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4731.6.</num>
    <text>Assignment of a contract or procurement shall not operate to transfer funds to support the assigned contract or procurement. Funds shall be transferred pursuant to an intra-District memorandum of understanding, reprogramming, or other appropriate
      process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DC 8805 (October 14, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 985, 1014 (February 10, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>