<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-4708</num>
  <heading>MARKET RESEARCH (§ 27-4708)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4708.1.</num>
    <text>Before issuing a solicitation or making a purchase, the Department shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Estimate the likely cost of the proposed procurement; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Conduct appropriate market research.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4708.2.</num>
    <text>Market research is designed primarily to familiarize the Department with the market for the goods or services it seeks to acquire in order to develop an appropriate strategy for conducting a prompt and efficient procurement that promotes reasonable
      competition between qualified firms. The extent of market research will vary depending on factors such as urgency, the size and complexity of the proposed procurement, and the Department’s existing knowledge of the market based on its or its key
      personnel’s past experience in procuring similar goods or services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4708.3.</num>
    <text>Market research, to the extent it is relevant to the particular procurement and not already known to the Department, generally should focus on obtaining information such as the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Customary practices in the relevant market;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The prospective sources that may be able to supply the goods or services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The opportunities for participation by firms that qualify as CBEs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The benchmarks available to evaluate the likely cost of the procurement and the reasonableness of prices or costs proposed by prospective contractors; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The requirements of any laws or regulations unique to the procurement.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4708.4.</num>
    <text>In conducting market research, the Department may solicit information from prospective sources on matters such as their interest in the potential procurement, the characteristics and costs of their products or services, their customary practices,
      and their knowledge of the industry generally.</text>
    <text>Such information may be solicited by requesting interested parties to submit written information (for example, by posting a notice on the Department’s website seeking information pertinent to the proposed procurement), through meetings or telephone
      contacts, by distributing and seeking comments on a draft solicitation, or through other prudent means.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4708.5.</num>
    <text>In addition to soliciting information from prospective contractors, the Department may also obtain information from other sources. For example, price information that can assist in estimating the likely cost of a procurement and in evaluating price
      reasonableness is frequently available from sources such as catalogs, Internet sites, or records of past procurements, and the Department may obtain information from these sources.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 8805 (October 14, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 985, 992 (February 10, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>