<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-4113</num>
  <heading>CARE, MAINTENANCE, AND USE OF DISTRICT PROPERTY (ยง 27-4113)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4113.1.</num>
    <text>The contractor shall be responsible for the proper care, maintenance, and use of District property in its possession or control from the time of receipt until properly relieved of responsibility, in accordance with sound industrial practice and the
      terms of the contract and this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4113.2.</num>
    <text>The removal of District property to storage, or its contemplated transfer, shall not relieve the contractor of the responsibilities set forth in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4113.3.</num>
    <text>The contractor shall be responsible [responsible] for a preventive maintenance program which includes the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Inspection of buildings at periodic intervals to ensure detection of deterioration and the need for repairs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Inspection of equipment at periodic intervals to ensure detection of maladjustment, wear, or impending breakdown;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Regular lubrication of bearings and moving parts in accordance with a lubrication plan;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Adjustments for wear, repair, or replacement of worn or damaged parts and the elimination of causes of deterioration;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Removal of sludge, chips, and cutting oils from equipment that will not be used for a period of time; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Taking necessary precautions to prevent deterioration caused by contamination, corrosion, and other substances.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4113.4.</num>
    <text>The contractor&amp;#8217;s maintenance program shall provide for disclosing and reporting to the contracting officer the need for major repair, replacement, and other capital rehabilitation work for District property in its possession or control.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4113.5.</num>
    <text>The contractor shall keep records of maintenance actions performed and any deficiencies in District property discovered as a result of inspections.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1744 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>