<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-4722</num>
  <heading>SIMPLIFIED CONTRACTING PROCEDURES (§ 27-4722)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4722.1.</num>
    <text>The basic purposes of simplified contracting procedures are to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Promote economy, efficiency, and innovation in contracting;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Reduce administrative costs to the Department; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Avoid unnecessary burdens or complexities that could reduce competition, such as by deterring smaller contractors from participating in a procurement.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4722.2.</num>
    <text>Simplified contracting procedures may be used only with contacts that have an estimated value equal to or less than one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4722.3.</num>
    <text>The Contracting Officer shall conduct simplified procurements in the manner that is most suitable, efficient, and economical based on the circumstances of each acquisition. As appropriate, the Contracting Officer may elect to use or adapt procedures
      that are part of the sealed bidding or competitive negotiation process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4722.4.</num>
    <text>On a simplified procurement, the Contracting Officer shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Promote competition to the extent practicable and efficient;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Establish reasonable deadlines for the submission of responses to solicitations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Evaluate quotations or offers in an impartial manner on the basis established in the solicitation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4722.5.</num>
    <text>If a contract that has an estimated value of more the ten thousand dollars ($10,000) is procured through the simplified contracting procedures, the Department shall obtain written quotes from at least two (2) potential contractors.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4722.6.</num>
    <text>If a contract that has an estimated value of less than ten thousand dollars ($10,000) is procured through the simplified contracting procedures, the Department need only obtain a written quote from a single potential contractor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4722.7.</num>
    <text>The Contracting Officer may solicit quotations orally in appropriate cases when doing so is practical and economical. When soliciting quotations orally, the Contracting Officer shall require contractors to respond in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4722.8.</num>
    <text>An oral solicitation shall provide a clear description of the Department’s requirements (for example the type of goods or services sought, quantities, and schedule) and the basis on which the award will be made.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4722.9.</num>
    <text>Written solicitations shall provide a complete statement of relevant information without being unnecessarily lengthy. A written solicitation should include the same information required in an oral solicitation plus the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Anticipated contract terms and conditions, including the extent to which they are negotiable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Applicable certifications or representations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Instructions for submitting responses.</text>
    </level>
    <text>The basis for an award may be price or cost alone or price and cost combined with other factors. Solicitations are not required to state the relative importance assigned to each evaluation factor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4722.10.</num>
    <text>The price and cost combined with other terms of the award shall be set forth in a written contract or purchase order. The Contracting Officer shall include a statement in the contract file briefly explaining the basis for the award decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4722.11.</num>
    <text>No later than ten (10) days after award of any contract pursuant to the procedures outlined in this section 4722, the Department shall post on the Department’s website the name of the contractor to whom the contract was awarded, a description of the
      services or goods procured and the value of the contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DC 8805 (October 14, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 985, 1009 (February 10, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>