<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-4199</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 27-4199)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4199.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>District-furnished property &amp;#8211; property in the possession of or directly acquired by the District and subsequently made available to the contractor.</text>
    <text>District-owned property &amp;#8211; all property owned by or leased to the District or acquired by the District under the terms of the contract, including District-furnished property.</text>
    <text>District supply sources &amp;#8211; sources available to the District from which a contractor or subcontractor may obtain supplies for use in certain contracts.</text>
    <text>Facilities &amp;#8211; property used for production, maintenance, research, development, or testing. The term includes plant equipment and real property, but does not include material. When used in a facilities contract, the term includes all property
      provided under the contract.</text>
    <text>Facilities contract &amp;#8211; a contract under which District facilities are provided to a contractor or subcontractor by the District for use in connection with performing one (1) or more related contracts for goods or services.</text>
    <text>Material &amp;#8211; property that may be incorporated into or attached to a deliverable end item or that may be consumed or expended in performing a contract. The term includes assemblies, components, parts, raw and processed materials, and small
      tools and goods that may be consumed in normal use in performing a contract.</text>
    <text>Non-profit organization &amp;#8211; any corporation, foundation, trust, or institution operated for scientific, educational, or medical purposes, not organized for profit, and no part of the earnings of which inures to the benefit of any private shareholder
      or individual.</text>
    <text>Personal property &amp;#8211; property of any kind or interest in property except real property and records of the District government.</text>
    <text>Plant equipment &amp;#8211; personal property of a capital nature (including equipment, machine tools, test equipment, furniture, vehicles, and accessory and auxiliary items) for use in manufacturing goods, in performing services, or for any administrative
      or general plant purpose.</text>
    <text>Preventive maintenance &amp;#8211; maintenance performed on a regularly scheduled basis to prevent the occurrence of defects and to detect and correct minor defects before they result in serious consequences.</text>
    <text>Property &amp;#8211; all property, both real and personal, including facilities and material.</text>
    <text>Real property &amp;#8211; land and rights in land, ground improvements, utility distribution systems, and buildings and other structures. The term does not include foundations and other work necessary for installing plant equipment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1746 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>