<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-4726</num>
  <heading>PAYMENT REQUESTS (§ 27-4726)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4726.1.</num>
    <text>Requests for payment must be submitted in writing by the contractor.</text>
    <text>Payment shall not be authorized without a valid written contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4726.2.</num>
    <text>Contractor payment requests shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Certify that the contractor is entitled to payment in the requested amount; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Include or attach any information necessary to demonstrate entitlement to the requested payment under the contract’s terms.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4726.3.</num>
    <text>Depending on the contract’s payment provisions, a payment request may consist of, for example, a statement that specified work has been completed in a satisfactory manner, documentation showing that contract deliverables have been accepted by the
      Office, or information detailing the reimbursable costs incurred by the contractor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4726.4.</num>
    <text>Unless the Contracting Officer authorizes the payments, they shall not be made. A Contracting Officer’s payment authorization shall not preclude the Department from seeking repayment or pursuing other remedies if it subsequently concludes that the
      contractor was overpaid or otherwise mispaid.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4726.5.</num>
    <text>In addition to the Contracting Officer’s payment authorization, the Department’s CFO or his or her designee shall certify and approve all payment requests prior to making any payment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DC 8805 (October 14, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 985, 1011 (February 10, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>