<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-4107</num>
  <heading>PROPERTY CONTROL SYSTEMS (ยง 27-4107)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4107.1.</num>
    <text>The contractor shall establish and maintain a system to control, protect, preserve, and maintain all District property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4107.2.</num>
    <text>The property control system shall be in writing unless the contracting officer determines that maintaining a written system is unnecessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4107.3.</num>
    <text>The property control system shall be reviewed and, if satisfactory, approved by the contracting officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4107.4.</num>
    <text>When the contracting officer finds any portion of the contractor&amp;#8217;s property control system to be inadequate, the contractor shall be required to take any necessary corrective action before the system can be approved.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4107.5.</num>
    <text>When District property is found to be in the possession or control of the contractor, although not provided under any contract, the contractor shall promptly record the property and furnish to the contracting officer all known circumstances and data
      pertaining to its receipt and a statement about whether it is needed for the performance of the contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4107.6.</num>
    <text>When unrecorded District property is found in the possession or control of the contractor, both the cause of the discrepancy and actions taken or needed to prevent recurrence shall be determined and reported to the contracting officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4107.7.</num>
    <text>The contractor shall promptly report to the contracting officer all District property it receives in excess of the amounts needed to complete full performance under the contracts providing it or authorizing its use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4107.8.</num>
    <text>The contractor shall furnish written receipts for all or specified classes of District property only when the contracting officer deems it essential for maintaining acceptable property controls.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4107.9.</num>
    <text>When overages, shortages, or damages are discovered upon receipt of District property, the contractor shall provide a statement of the condition and apparent causes to the contracting officer. Only the quantity of property actually received shall
      be recorded on the official records.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1740 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>