<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-4704</num>
  <heading>AUTHORITY AND DUTIES OF CONTRACTING OFFICER (ยง 27-4704)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4704.1.</num>
    <text>Only the CCO or a Contracting Officer shall have the authority to award, modify, or terminate contracts; provided, however, that prior to terminating any contract in excess of two hundred fifty thousand dollars ($250,000), the Contracting Officer
      shall first obtain the approval of the CCO. As necessary or appropriate in exercising his or her authority, a Contracting Officer shall request and consider the advice of specialists in auditing, law, technical disciplines, and other relevant fields.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4704.2.</num>
    <text>A Contracting Officer for a particular procurement shall be responsible for:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Making any determination or findings that may be required in connection with that procurement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Ensuring that all statutory and regulatory requirements that apply to the procurement have been identified and observed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Ensuring that all necessary preconditions to contract award have been satisfied before the contract is awarded;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Maintaining the contract file, which serves as the repository for all required documentation concerning the procurement and any resulting contracts; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Ensuring that all offerors participating in a procurement receive fair and impartial treatment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 8805 (October 14, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 985, 988 (February 10, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>