<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-599</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 27-599)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>599.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms have the meaning ascribed:</text>
    <text>Act &amp;#8211; Child and Youth, Safety and Health Omnibus Amendment Act of 2004, effective April 13, 2005 (D.C. Law 15-353; D.C. Official Code ยง 4-1501.01 et seq.)(2006 Supp.), as amended by Title II of the Omnibus Public Safety Amendment Act of
      2006, effective April 24, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-306; 54 DCR 6577).</text>
    <text>Applicant &amp;#8211; an individual who has filed a written application for employment, or who has made an affirmative effort through a written application or a verbal request to serve in an unsupervised volunteer position, with a private entity.</text>
    <text>Children &amp;#8211; individuals twelve (12) years of age and under.</text>
    <text>Covered child or youth services provider &amp;#8211; any District government agency providing direct services to children and youth and any private entity that contracts with the District to provide direct services to children and youth, or for the
      benefit of children or youth, that affect the health, safety, and welfare of children or youth, including individual and group counseling, therapy, case management, supervision, or mentoring.</text>
    <text>In accordance with Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order No. 2007-95, the following District agencies shall be subject to the criminal background check and traffic records check provisions of the Act and this chapter for purposes of their own activities, and the
      activities of private entities and who are parties to contracts entered into on behalf of the following agencies by the Office of Contracting and Procurement:</text>
    <text>*Department of Human Services</text>
    <text>*Department of Health</text>
    <text>*Department of Parks and Recreation</text>
    <text>*Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department</text>
    <text>*Metropolitan Police Department</text>
    <text>*Office of the State Superintendent of Education</text>
    <text>*Department of Mental Health</text>
    <text>*Child and Family Services Agency</text>
    <text>*Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services</text>
    <text>*Department of Employment Services</text>
    <text>*Department on Disability Services</text>
    <text>*Any other agency which, as a result of a permanent or temporary change to its mission such as may be caused by reorganization or a similar reason, shall become a covered child or youth services provider subject to the Act</text>
    <text>Criminal background check &amp;#8211; the investigation of an individual&amp;#8217;s criminal history through the record systems of the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the District of Columbia Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
    <text>Employee &amp;#8211; an individual who is employed on a full-time, part-time, temporary or contractual basis by a private entity.</text>
    <text>Private Entity &amp;#8211; any private entity that contracts with the District to provide direct services to children or youth, or for the benefit of children or youth, that affect the health, safety, and welfare of children or youth, including individual
      and group counseling, therapy, case management, supervision, or mentoring.</text>
    <text>Supervised &amp;#8211; any person who is under the direct supervision, at all times, of an employee or a volunteer who has received a current, satisfactory criminal background check.</text>
    <text>Volunteer &amp;#8211; an individual who works without any monetary or any other financial compensation for a private entity.</text>
    <text>Youth &amp;#8211; an individual between thirteen (13) and seventeen (17) years of age, inclusive.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 3490 (May 1, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>