<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-806</num>
  <heading>DEPARTMENT PROCESS FOR CERTIFIED BUSINESS ENTERPRISE STATUS (§ 27-806)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>806.1</num>
    <text>806.1 Upon receipt of an application for certification as a CBE, the Directorhall conduct a preliminary review of the submission for compliance with theequirements of the Act and this chapter and take one of the following actions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If the application is complete, it shall be accepted for review by theepartment; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the application is incomplete or lacks the required verification, ithall be returned to the applicant with a notice indicating the need fordditional actions or materials in order for the application to be accepted foreview.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.2</num>
    <text>806.2 The Director, or his/her designee, may conduct site inspections and holdnterviews or discussions with an applicant or applicant&amp;#8217;sepresentative(s) as part of the review process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.3</num>
    <text>806.3 Upon completion of the Department’s review, the Director shalletermine the eligibility of the applicant and advise the applicant in writingf the determination regarding its application. The Department shall deny anpplication if the applicant
      fails to demonstrate eligibility for certification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.4</num>
    <text>806.4 In addition to the information supplied in the application and documentsccompanying the application, the Director may require an applicant to supply orrovide access to additional information and documents relevant to theepartment’s investigation
      and determination of the applicant&amp;#8217;sligibility as a CBE.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.5</num>
    <text>806.5 An applicant shall report to the Department any changes that may affecthe eligibility for certification of the applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.6</num>
    <text>806.6 Upon the denial of an application for certification, the Departmenthall not accept, review, or evaluate for a period of six (6) months from theate the applicant receives notice of the decision to deny certification:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Amendments to or new information on the denied application; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A new certification application from the applicant, its agent(s),epresentative(s), or other members of the public on the applicant&amp;#8217;sehalf.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 9052 (December 4, 1992); as amendedy Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 8439 (October 23, 2009), incorporatingy reference text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5622, 5628 (July0, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>