<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-808</num>
  <heading>UPGRADE (ยง 27-808)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>808.1</num>
    <text>808.1 An applicant that has been certified by the Department as a CBE in oner more areas may expand the areas in which it is certified by submitting to theepartment a completed application for an upgrade. Each application for anpgrade shall comply
      with the requirements of this chapter and shall beccompanied by documentation indicating the applicant&amp;#8217;s qualifications,</text>
    <text>expertise, and/or resources which justify the upgrade.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>With respect to each category of construction and non-construction servicesor which an applicant seeks certification, the applicant shall demonstrate thathe applicant has the expertise, personnel, facilities, equipment, andxperience to perform the
        services on an on-going basis.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>With respect to SBEs as suppliers of goods and equipment, the applicanthall submit evidence that the applicant is a manufacturer of or regular dealern such goods.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In order to qualify as a manufacturer, an applicant shall own or lease on aegular basis an establishment that produces on the premises the materials,upplies, articles or equipment of the character in which the applicant claimso be a manufacturer;
        but the term does not include a business which performsnly minimal operations on or minimal assembly of the items being produced.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In order to qualify as a regular dealer under this section, an applicanthall meet the following minimum eligibility requirements:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Maintain an establishment in which materials, supplies, articles, orquipment of the character in which the applicant claims to be a regular dealerre bought, kept in stock, and sold to customers on a recurring basis in thesual course of business;
        and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Demonstrate that its business is an established and on-going entityegularly dealing in the particular materials, supplies, articles, or equipmentf the character offered in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>In making the determination whether the applicant is a regular dealer, theepartment shall consider the following factors:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Whether the applicant has performed the particular services for a client inhe course of its business in the one-year period prior to the application date;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>If the applicant is newly providing this type of service, whether thepplicant has made plans and committed resources to performing the particularervices for clients; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The customary practice in the industry.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 9052 (December 4, 1992); as amendedy Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 8439 (October 23, 2009), incorporatingy reference text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5622, 5629 (July0, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>