<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-819</num>
  <heading>ADDITIONAL REQUIREMENTS FOR CERTIFICATION UPON REVOCATION (ยง 27-819)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>819.1</num>
    <text>819.1 An applicant whose certification was revoked:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>May submit an application and all required supporting documentation asequired by this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Shall demonstrate compliance with the requirements of the Act and thishapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Shall satisfy the requirements under ยง 819.2.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>819.2</num>
    <text>819.2 An applicant for certification after revocation may be required toemonstrate fitness to be issued a certificate by submitting evidenceatisfactory to the Department that the applicant has the requisite businessntegrity, qualifications, financial
      responsibility and resources, competency,nd knowledge of District and federal laws necessary to resume doing businessith the District government as a CBE, and that the applicant&amp;#8217;sontracting with the District government will not be detrimental
      to the publicnterest or the integrity of these programs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>819.3</num>
    <text>819.3 In making determinations for certification after revocation, theepartment shall consider, among other factors, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The nature and circumstances of the violation for which thepplicant&amp;#8217;s certification was revoked;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The conduct of the applicant and its participants since the revocation,ncluding the steps taken to remedy the prior violation and prevent futureiolations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The present character of the applicant or its participants.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 9052 (December 4, 1992); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 8439 (October 23, 2009),ncorporating by reference text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5622,637 (July 10, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>