<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-825</num>
  <heading>EVIDENCE AT HEARINGS (§ 27-825)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>825.1</num>
    <text>825.1 In a proceeding before the Commission under this chapter, each partyhall have the right to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Present in person, or by counsel, that party’s case or defense,ncluding oral and documentary evidence;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Submit rebuttal evidence; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Cross-examine opposing witnesses.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>825.2</num>
    <text>825.2 For documentary evidence to be admitted at a proceeding before theommission, it shall be submitted to the Commission at least five (5) days prioro the hearing, unless otherwise allowed by the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>825.3</num>
    <text>825.3 Testimonial evidence received at Commission hearings shall be under oathr affirmation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>825.4</num>
    <text>825.4 The Commission shall exclude irrelevant, immaterial, or undulyepetitious evidence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>825.5</num>
    <text>825.5 The Commission may take official notice of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The laws of the District of Columbia, the United States, and any state orurisdiction of the United States; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any fact that is not subject to reasonable dispute because it is generallynown within the District of Columbia or is capable of accurate and readyetermination by resorting to reliable sources.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>825.6</num>
    <text>825.6 In an appeal of the Department’s decision to deny an applicant forertification, the burden of proof is on the applicant to establish that he orhe is eligible for certification by a preponderance of the evidence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>825.7</num>
    <text>825.7 In an action to revoke the respondent’s certificate of registration,he burden of proof is on the Department to establish by a preponderance of thevidence the basis for the revocation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 9052 (December 4, 1992); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 8439 (October 23, 2009),ncorporating by reference text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5622,640 (July 10, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>