<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-823</num>
  <heading>SUBPOENAS (ยง 27-823)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>823.1</num>
    <text>823.1 The Commission may upon its own motion, or upon the request of thepplicant or respondent, the Department, or the Assistant Attorney General ofecord, issue a subpoena requiring:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The attendance and testimony of witnesses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The production of evidence, including, but not limited to books, records,orrespondence, or documents in the possession or under the control of theerson subpoenaed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Access to evidence for the purpose of examination and copying.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>823.2</num>
    <text>823.2 The issuance and manner of service of a subpoena shall be as prescribedy the Civil Rules of the District of Columbia Superior Court.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>823.3</num>
    <text>823.3 The form of a subpoena may be prescribed by the Commission andubscribed by the Chairperson. A subpoena shall state the name and address ofts issuer; identify the evidence or person subpoenaed; the person to whom andhe place, date, and time at
      which it is returnable; the nature of the evidencehich is to be examined or copied; and the date and time when access isequested. A subpoena shall be returnable to the Chairperson of the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>823.4</num>
    <text>823.4 Upon failure of any person to comply with a subpoena issued under thisection, the Commission may seek enforcement of the subpoena through theistrict of Columbia Superior Court.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 9052 (December 4, 1992); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 8439 (October 23, 2009),ncorporating by reference text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5622,639 (July 10, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>