<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-1006</num>
  <heading>PLANNING COMMITTEE PROCEDURES (ยง 28-1006)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1006.1.</num>
    <text>In developing each of the elements of the plan set forth in ยง 1005, the Planning Committee shall follow the procedures set forth in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1006.2.</num>
    <text>With the assistance of the staff, the committee shall prepare recommendations accompanied by discussion papers explaining and justifying the recommendations. The papers shall set forth the planning assumptions, problem analysis, factual basis, supporting
      data, cost implications as appropriate, and provide concrete illustrations or examples where possible.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1006.3.</num>
    <text>With the assistance of staff, the committee shall prepare a list of alternatives and an analysis of those alternatives with a statement of costs, alternative planning assumptions, alternative interpretations of data, alternative formulations of priorities,
      and alternative programs which might be utilized.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1006.4.</num>
    <text>The committee shall request that the staff compile a list of problem areas and programmatic activities and suggestions regarding the allocation of resources from agencies and groups involved or interested in the criminal and juvenile justice systems,
      and an analysis of the relationship of those requests or suggestions to the statements required under ยง 1005.4(a) through (d).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1006.5.</num>
    <text>The list of &amp;#8220;requests&amp;#8221; shall be secured through members of the Board so that the Planning Committee can draw effectively upon input from the entire Board and institutions represented on the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1006.6.</num>
    <text>The committee shall request that the staff obtain commentaries on recommendations received from particular agencies and institutions which may be affected by those recommendations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1006.7.</num>
    <text>The committee shall request that staff prepare special studies, research, and issue papers as may be useful.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1006.8.</num>
    <text>With the assistance of staff, the committee shall prepare a summary of available and relevant data on the problems being addressed with particular emphasis on new developments, trends, changes for better or worse, and the problems faced by the criminal
      and juvenile justice systems.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1006.9.</num>
    <text>The committee shall request that the staff provide material to permit the evaluation of ongoing projects or reports on programs in the District and other jurisdictions that appear particularly relevant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1006.10.</num>
    <text>The committee shall solicit reports of committees with statutory legal responsibility for recommendations including, specifically, the Juvenile Justice Advisory Group and the Judicial Planning Committee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 1111, 1114-15 (March 14, 1980).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>