<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-1203</num>
  <heading>INVESTIGATIONS (ยง 28-1203)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1203.1.</num>
    <text>Complaints not involving criminal misconduct or physical structure shall be investigated by OCJPA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1203.2.</num>
    <text>At a minimum, OCJPA staff shall, independently or in cooperation with other District representatives, interview the complainant, the Director, and staff of the facility involved.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1203.3.</num>
    <text>When the facility is operated by or funded through the District government, the supervisors or contracting officers responsible for the facility shall also be interviewed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1203.4.</num>
    <text>Other interested parties shall be consulted when deemed necessary by OCJPA staff.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1203.5.</num>
    <text>Privately operated facilities not supported by District funds about which complaints are received shall be asked to voluntarily participate in the OCJPA investigation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1203.6.</num>
    <text>Agencies refusing voluntary participation shall be recorded and noted in quarterly summary and status reports.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1203.7.</num>
    <text>A preliminary investigation report for all non-criminal and non-physical complaints shall be prepared by OCJPA within fifteen (15) working days of complaint receipt.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1203.8.</num>
    <text>The preliminary report shall be made available to the complainant, the program, and appropriate District offices. The report shall include OCJPA findings concerning the validity of the complaint and suggested remedies or dispositions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1203.9.</num>
    <text>When, in the opinion of OCJPA, additional time is required for further investigation, a recommendation for additional time for investigation shall be included in the preliminary report.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 1107, 1109 (March 14, 1980).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>