<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-2099</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 28-2099)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2099.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Chairperson &amp;#8211; The Chairperson of the Commission, or the Vice Chairperson or Acting Chairperson designated by the Commission when acting as Chairperson.</text>
    <text>Evaluation &amp;#8211; The process whereby the Commission, pursuant to ยง433(c) of the Self-Government Act, prepares and submits to the President of the United States a written report evaluating the performance and fitness of a candidate for reappointment
      to a District of Columbia court.</text>
    <text>Investigation &amp;#8211; an inquiry to determine whether a proceeding should be instituted.</text>
    <text>Judge &amp;#8211; a judge, senior judge, or retired judge of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals or of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Proceeding &amp;#8211; a formal proceeding, initiated by a Notice of Proceeding, to hear and determine charges as to a judge&amp;#8217;s conduct or health pursuant to ยง432 (a)(2) or (b) of the Self-Government Act.</text>
    <text>Recommendation &amp;#8211; The process whereby the Commission, pursuant to D.C. Code, Title 11, ยง11-1504, prepares and submits a written report of its recommendation and findings to the chief judge of a District of Columbia court regarding the appointment
      of senior judges to the court.</text>
    <text>Self-Government Act &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act of 1973, Pub. L. 93-198.</text>
    <text>Special Counsel &amp;#8211; any member of the District of Columbia Bar retained by the Commission to assist it.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 24 DCR 9391, 9394 (May 5, 1978); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 6032, 6050-51 (September 14, 1990); and Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 9333, 9351-52 (December 11, 1992); as amended by Final
        Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 108 (January 6, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 12322 (December 21, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>