<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-2044</num>
  <heading>CONFIDENTIALITY (§ 28-2044)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2044.1.</num>
    <text>Commission records shall not be available for public inspection, except the following;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Time and attendance data reported pursuant to the provisions of D.C. Code §§11-709 and 11-909; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Financial data reported pursuant to the provisions of D.C. Code §§11-1530(a)(2) and (a)(7).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2044.2.</num>
    <text>The record of investigations, proceedings, evaluations, and recommendations conducted or made by the Commission, as well as all financial and medical information received by the Commission pursuant to this chapter, other than the financial data referred
      to in §2044.1, shall be confidential, except:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>when disclosed, in the Commission&amp;#8217;s discretion or as provided by this chapter, to the judge who is the subject of the information, investigation, proceeding, evaluation, or recommendation; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>where the judge who is the subject of the information, investigation, proceeding, evaluation, or recommendation, consents to disclosure; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>when disclosed in a proceeding, or in a Commission decision in a proceeding; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>when disclosed in a Commission evaluation of a judge who is a candidate for reappointment, or to the President of the United States in connection therewith; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>when disclosed to the Chief Judge of a District of Columbia court in connection with a judge who has requested the Commission&amp;#8217;s recommendation for appointment as a senior judge; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>when disclosed, on a privileged and confidential basis, to the District of Columbia Judicial Nomination Commission in response to a request concerning a judge whose elevation to the District of Columbia Court of Appeals or for Chief Judge of a District
        of Columbia court is being considered; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>when disclosed, to the extent required, on judicial review of a Commission decision or in the prosecution of a witness for perjury.</text>
    </level>
    <text>For purposes of this Rule, the record of an investigation, proceeding, evaluation, or recommendation shall include all papers filed or submitted and all information furnished to or considered by the Commission in connection therewith (including, but
      not limited to, the substance of any complaint by or communications with individuals or organizations, financial and medical information obtained pursuant to this chapter, depositions, grants of immunity, and the notice and transcript of proceedings,
      if any).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2044.3.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any provision of §2044.2, the identity of any individual or organization submitting a complaint, or furnishing information to the Commission in connection with an investigation, proceeding, evaluation of a candidacy for reappointment,
      or request for recommendation for appointment as a senior judge, shall not be disclosed to anyone, including the judge who is the subject of the complaint or information, except:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>where the individual or organization consents to such disclosure; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>when disclosed in a proceeding where the individual or a person connected with the organization is called as a witness; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>when disclosed by the Commission to the President of the United States at his or her request when it concerns a judge evaluated by the Commission as &amp;#8220;qualified&amp;#8221; whose possible renomination the President is considering; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>when disclosed, upon request, on a privileged and confidential basis, to the District of Columbia Judicial Nomination Commission, concerning a judge being considered by such Nomination Commission for elevation to the District of Columbia Court of
        Appeals or for Chief Judge of a District of Columbia Court; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>when disclosed, to the extent required, on judicial review of a Commission decision or in the prosecution of a witness for perjury.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2044.4.</num>
    <text>Hearings in proceedings shall be conducted in closed session, unless the judge who is the subject of the proceeding shall consent to make the hearing open to the public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 6032, 6048-49 (September 14, 1990); and Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 9333, 9349-50 (December 11, 1992); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 108 (January 6, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 54 DCR 12322 (December 21, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>