<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-2013</num>
  <heading>ANSWER AND HEARING DATE (ยง 28-2013)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2013.1.</num>
    <text>Within twenty (20) days after service of a notice of proceeding, the judge may file an answer with the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2013.2.</num>
    <text>Upon the filing of an answer, unless good reason to the contrary appears in the answer, or if no answer is filed within the time for its filing, the Commission shall order a hearing to be held before it concerning the matters specified in the notice
      of proceeding.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2013.3.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall set a time and place for the hearing and shall mail a notice of the hearing time and place to the judge by registered or certified mail addressed to the judge at his or her chambers at least thirty (30) days prior to the date
      set.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2013.4.</num>
    <text>The Chairperson may extend the time either for filing an answer or for the commencement of a hearing for periods not to exceed thirty (30) days in the aggregate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2013.5.</num>
    <text>The notice of proceeding and the answer shall constitute the pleadings. No further pleadings or motions shall be filed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2013.6.</num>
    <text>The judge shall include in the answer all procedural and substantive defenses and challenges which the judge desires the Commission to consider.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2013.7.</num>
    <text>The Commission may rule on the defenses and challenges at the outset of the hearing or may take them under advisement to be determined during, at the close of, or at a time subsequent to the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 24 DCR 9391, 9403-04 (May 5, 1978); Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 6032, 6037-38 (September 14, 1990); and Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 9333, 9403-04 (December 11, 1992); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 53 DCR 108 (January 6, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 12322 (December 21, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>