<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-2005</num>
  <heading>PRECEDENTS (ยง 28-2005)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2005.1.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section shall apply to determinations by the Commission of grounds for removal under ยง432(a)(2) of the Self-Government Act, and to evaluations by the Commission of judges who are candidates for re-nomination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2005.2.</num>
    <text>Each judge shall be deemed to be on notice of the following; Provided, that copies of the decisions, evaluations, reports, or communications have been filed by the Commission with the Chief Judge of each court:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Commission&amp;#8217;s decisions in proceedings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Commission&amp;#8217;s evaluations of judges who have been candidates for re-nomination;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The annual reports of the Commission; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any communication by the Commission to either of the Chief Judges of the courts of the District of Columbia specifying that the judges are to take notice of the communication.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2005.3.</num>
    <text>Expressions by the Commission in the decisions, evaluations, and communications listed in ยง2005.2 shall be pertinent precedents to be taken into account by the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2005.4.</num>
    <text>Each judge shall be deemed to be on notice of provisions promulgated by the Advisory Committee on Judicial Activities of the Judicial Conference of the United States regarding the Code of Judicial Conduct for United States Judges.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2005.5.</num>
    <text>Insofar as the opinions of the Advisory Committee on Judicial Activities deal with provisions of the Code of Judicial Conduct that are similar to requirements applicable to judges of District of Columbia courts, the Commission shall regard them as
      persuasive.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 24 DCR 9391, 9399 (May 5, 1978); Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 6032, 6034-35 (September 14, 1990); and Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 9333, 9335-36 (December 11, 1992); as amended by Final Rulemaking published
        at 53 DCR 108 (January 6, 2006); and as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 12322 (December 21, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>