<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-506</num>
  <heading>FILING AND INVESTIGATION OF CHARGES (ยง 28-506)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>506.1.</num>
    <text>After a disciplinary report (also referred to in this section as the &amp;#8220;report&amp;#8221;) is prepared by the accusing official, it shall become an important document which constitutes a record of the alleged offense and indicates the identities
      of the resident and the person submitting the report.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>506.2.</num>
    <text>Any official who becomes aware of an alleged violation of the Code of Offenses (an &amp;#8220;offense&amp;#8221;) by a resident shall make sufficient investigation to ensure that before preparing a disciplinary report the official has available all
      the facts pertaining to the alleged offense.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>506.3.</num>
    <text>The accusing official who has investigated an alleged offense shall fill out and sign a disciplinary report setting forth the official&amp;#8217;s understanding of the facts constituting the alleged offense, including the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The date of the incident;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The time and location of the incident;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any witnesses to the alleged offense; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The name and section number of the offense which is charged.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>506.4.</num>
    <text>An accusing official shall file the disciplinary report with the Shift Supervisor within twenty-four (24) hours of the alleged offense, except in exceptional circumstances when the report shall be filed within two (2) working days of the alleged offense.
      The exceptional circumstances shall be noted on the report.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>506.5.</num>
    <text>After the Shift Supervisor has received the disciplinary report, the Shift Supervisor shall immediately investigate the alleged offense, summarize the results of that investigation in an investigative report, and take other actions set forth in ยง
      507.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>506.6.</num>
    <text>Any other reports, memoranda, or records concerning an alleged offense may be submitted with or attached to the investigative report; provided, that they shall be treated in accordance with the procedures outlined in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 865, 878-79 (February 27, 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>