<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-526</num>
  <heading>HEARING BOARD DETERMINATIONS (ยง 28-526)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>526.1.</num>
    <text>If, after a hearing, the Board determines that the resident should be placed in segregation, the Board shall prepare, within three (3) working days of the hearing, a written statement containing the Board&amp;#8217;s decision and the factual information
      upon which the decision is based.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>526.2.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in ยง 526.3, a copy of the entire written statement shall be furnished to the resident and the resident&amp;#8217;s representative within two (2) working days of its preparation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>526.3.</num>
    <text>If disclosing the name of any individual or any of the evidence on which the Board relied in making its determination would, in the Board&amp;#8217;s judgment, pose a threat to the safety of any resident or other person, or cause a riot or other major
      disturbance or damage to property, the Board shall include that determination in the written statement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>526.4.</num>
    <text>The Board may delete material designated under ยง 526.3 from the copy of the written statement given to the resident and the resident&amp;#8217;s counsel or substitute counsel. The Board shall specifically describe in the written statement the nature
      of information deleted (for example, &amp;#8220;telephone call from anonymous informant,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;testimony of eyewitness,&amp;#8221; or other similar designation).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>526.5.</num>
    <text>If the Board makes any deletions, it shall transmit to the Administrator of the institution a copy of the entire record before the Board, including the entire written statement. This copy of the record shall be retained by the Administrator for a
      period of at least two (2) years from the date of the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 865, 896-97 (February 27, 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>