<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-699</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 28-699)
    <text>For purposes of this chapter, the following terms shall have the meaningscribed:</text>
    <text>“Department of Corrections facility” – means a facility that houses annmate committed to the District of Columbia Department of Corrections.</text>
    <text>“Disciplinary violation” – means a guilty finding pursuant to theepartment of Corrections Policy on Inmate Discipline and Administrative Housingor any institutional Class I, II, and III offenses as defined in Chapter 5 ofhis title.</text>
    <text>“Disciplinary Board” – means a Board established pursuant to theepartment of Corrections Policy on Inmate Discipline and Administrative Housinghat conducts hearings, makes findings, and imposes appropriate sanctions forncidents of inmate disciplinary
      violations.</text>
    <text>“Expiration of the sentence” – means that an inmate’s sentence hasxpired, requiring the release from incarceration without further supervision ofn inmate because he or she:</text>
    <text>Has served the maximum term of commitment; or</text>
    <text>Has served the maximum term of commitment less the diminution credits awardedursuant to the District of Columbia Good Time Credits Act of 1986, effectivepril 11, 1987 (D.C. Law 6-218; D.C. Official Code § 24-221.01 et seq.).</text>
    <text>“Good time credit” – means either good behavior credit pursuant to section03.4 or other credit or pursuant to sections 603.5, 603.6, or 603.7 earned as aesult of successful participation in rehabilitative programs, work details, andpecial projects.</text>
    <text>“Incarceration” – means residence resulting from pretrial or presentenceetention, a sentence, or detention pending a hearing on revocation of probationr release in the Central Detention Facility, Correctional Treatment Facility,r another secure facility
      under contract to the District of Columba Departmentf Corrections.</text>
    <text>“Rehabilitative program” – means a program providing opportunities forelf improvement, including treatment, academic, or vocational programs.</text>
    <text>“Special project” – means a designated, non-recurring project.</text>
    <text>“Successful participation” means active and constructive participation andncludes satisfactory attendance and compliance with any rehabilitative program,ork detail, or special project.</text>
    <text>“Term of commitment” – means the period of an inmate’s currentncarceration. The term “term of commitment” includes the following:</text>
    <text>A single sentence;</text>
    <text>A combination of concurrent sentences (a concurrent sentence is two (2) or moreentences that run simultaneously), in which case the term of commitment is theeriod of commitment between the earliest starting date of those sentences andhe latest expiration
      date of those sentences;</text>
    <text>A combination of consecutive sentences (a consecutive sentence is two (2) orore sentences following one after the other in uninterrupted succession), inhich case the term of commitment is the period of commitment between thetarting date of the first
      consecutive sentence and the expiration of the lastonsecutive sentence;</text>
    <text>A combination of concurrent and consecutive sentences in which case the term ofommitment is the period of commitment between the earliest starting date of theentences and the last expiration date of the sentences;</text>
    <text>A combination of sentences imposed before and after release on parole orrobation and the probation or parole is revoked, in which case the term ofommitment is the period of commitment between the earliest starting date of theentences and the latest
      expiration date of the sentences, excluding time out ofustody for which credit is not allowed.</text>
    <text>“Work detail” – means assignment to a recurring task pursuant to annstitutional work program.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>District of Columbia Good Time Credits Amendment Act of 2010, effectiveay 17, 2011 (D.C. Law 18-372), published at 58 DCR 7 (January 7, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>