<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-603</num>
  <heading>APPLICABILITY OF GOOD TIME CREDITS (§ 28-603)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>603.01.</num>
    <text>Each inmate committed to the Department of Corrections who is sentenced for a misdemeanor pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 24-403.02 may be eligible for credits to be applied to his or her sentence pursuant to the District of Columbia Good Time Credits
      Act of 1986, effective April 11, 1987 (D.C. Law 6-128; D.C. Official Code § 24-221.01 et seq.), in one or more of the following categories:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Good behavior;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Rehabilitative programs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Work details; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Special projects.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.02.</num>
    <text>Credit shall be calculated from the first day of incarceration but does not accrue before the 20th day of incarceration. The credit shall be calculated regardless of whether the inmate is pre-trial, pre-sentence, or sentenced. One credit is equal
      to a full day of reduction in a sentence.</text>
    <text>Except in the case of good behavior credit awarded pursuant to section 603.04, all credits shall accrue each calendar month for successful participation in rehabilitative programs, work details, and special projects, in the following manner:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If participation in the program, detail, or project last twenty (20) days or less: one credit;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If participation in the program, detail, or project lasts more than twenty (20) days, but less than twenty-six (26) days: two (2) credits; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If participation in the program, detail, or project lasts twenty-six (26) days or more: three (3) credits.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.03.</num>
    <text>After an inmate has been released, either to probation or by the expiration of his or her sentence, good time credits awarded during the period of incarceration are of no further effect and shall not be used to shorten the period of probation, to
      shorten the period of incarceration which the inmate may be required to serve for violation of probation, or to shorten any subsequent sentence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.04.</num>
    <text>Good behavior credit.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An inmate shall be awarded good behavior credit at the inception of his or her incarceration for anticipated future good behavior and institutional adjustment that will result in the automatic reduction of the inmate’s term of commitment unless
        all or part of such credits are revoked pursuant to section 604.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The reduction described in paragraph (a) of this subsection shall be calculated from the first date of commitment at a rate of three (3) days for each full calendar month during the inmate’s commitment or, if the inmate is committed for less than
        a full calendar month, at a rate of one day for each 10-day period within a calendar month in which an inmate is committed.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An inmate shall not receive credit under this subsection for any 10-day period during which the inmate is not incarcerated, including a period where the inmate’s sentence is stayed or the inmate has escaped.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The amount of good behavior credit is subject to disciplinary revocation under section 604.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.5.</num>
    <text>Rehabilitative programs credit</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An inmate shall be eligible for a good time credit deduction from the inmate’s term of commitment for successful participation in one or more self-improvement programs.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The deduction described in paragraph (a) of this subsection shall be calculated from the first day the inmate demonstrates successful participation in the program using the formula set forth in section 603.04(b).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.6.</num>
    <text>Work detail credit</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An inmate shall be eligible for a good time credit deduction from the inmate’s term of commitment for demonstrating successful participation of assigned work tasks.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The deduction described in paragraph (a) of this subsection shall be calculated from the first date of assignment and continue through termination from detail assignment or release from custody using the formula set forth in section 603.04(b).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.07.</num>
    <text>Special projects credit</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An inmate shall be eligible for a good time credit deduction from the inmate’s term of commitment for demonstrating successful participation in a designated non-recurring special project.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The deduction described in paragraph (a) of this subsection shall be calculated from the first date of assignment and continue through the completion of the assignment or as long as the inmate is committed to the Department of Corrections, whichever
        is shorter, using the formula set forth in section 603.04(b).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1077 (February 19, 1988); amended by District of Columbia Good Time Credits Amendment Act of 2010, effective May 17, 2011 (D.C. Law 18-372), published at 58 DCR 7 (January 7, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>