<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-708</num>
  <heading>APPEALS (ยง 28-708)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>708.1.</num>
    <text>At the conclusion of a hearing in which a sanction has been imposed, the Disciplinary Team must advise the defendant of his/her right to appeal the decision to the CCC Administrator/Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>708.2.</num>
    <text>The appeal must be filed within three (3) days following the delivery of written hearing results to the defendant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>708.3.</num>
    <text>The appeal must be sent to the CCC Administrator/Director; however, the sanction may be imposed prior to the Administrator&amp;#8217;s/Director&amp;#8217;s decision concerning the appeal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>708.4.</num>
    <text>The appeal must contain the defendant&amp;#8217;s version of the facts and the argument outlining the specific aspects of the hearing that the defendant is appealing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>708.5.</num>
    <text>The CCC Administrator/Director must act on the appeal within five (5) days, excluding holidays and weekends, of receipt of the appeal, and may take one of the following actions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Affirm the actions of the Disciplinary Team;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Dismiss the actions of the Disciplinary Team and dismiss the sanction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Modify the decision by reducing or suspending the sanction.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>708.6.</num>
    <text>The CCC Administrator/Director shall consider the merit of appeals based upon the following factors:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Whether there was evidence to support the charges;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Whether there was substantial compliance with applicable disciplinary policies and procedures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Whether the sanctions imposed were proportionate to the rule violation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>708.7.</num>
    <text>The decision of the CCC Administrator/Director shall be final and exhausts the defendant&amp;#8217;s available administrative recourse under these rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 4558, 4569 (May 17, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>