<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-1906</num>
  <heading>REQUIREMENTS FOR DIRECT SUPPORT PROFESSIONALS (ยง 29-1906)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1906.1.</num>
    <text>Each provider shall develop and adhere to policies which ensure that each client receiving services has the following rights:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>To be treated with courtesy, dignity and respect:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>To participate in the planning of his or her care and treatment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>To receive treatment, care and services consistent with the IHP and ISP;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>To receive services by competent personnel who can communicate with the client;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>To refuse all or part of any treatment, care or service and be informed of the consequences;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>To be free from mental and physical abuse, neglect and exploitation from persons providing services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>To be assured that for purposes of record confidentiality, the disclosure of the contents of the client&amp;#8217;s records is subject to all the provisions of applicable District and federal laws and rules;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>To voice a complaint regarding treatment or care, lack of respect for personal property by persons providing services without fear of reprisal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>To have access to his or her records; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>To be informed orally and in writing of the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Services to be provided, including any limitations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The amount charged for each service, the amount of payment required by the client and the billing procedures, if applicable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Whether services are covered by health insurance, Medicare, Medicaid or any other third party source;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Acceptance, denial, reduction, or termination of services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Complaint and referral procedures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The name, address and telephone number of the provider; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The telephone number of the hotline maintained by MRDDA.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1906.2.</num>
    <text>Each provider shall notify MRDDA and MAA, Office of Disabilities and Aging of any client incidents as set forth in MRDDA&amp;#8217;s Policy and Procedure entitled &amp;#8220;Incident Management System&amp;#8221;.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1906.3.</num>
    <text>MRDDA shall notify MAA in writing of any complaints regarding treatment, care and services rendered by Waiver providers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 10207 (November 5, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>