<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-1211</num>
  <heading>HEARING DECISION, DISPOSITION AND APPEAL (§ 29-1211)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1211.1.</num>
    <text>All hearing decisions shall be read to the youth in the hearing room and the Chair of the Community Status Review Panel or designee shall provide the written findings to the youth, his or her parent(s) or guardian(s), and attorney of record or alternate
      counsel, and the Chief of the Juvenile Section of the Office of Attorney General within five (5) business days of its issuance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1211.2.</num>
    <text>If the decision of the panel is to continue the community status, the youth shall be returned to the same placement he or she enjoyed before the hearing was held under either the conditions of the existing Community Release Agreement or conditions
      of a new agreement, consistent with subsection 1202.3.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1211.3.</num>
    <text>The panel may decide to permit the youth to remain in the community, but under different conditions spelled out in a new Community Release Agreement, consistent with subsection 1202.3.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1211.4.</num>
    <text>If the decision of the Community Status Review Panel is to terminate the youth’s community status, the panel shall determine the youth’s level of restrictiveness.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1211.5.</num>
    <text>The Case Worker shall make efforts to identify an appropriate placement, consistent with the youth’s level of restrictiveness, and make appropriate referrals within a reasonable time after the Community Status Review Hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1211.6.</num>
    <text>The panel, youth, and attorney of record, alternate counsel, or representative may seek to resolve the case by stipulation, agreed settlement, or consent order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1211.7.</num>
    <text>The youth may appeal the results of the Community Status Review Hearing, to the DYRS Director within seven (7) business days from receipt of the Community Status Review Panel’s written findings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1211.8.</num>
    <text>The DYRS Director shall review the request for appeal and make a final written determination within ten (10) business days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1211.9.</num>
    <text>The DYRS Director’s final written determination may be appealed to the appropriate venue for review.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>56 DCR 4756 (August 28, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>