<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-1799</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 29-1799)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1799.1.</num>
    <text>For purposes of Chapter 17 of this Title, the following terms shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Caretaker &amp;#8211; A parent, relative, guardian, or other person whose needs are included in a public assistance payment for a dependent child and who is using those payments for the benefit of the dependent child.</text>
    <text>Consumer Reporting Agency &amp;#8211; This term shall have the same meaning as used in §603(f) of the Consumer Credit Protection Act (15 U.S.C. §1681a (f)).</text>
    <text>Court &amp;#8211; The Superior Court, Family Division, of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>CSED &amp;#8211; the Child Support Enforcement Division of the Office of the Corporation Counsel, or a private entity with which the Child Support Enforcement Division contracts for services.</text>
    <text>Custodian &amp;#8211; The parent, relative, guardian, or other person with whom the dependent child resides.</text>
    <text>Department &amp;#8211; The District of Columbia Department of Human Services.</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; The Director of the Department of Human Services.</text>
    <text>District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982 &amp;#8211; The District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982, effective April 6, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-101, D.C. Code, 2001 Ed. §4-201.01 et seq.).</text>
    <text>IMA &amp;#8211; The Income Maintenance Administration, Department of Human Services.</text>
    <text>Obligor &amp;#8211; Any responsible relative or person ordered to pay pursuant to any order or decision listed in §8 of the District of Columbia Child Support Enforcement Amendment Act of 1985, D.C. Code, 2001 Ed. §46-207.</text>
    <text>OPCSE &amp;#8211; the Office of Paternity and Child Support Enforcement, Department of Human Services, or a private entity with which the Office of Paternity and Child Support Enforcement contracts for services.</text>
    <text>Overdue support &amp;#8211; This term shall have the same meaning as used in §466(e) of the Social Security Act, approved August 16, 1984 (42 U.S.C. §666(e)).</text>
    <text>Responsible Relative &amp;#8211; Any person obligated under law for the support of a dependent child.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 2756, 2759 (April 15, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 1845a (March 27, 1998), adopting Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 5994, 6002 (October 17, 1997); and by Final
        Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 10251, 10260 (November 9, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>