<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-150</num>
  <heading>NOTICE OF DOCKETING OF A PRE-HEARING CONFERENCE AND A HEARING OF THEDMINISTRATIONS DETERMINATION, ORDER, OR ANSWER (§ 29-150)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>150.1.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of a request for a hearing, the Office of Administrative Hearings shall promptly send to each party, including the designated representative of the applicant or client, if any, a notice of docketing of pre hearing conference and a notice
      of a hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.2.</num>
    <text>The Office of Administrative Hearings shall send a copy of the applicant’s or client’s request for a hearing to the Administration at the same time that the Office sends the notice of docketing of pre-hearing conference to the Administration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.3.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt by the Administration of a notice of docketing or notice of pre-hearing conference and hearing, the Administration shall file with the Office of Administrative Hearings any written decision which may have resulted in the request for a
      hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.4.</num>
    <text>If no written decision has been issued by the Administration, the Administration shall file a brief statement concerning the determination or incident which led to the request for a hearing by the Office of Administrative Hearings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.5.</num>
    <text>The Administration shall provide a copy of each document submitted to the Office of Administrative Hearings to the applicant or client, and his or her designated representative, if any, at the same time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.6.</num>
    <text>The Administration’s determination, order, or statement required by § 150.3 or 150.4, shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The complete factual statement of the reasons for the Administration’s actions, including the date, and nature of the action; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The relevant provisions from the applicable statutes, regulations, or departmental handbooks or manuals.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 38 DCR 2034 (April 5, 1991); as amended by 54 DCR 6020 (June 22, 2007); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 4612 (May 28, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>