<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-1451</num>
  <heading>INCOME LEVELS FOR CHORE AND HOMEMAKER SERVICES PROGRAMS (§ 29-1451)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1451.1.</num>
    <text>An individual or family is eligible to receive not more than six (6) hours a week of chore services and an individual is eligible to receive not more than six (6) hours a week of homemaker services, if the individual or family meets one of the criteria
      prescribed in this section, except that the six (6) hour limit shall not apply to a person or family described in §1451.4(a)(3) or §1451.4(b)(2).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1451.2.</num>
    <text>An individual or family with gross annual income which does not exceed the income levels for the family size listed below is eligible:</text>
    <text>Family Size</text>
    <text>Annual Income Level</text>
    <text>Monthly</text>
    <text>1</text>
    <text>$10,598</text>
    <text>$833</text>
    <text>2</text>
    <text>13,859</text>
    <text>1,155</text>
    <text>3</text>
    <text>17,120</text>
    <text>1,427</text>
    <text>4</text>
    <text>20,381</text>
    <text>1,698</text>
    <text>5</text>
    <text>23,642</text>
    <text>1,970</text>
    <text>6</text>
    <text>26,902</text>
    <text>2,242</text>
    <text>7</text>
    <text>27,514</text>
    <text>2,293</text>
    <text>8</text>
    <text>28,127</text>
    <text>2,344</text>
    <text>9</text>
    <text>28,737</text>
    <text>2,395</text>
    <text>10</text>
    <text>29,348</text>
    <text>2,446</text>
    <text>11</text>
    <text>29,960</text>
    <text>2,497</text>
    <text>12</text>
    <text>30,571</text>
    <text>2,548</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1451.3.</num>
    <text>Determinations of financial eligibility for participation in the chore and homemaker services programs shall be based only on an assessment of the gross monthly income of each individual or family.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1451.4.</num>
    <text>An individual or family who is a member of one of the following categories shall be eligible for services:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Homemaker Services:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Recipients of Aid to Families with Dependent Children;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Recipients of Supplemental Security Income; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Adults and families with children while in need of and receiving protective services from the Family Services Administration of the Department of Human Services or the Social Services Division of the D.C. Superior Court (abused children only) without
        regard to income.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Chore Services:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Adult recipients of Supplemental Security Income; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Adults while in need of and receiving adult protective services from the Family Services Administration of the Department of Human Services without regard to income.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>The authority for §§1451 and 1452 is Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1986, 3 D.C. Code, 2001 Ed. at 382; Commissioner’s Order 70-83 (March 6, 1970), as amended by Mayor’s Order 79-144 (July 11, 1979); Mayor’s Order 75-89 (April 23, 1979); and D.C.
        Code, 2001 Ed. §§4-104, 4-110(3), 4-1303.03(a)(3), 4-1303.04(a)(4), and 7-1901 et seq.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 4705 (July 20, 1990); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 43 DCR 309 (January 26, 1996); as amended by emergency Rulemaking at 48 DCR 7775 (August 17, 2001) [EXPIRED].</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>