<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-1105</num>
  <heading>FAIR HEARING (§ 29-1105)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1105.1.</num>
    <text>Applicants or recipients may request orally, or in writing a Fair Hearing from the D.C. Energy Office, for any of the following reasons:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If the application is denied;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the application is neither denied nor approved within forty-five (45) days of applying to the agency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If the amount of the energy payment is less than the recipient believes it should be; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>If the applicant challenges the basis for a reduction in the energy payment or the termination of the energy payment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1105.2.</num>
    <text>The Office of Energy shall conduct a case review to seek administrative resolution of a contested case prior to a hearing. If the case review does not resolve the issue, the client may request a Fair Hearing at the Fair Hearing Office of the Department
      of Human Services, located at the following address:</text>
    <text>1170 12th Street, N.W.</text>
    <text>Second Floor</text>
    <text>Washington, D.C. 20005</text>
    <text>Telephone: 724-5432</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1105.3.</num>
    <text>Hearings shall be held in a place reasonably convenient to the claimant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1105.4.</num>
    <text>The claimant shall be afforded an opportunity to review his or her CEAP file.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1105.5.</num>
    <text>The hearing officer shall be a District of Columbia employee who is not involved in the decision being appealed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1105.6.</num>
    <text>The following rights shall be guaranteed the claimant:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The right to have a representative at the hearing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The right to present oral and written statements or other evidence;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The right to request access to, and the production of relevent documents and witnesses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The right to cross examine witnesses; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The right to bring an interpreter if needed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1105.7.</num>
    <text>Testimony shall be given under oath.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1105.8.</num>
    <text>The hearings shall be recorded and the decision shall be based on the record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1105.9.</num>
    <text>The claimant shall request a fair hearing within sixty (60) days of the denial of application, the contested change in payment or the termination notice, but a recipient notified of a reduction or a termination under §§1104.2 and 1104.3 of these rules
      shall request a hearing within the ten (10) day period under those subsections to continue to receive benefits pending a hearing decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1105.10.</num>
    <text>Hearing decisions shall be made within thirty (30) days after a request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 2934 (April 22, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>