<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-1713</num>
  <heading>PROCEDURES FOR FINDING GOOD CAUSE (§ 29-1713)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1713.1.</num>
    <text>CSED shall make a determination whether good cause exists no later than one hundred and eighty (180) days from the day that an applicant or recipient makes such a claim.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1713.2.</num>
    <text>CSED may make a determination after the one hundred and eighty (180) day period only if one (1) of the following occurs:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The agency needs additional time because the information required to verify the claim cannot be obtained within one hundred and eighty (180) days; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The claimant did not provide substantiating evidence within the period required by §1712.1 and 1712.2.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1713.3.</num>
    <text>Until CSED makes a finding concerning an applicant’s or recipient’s good cause claim, the applicant’s or recipient’s eligibility for Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF) shall be determined without regard to child support cooperation, provided
      that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The applicant or recipient asserted and made timely substantiation of the good cause claim; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>CSED has failed to determine whether good cause exists within the time period permitted to process a TANF application or redetermination.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1713.4.</num>
    <text>CSED may further verify a good cause claim if the applicant’s or recipient’s statement of the claim, together with the substantiating evidence, do not provide a sufficient basis for finding good cause. CSED shall not contact the non-custodial parent
      or obligor from whom support would be sought, without first:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Obtaining prior approval from the applicant or recipient;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Permitting the applicant or recipient to provide additional substantiating evidence that would make the contact unnecessary;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Permitting the applicant or recipient to withdraw the application for assistance or have the case closed; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Permitting the applicant or recipient to have the good cause claim denied.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1713.5.</num>
    <text>CSED shall determine whether to find good cause for noncooperation based upon:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The content and credibility of the statement of the applicant or recipient;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The content and credibility of all substantiating evidence; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any further verification by CSED.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1713.6.</num>
    <text>A determination concerning good cause shall be reviewed for approval by CSED supervisory personnel, and the findings will be recorded in the case record(s).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1713.7.</num>
    <text>If the applicant or recipient fails to meet the requirements set forth in §1710.1 of this chapter, CSED shall determine that good cause does not exist.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 1845a (March 27, 1998); as Emergency Rulemaking at 46 DCR 4349(May 14, 1999) [EXPIRED]; as Emergency Rulemaking at 47 DCR 5615(July 7, 2000) [EXPIRED]; as Emergency Rulemaking at 47 DCR 6746(August 8, 2000) [EXPIRED];
        as Emergency Rulemaking at 48 DCR 3906(May 4, 2001) [EXPIRED]; as Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 10251(November 9, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>