<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-136</num>
  <heading>NOTICE AND RIGHT TO DUE PROCESS REMEDIES (§ 29-136)
    <text>Pursuant to 34 C.F.R. § 361.57, each applicant or consumer of VRSD or DSB shalle informed in writing, that he or she is entitled to each of the following:</text>
    <text>The right to request an informal administrative review meeting, mediation ormpartial due process hearing;</text>
    <text>An informal administrative review meeting, mediation or impartial due processearing;</text>
    <text>The availability of the Client Assistance Program (“CAP”) to assist thepplicant or consumer during the informal administrative review meeting,ediation or impartial due process hearing;</text>
    <text>The right to request a qualified interpreter, fluent in the primary languageincluding sign language) of the applicant/consumer or other methods ofommunication used by an individual due to his or her disability; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The right to request auxiliary aids to ensure that communications withndividuals with hearing, vision, or speech impairments are as effective asommunications with others. &amp;#8220;Auxiliary aids&amp;#8221; include such servicesr devices as qualified
        interpreters, assistive listening headsets, televisionaptioning and decoders, telecommunications devices for deaf personsTDD&amp;#8217;s), videotext displays, readers, taped texts, brailed materials, andarge print materials.</text>
    </level>
    <text>An applicant, a consumer or his or her authorized representative shall receiveritten notification of his or her due process remedies, at the following times:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>During the Application process;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Assignment to an order of selection category;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Development of an IPE; or</text>
    </level>
    <text>Upon reduction, suspension, and/or termination (including case closure) of anyetermination concerning the furnishing or denial of vocational rehabilitationervices.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 38 DCR 2034 (April 5, 1991); as amendedy 54 DCR 6020 (June 22, 2007); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57CR 4612, 4614 (May 28, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>