<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-1613</num>
  <heading>JOB FUNCTIONS AND STAFF QUALIFICATIONS (§ 29-1613)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1613.1.</num>
    <text>Each child-placing agency shall employ a minimum of three (3) persons including an executive director, director of social services, and office staff person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1613.2.</num>
    <text>The executive director shall manage and administer the agency in accordance with the licensing requirements and policies of the governing body. The executive director shall prepare the annual budget in conjunction with the Board, and keep the Board
      informed of the financial needs of the agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1613.3.</num>
    <text>The executive director shall have a doctoral degree or a master’s degree plus three (3) years of experience in a social services agency or program, including one (1) year in administration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1613.4.</num>
    <text>Section 1613.3 shall not apply to a person employed as executive director prior to the effective date of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1613.5.</num>
    <text>If the executive director’s degree is not in social work from a college or university accredited by the Council on Social Work Education, then a director/supervisor of social services shall be responsible for all caseload services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1613.6.</num>
    <text>The executive director shall be responsible for case work decisions except where a director of social services has been assigned those duties. The duties shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Ensuring that the child-placing agency complies with this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Developing, implementing, and maintaining policies and procedures for the operation of the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Representing the child-placing agency in the community and in cooperation with the governing body, interpreting the financial needs of the child-placing agency and the population it serves;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Delegating responsibilities to staff;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Recruiting, supervising, evaluating, training, and terminating staff in accordance with established personnel policies; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Advising the governing body in carrying out its responsibilities and making recommendations for needed changes in policy and assisting in periodic evaluation of the agency’s services.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1613.7.</num>
    <text>The director of social services shall supervise, evaluate, and monitor the work of the social services staff and assist in the formulation and implementation of the child-placing agency’s policies and programs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1613.8.</num>
    <text>The director of social services shall have a master’s degree in social work from a college or university accredited by the Council on Social Work Education, plus three (3) years experience in providing casework services to children and their families
      including one (1) year as an administrator or supervisor of casework services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1613.9.</num>
    <text>Office staff shall have the responsibility of bookkeeping and maintaining correspondence and personnel and client records.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1613.10.</num>
    <text>A child-placing agency shall employ a person to supervise program staff and casework activities. The supervisor shall have a master’s degree in social work from a college or university accredited by the Council on Social Work Education, plus two (2)
      years of experience in providing casework services to families and children and shall be licensed as a social worker in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1613.11.</num>
    <text>A social worker shall provide services to children, birth parents, foster and adoptive families, and any other individual involved in a case. Social workers shall have a master’s degree in social work from a college or university accredited by the
      Council on Social Work Education and shall be licensed as a social worker in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1613.12.</num>
    <text>Social services aides shall assist the social worker. A social services aide shall have a bachelor’s degree in social work from a college or university accredited by the Council on Social Work Education or a bachelor’s degree in a related field.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 3033, 3039 (May 11, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>