<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-1813</num>
  <heading>GRANT CLOSE OUT (§ 29-1813)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1813.1.</num>
    <text>All grantees and subgrantees are subject to audit in connection with the close out of the grant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1813.2.</num>
    <text>A grantee or subgrantee that has been designated high risk, or has expended $500,000 more in grant funds during the grant year, an independent and in-depth financial statement and audit of the type required by OMB Circular A133’s “single audit” for
      any entity that expends $500,000 or more of grant funds during the grant year is required.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1813.3.</num>
    <text>A grantee or sub-grantees that are assigned a “medium-risk” assessment by their awarding Department, or those that expend between $499,999 and $250,000, shall be required to prepare and file at close-out a less-extensive financial statement report
      prepared by an independent accountant containing:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An income statement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A balance sheet;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A reconciliation of cash balances;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A reconciliation of stockholder equity (if the grantee is a for-profit entity); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>An independent review of management’s internal controls.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1813.4.</num>
    <text>A grantee or sub-grantee receiving and expending between $25,000 and $249,999 during the grant year shall be required to file a financial statement that contains:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An income statement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A balance sheet;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A reconciliation of cash balances; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A review of management’s internal controls.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1813.5.</num>
    <text>A grantee or sub-grantee assigned a “low-risk” designation, and any other grantee or sub-grantee that receives and spends up to $24,999, shall file a simple financial report containing:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An income statement; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A balance sheet.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 15243 (November 1, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>