<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-1707</num>
  <heading>COOPERATION IN ESTABLISHING PATERNITY AND OBTAINING SUPPORT (§ 29-1707)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1707.1.</num>
    <text>The Child Support Enforcement Division of the Office of Corporation Counsel (“CSED”) shall determine whether an applicant or recipient is cooperating in good faith by applying the standards set forth under this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1707.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant or recipient is cooperating in good faith pursuant to §1708 of the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982, effective April 6, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-101, D.C. Code, 2001 Ed. §4-217.08), if the applicant or recipient:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Provides the Director, or his or her designee, or CSED with the name of the non-custodial parent or other obligor of child support for a child with respect to whom assistance is claimed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Provides the Director, or his or her designee, or CSED with other relevant information regarding the non-custodial parent or obligor, if known to, possessed by, or reasonably obtainable by the applicant or recipient, which may include:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Age or date of birth;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Last known home address;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Social security number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Home and work telephone numbers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Last known employer name and address;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Occupation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Union or trade association affiliation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>School;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Names and addresses of relatives or associates;</text>
    </level>
    <text>(10) Date and place of any arrest, if any;</text>
    <text>(11) Make, model or license plate number of car;</text>
    <text>(12) Driver’s license number;</text>
    <text>(13) Bank account or credit card information; or</text>
    <text>(14) Any additional information necessary to establish paternity for the child with respect to whom assistance is claimed, or to establish, modify, or enforce a support order for the child;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Appears at interviews, hearings, and legal and administrative proceedings regarding the support of the child with respect to whom assistance is claimed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Submits to genetic tests pursuant to judicial or administrative order;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Submits the child, with respect to whom assistance is claimed, to genetic tests pursuant to judicial or administrative order;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Pays to the District any support payments received from the non-custodial parent or obligor that are subject to assignment, as required by §519 of the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982, effective April 6, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-101, D.C.
        Code, 2001 Ed. §4-205.19); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Attests to lack of information under penalty of perjury, if the applicant or recipient, in good faith, is unable to identify or assist in locating the noncustodial parent or obligor. CSED shall make a finding whether the applicant or recipient could
        reasonably be expected to provide the information, if the applicant or recipient makes such an attestation. In making the finding, CSED shall consider:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The age of the child for whom support is sought;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The circumstances surrounding the conception of the child;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The age and mental capacity of the applicant or recipient;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The time that has elapsed since the individual last had contact with the alleged non-custodial parent or obligor; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The relationship between the applicant or recipient and the child for whom support is sought.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1707.3.</num>
    <text>CSED may request that the applicant or recipient sign a voluntary acknowledgment of paternity, where appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1707.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant or recipient shall not be required as a condition of cooperation and eligibility for assistance to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Sign the voluntary acknowledgment of paternity set forth in §1707.3; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Relinquish the right to seek genetic tests of another person.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>The authority for §1707-1715 is the Self-Sufficiency Promotion Amendment Act of 1988 §2(f), D.C. Law 12-241, D.C. Code, 2001 Ed. §4-201.01 et seq.; and Mayor’s Order 99-65 (April 26, 1999).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 1845a (March 27, 1998); as Emergency Rulemaking at 46 DCR 4349(May 14, 1999) [EXPIRED]; as Emergency Rulemaking at 47 DCR 5615(July 7, 2000) [EXPIRED].</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>