<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-1101</num>
  <heading>ELIGIBILITY (§ 29-1101)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1101.1.</num>
    <text>Persons shall be eligible to initially receive assistance who meet the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Referred by Vocational Rehabilitation after employment; have been referred by the AFDC program after denial or termination due to earned income; have been referred from the subsidized Adoption and Foster Care Programs after all other eligibility
        requirements have been met;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Are residents of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Have combined earned income not exceeding $20,000 annually from partial or full-time employment; annual household income shall be calculated in accordance with the U.S. Office of Management and Budget’s guidelines defining 150 percent of the poverty
        level;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Be the head of the household which has at least one dependent under the age of 21 years who resides in the household; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Have filed a completed CEAP application with the Office of Energy.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1101.2.</num>
    <text>To remain eligible for CEAP assistance, persons who have satisfied the initial eligibility requirements shall continue to meet the following standards:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Remain residents of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Have combined earned income not exceeding $20,000 annually from full-time or part-time employment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Be the head of the household and have at least one dependent under 21 years of age residing in the household;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Present annually to the Office of Energy documentation clearly demonstrating compliance with CEAP eligibility; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Be certified by the Office of Energy to continue to receive CEAP assistance based upon the criteria set forth herein.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 2934 (April 22, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>