<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-127</num>
  <heading>TRANSITION SERVICES FOR SECONDARY SCHOOL STUDENTS (§ 29-127)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>127.1.</num>
    <text>The Rehabilitation Services Administration shall provide transition services to students with disabilities, as defined by § 199 of these regulations, who are referred to the Rehabilitation Services Administration or who apply for transition services.
      Transition services shall plan for a student&amp;#8217;s employment outcome or independent living after the student leaves secondary education.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>127.2.</num>
    <text>The Rehabilitation Services Administration shall provide transition services two years before the student&amp;#8217;s anticipated exit from secondary education. Transition services shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Outreach through technical assistance and general information to secondary school staff, students and families on the vocational rehabilitation program and independent living program, including information on eligibility requirements, the application
        process, scope of services, and linkages with other agencies and organizations to enable the student to move smoothly from secondary education to vocational activities leading to an employment outcome, or an independent living program leading
        to self-sufficiency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Consultation and technical assistance to students referred to or requesting transition services in development of vocational or independent living goals that will be identified in their Individualized Plan for Employment (IPE) or Independent Living
        Plan (ILP), based on the student&amp;#8217;s needs, taking into account the student&amp;#8217;s preferences and interests; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>During the student&amp;#8217;s final academic year of secondary education, the Rehabilitation Services Administration shall:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Assist the student with completing and submitting an application for vocational rehabilitation or independent living services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Determine the student&amp;#8217;s eligibility for services; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Develop and approve an IPE or Independent Living Plan (ILP) for each eligible student consistent with §§ 110 and 111, to be implemented upon the student&amp;#8217;s exiting the secondary educational institution.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>127.3.</num>
    <text>The Rehabilitation Services Administration shall implement an eligible student&amp;#8217;s IPE or ILP after the student exits the secondary educational institution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>127.4.</num>
    <text>The Rehabilitation Services Administration shall enter into a formal interagency agreement with the state education agency for collaboration in the provision of transition services that includes:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Consultation and technical assistance to educational agencies in planning for the transition of students with disabilities from school to post school activities, including vocational rehabilitation and independent living services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Joint transition planning that facilitates the development, completion and approval of the student&amp;#8217;s Individualized Education Plan (IEP), IPE, and ILP;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The roles and responsibilities, including financial responsibilities, of each agency; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Procedures for outreach to and identification of students with disabilities who are in need of transition services.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 6189 (August 1, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 6020 (June 22, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>