<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-1633</num>
  <heading>PLACEMENT CONSIDERATION FOR ADOPTION (§ 29-1633)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1633.1.</num>
    <text>The child-placing agency shall make a written assessment of the needs and strengths of the child prior to selection of an adoptive family.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1633.2.</num>
    <text>When adoption is the placement of choice for a child and all adoptive requirements have been met, the child-placing agency shall ensure that the child is placed expeditiously in a permanent home.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1633.3.</num>
    <text>The child-placing agency shall place siblings together whenever possible.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1633.4.</num>
    <text>In selecting an adoptive family, the agency shall make maximum efforts to place the child in a home of persons of the same race to help preserve the racial heritage. This effort shall not jeopardize the child’s right to permanent care.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1633.5.</num>
    <text>In placing a child for adoption, the child-placing agency shall take into consideration a child’s religious heritage.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1633.6.</num>
    <text>The child-placing agency shall prepare each child for the separation from his family prior to the actual placement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1633.7.</num>
    <text>The child-placing agency shall ensure that permanent placement is the best plan, that the child is prepared for placement, and that the adoptive family is able to meet the child’s needs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1633.8.</num>
    <text>Based upon the best interest of the child, the child-placing agency shall consider the child’s needs, particularly for older children, to maintain contact with the birth family or significant others.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 3033, 3059 (May 11, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>