<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-1805</num>
  <heading>NOTICE OF FUNDS AVAILABILITY (NOFA) (§ 29-1805)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1805.1.</num>
    <text>Before making a grant or subgrant, the Department shall prepare a Notice of Funds Availability (NOFA) which shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A brief description of the purposes for which funds are available;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The criteria for eligible applicants; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The time and location at which the Request for Application (RFA) may be obtained and the process and timetable for submission.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1805.2.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in Section 1805.3, the Department shall forward the NOFA to the Office of the Secretary (Office of Documents and Administrative Issuance) for publication in the D.C. Register no later than 14 days prior to the release of the RFA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1805.3.</num>
    <text>The Department may submit the NOFA for publication less than 14 days prior to release of the RFA where the Department determines there is good cause to do so.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1805.4.</num>
    <text>The Department shall provide a copy of its NOFAs and RFAs to the Office of the City Administrator and the Office for Partnerships and Grant Services (OPGS) no later than three (3) business days prior to publication in the weekly Funding Alert and
      posting on the District’s Grants Clearinghouse on the OPGS website.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1805.5.</num>
    <text>The Department may choose to disseminate a NOFA by publishing it in local newspapers and community newsletters, direct mailing to all prospective applicants or any other reasonable form of distribution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 481 (January 24, 1997); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 5614 (April 12, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 15243 (November 1, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>