<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-1202</num>
  <heading>RESCISSION OF COMMUNITY PLACEMENT STATUS (§ 29-1202)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1202.1.</num>
    <text>DYRS shall hold youth, who have entered into a Community Release Agreement, accountable for behavior contrary to public safety or the terms of the Community Release Agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1202.2.</num>
    <text>DYRS shall initiate a review of the youth’s community placement status within three (3) business days and shall convene a Community Status Review Hearing when DYRS becomes aware that a committed youth has been charged for the commission, attempted
      commission, or conspiracy to commit any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Homicide, attempted homicide, or assault with intent to commit homicide;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Sexual abuse in the 1st or 2nd degree, forcible rape, attempted forcible rape, assault with intent to commit forcible rape, or sodomy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Robbery while armed, attempted robbery while armed, robbery, attempted robbery, assault with intent to commit robbery while armed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Carjacking;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Armed Carjacking;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Burglary;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Kidnapping;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Arson;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Assault with intent to kill;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Malicious disfigurement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Manslaughter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Mayhem; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Murder.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1202.3.</num>
    <text>DYRS shall initiate a review of the youth’s community status within three (3) business days and may convene a Community Status Review Hearing if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>DYRS becomes aware that a youth has violated two or more terms of their Community Release Agreement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>DYRS becomes aware that a youth has violated a term of their Community Release Agreement at least twice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>DYRS becomes aware that a youth has unjustifiably absconded from the placement specified in the Community Release Agreement; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>DYRS Case Worker determines, based upon on a complete evaluation of the youth&amp;#8217;s performance under the Community Release Agreement, that he or she should initiate the Community Status Review process.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1202.4.</num>
    <text>Juveniles who violate twice or more any of the terms of their release agreement (not necessarily the same terms) may be subject to the same revocation process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1202.5.</num>
    <text>The social service worker shall determine, based on a complete evaluation of the child&amp;#8217;s performance under the release agreement, whether to start the revocation process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>56 DCR 4756 (August 28, 2009).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 1349, 1350 (March 27, 1981); 56 DCR 4756 (August 28, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>