<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2348</num>
  <heading>SERVICES AND SUPPORTS[COLON] STANDARDS FOR CORE REQUIREMENTS &amp;#8212; DRUGCREENING AND LABORATORY SERVICES (§ 29-2348)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2348.1.</num>
    <text>The facility or program shall conduct tests or drug-screening analyses to determine and detect the use of alcohol and other drugs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2348.2.</num>
    <text>The facility or program shall identify its goals, policies and procedures regarding drug testing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2348.3.</num>
    <text>The facility or program shall implement written policies and procedures regarding the collection, storage and handling of specimens.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2348.4.</num>
    <text>A laboratory that analyzes specimens shall meet all applicable District and federal laws and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2348.5.</num>
    <text>The facility or program shall implement written policies and procedures outlining the interpretation of results and actions to be taken when test results indicate the presence of alcohol and/or other drugs. Presumptive lab results shall be distinguished
      from definitive lab results.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2348.6.</num>
    <text>The facility or program shall ensure that test results and the resulting actions are documented in the patient’s record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2348.7.</num>
    <text>The facility or program shall conduct tests or analyses for drug use on a randomly scheduled basis, under appropriate supervision, as indicated by the patient’s needs and in compliance with applicable District and federal laws and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2348.8.</num>
    <text>Clinical laboratory services provided on the premises of a substance abuse treatment facility or program, and testing not performed on the premises, shall comply with the Clinical Laboratory Act of 1988, effective March 16, 1989 (D.C. Law 7-182, D.C.
      Code, 2001 Ed. §44-201 et seq.), and all District and federal laws and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2348.9.</num>
    <text>A facility or program shall conduct random drug screenings on the following substances, including but not limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Opiates;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Methadone;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Cocaine;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Benzodiazepines;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Marijuana;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Phencyclidine (PCP); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Amphetamines.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2348.10.</num>
    <text>Facilities or programs may add or delete substances specified in §2348.9 based on area use and trends with the Department’s approval.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9341 (November 24, 2000), adopting Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7708, 7774 (September 22, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>