<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2512</num>
  <heading>CLIENT RIGHTS (§ 29-2512)
    <text>At all times, clients shall be treated by Providers and the Department withignity and respect.</text>
    <text>Clients shall be able to access services within the Continuum of Care free fromiscrimination on the basis of race, color, religion, national origin, language,ulture, sex, age, marital status, personal appearance, sexual orientation,ender identity
      or expression, familial status, family responsibilities,atriculation, political affiliation, genetic information, disability, source ofncome, and status as a victim of an intrafamily offense in accordance with theuman Rights Act of 1977, effective
      December 13, 1977 (D.C. Law 2-38; D.C.fficial Code §§ 2-1401.01, et seq.(2007 Repl.; 2011 Supp.)), the Americansith Disabilities Act of 1990, approved July 26, 1990 (104 Stat. 328; 42 U.S.C.§ 12101, et seq.), the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, approved
      August 7, 1998112 Stat. 1095; 29 U.S.C. §§ 701, et seq.), Title II of the Civil Rights Actf 1964, approved July 2, 1964 (78 Stat. 243; 42 U.S.C. §§ 2000a, et seq.),nd the Language Access Act of 2004, effective June 19, 2004 (D.C. Law 15-167;.C.
      Official Code §§ 2-1931, et seq.(2007 Repl.).</text>
    <text>Clients shall receive reasonable modifications to policies, practices, orrocedures when the modifications are necessary to avoid discrimination on theasis of disability, unless the client’s Provider demonstrates that theodifications would fundamentally
      alter the nature of the services.</text>
    <text>Clients shall be able to access services within the Continuum of Care free fromerbal, emotional, sexual, financial, and physical abuse and exploitation.</text>
    <text>Clients shall receive shelter in severe weather conditions.</text>
    <text>Clients shall, at a reasonable time and with reasonable prior notice, beermitted to view and copy, or have an authorized representative view and copy,ll records and information that are related to the client and maintained by thelient&amp;#8217;s
      Provider, including any relevant personal, social, legal,inancial, educational, and medical records and information, subject to therovisions of subsection 2512.7.</text>
    <text>Clients shall be entitled to confidential treatment by the Department androviders of personal, social, legal, financial, educational, and medicalecords and information related to a client or any member of a client’samily, whether obtained from the
      client or from any other source, in a manneronsistent with the confidentiality requirements of District and federal law.</text>
    <text>Clients shall be permitted to engage in or abstain from the practice ofeligion, including the religion of a particular Provider or other clients.</text>
    <text>Upon request, Clients shall be provided with the name and job title of anyrovider staff member delivering services.</text>
    <text>Clients shall be permitted to provide input and feedback to Providers on theirelivery of services. Providers shall offer a means of providing such input inn anonymous or confidential manner.</text>
    <text>Clients shall be permitted to file complaints with, testify before, or providenformation to a Provider or the Mayor regarding the Provider’s delivery ofervices or treatment of the client.</text>
    <text>Clients shall be permitted and encouraged to participate actively in theevelopment of their Service Plan, in the progress made toward the goals of thatervice Plan, and in any alterations made to that Service Plan during thelient’s tenure in the Program.
      Clients shall also have the right to receive review of the Service Plan upon request;</text>
    <text>Clients shall not be subject to testing for drugs or alcohol except when:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Program guidelines prohibit intoxication and a licensed social worker withxperience identifying indications of drug or alcohol use or a certifiedddiction counselor determines that there is reasonable cause to believe thathe client is engaging in
        drug or alcohol use; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A client consents to drug or alcohol testing as part of the client&amp;#8217;service Plan developed in accordance with subsection 2512.12.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Clients shall be permitted to meet and communicate privately with attorneys,dvocates, clergy, physicians, and other professionals.</text>
    <text>Clients shall be given timely and adequate notice of a Provider’s Programules as set forth in subsection 2515.20.</text>
    <text>Clients shall be given timely and adequate notice of any denial of services,ransfer to another Provider, or suspension or termination of services as setorth in this chapter.</text>
    <text>Clients shall be permitted to appeal where permitted by subsections 2550.1 and550.2 any decision by the Department or a Provider that adversely affects thelient’s receipt of shelter or supportive housing services.</text>
    <text>Clients shall be free from retaliation, punishment, or sanction for exercisingny right provided under the Act.</text>
    <text>Clients shall be provided continuation of shelter and supportive housingervices without change, other than transfer pursuant to section 20 of the ActD.C. Official Code § 4-754.34 (2008 Repl.) or emergency transfer, suspension,r termination pursuant
      to section 24 of the Act (D.C. Official Code § 4-754.382008 repl.)), pending the outcome of any fair hearing requested within fifteen15) calendar days of receipt of written notice of a suspension or termination.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 470, 488 (January 24, 1992); asmended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 6438July 23, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice Emergency Rulemaking published at7 DCR 11353 (November
        26, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergencyulemaking published at 58 DCR 3007 (April 8, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended byotice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 7442, 7451 (August 19, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>