<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2307</num>
  <heading>CERTIFICATION &amp;#8212; STATEMENT OF DEFICIENCIES AND CORRECTIVE ACTION PLANS (§9-2307)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2307.1.</num>
    <text>The Department shall issue a statement of deficiency within thirty (30) days of completing an inspection. Statements of deficiencies shall constitute a finding of non-compliance with a certification standard.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2307.2.</num>
    <text>When a finding of non-compliance with a certification standard is determined to pose a danger to the health, safety or welfare of patients or staff, immediate corrective action may be required.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2307.3.</num>
    <text>The Department shall maintain a record of each statement of deficiency made of a substance abuse facility or program within the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2307.4.</num>
    <text>The Department shall treat the statement of deficiencies as a public document and shall make it available for disclosure to a person who requests it as provided in the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act (DCAPA) approved October 21,
      1968 (82 Stat. 1204, D.C. Code, 2001 Ed. §§2-501 to 2-511).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2307.5.</num>
    <text>The Department shall require a facility or program to submit a plan to correct deficiencies identified during an on-site inspection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2307.6.</num>
    <text>The plan of correction for each deficiency shall include but not be limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A statement of the deficiency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A description of the corrective action(s) to be taken;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The date of completion for each action; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The signature of the person responsible for the program.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2307.7.</num>
    <text>The plan of correction shall be submitted to the Department within thirty (30) calendar days of the facility’s or program’s receipt of the statement of deficiencies. The Department shall make a determination whether or not the plan of correction is
      acceptable and shall provide written notification to the facility or program of its decision within fifteen (15) business days of receiving a plan of correction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9341 (November 24, 2000), adopting Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7708, 7717 (September 22, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>