<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2536</num>
  <heading>PSH PROGRAM – ELIGIBILITY (§ 29-2536)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2536.1.</num>
    <text>In addition to the general eligibility requirements set forth in subsection 2501 an individual or family shall, in order to be eligible for participation in the PSH Program:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Have been homeless:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For one (1) year or more; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>On multiple occasions interrupted by stays in other temporary settings such as a hospital, jail, or prison; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Have one (1) or more chronic health conditions that are at least episodically disabling including mental illness, substance use, cirrhosis, end stage renal disease, or cold weather injuries; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Have one (1) or more other substantial barriers to housing stability, such as domestic violence, trauma, or a history of out-of-home placements, or extensive involvement with the District of Columbia Child and Family Services Agency; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>For the Family Permanent Supportive Housing Program meet the definition of “family” as set forth in section 2599.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2536.2.</num>
    <text>The PSH Program, through the Department or its designee, shall conduct, on a periodic basis, subject to funding and unit availability, assessments designed to measure the vulnerability of homeless persons living on the street and in shelters. Any
      person living in a shelter or on the street may ask to take a vulnerability assessment by inquiring of a PSH Program staff person. All shelters shall have an information sheet to provide interested persons with how to contact the PSH Program. Persons
      may also be identified by any service Provider, the PSH Program, a Department employee, outreach worker, or others, and asked if the PSH Program may conduct a vulnerability assessment of the individual or family.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2536.3.</num>
    <text>Referral for available placements in the PSH Program shall be prioritized based on an individual’s or family’s score on a vulnerability assessment administered by the PSH Program. The highest score shall receive the next available referral. Information
      provided by the subject of a vulnerability assessment may be subject to verification by the PSH Program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2536.4.</num>
    <text>In addition to the criteria set forth in subsection 2536.3, placements may be further prioritized based on:</text>
    <text>Length of homelessness;</text>
    <text>The chronological order of an individual’s or family’s vulnerability assessment;</text>
    <text>Availability of appropriate sized units based on household size;</text>
    <text>Availability of funding for particular housing subsidy programs for which an individual or family may be eligible; and</text>
    <text>Availability of funding for the PSH Program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2536.5.</num>
    <text>In addition to a vulnerability assessment, an individual or family shall be required to complete an application on a form prescribed by the Department prior to placement in the PSH Program; except that if the PSH Program is unable to obtain certain
      information from a person referred for placement, the PSH Program shall have the discretion to make the placement with the available information, and endeavor to complete the application post-placement to the extent possible.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2536.6.</num>
    <text>If an interested individual or family submits an application and completes a vulnerability assessment administered by the PSH Program, but is found not to be eligible, the Department or its designee shall provide the applicant with a Notice of Denial
      of Eligibility, which shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A clear statement of the applicant’s eligibility determination;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A clear and detailed statement of the factual basis of the denial, including a reference to the eligibility criteria set forth in section 2501 or subsection 2536.1 that has not been met; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A clear and complete statement of the client’s right to appeal the denial of eligibility through a fair hearing and administrative review including the appropriate deadlines for instituting the appeal.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2536.7.</num>
    <text>In addition to the provisions for denial of eligibility in subsection 2536.6, an individual or family who has begun the placement process but who has not yet been housed and is determined to be ineligible for the PSH Program, shall be issued a Notice
      of Denial of Eligibility. Such individual or family shall not have a right to continue the placement process during the appeal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2536.8.</num>
    <text>If an individual or family issued a Notice of Denial of Eligibility pursuant to subsection 2536.7 is successful in their appeal, the individual or family shall be reinstated in the placement process for the next available uncommitted housing placement.
      Should there be no uncommitted housing placement available, the individual or family shall be given priority for the next future available housing placement. Uncommitted housing placement shall have the meaning set forth in subsection 2542.7.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2536.9.</num>
    <text>An individual or family that is found to be ineligible for the PSH Program may reapply at any time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 6438 (July 23, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice Emergency Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11353 (November 26, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergency Rulemaking published
        at 58 DCR 3007 (April 8, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 7442, 7481 (August 19, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>