<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2902</num>
  <heading>POLICE INVESTIGATIONS IN ADULT PROTECTIVE SERVICES CASES (ยง 29-2902)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2902.1.</num>
    <text>When the police have been notified by the Department of Human Services of the possible existence of an immediate, substantial risk of life threatening harm to an adult in need of protective services or when the police otherwise determine such a risk
      exists, the police shall conduct a prompt investigation to determine the need for police intervention.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2902.2.</num>
    <text>When the police determine that there is a need for police intervention, further action, including investigation, arrests, searches, or seizures, shall be performed promptly in accordance with established police procedure and shall be subject to applicable
      constitutional safeguards.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2902.3.</num>
    <text>When the police determine that police intervention is not warranted, they shall inform the Department of Human Services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2902.4.</num>
    <text>To the extent it is practicable and will not impede appropriate police action, Adult Protective Services (APS) workers shall be permitted to conduct their investigation to determine the need for protective services at the same time as the police investigation
      is conducted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2902.5.</num>
    <text>The police shall provide the Department of Human Services and, where appropriate, the Office of the Corporation Counsel with any information that is obtained by the police pertaining to the issue of an adult in need of protective services, provided
      that evidence relating to the commission of a crime shall be released only in such form as may be appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2902.6.</num>
    <text>The Department of Human Services or any APS worker involved in the investigation of a matter requiring police intervention shall provide the police with copies of any reports relevant to possible criminal activity and shall further cooperate with
      the police as needed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 6646, 6647 (October 19, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>