<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-218</num>
  <heading>DUE PROCESS SCOPE AND PROCEDURES FOR BLIND VENDORS AND RSVFP TRAINEES RECEIVINGOCATIONAL REHABILITATION SERVICES (ยง 29-218)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>218.1.</num>
    <text>The purpose of these regulations is to establish procedures pursuant to the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, as amended, and 34 C.F.R. ยง 395.11, which provide vendors and/or RSVFP trainees the opportunity to resolve disagreements with any determination
      concerning the furnishing or denial of vocational rehabilitation services offered in connection with the Randolph-Sheppard Vending Facility Program (RSVFP).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>218.2</num>
    <text>218.2 (a) A Vendor or RSVFP trainee who is dissatisfied with any determination concerning the furnishing or denial of vocational rehabilitation services or training, provided under the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 and/or 34 C.F.R. ยง 395.11, has the
      right to pursue any or all of the following options provided in 34 C.F.R. ยง 361.57:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Informal administrative review meeting with the Chief of the Division of Services for the Blind (DSB);</text>
    </level>
    <text>Mediation; and</text>
    <text>Impartial due process hearing before the D.C. Office of</text>
    <text>Administrative Hearings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>218.3.</num>
    <text>A service determination dispute regarding vocational rehabilitation services may be resolved at any level within the appeals process. The appeal process is initiated when a vendor or RSVFP trainee requests an informal administrative review meeting.
      However, a vendor or RSVFP trainee is not precluded from beginning his or her appeal by requesting mediation or requesting an impartial due process hearing, as a means to resolve a determination that affects the provision of vocational rehabilitation
      services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 8538 (December 9, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 4612, 4620 (May 28, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>