<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2328</num>
  <heading>ADMINISTRATIVE SERVICES[COLON] HUMAN RESOURCES &amp;#8212; CLINICAL SUPERVISION ANDREDENTIALING STANDARDS (§ 29-2328)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2328.1.</num>
    <text>Supervision shall be provided to all staff consistent with their job functions and responsibilities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2328.2.</num>
    <text>All staff providing services shall receive supervision in accordance with the facility’s or program’s written policy that shall require at a minimum:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Supervision of registered addiction counselors and community support workers such as face-to-face discussion of an individual’s rehabilitation, co-therapy or observation of staff performance, case staffing, review of written documentation, and consultation
        on an as needed basis to resolve staff questions or concerns;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Supervision of community support workers by addiction counselors; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Performance appraisals completed at least annually.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2328.3.</num>
    <text>Individual and group addiction counseling services shall be provided by the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A licensed professional counselor, licensed psychologist, licensed individual clinical social worker (LICSW), licensed psychiatric or chemical dependency nurse, or physician licensed in the District who has at least one (1) year of full-time experience
        in the treatment or rehabilitation of substance abuse; or,</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An addiction counselor with credentials consistent with the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, as amended, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99, D.C. Code, 2001 Ed. §3-1201.01 et seq.).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2328.4.</num>
    <text>All addiction counselor functions shall be performed pursuant to a supervisor’s control, oversight, guidance and full professional responsibility. A supervisory counselor or other professional staff shall review and countersign all counseling documentation
      in the records made by the subordinate staff.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2328.5.</num>
    <text>A licensed professional, as specified in §2328.3(a), shall countersign the following documentation: assessments, rehabilitation plans, updates, continuing care plans, aftercare plans, and discharge summaries.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9341 (November 24, 2000), adopting Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7708, 7743 (September 22, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>