<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2547</num>
  <heading>FILING A COMPLAINT WITH THE ADA COORDINATOR (§ 29-2547)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2547.1.</num>
    <text>Any qualified individual with a disability or authorized representative may file a complaint with the Department alleging noncompliance with the provisions of Title II of the ADA or the federal regulation promulgated thereunder in the provision of
      shelter or supportive housing covered by this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2547.2.</num>
    <text>If applicable, clients are encouraged to make a reasonable modification request to the shelter or supportive housing Provider and allow a reasonable time for the Provider to respond before filing a complaint under this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2547.3.</num>
    <text>A client may file a complaint with the Department’s ADA Coordinator at the following address:</text>
    <text>ADA Coordinator</text>
    <text>Department of Human Services</text>
    <text>Office of the Director</text>
    <text>64 New York Avenue, NE,</text>
    <text>6th Floor</text>
    <text>Washington, DC 20002</text>
    <text>Telephone: 202-671-4200</text>
    <text>Fax: 202-671-0180</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2547.4.</num>
    <text>A complaint shall be filed as soon as possible but no later than one hundred eighty days (180) days after the complainant becomes aware of the alleged violation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2547.5</num>
    <text>2547.5 The complaint shall be filed with the ADA Coordinator in writing or in another accessible format suitable to the complainant, and shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The complainant&amp;#8217;s name and address;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The nature of the individual&amp;#8217;s disability;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A description of the alleged noncompliance in sufficient detail to inform the Department of the nature of the allegation, including dates and place of the alleged violation and names of persons involved, if known;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>If the complaint concerns a reasonable modification request that was made to a Provider but not resolved to the satisfaction of the client, the complaint shall include information regarding the reasonable modification request, including date and
        nature of request, and response, if any, from the Provider;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The modification, accommodation, or remedy desired;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the person’s authorized representative, if any; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The signature of the complainant or complainant’s authorized representative.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2547.6.</num>
    <text>If the complaint is not in writing, the ADA coordinator shall transcribe or otherwise reduce the complaint to writing upon receipt of the complaint.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2547.7.</num>
    <text>Any person other than the ADA Coordinator who receives a complaint alleging a violation of the ADA shall submit the complaint to the ADA Coordinator within three (3) business days of receipt.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>TTY</heading>
      <text>202-671-4495</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 6438 (July 23, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice Emergency Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11353 (November 26, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergency Rulemaking published
        at 58 DCR 3007 (April 8, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 7442, 7494 (August 19, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>