<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2099</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 29-2099)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2099.1.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this chapter, the following terms shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Department &amp;#8211; The District of Columbia Department of Health.</text>
    <text>Eligible Drug &amp;#8211; Retrovir (AZT), alpha interferon, aerosolized pentarnadine, or another drug that is approved by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration for therapeutic treatment of persons with HIV/AIDS or related illnesses and that is certified
      for inclusion in this program in a notice published in the D.C. Register.</text>
    <text>Insurance Co-Payment &amp;#8211; Any portion of the cost of the eligible drug expected to be paid by the patient under the terms of his or her health insurance policy or other third-party coverage agreement, including the amount of any insurance deductible
      directly associated with the purchase of an eligible drug.</text>
    <text>Insured Applicant &amp;#8211; An applicant for financial assistance under this program who has existing health insurance coverage, or other form of insurance or third-party payment assistance, for the purchase of an eligible drug.</text>
    <text>Uninsured Applicant &amp;#8211; An applicant for financial assistance under this program who has no existing health insurance coverage, or other form of insurance or third-party payment assistance for health care needs, and who is not approved for
      assistance under the District of Columbia Medicaid Program. For purposes of this chapter, an individual whose existing insurance provides no coverage for the purchase of an eligible drug shall be considered uninsured.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 4935, 4939 (July 14, 1989); as Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 2360 (March 16, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>