<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2356</num>
  <heading>SPECIALITY SERVICES &amp;#8212; STANDARDS FOR DAY TREATMENT (§ 29-2356)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2356.1.</num>
    <text>A substance abuse treatment program providing day treatment shall provide services that are part of a comprehensive package of services and therapeutic structured activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2356.2.</num>
    <text>Day treatment services shall be consistent with the patient’s rehabilitation plan, which is designed to achieve and promote recovery from substance abuse/dependency and improve client functioning and shall be provided a supervised substance-free facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2356.3.</num>
    <text>Key service functions of day treatment shall include, but are not limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Activities to address the patient’s immediate need to abstain from substance use;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Activities and structure which provide a meaningful, constructive alternative to substance abuse;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Activities which promote individual responsibility for recovery;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Activities that enhance life skills;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Activities that address functional skills;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Activities that enhance the use of personal support systems; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Activities which promote development of interests and hobbies to constructively use leisure time.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2356.4.</num>
    <text>The required service components which shall be used to achieve key service functions of day treatment include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Individual counseling;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Group counseling;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Group education;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Family and individual therapy; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Supervision of patients and structured programming to promote and reinforce a substance-free lifestyle including, but not limited to, organized recreational activities, skill building, structured self-study sessions, promotion of self-help, and
        peer support activities.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2356.5.</num>
    <text>The ratio of patients to staff for day treatment components shall not exceed the maximums set forth in the provider manual. The number of staff required shall be increased as necessary based on the mix of patients in a program, the age of patients,
      the number of family members or others at the facility, off-site program activities, and the size and configuration of the day treatment facility space.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2356.6.</num>
    <text>At least one (1) addiction counselor shall be present and providing services at all times when day treatment services are in operation and patients are in the day treatment facility. On weekends and holidays, an addiction counselor may provide on-call
      coverage rather than being physically present at the treatment facility. On-call coverage must be prompt and responsive to patient’s needs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2356.7.</num>
    <text>Day treatment services shall be offered seven (7) days per week. The day treatment program shall maintain a current activity schedule, which offers a minimum of thirty (35) hours of structured, planned, therapeutic activity per week.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2356.8.</num>
    <text>Therapeutic activity shall include individual counseling, group education, family therapy, structured recreational activity, events involving patients and family members, and peer support activities at the site.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2356.9.</num>
    <text>Therapeutic activity does not include time allocated for unstructured leisure, meals, or chores.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2356.10.</num>
    <text>Counseling and group education are minimally required daily activities in which all patients must participate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2356.11.</num>
    <text>Each patient shall participate in at least two (2) hours of individual counseling per week. Family therapy may substitute for one (1) hour of required individual counseling.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2356.12.</num>
    <text>Each patient shall to participate in at least eighteen (18) hours of group education and group counseling. At least six (6) of the required hours shall be group counseling. The remaining hours may be group education, group counseling, or group therapy,
      according to the needs of the target population and the program philosophy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9341 (November 24, 2000), adopting Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7708, 7784 (September 22, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>