<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2908</num>
  <heading>FEES AND REIMBURSEMENT (§ 29-2908)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2908.1.</num>
    <text>The Department shall not charge any fee to the adult or legally responsible person for the initial investigation, set forth under D.C. Code, 2001 Ed. § 7-1904, or for incidental services normally provided by the APS in preparation of referrals, consultation
      with relevant service providers or counseling with the adult, relative, or caretaker as part of the overall supervision of the case.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2908.2.</num>
    <text>Except for services, pursuant to § 2908.1 of these rules, for which no fee shall be charged, the Department may charge a fee and set a sliding fee schedule for specific protective services which the APS provides in furnishing protective services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2908.3.</num>
    <text>Any fees charged shall be set by separate rulemaking after appropriate consultation with the Mayor’s User Charge Review Committee, established pursuant to Mayor’s Order 82-289, dated December 13, 1983.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2908.4.</num>
    <text>The Department may charge an adult receiving protective services under the Act or legally responsible person the cost for specific protective services which the Department provides pursuant to a contract or agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2908.5.</num>
    <text>Other private or public agencies including District agencies, providing services on behalf of the Department under the Act, shall apply their own criteria to determine eligibility and payment of services, unless some other arrangement shall be agreed
      upon by the agency and the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2908.6.</num>
    <text>Services provided by the Department and other agencies may include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Food;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Heat;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Shelter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Clothing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Health care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Home care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Legal assistance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Placement; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Counseling.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2908.7.</num>
    <text>Legal services shall be provided for indigents in accordance with D.C. Code, 2001 Ed. § 7-1906(c). Payment and costs for legal assistance may be determined accordingly.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2908.8.</num>
    <text>If an agency is designated by the Department to provide services, it shall charge only the fees that are consistent with other similar services provided by the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2908.9.</num>
    <text>Any fees charged by a designated agency shall be subject to the Department’s review prior to the Department designating the agency to provide services under the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2908.10.</num>
    <text>Any contribution or reimbursements collected by the Department shall be handled in accordance with appropriate accounting procedures applicable to the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2908.11.</num>
    <text>All fees billable to or collected by an agency shall be handled according to the agency’s normal procedures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 6646, 6654 (October 19, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>