<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-207</num>
  <heading>PROMOTION AND TRANSFER OF VENDORS (ยง 29-207)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>207.1.</num>
    <text>The licensing agency, with the active participation of the Committee of Blind Vendors, shall establish a promotion and transfer system for vendors that shall be uniformly applied to all vacancies which develop or occur in the Program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>207.2.</num>
    <text>Eligibility for promotion and transfer within the Program shall be governed by a point system which determines the ranking of all licensed vendors.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>207.3.</num>
    <text>Rating points, as described in this section shall be awarded on the basis of seniority and performance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>207.4.</num>
    <text>When a vending facility vacancy occurs, the vendor with the highest number of rating points shall be offered the opportunity to transfer to the vacant facility. If that vendor declines, the transfer shall be offered to the next highest ranked vendor.
      This procedure shall continue until the vacancy is filled.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>207.5.</num>
    <text>All vendors shall be guaranteed the right to decline a transfer without penalty and shall be allowed up to forty-eight (48) hours in which to accept or reject a transfer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>207.6.</num>
    <text>Vendors may be denied the opportunity to transfer, on a temporary basis, if documentation developed with the active participation of the Blind Vendors Committee reflects serious managerial problems which prevent a vendor from operating in an acceptable
      manner. The right to transfer shall be reinstated when the vendor demonstrates acceptable overall managerial performance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>207.7.</num>
    <text>Seniority shall be determined by the length of time during which persons have been licensed as vendors in the Program in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>207.8.</num>
    <text>Seniority shall begin to accrue upon the date of issuance of the original license to a vendor and continue until resignation, death, or dismissal from the Program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>207.9.</num>
    <text>If a former licensee returns to the Program, the seniority points earned during the prior tenure shall be reinstated, unless the Promotion and Transfer Committee votes unanimously to deny the reinstatement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>207.10.</num>
    <text>A vendor shall accumulate one (1) rating point for each six (6) months of seniority until he or she has received forty (40) points. After accumulating forty (40) points, a vendor shall then accumulate one (1) point for each twelve (12) months of seniority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>207.11.</num>
    <text>A semi-annual evaluation of performance shall be made according to the following performance criteria and rating points system:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <text>Supervision of personnel</text>
    <text>5points;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <text>Knowledge of business</text>
    <text>5points;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <text>Ability to serve</text>
    <text>5points;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <text>Care and utilization of equipment</text>
    <text>5points;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <text>Recordkeeping</text>
    <text>5points;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <text>Sanitation</text>
    <text>5points;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <text>Customer relations</text>
    <text>5points; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <text>Adherence to rules and regulations</text>
    <text>5points.</text>
    <text>Maximum:</text>
    <text>40 points</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>207.12.</num>
    <text>Performance ratings shall be judged on the manner in which vendors apply themselves to all the various phases of vending facility operation and the degree to which they meet the requirements and standards of the Program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>207.13.</num>
    <text>Performance shall be determined by a semi-annual evaluation of all vendors conducted by the Promotion and Transfer Committee, based upon reports of supervisory personnel of the nominee organization and other pertinent reports including documented
      complaints.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>DCRR Title 6C, as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 4611 (October 17, 1980).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>