<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2364</num>
  <heading>SPECIALITY SERVICES &amp;#8212; STANDARDS FOR MEDICAL DETOXIFICATION PERSONNEL (§9-2364)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2364.1.</num>
    <text>A substance abuse treatment facility or program shall have on staff a supervising physician who has the responsibility for administering all medical and pharmaceutical procedures. The physician shall be licensed to practice medicine in the District
      of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2364.2.</num>
    <text>Staff shall be trained and competent in medical management and supervision of detoxification from alcohol and drugs. Documentation of staff training shall be retained in each employee’s personnel file.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2364.3.</num>
    <text>Staffing shall provide twenty-four (24) hours awake supervision, seven (7) days a week. Adequate staffing levels shall be maintained to admit, treat, and discharge patients.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2364.4.</num>
    <text>A substance abuse treatment facility or program shall provide on-site physician coverage twenty-four (24) hours a day, seven (7) days a week.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2364.5.</num>
    <text>A substance abuse treatment facility or program shall have a designated registered nurse responsible for the general supervision of the nursing staff. He or she shall be licensed to practice nursing in the District of Columbia, and certified in chemical
      dependency. He or she shall participate in ongoing professional development in the area of substance abuse. Documentation of .such training shall be retained in each employee’s personnel file.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2364.6.</num>
    <text>The number of licensed nursing staff shall be commensurate with the number of patients being served. The patient: nurse ratio on the day shift shall not exceed 12:1; on the evening shift 17:1; and on the night shift 25:1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2364.7.</num>
    <text>Staffing shall be appropriate in number to ensure the safety of the patient and staff. Staff shall have the necessary training and be competent to recognize signs and symptoms of chemical dependency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9341 (November 24, 2000), adopting Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7708, 7803 (September 22, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>