<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2104</num>
  <heading>LOAN PROGRAM AGREEMENT (ยง 29-2104)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2104.1.</num>
    <text>Each loan recipient shall sign a loan agreement which shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Amount of the loan;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The schedule for repayment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The date the payment is due;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The amount of the installment payment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The late payment fees; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The date the late payment fee is applicable.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2104.2.</num>
    <text>The recipient shall repay each loan in monthly installments, according to a schedule agreed upon by the recipient, not to exceed twenty-four (24) months after the date in which the loan was made.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2104.3.</num>
    <text>At least four (4) members or representatives of the recipient group or entity shall sign the loan agreement. The eligible group or entity shall acknowledge in writing, as part of the application process, its individual and collective responsibility
      to pay each monthly installment payment when due or to repay the loan until the entire loan has been paid in full.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2104.4.</num>
    <text>The eligible group or entity shall designate at the time of application the person who shall serve as the agent on behalf of the group or entity for purpose of receiving loan monies and implementing the administrative management functions under the
      loan agreement. This designation shall be notarized.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2104.5.</num>
    <text>The group or entity requesting the loan shall agree to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That the house be maintained in an alcohol and drug free environment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That the residents of the house remain alcohol and drug free;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>That the cost of housing, including rent and utilities, be borne by the residents;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>That the monthly installment payments on the loan be borne by the residents until paid in full; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>That any resident of the house who violates the pledge of remaining alcohol and drug free or of bearing his or her share of the household expenses be expelled from the house in accordance with the criteria of ยง2104.5.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2104.6.</num>
    <text>The residents of the housing unit of the prospective borrower shall establish through a majority vote of the residents, the rules governing the management of the house. The rules shall include, but not be limited to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The officers of the house, the criteria for electing the officers, their term of office, and their duties;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Criteria for admitting new residents and expelling residents who violate the governing rules of the house;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Frequency, schedule, and purpose of resident meetings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Process for collecting funds from residents for the operation and maintenance of the house, financial transactions and any other expenses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Procedures for determining how expenses shall be shared among the residents;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Guidelines for determining how household chores will be assigned to residents;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Procedures for resolving problems, disputes, and disagreements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Procedures for accounting for funds collected from residents and for monthly reporting of the financial status of the housing; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Other rules as necessary governing the safe, hygienic, harmonious operation of the house, such as:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Curfews (if necessary);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Assigning clean-up chores;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Assigning beds;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Rules for use of common living areas; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Parking.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 38 DCR 603, 605 (January 18, 1991).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>