<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2399</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 29-2399)
    <text>Access to Recovery Program or ATR Program &amp;#8211; The voucher program for therovision of recovery support services under section 4a of the Choice in Drugreatment Act of 2000, effective July 18, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-146; D.C. Officialode § 7-3003.01).</text>
    <text>Act &amp;#8211; The District of Columbia Substance Abuse Treatment and Preventionct of 1989 (&amp;#8220;Act&amp;#8221;) effective March 15, 1990 (D.C. Law 8-80; D.C.fficial Code § 44-1201 et seq.).</text>
    <text>Admission &amp;#8211; Entry into the substance abuse treatment facility or programfter completion of intake screening and initial assessment and a determinationhat an individual is eligible for admission into a program.</text>
    <text>Addiction counselor &amp;#8211; A person who possesses and utilizes a uniquenowledge and skill base to assist: (i) a substance abuser, or (ii) a person orroup affected by a problem affected by substance abuse, or (iii) the public forhom the prevention
      of substance abuse is a primary concern. This knowledge andkill base may be attained through a combination of specialized training,ducation, supervised work experience, and life experience.</text>
    <text>Alcohol abuse &amp;#8211; Any pattern of pathological use of alcohol that causesmpairment in social or occupational functioning, or that produces physiologicalependency evidenced by physical intolerance or by physical symptoms when it isithdrawn.</text>
    <text>Alternative housing &amp;#8211; Arrangement or provision of safe, appropriate,ubstance-free housing in the community on a long or short term basis in ordero facilitate community based substance abuse treatment and rehabilitation, toaximize its benefits,
      and to maintain recovery.</text>
    <text>Applicant &amp;#8211; A facility or program that has applied to the Department forertification as a substance abuse treatment facility or program.</text>
    <text>Case management &amp;#8211; Specific coordination activities with or on behalf of aarticular client in accordance with an individual rehabilitation plan. The aimf the activities is to maximize the client’s adjustment and functioningithin the community
      while promoting sobriety and recovery promoting clientndependence and responsibility, and maximizing client involvement in theommunity and its support systems.</text>
    <text>Case manager &amp;#8211; Facility or program staff specially designated to providease management activities with or on behalf of a patient to maximize theatient’s adjustment and functioning within the community while achievingobriety and sustaining
      recovery.</text>
    <text>Certification &amp;#8211; The process of establishing that standards of careescribed in this document are met; or approval from the Department indicatinghat the applicant has successfully complied with all requirements for theperation of a substance
      abuse treatment facility or program in the District ofolumbia.</text>
    <text>Chemical restraints &amp;#8211; Drugs which are prescribed or administered in anmergency to restrain temporarily, through the use of chemicals, a patient whoresents a likelihood of serious physical harm to self or to others.</text>
    <text>Childcare, short-term, on-site &amp;#8211; Support provided to a patient for theare of a child while the patient is engaged in treatment and rehabilitationctivities deemed clinically and programmatically necessary.</text>
    <text>Child development facility &amp;#8211; A center, home, or other structure thatrovides care and other services, supervision, and guidance for children up to5 years of age on a regular basis, regardless of its designated name, but doesot include a public
      or private elementary or secondary school engaged inegally required educational and related functions.</text>
    <text>Clinician &amp;#8211; A licensed or certified professional with expertise in one ofhe following areas: physical medicine, addiction medicine, psychiatry, orocial work.</text>
    <text>Codependent &amp;#8211; A person who is a member of a family in which there is aubstance abuser receiving treatment for substance abuse.</text>
    <text>Communicable disease &amp;#8211; Any disease as defined in Title 22, §201 of theistrict of Columbia Municipal Regulations (DCMR).</text>
    <text>Community-based service &amp;#8211; Service delivery conducted in accordance withhe principles of community integration and patient self-determination.</text>
    <text>Crisis &amp;#8211; A time, stage or event for a patient characterized by one or morehreats or losses such as loss of housing, employment, or personal support(s),r legal or medical problems, or imminent or actual relapse.</text>
    <text>Day(s) &amp;#8211; Refers to calendar day unless specifically stated otherwise.</text>
    <text>Day Treatment &amp;#8211; A comprehensive package of services and structuredctivities provided consistent with patient’s rehabilitation plan which isesigned to achieve and promote recovery from substance abuse/dependency and isrovided in a supervised
      substance-free facility that provides for a minimum ofive (5) visits per week for five (5) hours per day.</text>
    <text>Department &amp;#8211; The District of Columbia Department of Health, Addictionrevention and Recovery Administration.</text>
    <text>Detoxification &amp;#8211; A program designed to achieve systematic reduction in theegree of physical dependence on alcohol or drugs.</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; Director of the Department of Health and/or the Administratorf the Addiction Prevention and Recovery Administration.</text>
    <text>Discharge &amp;#8211; The time when a patient’s active involvement with theacility or program is terminated as documented in the facility or program’secords.</text>
    <text>Discharge planning &amp;#8211; Activities with or on behalf of an individual torrange for appropriate follow-up care to sustain recovery after beingischarged from the Program, including educating the individual how to access oreinitiate additional
      services, as needed.</text>
    <text>Discrete patients &amp;#8211; Children, accompanied by a parent into a treatmentnvironment, that are clinically determined to require admission as a patientith their own separate and distinct assessment, treatment plan, course ofreatment and record,
      but does not include children who receive servicesrimarily to support a parent’s recovery.</text>
    <text>District &amp;#8211; The District of Columbia government.</text>
    <text>Drug &amp;#8211; Any chemical substance used in the diagnosis, cure, mitigation,reatment, or prevention of disease in man or animal.</text>
    <text>Dual Diagnosis &amp;#8211; The presence of concurrent diagnosis of substancebuse/dependency and a mental disease or disorder.</text>
    <text>Facility &amp;#8211; Any individual, public or private service provider, firm,orporation, partnership, society or association which represents itself eitherhrough name, advertisement, practice, or reputation to offer any servicencluding treatment,
      counseling, or rehabilitation to alcoholics, drug abusersr drug dependent individuals. Such services may be in addition to providingnformation, education, prevention, and aftercare services related to substancebuse and addiction, but does not include
      providers offering only information,ducation, prevention and aftercare services.</text>
    <text>Family &amp;#8211; Individuals who comprise a household, who may or may not beelated by marriage or ancestry.</text>
    <text>Family therapy &amp;#8211; Planned face-to-face, goal-oriented, therapeuticnteraction by a qualified individual with a client and/or one (1) or moreembers of the client’s family in order to address and resolve the familyystem’s dysfunction as it relates
      to the patient’s substance abuse problemn accordance with the patient’s rehabilitation plan.</text>
    <text>Group addiction counseling &amp;#8211; A face-to-face, goal-oriented therapeuticnteraction among a counselor and two (2) or more patients as specified inndividual rehabilitation plans designed to promote self-understanding,elf-esteem and resolution
      of personal problems through personal disclosure andnterpersonal interaction among group members.</text>
    <text>Group education &amp;#8211; The presentation of general information and applicationf the information to participants through group discussion in accordance withndividualized rehabilitation plans. The plans are designed to promote recoverynd enhance
      social functioning.</text>
    <text>Individual addiction counseling &amp;#8211; A structured, goal-oriented therapeuticrocess in which a patient interacts on a face-to-face basis with a counselor inccordance with the patient’s rehabilitation plan in order to resolve problemselated to
      alcohol or other drugs, or both, which interfere with the patient’sunctioning.</text>
    <text>Individual psychotherapy services &amp;#8211; Services designed to enhance ormprove an individual’s psychological and social functioning, improveelf-esteem and increase coping abilities in accordance with a patient’sehabilitation plan, where the patient
      interacts on a face-to-face basis with aualified mental health professional.</text>
    <text>Intake screening and assessment &amp;#8211; The process of gathering and evaluatingelevant information about an individual to determine initial admission forehabilitation program services and development of an initial treatment plan andeferral.</text>
    <text>Inpatient services &amp;#8211; Therapeutic services that are medically orsychologically necessary and that are provided in a hospital or a non-hospitalesidential facility to patients admitted to the hospital or non-hospitalesidential facility.</text>
    <text>In-service training &amp;#8211; Activities to achieve or improve competency ofmployees to perform present jobs or to prepare for other jobs or promotions.</text>
    <text>Mayor &amp;#8211; The Mayor of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Mechanical restraint &amp;#8211; Any device, instrument or physical object used toestrict an individual’s freedom of movement except for orthopedic, surgicalnd other medical purposes as ordered by a physician.</text>
    <text>Medical waste &amp;#8211; Any solid waste that is generated in the diagnosis,reatment, or immunization of human beings, or in research pertaining thereto,r in the testing of biologicals, including but not limited to, soiled orlood-soaked bandages,
      needles- used to give shots or draw blood, and lancets.</text>
    <text>Medication Management &amp;#8211; Patient service component of a program dealingith the acquisition, storage, handling, accounting, prescribing, dispensing,dministering, and self-administering of drugs used for therapeutic purposes.</text>
    <text>Medically or psychologically necessary &amp;#8211; Services that are essential forhe treatment of substance abuse, as determined by a physician, psychologist, orocial worker as they relates to patient’s medical or psychiatric condition.</text>
    <text>Narcotic Treatment program &amp;#8211; A substance abuse treatment program that isertified by the Department and certified by the Food and Drug Administration asn opioid replacement treatment program.</text>
    <text>Nutritional services &amp;#8211; Services provided by a registered dietitian in aubstance abuse treatment facility or program.</text>
    <text>Opioid Drug &amp;#8211; Any drug having an addiction-forming or addiction sustainingbility similar to morphine or being capable of conversion into a drug havinguch addiction-forming or addiction-sustaining ability.</text>
    <text>Opioid treatment &amp;#8211; The dispensing of an opioid agonist treatmentedication, along with a comprehensive range of medical and rehabilitativeervices, when clinically necessary, to an individual to alleviate the adverseedical, psychological,
      or physical effects incident to opioid addiction.</text>
    <text>Orientation &amp;#8211; Introduction of new, promoted or transferred employees tohe philosophy, organization, practices, procedures and goals of the program.</text>
    <text>Outcomes of care &amp;#8211; Includes abstinence or reduction of abuse ofubstances, elimination or reduction of criminal activity, reduction ofntisocial activity associated with substance abuse, reduction in need foredical or mental health services,
      reduction of need for substance abusereatment, increase in pro-social involvement, and increase in productivity andmployment.</text>
    <text>Outpatient services &amp;#8211; Therapeutic services that are medically orsychologically necessary and that are provided to a patient according to anndividualized treatment plan that does not require the patient’s admission to hospital or a non-hospital
      residential facility. The term “outpatientervices” refers to services that may be provided (on an ambulatory basis) in hospital, a non-hospital residential facility, an outpatient treatmentacility, or the office of a licensed physician, psychologist,
      or social worker.</text>
    <text>Outpatient treatment facility &amp;#8211; A clinic, counseling center, or otherimilar establishment that is certified by the District or by any state orerritory as a qualified provider of outpatient services for the treatment ofubstance abuse. The
      term “outpatient treatment facility” includes anyacility operated by the District, any state or territory, or the United Stateso provide these services on an outpatient basis, or any private, for profit orot for profit but excluding a group practice
      consisting solely of licensedhysicians, psychologists, or social workers.</text>
    <text>Outreach &amp;#8211; Efforts to inform and facilitate access to the program’services.</text>
    <text>Parent &amp;#8211; A person who has custody of a child as a natural parent,tepparent of the child, has adopted the child, or has been appointed as auardian for the child by a court of competent jurisdiction.</text>
    <text>Patient &amp;#8211; A person who is admitted to a substance abuse treatment facilityr program who is judged to need substance abuse treatment services based on theesults of an intake screening and initial assessment.</text>
    <text>Physical abuse &amp;#8211; The abuse of a patient with more force than is reasonabler apparently necessary for proper control, treatment or management;urposefully beating, striking, wounding or injuring any patient; or theistreating or maltreating
      of a patient in a brutal or inhumane manner.</text>
    <text>Physical restraint &amp;#8211; Physical holding of a patient to temporarily restrictreedom of movement in an emergency when the patient appears likely to inflicterious physical harm to self or others.</text>
    <text>Postpartum &amp;#8211; A period of time for up to six (6) months after birth offfspring.</text>
    <text>Program Director &amp;#8211; An individual having authority and responsibility forhe day-to-day operation of a substance abuse treatment facility or program.</text>
    <text>Provider &amp;#8211; A person, firm, corporation, partnership, or organization thatrovides recovery support services, substance abuse treatment services, or aombination of substance abuse treatment services and recovery support services.</text>
    <text>Recovery support services &amp;#8211; Services provided through the Access toecovery Program, which may include care coordination services, spiritual andaith based support services, community based support services, educationalupport services, parenting
      classes, family counseling services, child care,ransportation, and other services related to, but not including, substancebuse treatment, with the exception of methamphetamine-related treatmentervices. Methamphetamine-related treatment services
      provided through the Accesso Recovery Program shall be provided solely by providers certified pursuant toection 2300, not including section 2300.14</text>
    <text>Referral &amp;#8211; Activities with and on behalf of a specific patient tostablish initial linkage and facilitate access to other substance abusereatment facilities or programs and support service providers.</text>
    <text>Rehabilitation &amp;#8211; The process of maximizing a patient’s ability tochieve and maintain sobriety and to function in his/her current socialnvironment through structured therapeutic activities designed to developkills, attitudes and behaviors
      based on the patient’s rehabilitation plan.</text>
    <text>Rehabilitation Plan &amp;#8211; The course of action taken to address the issueshat are identified in the assessment. The plan includes the type of serviceseeded, frequency of services, the type of personnel providing the service,onitoring of patient’s
      progress and periodic plan revision.</text>
    <text>Research &amp;#8211; Experiments including new interventions of unknown efficacypplied to patients whether behavioral, psychological, biomedical orharmacological.</text>
    <text>Serious Mental Illness &amp;#8211; A diagnosis of mental illness as defined by theost recent Diagnostic Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders. The Americansychiatric Association in 1994 published the fourth edition of this manual.</text>
    <text>Sexual abuse &amp;#8211; Any touching, directly or through clothing, of theenitals, anus, or breasts of a person for other than medical purposes by anmployee or patient, or failing to exercise a duty to stop or prevent sexualarassment between patients
      or causing patients to touch or fondle an employeehrough either the clothing of the employee or direct body contact.</text>
    <text>Static capacity &amp;#8211; Maximum number of patients a facility or program canerve at any given time.</text>
    <text>Substance abuse &amp;#8211; A pattern of pathological use of a drug or alcohol thatauses impairment in social or occupational functioning or produceshysiological dependency evidenced by physical tolerance or physical symptomshen the drug or alcohol
      is not used.</text>
    <text>Substance Abuse Treatment Program &amp;#8211; Any individual, public or privateervice provider, firm, corporation, partnership, society or association whichepresents itself either through name, advertisement, practice, or reputation toffer any service
      including treatment, counseling, or rehabilitation, tolcoholics, drug abusers or drug dependent individuals. Such services may be inddition to providing information, education, prevention, and aftercare serviceselated to substance abuse and addiction,
      but does not include providersffering only information, education, prevention and aftercare services.</text>
    <text>Support services &amp;#8211; Include, but are not limited to, such services asocational training, education, and placement activities either providedirectly by the program or arranged for patients by the program through referralo outside community
      resources.</text>
    <text>Therapeutic Assistant Services &amp;#8211; Services provided by an individual whorovides a variety of services within the substance abuse treatment facility orrogram that are prescribed on the individual’s rehabilitation plan.</text>
    <text>Treatment &amp;#8211; Any effort to accomplish a change in the cognitive ormotional conditions or the behavior of a patient consistent with generallyecognized principles or standards in the substance abuse treatment field.</text>
    <text>Verbal abuse &amp;#8211; Staff or volunteers referring to a patient in theatient’s presence, with profanity or in a demeaning, undignified orerogatory manner.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9341 (November 24, 2000), adoptingmergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7708, 7809 (September 22,000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 8869(August 15, 2008)</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>