<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2320</num>
  <heading>ADMINISTRATIVE SERVICES[COLON] PROGRAM DESCRIPTION &amp;#8212; POLICIES ANDROCEDURES (§ 29-2320)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2320.1.</num>
    <text>A facility or program shall develop and implement plans, policies and procedures that shall include descriptions of program operations and service delivery as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>For the parent organization in which the substance abuse treatment facility or program is affiliated the plan shall show the:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Leadership structure as defined by the governing board, organization, and methods of personnel utilization; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Relationship among components within the organization and with agencies outside of the facility or program as defined by the governing board.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A written mission statement with clear identification of philosophy, purpose, and goals, as developed by the governing board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A statement of objectives required to meet goals, including the treatment philosophy and design, treatment outcomes and treatment process methods that shall include but not be limited to:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Recognition of personal dignity and respect for individual choice of patients;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The development of rehabilitation plans and provision of services based on the individual needs of the target population inclusive of “special needs” (i.e. support, mental health, sign language/TTI, and language services for monolingual or limited
        English speaking consumers);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Commitment to place patients in the least restrictive setting necessary to address the severity of the individual’s presenting illness and circumstances; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Serve only those individuals whose service needs are consistent with the program or facility description but which provides for referring and facilitating access to other more appropriate services for individuals deemed inappropriate for admission.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A written description of the program or facility that accurately describes its services to include but not be limited to:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Services provided;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Characteristics and needs of the population served;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Contract services, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Affiliation agreements, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Admission and exclusion criteria;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Termination of treatment and discharge or transition criteria;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Type and role of staff; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Service delivery policies and procedures as specified in SERVICES AND SUPPORT &amp;#8211; REHABILITATION SERVICES STANDARDS.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Location of service sites and specific designation of the geographic area to be served;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Hours and days of operation of each site;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The outreach plan for all services offered;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Community support plan for patients to access wraparound services critical to achieving planned outcomes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Infection control procedures and use of universal precautions, addressing at least those infections that may be spread through contact with bodily fluids and routine tuberculosis screening for staff;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>The scope~of volunteer activities, and rules governing the use of volunteers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Safety precautions and procedures for participant volunteers, employees and others;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Record management procedures in accordance with “Confidentiality of Alcohol and Drug Abuse Patient Records” 42 C.F.R., Part 2, this chapter, and any other District laws and regulations regarding the confidentiality of patient records;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Crisis intervention and medical emergency procedures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>Staff communication with the governing body;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>The on-site limitations on use of tobacco, alcohol and other substances;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(p)</num>
      <text>Patients’ rules of conduct and commitment to treatment regimen, including restrictions on carrying weapons and specifics of appropriate behavior while in or around the facility or program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(q)</num>
      <text>Patients’ rights;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(r)</num>
      <text>Methodology for addressing and investigating unusual incidents;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(s)</num>
      <text>Methodology for addressing patient grievances; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(t)</num>
      <text>Methodology for addressing issues of patient non-compliance with</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Established treatment regimen; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Other policies governing behavior, sobriety and any other specified requirements while on the premises.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9341 (November 24, 2000), adopting Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7708, 7728 (September 22, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>