<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2105</num>
  <heading>LOAN APPLICATION REVIEW PROCESS (§ 29-2105)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2105.1.</num>
    <text>The Chief, Office of Health Planning and Development, shall convene a loan application review panel which shall be comprised of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Chief, Office of Health Planning and Development, or his or her designee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Administrator, Alcohol and Drug Abuse Services Administration, or his or her designee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Controller, Office of the Controller, or his or her designee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Qualified Health Professional, in accordance with these regulations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Representative, Office of Business and Economic Development; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Non-governmental Representative.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2105.2.</num>
    <text>The panel may be expanded up to seven (7) members to include other representatives agreed upon by the six (6) members cited in §2106.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2105.3.</num>
    <text>The panel shall utilize criteria for determining eligibility of prospective borrowers as described in §2104 in determining eligibility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2105.4.</num>
    <text>At the first meeting of the review panel, the members shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Agree upon criteria to be used in addition to that delineated in §2104;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Assign a numeric weight to each criterion according to this importance in determining eligibility for a loan; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Determine the numeric ranges for approving and denying loans using the weighted criteria.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2105.5.</num>
    <text>The review panel shall convene on the first and third week of the month to review new applications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2105.6.</num>
    <text>Loan applications presented for review shall be received by the Office of Health Planning and Development forty-eight (48) hours prior to the next regularly scheduled review panel meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2105.7.</num>
    <text>The Department shall notify the prospective borrower in writing of the approval or denial of the loan application within five (5) working days, subsequent to the review panel decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2105.8.</num>
    <text>The Department shall inform the prospective borrower in writing of the reason(s) for denial of the loan application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2105.9.</num>
    <text>The Office of Health Planning and Development shall notify the prospective borrower, and the Office of the Controller of loan approvals. Each office shall receive a copy of the Notice of Revolving Loan Approval.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2105.10.</num>
    <text>The approval notice shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of borrowers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The amount of the loan;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The names of at least four (4) persons to reside in the new housing; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The name of the primary agent, as described in §2104.3, to whom the loan check shall be made.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 38 DCR 603, 607 (January 18, 1991).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>