<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2337</num>
  <heading>SERVICES AND SUPPORTS &amp;#8212; ON-SITE CRISIS INTERVENTION AND CLINICAL EMERGENCYTANDARDS (§ 29-2337)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2337.1.</num>
    <text>The facility or program shall develop and implement a crisis intervention policy that includes a mechanism for obtaining urgent or emergency medical services if on-call physician back-up is not available during normal operating hours. This requirement
      does not apply to non-hospital detoxification facilities or programs since they are required to have twenty-four (24) hour medical staff coverage.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2337.2.</num>
    <text>The facility or program shall document in the patient’s record the provision of crisis intervention services to include but not be limited to identification of the patient in crisis, the nature of the crisis, the resolution of the crisis, the disposition
      of the patient, and the follow-up plan, if applicable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2337.3.</num>
    <text>The facility or program shall develop and implement written policies and procedures for prompt intervention in the event of patient medical and psychiatric emergencies that include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Definition of medical or psychiatric emergency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Procedures for immediate access to appropriate internal and external resources;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Staff responsibilities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Location of client emergency medical information; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The telephone number and location of the nearest hospital, ambulance service, rescue squad or other trained medical personnel, the nearest poison control center and the police.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2337.4.</num>
    <text>A facility or program shall have immediate access to emergency medical information about a patient that shall include but is not limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and telephone number of the patient’s physician, if available;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name, address and telephone number of the patient’s relative or other person to be notified;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Medical insurance company name and policy or Medicaid, Medicare or CHAMPUS number, if any; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Information concerning medications used, medication and food allergies, history of substance abuse, and significant medical problems.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2337.5.</num>
    <text>Medical or psychiatric emergencies which occur on-site during the course of service provision shall be documented in the patient’s record and shall include but not be limited to events precipitating the emergency, the nature of the emergency, treatment
      received, the disposition of the patient, and the follow-up plan, if applicable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9341 (November 24, 2000), adopting Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7708, 7762 (September 22, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>