<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2310</num>
  <heading>NOTICE REQUIREMENTS &amp;#8212; OPERATIONAL CHANGES (§ 29-2310)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2310.1.</num>
    <text>A substance abuse treatment program or facility shall notify the Department in writing thirty (30) days prior to implementing any of the following operational changes, including all aspects of the operations materially affected by the changes:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A change in the program’s or facility’s geographic location;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A change in the settings where services are performed (e.g. outpatient clinic to home-based);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A planned sale, lease, or change in ownership;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The proposed addition or deletion of major service components;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A change in required staff qualifications;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A proposed change in organizational structure;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A change in the population served;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>A change in bed capacity, and;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>A change in program capacity.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2310.2.</num>
    <text>Written notice of any change in the ownership of a facility or program owned by an individual, partnership, or association, or in the legal or beneficial ownership of 10% or more of the stock of a corporation that owns or operates a facility or program,
      shall be given to the Department at least thirty (30) calendar days prior to the change in ownership.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2310.3.</num>
    <text>The Department, upon notification, may at its discretion require reinspection to ensure that the facility or program will remain in compliance with the provisions of the Act, this chapter, and all other applicable provisions of law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2310.4.</num>
    <text>A substance abuse treatment program or facility shall provide other notifications as required by applicable District and federal laws and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9341 (November 24, 2000), adopting Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7708, 7718 (September 22, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>