<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2903</num>
  <heading>POLICE ACCOMPANIMENT OF ADULT PROTECTIVE SERVICES WORKER (APS) (ยง 29-2903)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2903.1.</num>
    <text>An APS worker may request, when appropriate, that the Metropolitan Police Department assign a police officer to accompany him or her while conducting an initial or follow-up investigation to determine the need for protective services or while providing
      protective services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2903.2.</num>
    <text>Appropriate circumstances under which the police shall accompany an APS worker shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>When a report received by the Department of Human Services alleges the existence of an immediate substantial risk of life threatening harm to an adult in need of protective services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>When an APS worker articulates to the police a basis for suspecting that an adult in need of protective services or the APS worker is in danger of bodily harm or violence from any source;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>When a court order has been issued which authorizes protective services and the APS worker articulates a basis for suspecting resistance to the court order or a threat to the APS worker or the client; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>When any other circumstances exist in which the police agree that police presence may be needed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2903.3.</num>
    <text>When a police officer believes that his or her presence is no longer necessary for the safe and effective performance of the duties of an APS worker, the police officer shall properly notify the APS worker before leaving the scene.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2903.4.</num>
    <text>If a police officer is in the company of an APS worker, and a situation arises which involves an immediate, substantial risk of life threatening harm to any person, it shall be the responsibility of the police officer to take such action as he or
      she believes appropriate to eliminate or control the risk.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2903.5.</num>
    <text>The APS worker shall curtail further action at the scene until the danger described in ยง 2903.4 has been eliminated or controlled.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2903.6.</num>
    <text>In the event that police action or the efforts of the APS worker are unable to resolve a life threatening situation, the APS worker shall immediately refer the matter to D.C. Corporation Counsel who shall immediately initiate appropriate Court proceedings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 6646, 6648 (October 19, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>