<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2801</num>
  <heading>PROCEDURES, FORMS AND REGISTRATION, GENERAL STATUTE REQUIREMENTS (§ 29-2801)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2801.1.</num>
    <text>Each form, certificate, and report constituting the system of vital records shall be filed and registered with the Registrar. Vital records are considered to be registered only upon acceptance of the document by the Registrar.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2801.2.</num>
    <text>Each form, certificate, and report used in the system of vital records is the property of the Department of Health and shall be surrendered to the Registrar upon demand.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2801.3.</num>
    <text>Each form prescribed and distributed by the Registrar for reporting vital events shall be used only for official purposes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2801.4.</num>
    <text>Only a form furnished or approved by the Registrar shall be used in the reporting or correcting of vital events.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2801.5.</num>
    <text>Each certificate and record relating to vital records shall be prepared in black type.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2801.6.</num>
    <text>Each signature required on a document filed with the Registrar shall be in black, unfading ink.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2801.7.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § 2801.08 or otherwise directed by the Registrar, a document shall be considered to be complete, and acceptable for registration if it meets the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Has the certifier’s name typed or printed legibly under his or her signature;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Includes each item of information requested on the form or satisfactorily accounts for its omission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Contains no alterations or erasures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Has original handwritten signatures, unless the document is submitted by electronic means pursuant to § 2801.8;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>May not be marked a “copy” or “duplicate”;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>May not be a carbon copy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Is prepared on required form;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Contains no improper or inconsistent data;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>In the case of death registration, it must state a definite cause of death and not only symptoms of disease or conditions resulting from disease; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Shall be prepared in conformity with these rules.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2801.8.</num>
    <text>Information that is properly transmitted to and received by the Registrar through electronic means shall be considered to be registered as of the date of transmission, provided that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Registrar has authorized the transmitting institution to transmit the information;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The electronic means by which the document is transmitted is secure within parameters the Registrar establishes in writing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Registrar acknowledges and verifies receipt of the information; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The transmitting institution subsequently files a properly completed original certificate with the Registrar.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 38 DCR 781 (January 25, 1991); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 9183 (September 24, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 1664 (February 23, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>