<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2350</num>
  <heading>SERVICES AND SUPPORTS[COLON] STANDARDS FOR CORE REQUIREMENTS &amp;#8212; CONTINUINGARE PLANS (§ 29-2350)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2350.1.</num>
    <text>A substance abuse treatment facility or program shall develop and implement policies and procedures to ensure continuity of care when developing continuing care plans for patient’s who will need additional treatment after discharge.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2350.2.</num>
    <text>A written continuing care plan shall be developed in partnership with the patient before discharge, when the need for treatment at a higher or lower level of service intensity is indicated by the patient’s progress or lack thereof, in meeting goals
      established in the rehabilitation plan. The plan shall be based on a review of the rehabilitation plan and an updated assessment to determine the appropriate placement for the patient to receive ongoing structured care.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2350.3.</num>
    <text>The facility or program shall facilitate arrangements for the patient to be admitted to an appropriate facility or program consistent with the assessed need.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2350.4.</num>
    <text>The continuing care plan shall be signed and dated by the patient and the counselor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2350.5.</num>
    <text>A copy of the continuing care plan shall be provided to the patient and added to the patient’s record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2350.6.</num>
    <text>The continuing care plan shall indicate the requirements that must be met for re-admission to the facility or program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2350.7.</num>
    <text>The facility or program shall accompany, transport or arrange transportation to the new facility or program for any patient in need.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2350.8.</num>
    <text>The facility or program shall follow up and document in the patient’s record confirmation of a successful referral or the patient’s failure to comply with the established plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9341 (November 24, 2000), adopting Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7708, 7776 (September 22, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>