<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2526</num>
  <heading>STI PROGRAM – APPLICATION AND ELIGIBILITY DETERMINATION (§ 29-2526)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2526.1.</num>
    <text>Application to the STI Program shall be made by a family at a family intake center. The application shall be in writing and shall be signed by the applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2526.2.</num>
    <text>To be eligible for the STI Program, an applicant shall meet the requirements set forth in subsection 2501.1 and shall meet the definition of a family, set forth in section 2599.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2526.3.</num>
    <text>In addition to meeting the eligibility requirements set forth in subsection 2501.2, participation in the STI Program is conditioned upon the applicant being willing and able to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Enter into a lease and comply with the terms of such lease;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Contribute up to thirty percent (30%) of his or her adjusted annual income toward the cost for housing, pursuant to section 2529;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Accept a unit that meets the program unit criteria set forth in section 2532;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Actively participate in case management and meet the case management requirements, as set forth in section 2511, in order to transition to more permanent housing; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Apply for all public benefits and housing assistance for which the applicant is eligible and as provided for in the applicant’s Service Plan, including applying for housing assistance from the District of Columbia Housing Authority.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 6438 (July 23, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice Emergency Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11353 (November 26, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergency Rulemaking published
        at 58 DCR 3007 (April 8, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 7442, 7473 (August 19, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>