<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2518</num>
  <heading>ADDITIONAL TEMPORARY SHELTER AND SUPPORTIVE HOUSING REQUIREMENTS (§ 29-2518)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2518.1</num>
    <text>2518.1 Providers of temporary shelter and supportive housing shall meet the requirements of sections 2515 through 2517, as well as the additional requirements set forth in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2518.2.</num>
    <text>Providers under this section shall ensure that an appropriately trained, qualified, and supervised case manager provides each client an assessment in order to identify each client’s service needs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2518.3.</num>
    <text>Providers under this section shall ensure direct provision of, or referral to, appropriate supportive services to enable the client to fulfill the goals and requirements in the client’s Service Plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2518.4.</num>
    <text>Providers under this section of programs in which clients do not have independent units shall provide mail and phone services, or procedures for handling mail and phone messages, that enable the client to receive mail and messages without identifying
      the client as residing in temporary shelter or supportive housing and that respect the client’s right to privacy in regards to their mail and telephone messages.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2518.5.</num>
    <text>Providers under this section in which clients do not have independent units shall provide private, secure space for the temporary storage of personal belongings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2518.6.</num>
    <text>Providers under this section shall provide access to laundry facilities in the immediate vicinity of the shelter or supportive housing facility when all of the units are in one location.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2518.7.</num>
    <text>Providers under this section in which clients do not have independent units shall provide reasonable access to phones during reasonable hours and during emergencies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2518.8.</num>
    <text>Providers under this section shall provide clients with the opportunity to establish a voluntary savings or escrow account. Providers may encourage clients, as part of the financial planning section of the client’s Service Plan, to establish a savings
      or escrow account based on the client’s individual circumstances and service goals.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2518.9.</num>
    <text>Providers of family shelter or supportive housing shall provide clients with access to immediate indoor or outdoor areas equipped with basic facilities for exercise and play for use by minor children.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 6438 (July 23, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice Emergency Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11353 (November 26, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergency Rulemaking published
        at 58 DCR 3007 (April 8, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 7442, 7460 (August 19, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>