<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2706</num>
  <heading>LIMITATIONS AND REQUIREMENTS FOR CERTAIN SERVICES (§ 29-2706)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2706.1</num>
    <text>2706.1 All claims submitted by participating providers shall only beeimbursed if they meet relevant quantity/day supply and refill limitationsstablished by DHCF and are available in the on-line provider manual atww.dcpbm.com.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2706.2</num>
    <text>2706.2 Prior authorization shall be required from the DHCF designatedharmacy Benefit Manager (PBM) for the following medications:</text>
    <text>Any drug listed as non-preferred on the District’s Medicaid Preferred Drugist;</text>
    <text>Any drug requiring medication therapy management; and</text>
    <text>Any drug requiring closer utilization monitoring.</text>
    <text>The drugs or classes of drugs listed in Section 1927(d)(2) of Title XIX of theocial Security Act (42 U.S.C. § 1396r-8(d)(2)) shall be excluded from coveragenless specifically placed, either individually or by drug class, on theedicaid Preferred Drug
      List of prior authorized drugs based on U.S. Food andrug Administration (FDA)-approved indications. The following categories ofedications shall be excluded from the Medicaid outpatient pharmacy benefit:</text>
    <text>A drug which has been issued a “less than effective” (LTE) rating by the FDAr a drug that is “identical, related or similar” to an LTE drug;</text>
    <text>A drug that has reached the termination date established by the druganufacturer;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A drug that the drug manufacturer has not entered into or has not compliedith a rebate agreement for in accordance with Section 1927(a) of Title XIX ofhe Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. § 1396r-8(a)), unless DHCF reviewed andetermined that it shall
        be in the best interest of a Medicaid beneficiary toake a payment for the non-rebated drug;</text>
    </level>
    <text>Weight loss;</text>
    <text>Fertility;</text>
    <text>Cosmetics;</text>
    <text>Non-prescription cough and cold;</text>
    <text>Non-prescription vitamin and mineral products;</text>
    <text>Erectile dysfunction; and</text>
    <text>Medicare Part D drugs for dual eligibles entitled to receive Medicare benefitsnder Medicare Part A or B.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 2298, 2303 (March 23,012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>