<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2305</num>
  <heading>CERTIFICATION &amp;#8212; RE-CERTIFICATION PROCEDURES (ยง 29-2305)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2305.1.</num>
    <text>A facility shall submit an application for re-certification to the Department at least ninety (90) calendar days prior to expiration of its certificate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2305.2.</num>
    <text>The Department may re-certify a facility or program pending satisfactory completion of an inspection conducted by the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2305.3.</num>
    <text>A facility or program shall provide written notice to the Department at least ninety (90) calendar days prior to the effective date of relocating, discontinuing a program service, or adding a program site.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2305.4.</num>
    <text>The Department, upon notification, may at its discretion require a reinspection and re-certification to ensure that the facility or program remains in compliance with the provisions of the Act, rules adopted pursuant to this chapter, and all other
      applicable provisions of law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2305.5.</num>
    <text>A transferee or his or her agent shall submit an application for re-certification to the Department. The Department may issue a certification to the transferee for the continued operation of the facility, at the same location, subject to an inspection
      for compliance with this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2305.6.</num>
    <text>The continued operation of a facility or program shall not be deemed unlawful if a completed application for re-certification was timely filed, but through no fault of the facility or program the Department failed to re-certify the applicant before
      its certification expired.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9341 (November 24, 2000), adopting Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7708, 7715 (September 22, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>