<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2901</num>
  <heading>REPORTING REQUIREMENTS OF THE METROPOLITAN POLICE DEPARTMENT (§ 29-2901)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2901.1.</num>
    <text>When the police receive information which provides substantial cause to believe that an adult is in need of protective services because of abuse, neglect, or exploitation by another, the appropriate police office shall immediately transmit an oral
      report to the Department of Human Services followed immediately by a written report.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2901.2.</num>
    <text>The report shall include, if known, the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name, age, physical description and location of each adult alleged to be in need of protective services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name and location of each person allegedly responsible for the abuse, neglect, or exploitation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The nature and extent of the abuse, neglect, or exploitation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The basis or source of the reporter’s knowledge;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any other information the reporter believes may be helpful to an investigation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The identity of the reporting officer; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The identity of the person to whom the report was made.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2901.3.</num>
    <text>In the event that information received by the police indicates that an adult in need of protective services or any other person is in immediate, substantial risk of life threatening harm or immediate police action is otherwise warranted, the police
      shall take such prompt action as the circumstances may require.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 6646 (October 19, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>