<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2817</num>
  <heading>AMENDMENT OF VITAL RECORDS, GENERAL (§ 29-2817)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2817.1.</num>
    <text>Only the Registrar may amend a vital record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2817.2.</num>
    <text>An amendment made by annotation shall be placed on the front lower margin of the record but may not obscure or alter the original entries in any way.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2817.3.</num>
    <text>Each amendment to a vital record shall be supported by each of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An affidavit setting forth:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Information that identifies the certificate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The data requiring amendment as it is listed on the certificate; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The data as it should appear; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>One (1) or more items of documentary evidence to support the alleged facts which were established at least five (5) years prior to the date of application for the amendment or within seven (7) years of the date of the event, as may be required by
        the Registrar.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2817.4.</num>
    <text>The Registrar may consider the order of a court outside of the District as evidence to support an amendment to a vital record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2817.5.</num>
    <text>The Registrar shall evaluate the evidence submitted in support of any requested amendment; and, if for any reason there is doubt of its validity or adequacy, the amendment may be rejected and the applicant advised of the reasons for that action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2817.6.</num>
    <text>A statement in a vital record which is medical in nature may only be amended upon receipt of a signed statement from the person who completed the statement. The Registrar may require documentary evidence to support the requested amendment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2817.7.</num>
    <text>A certificate of birth or death amended pursuant to these rules shall be amended by appending a change to the existing certificate. The amended certificate shall be marked “amended”.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2817.8.</num>
    <text>If an item of information on a vital record is amended the information shall not be amended again without an order of the court.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 38 DCR 781, 794 (January 25, 1991).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>