<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2503</num>
  <heading>INTAKE FOR LOW BARRIER SHELTER FOR INDIVIDUAL ADULTS (ยง 29-2503)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2503.1.</num>
    <text>Intake for low barrier shelter for individual adults shall consist of an eligibility determination and placement in a shelter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2503.2.</num>
    <text>An individual adult applicant shall apply directly to and be determined eligible for low barrier shelter by the Provider from whom the individual is seeking services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2503.3.</num>
    <text>Placement of eligible applicants in a specific low barrier shelter shall be on a first come, first served basis, except as provided for in subsections 2503.4 and 2503.5.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2503.4.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection 2503.3, low barrier shelters may allow clients who stayed at the shelter the previous night to enter the shelter first. Admittance of returning clients, however, shall be completed within one half (1/2) hour of the start
      time of admittance and followed directly by first come, first served admittance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2503.5.</num>
    <text>In addition to the returning client exception set forth in subsection 2503.3, low barrier shelters may also make an exception to the first come, first served policy for persons who have difficulty meeting the intake time due to work, a medical appointment,
      or other necessary obligation. Providers shall give notice to clients of the procedures the client must comply with in order to receive this exception in the shelter Program Rules. Providers shall limit the number of exceptions that are granted
      to ensure that the substantial majority of beds remain available for clients not receiving this exception.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2503.6</num>
    <text>2503.6 If an applicant to a low barrier shelter is determined eligible, but there is no available space in the shelter, the shelter may arrange transportation to another appropriate shelter that has available space.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2503.7.</num>
    <text>A Provider of low barrier shelter may fill a bed or unit allocated to an individual who leaves the facility for more than thirty (30) minutes after lights out. If the individual later returns to the shelter and the original bed was given to another
      individual, the Provider shall give the individual another bed. If no bed is available, the Provider may arrange transportation for the individual to a low barrier shelter with an available bed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 470, 474 (January 24, 1992); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 6438 (July 23, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice Emergency Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11353 (November
        26, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergency Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 3007 (April 8, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 7442, 7444 (August 19, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>