<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2321</num>
  <heading>ADMINISTRATIVE SERVICES[COLON] HEALTH AND SAFETY MANAGEMENT &amp;#8212; EMERGENCYREPAREDNESS PLAN (ยง 29-2321)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2321.1.</num>
    <text>A facility or program shall have an emergency preparedness plan. The plan shall address:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Medical emergencies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Natural emergencies, such as earthquakes, severe storms, tornados or floods;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Power failures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Hazardous environmental conditions such as, excessively high or low temperatures, chemical exposure, unusual fumes, and gas leaks.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Fires;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Behavioral crises, such as, bomb threats, terrorist threats, other workplace threats and acts of violence;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Abuse or neglect of patients or staff;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Injury or death of patients or staff; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Arrest or detention of patients or staff in the facility or program.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2321.2.</num>
    <text>Each facility or program shall orient staff to the emergency preparedness plan by doing the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Reviewing the emergency preparedness plan with all staff at least annually;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Conducting annual drills;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Addressing the use and function of the fire alarm and the detection system, notification of authorities and the protection of lives including evacuation plans and fire extinguisher;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Posting evacuation routes; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Notifying staff of any changes in the plan.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9341 (November 24, 2000), adopting Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7708, 7731 (September 22, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>