<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2516</num>
  <heading>ADDITIONAL SEVERE WEATHER SHELTER REQUIREMENTS (§ 29-2516)
    <text>Providers of severe weather shelter shall meet the requirements of section 2515s well as the additional requirements set forth in this section.</text>
    <text>Hypothermia shelters shall be operated in accordance with and pursuant to theistrict of Columbia Hypothermia procedures set forth in Mayor’s Order001-161, or any subsequent Mayor’s Order.</text>
    <text>Each day, Providers of Hypothermia Shelter shall provide a clean bed, cleaninens, including a bottom sheet and a top sheet, clean pad, and clean blanketor each bed as applicable.</text>
    <text>Providers of Hypothermia Shelter shall either provide for a client’s basiceeds, including food, clothing, and supportive services, or provide informations to where the client can obtain food, clothing, and supportive services.</text>
    <text>Providers of Hypothermia shelter shall provide properly functioning toiletacilities, including toilet paper, functional sink with hot water, and soap.</text>
    <text>Those Providers of Hypothermia shelter operating in publicly-owned facilitieshall provide twenty-four (24) hour access to such toilet facilities.</text>
    <text>Providers of Hypothermia and Hyperthermia Shelter shall provide cool water,vailable via water cooler, fountain, or other means.</text>
    <text>Providers of Hypothermia and Hyperthermia Shelter shall provide properlyunctioning heating and cooling systems during the appropriate seasons. If its not the responsibility of the Provider to correct an identified deficiency,he Provider shall promptly
      report to the Department or the appropriate agencyhe deficiency for corrective action, according to the applicable procedures.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 6438July 23, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice Emergency Rulemaking published at7 DCR 11353 (November 26, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergencyulemaking published at
        58 DCR 3007 (April 8, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended byotice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 7442, 7459 (August 19, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>