<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-375</num>
  <heading>REQUIREMENTS FOR INFANT SOLID FOOD (ยง 29-375)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>375.1.</num>
    <text>Each Child Development Facility shall comply with the following requirements concerning infant solid food:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Each solid food provided to an infant shall be served according to written instructions, which specify the amount(s) and type(s) of food and feeding times, that are requested and obtained by the Facility from the parent(s) or guardian(s) of that
        child or from the child&amp;#8217;s licensed health care practitioner.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Each container of infant food that is provided to the Facility by the parent(s) or guardian(s) of a child for feeding to that child shall be labeled with the child&amp;#8217;s first and last name and the date of receipt;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Each container of infant food shall be refrigerated immediately upon its arrival at the Facility, with the exception of unopened containers of commercially prepared bottled or canned food that may be stored at room temperature until opened;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The uneaten portion of any container of infant food shall be immediately refrigerated, and may not be held for further consumption for longer than two (2) days; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>If the Facility fails to obtain adequate written feeding instructions from the parent(s) or guardian(s) of a particular child, the Facility shall serve the infant breast milk, formula and/or food in sufficient amounts to meet the current Recommended
        Dietary Allowances (&amp;#8220;RDA&amp;#8221;) or Dietary Reference Intakes (&amp;#8220;DRI&amp;#8221;) as specified by the Food and Nutrition Board of the Institute of Medicine, National Academy of Sciences.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 003793 (April 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>