<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-3299</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 29-3299)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3299.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms shall have the meaning ascribed below:</text>
    <text>Abuse &amp;#8211; the infliction of physical or mental harm on a nursing home resident.</text>
    <text>Cooperating agency &amp;#8211; an agency, other than the training facility which is utilized in providing learning experiences for nurse aide trainees.</text>
    <text>Department &amp;#8211; the Department of Health.</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; the Director of the Department of Health, or his or her designee.</text>
    <text>District &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Facility &amp;#8211; a licensed nursing home in the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>LTCA &amp;#8211; the Department of Health.</text>
    <text>Misappropriation &amp;#8211; to apply wrongfully or dishonestly to one&amp;#8217;s own an item or money belonging to a nursing home resident.</text>
    <text>Neglect &amp;#8211; to fail to carry out or perform, or to be remiss in the care or treatment of a nursing home resident.</text>
    <text>Nurse aide &amp;#8211; an individual, who as a result of training and demonstrated competencies, provides nursing or nursing related services to residents in a nursing facility. This definition does not include an individual who volunteers to provide
      such services without pay, but does include individuals who are hired by residents and their families to provide care to residents in a nursing facility and includes nurse aides supplied by an agency as well as those actually employed by the facility.</text>
    <text>Nurse Aide Abuse Registry &amp;#8211; a permanent record containing names of individuals who worked as nurse aides and were determined to have abused or neglected a resident or misappropriated a nursing home resident&amp;#8217;s property.</text>
    <text>Nurse Aide Registry &amp;#8211; a listing of names of individuals who have met the criteria for certification in the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Nurse aide trainee &amp;#8211; an individual enrolled in a District approved nurse aide training program.</text>
    <text>Nursing home administrator &amp;#8211; the licensed person responsible for planning, organizing, directing, and controlling the operation of a nursing facility licensed in the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Pass rate &amp;#8211; percentage of first time candidates who receive a passing score on the competency evaluation.</text>
    <text>Registry &amp;#8211; the Nurse Aide Registry.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking Published at 38 DCR 2008 (April 5, 1991); as amended by Final Rulemaking Published at 49 DCR 3696 (April 19, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>