<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-348</num>
  <heading>STAFFING AND GROUP SIZE FOR OUT-OF-SCHOOL-TIME PROGRAMS (ยง 29-348)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>348.1.</num>
    <text>Each group in a Child Development Center that provides out-of-school-time care shall be supervised by at least two (2) adults at all times.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>348.2.</num>
    <text>Each group containing one or more children eleven (11) years of age or younger shall be supervised by, at a minimum, a group leader and an assistant group leader. A group containing children all of whom are twelve (12) years of age and older may be
      occasionally supervised by a volunteer in addition to the group leader, provided that the volunteer is at least two (2) years older than the oldest child in the group.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>348.3.</num>
    <text>The group sizes and adult/child ratios specified in section 343 of this Chapter shall apply to out-of-school-time care programs, except as specified further in this section. For the purpose of achieving the required ratio for any group, the Facility
      may count all staff members, including those who meet the qualifications of Center Director, group leader and assistant group leader, provided that each such staff member is so counted only for the time that he or she is directly caring for that
      group of children.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>348.4.</num>
    <text>The Director may approve reasonable variations to the prescribed group size limitations for a facility, including flexible groupings and sub-groupings, taking into consideration the following areas:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Qualifications and numbers of staff and volunteers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Program structure and focus;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Ages and developmental levels of children served;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Usable space; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The Facility&amp;#8217;s past history of compliance</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>348.5.</num>
    <text>The Facility shall have a written staffing plan to ensure the supervision of all enrolled children at all times. If written approval is obtained from the Director, the staffing plan may permit different levels of supervision at different times, consistent
      with the level of risk involved in each activity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>348.6.</num>
    <text>The Facility shall ensure that its staff members keep each enrolled child within continuous visual and hearing range at all times when the child is in the care of the facility, both on the facility premises and elsewhere. When a child uses the toilet,
      the staff shall supervise with appropriate respect for the child&amp;#8217;s privacy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 003793 (April 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>