<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-307</num>
  <heading>FEES (ยง 29-307)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>307.1.</num>
    <text>License fees for Child Development Facilities shall vary in accordance with the Facility&amp;#8217;s license capacity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>307.2.</num>
    <text>Each applicant for a license to operate a Child Development Center shall pay an initial application/pre-licensure inspection fee, in the amount of $75.00.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>307.3.</num>
    <text>The initial license fee, annual renewal license fee, and license replacement fee for each Child Development Facility shall be as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <text>Child Development Homes</text>
    <text>$ 75.00</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <text>Child Development Centers, 1 &amp;#8211; 50 Children</text>
    <text>$200.00</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <text>Child Development Centers, 51 &amp;#8211; 100 Children</text>
    <text>$300.00</text>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <text>Child Development Centers, 101 &amp;#8211; 175 Children</text>
    <text>$400.00</text>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <text>Child Development Centers, Over 175 Children</text>
    <text>$500.00</text>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <text>Replacement of License (all facilities)</text>
    <text>$ 25.00</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>307.4.</num>
    <text>Facilities operated by the District of Columbia Government shall not be required to pay a fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>307.5.</num>
    <text>The Director may make reasonable adjustment to license fees, as appropriate; a new fee schedule shall be published by the Director at least thirty (30) days before any new fee is implemented.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>307.6.</num>
    <text>A fee shall be paid whenever there is a required amendment to a license, including a change of ownership or a change of address.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>307.7.</num>
    <text>A fee payment submitted with an application shall not be transferred to any other application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>307.8.</num>
    <text>Fee payment is non-refundable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>307.9.</num>
    <text>A late fee, in the amount of $25.00 for Child Development Homes and $50.00 for Child Development Centers, shall be imposed if a license renewal application is not timely filed as specified in subsection 308.1 of this Chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 74-34 published at 21 DCR 1333 (December 27, 1974); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 3793 (April 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>