<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-304</num>
  <heading>CERTIFICATE OF OCCUPANCY AND HOME OCCUPATION PERMIT (ยง 29-304)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>304.1.</num>
    <text>Before applying for a license, each Child Development Facility shall secure a Certificate of Occupancy or Home Occupation Permit for the premises, or equivalent proof that the premises comply with all applicable federal and District of Columbia fire,
      safety, building, and zoning regulations and codes. The Certificate, Permit, or other proof shall include certification that the premises are fit and suitable for the operation of a Child Development Facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>304.2.</num>
    <text>A new or revised Certificate of Occupancy, Home Occupation permit, or equivalent proof as noted in subsection 304.1 shall be required:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Upon initial application for a license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>At the time of any major modification or alteration of any existing premises or structure used by the Facility, but prior to the continued use of the modified or altered portions of the premises or structure for child development purposes; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Prior to the use of any portion of the premises or structure that was not previously inspected and approved for use as a Child Development Facility.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>304.3.</num>
    <text>In the case of a Facility providing out-of-school-time care only, located in a District of Columbia government building exempt from Certificate of Occupancy requirements, the requirements of this section may be met by providing, in lieu of the Certificate
      of Occupancy, a Building Use Agreement executed by the Facility and the District of Columbia government agency with responsibility for that building, including a certification from said government agency that it assumes responsibility for the maintenance
      and safety of the premises in which the Facility is located.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 003793 (April 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>