<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-399</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 29-399)
    <text>For the purposes of this Chapter, the term:</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Act&amp;#8221; means the Child Development Facilities Regulation Act of 1998,ffective April 13, 1999, D.C. Law 12-215, D.C. Official Code §§ 7-2031 eteq.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Abuse&amp;#8221; means the physical or mental injury of a child by a parent,uardian or custodian, under circumstances that indicate that the child&amp;#8217;sealth or welfare is significantly harmed or at risk of being significantlyarmed.
      Abuse includes sexual abuse of a child, whether or not physical injuriesre sustained.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Adult&amp;#8221; means a person who is eighteen (18) years of age or older.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Americans with Disabilities Act&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;ADA&amp;#8221; means the lawhat requires that persons with disabilities not be denied public accommodationshat are designed to afford them the opportunity to participate in programs
      orctivities that are not separate or different. (P.L. 101-336; 104 Stat. 327; 42.S.C. 12101 et seq.).</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Associate Caregiver&amp;#8221; means an individual who provides care in anxpanded Child Development Home and who is subordinate to the Primary Caregiver;his person need not reside in the dwelling where the Facility is located.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;CDA&amp;#8221; means Child Development Associate, a credential obtained underhe award system of the Council for Professional Recognition.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;CPR&amp;#8221; means cardiopulmonary resuscitation.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Care by a Related Person&amp;#8221; means care of a child by thathild&amp;#8217;s parent, step-parent, grandparent, brother, sister, step-brother,tep-sister, uncle, or aunt, said relationship having been established by blood,arriage, or
      adoption, or by that child&amp;#8217;s legal guardian.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Caregiver&amp;#8221; means an individual who is in charge of, and responsibleor the direct care, supervision, and guidance of, children in a Childevelopment Home or Expanded Child Development Home.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Center Director&amp;#8221; means a Child Development Center staff member whos in charge of the day-to-day operations of the Center.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Change in Ownership&amp;#8221; means a transfer of controlling legal orquitable interest and authority resulting from a sale or merger.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Child&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;Children&amp;#8221; means an individual or individualsrom birth to fifteen (15) years of age, except when &amp;#8220;infant/s&amp;#8221;nd/or &amp;#8220;toddler/s&amp;#8221; are specified within the same provision,
      in whichase &amp;#8220;child&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;children&amp;#8221; means an individual orndividuals from two (2) to fifteen (15) years of age.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Child Development Center&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;Center&amp;#8221; means a Childevelopment Facility located in premises other than a dwelling occupied by theperator of the Facility.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Child Development Facility&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;Facility&amp;#8221; means aenter, home, or other structure that provides care and other services,upervision and guidance for children, infants, and toddlers on a regular basis,egardless
      of its designated name &amp;#8220;Child Development Facility&amp;#8221;ncludes &amp;#8220;Child Development Home,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Expanded Child Developmentome,&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;Child Development Center.&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Childevelopment
      Facility&amp;#8221; does not include a public or private elementary orecondary school engaged in legally required educational and related functions.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Child Development Home&amp;#8221; means a Child Development Facility locatedn a private dwelling occupied by the operator of the Facility. &amp;#8220;Childevelopment Home&amp;#8221; also includes those Facilities classified as#8220;Expanded
      Child Development Home&amp;#8221;.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Department&amp;#8221;, unless otherwise specified, means the Department ofealth or its successor agency, acting by and through its Director or his or heresignee.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Director&amp;#8221; means the Director of the Department of Health or of itsuccessor agency.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;District of Columbia Director Credential&amp;#8221; means a credentialwarded by or under the auspices of the District of Columbia Department of Humanervices Early Care and Education Administration, or its successor agency, uponatisfactory
      completion of a program of classroom study and practicum experiencen fields of study directly related to the operation and administration of Childevelopment Facilities.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Expanded Child Development Home&amp;#8221; means a Child Development Home inhich child care is provided by two (2) or more Caregivers for up to twelve (12)hildren.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Facility&amp;#8221; means Child Development Facility.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Fever&amp;#8221; means a temperature of one hundred degrees Fahrenheit (100°) or higher if taken under the arm, one hundred and one degrees Fahrenheit101° F) if taken orally, or one hundred and two degrees Fahrenheit (102 ° F)f taken rectally.
      For children under the age of four (4) months, a fever is aemperature of one hundred and one degrees Fahrenheit (101°) or higher taken byny method.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Guardian&amp;#8221; means a person, other than the child&amp;#8217;s parent, whoas been granted legal authority over and responsibility for a child.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Hour&amp;#8221; means, when used in the context of training and/or continuingducation, &amp;#8220;clock hour&amp;#8221; as that term is defined and used in thecademic and educational fields.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Infant&amp;#8221; means a child younger than twelve (12) months of age.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Licensed Health Care Practitioner&amp;#8221; means a Physician, aurse-Practitioner (also known as an Advanced Practice Registered Nurse), or ahysician&amp;#8217;s Assistant licensed to practice health care by the D.C. Boardf Medicine or
      Board of Nursing, or by a comparable body in another state.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Licensee&amp;#8221; means a Child Development Facility licensed pursuant tohis Chapter, or the operator of such a Facility.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Neglect&amp;#8221; means the failure to provide care, services andupervision necessary to avoid physical harm or mental anguish.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Non-Ambulatory Child&amp;#8221; means a child who is: (1) unable to leave auilding under emergency conditions without assistance; (2) unable to walkorward or backward without assistance; (3) unable to go up or down stepsithout assistance;
      or (4) dependent upon mechanical aids such as crutches,alkers or wheelchairs.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Non-peak hours&amp;#8221; means: for programs operating during traditionalaytime hours, before 9:00 a.m. and after 4:00 p.m.; and for programs operatingutside of traditional daytime hours, time periods as specified in writing to,nd accepted
      by, the Director.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Out-of-school-time Care&amp;#8221; means care and other services, supervisionnd guidance provided to one or more children of legal school age and under thege of fifteen (15) years, who are enrolled in public, private, or charterchools,
      before and after normal school hours.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Parent&amp;#8221; means the mother or father of a child, by blood, adoption,oster care placement, or appointment as legal guardian or custodian of thathild by a court of competent jurisdiction.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Preschool&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;Preschooler&amp;#8221; refers to a child olderhan twenty-four (24) months of age but younger than compulsory schoolttendance age, and who is not enrolled in a public, charter, or private school.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Primary Caregiver&amp;#8221; means an individual who operates an Expandedhild Development Home and who is in charge of the day-to-day operations of theome; this person must reside in the dwelling where the Facility is located.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Special Needs&amp;#8221; means conditions or characteristics of a person thateflect a need for particular care, services or treatment, most commonlyhysical and/or mental disabilities and/or delays.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Staff&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;Staff Member&amp;#8221; means an adult who rendershild care or related services directly to a Child Development Facility, whetherompensated or uncompensated. &amp;#8220;Staff&amp;#8221;&amp;#8216; includes
      paid employeesnd volunteers.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Toddler&amp;#8221; means an individual older than twelve (12) months butounger than twenty-four (24) months of age.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Unusual Incident&amp;#8221; means any accident, injury, or otherxtraordinary event that involves a child in care, a staff member, or theperation of a Child Development Facility, including suspected childaltreatment or abuse.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Volunteer&amp;#8221; means a person rendering services to a Child Developmentacility without compensation by the Facility, including a person so renderingervices as part of an internship or otherwise under the auspices of anducational or
      training program.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 74-34 published at 21 DCR 1333 (December 27, 1974); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 3793 (April 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>