<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-361</num>
  <heading>TOILETS AND SINKS (ยง 29-361)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>361.1.</num>
    <text>Each Child Development Center serving preschoolers shall provide at least one (1) flush toilet and one (1) sink for every ten (10) occupants of the Facility, including staff.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>361.2.</num>
    <text>Each Center providing out-of-school-time care to school-age children shall provide at least one (1) flush toilet and one (1) sink for every twenty (20) occupants of the Facility, including staff.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>361.3.</num>
    <text>Urinals may be substituted for flush toilets in Centers in a ratio of two (2) urinals to (1) flush toilet, provided that at least two-thirds (2/3) of the required number of flush toilets are maintained.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>361.4.</num>
    <text>Each Center shall provide bathroom facilities for use by adults separately from those for use by children and/or infants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>361.5.</num>
    <text>If any toilet or sink in a Child Development Facility is too high to be used by one or more enrolled children without assistance, the Facility shall provide a block or step for the child or children&amp;#8217;s use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>361.6.</num>
    <text>Each Facility shall provide toilet training chairs and/or seats, at the discretion of the Facility, for use by any child or children who require them. Training chairs shall be emptied promptly and sanitized after each use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>361.7.</num>
    <text>Each Facility shall provide soap and single-use paper towels in each bathroom.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 74-34 published at 21 DCR 1333 (December 27, 1974); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 3793 (April 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>