<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-325</num>
  <heading>CHILDREN&amp;#8217;S HEALTH RECORDS (§ 29-325)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>325.1.</num>
    <text>Each child attending a Child Development Facility shall, upon enrollment and prior to admission, submit to the Facility, on forms approved by the Mayor, complete documentation of a comprehensive physical health examination, including age- appropriate
      screenings and up-to-date immunizations, and, for each child three (3) years of age or older, complete documentation of an oral health examination, each examination having been performed by a licensed health care professional within one (1) year
      prior to the date of admission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>325.2.</num>
    <text>Each child attending a Child Development Facility shall, at least annually, submit to the Facility, on forms approved by the Mayor, complete documentation of a comprehensive physical health examination, including age-appropriate screenings and up-to-date
      immunizations, and, for each child three (3) years of age or older, complete documentation of an oral health examination, each examination having been performed by a licensed health care professional within the preceding one (1) year period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>325.3.</num>
    <text>The Facility shall maintain, for each enrolled child, the initial and annual health record documentation required under subsections 325.1 and 325.2, including:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The full name, gender, date of birth, and home address of the child;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The dates of the physical and oral health examinations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The child&amp;#8217;s height and weight at the time of the physical health examination;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Each licensed health care practitioner&amp;#8217;s clinical findings, concerns, and recommendations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The child&amp;#8217;s significant health history, including allergies, health conditions, communicable illness, and restrictions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Specific immunizations received by month, day and year;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Results of tuberculosis exposure risk assessment, and of testing where indicated;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Results of lead exposure risk assessment, and of testing in accordance with subsections 325.4 and 325.5;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Identification of long-term medications and special health care requirements or accommodations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>The name, address, phone number and signature of the examining licensed health care practitioner.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>325.4.</num>
    <text>In addition to the information otherwise required under this section, each child under six (6) years of age attending a Child Development Facility shall submit, and the Facility shall maintain, documentation of the following with respect to blood
      tests for lead poisoning:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Proof that the child was tested between the ages of six (6) months and nine (9) months, and again between the ages of twenty-two (22) months and twenty-six (26) months; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Proof that, if the child was not tested before the age of twenty-six (26) months, the child was or will be tested two (2) times before the age of six (6) years, having been or intending to be tested at intervals at least twelve (12) months apart,
        or according to a schedule determined by the child&amp;#8217;s licensed health care practitioner; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Proof that lead testing for the child complies with any applicable Federal or District of Columbia law or rule that requires lead testing for children under the age of six (6) years.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>325.5.</num>
    <text>Blood tests for lead poisoning shall be conducted, and results shall be disseminated and maintained, in accordance with the Childhood Lead Poisoning Screening and Reporting Act of 2002, effective October 1, 2002 (D.C. Law 14-190, D.C. Official Code
      §§ 7-1031 et seq.)</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 74-34 published at 21 DCR 1333 (December 27, 1974); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 3793 (April 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>