<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-327</num>
  <heading>ADMINISTRATIVE RECORDS ON STAFF OF ALL FACILITIES AND ON PERSONS RESIDING INOME FACILITIES (ยง 29-327)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>327.1.</num>
    <text>Each Facility shall maintain, on the Facility premises, the following information for each employee:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The full name, gender, social security number, date of birth and home address;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Position title and job description;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Documentation and results of criminal and background history checks in accordance with this Chapter and with all other applicable federal and District of Columbia laws and rules;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A copy of the employee&amp;#8217;s resume, required degrees, certificates, transcripts, and letters of reference;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Verification of the employee&amp;#8217;s orientation to his/her duties and responsibilities and to the Facility&amp;#8217;s policies and procedures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>An ongoing record of continuing education;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>First Aid and CPR Certification for children, as required;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Date of appointment to, or withdrawal from, any position in the Facility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Reason for withdrawal from a position; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>A copy of the employee&amp;#8217;s signature.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>327.2.</num>
    <text>The Facility shall maintain a health record for each staff member, including paid employees and volunteers, which shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Results of a pre-employment physical examination of the staff member by a licensed health care practitioner, not more than twelve (12) months prior to the start of employment or volunteer work;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Results of an annual physical examination of the staff member by a licensed health care practitioner;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Written and signed documentation from the examining licensed health care practitioner that the staff member, at the time of his or her examination, was free from tuberculosis and apparent communicable disease;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Written and signed documentation from the examining licensed health care practitioner that the staff member, if noted to have an identified medical problem, is capable of caring for children in a licensed Child Development Facility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Health insurance information, if applicable; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The names and phone numbers of the staff member&amp;#8217;s primary licensed health care practitioner and of an emergency contact person.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>327.3.</num>
    <text>Each Child Development Home shall obtain and maintain documentation establishing that each person living in the home that houses the Facility has been, within the preceding one (1) year period, examined by a licensed health care professional and certified
      by that professional to be free of communicable disease.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 74-34 published at 21 DCR 1333 (December 27, 1974); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 3793 (April 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>