<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-300</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 29-300)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>300.1.</num>
    <text>This Chapter is promulgated pursuant to the Child Development Facilities Regulation Act of 1998, effective April 13, 1999 (D.C. Law 12-215, D.C. Official Code §§ 7-2031 et seq.) (hereinafter &amp;#8220;the Act&amp;#8221;).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>300.2.</num>
    <text>The purpose of this Chapter is to protect the health, safety and well-being of children in licensed Child Development Facilities and to ensure the provision of developmentally appropriate programs to those children.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>300.3.</num>
    <text>Unless specifically exempted, the provisions of the Act and of this Chapter shall apply to every Caregiver and Child Development Facility, regardless of the name by which the Facility is designated.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>300.4.</num>
    <text>A listing of licensed Facilities shall be maintained by the Department of Health and shall be made available to the public upon request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>300.5.</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise specified herein, each Child Development Facility that is licensed on the effective date of these rules shall have a period of one (1) year from the effective date of these rules to comply with any requirement contained within
      this Chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for the enactment of this chapter was set forth in section 7 of the Child Development Facilities Regulation Act of 1998 effective April 13, 1999, D.C. Law 12-215, D.C. Official Code § 7-2036, and in accordance
        with Mayor’s Order 2000-124, dated August 3, 2000.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 74-34 published at 21 DCR 1333 (December 27, 1974) and D.C. Act 12-156 published at 44 DCR 6044 (October 17, 1997); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 3793 (April 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>