<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-321</num>
  <heading>NOTICE REQUIREMENTS FOR CHANGES IN OPERATION (ยง 29-321)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>321.1.</num>
    <text>Each Facility shall inform the Director, in writing, of any of the following planned changes in operation no less than ten (10) days before implementation of the change(s):</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Change of ownership;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Change in location, name and/or telephone number of the Facility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Renovation or alteration of the premises that substantially changes the indoor or outdoor space of the Facility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>In the case of a Child Development Home, the inclusion of an additional member in the household, including the new member&amp;#8217;s criminal history, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>In the case of a Child Development Home, a change in primary Caregiver(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>In the case of a Child Development Center, a change in Center Director; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A significant change in the operation of the program, including, but not limited to, hours of operation, services provided, and capacity load.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>321.2.</num>
    <text>If a Facility undergoes any of the changes in operation listed in subsection 321.1 without the change being planned in advance, the Facility shall notify the Director immediately.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>321.3.</num>
    <text>Upon notification of the proposed change(s), the Director may inspect the Facility to evaluate the impact of the change(s) on the provision of child development services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>321.4.</num>
    <text>The Director shall issue an amended license, consistent with the approved change(s), as required by and subject to the provisions of this Chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 74-34 published at 21 DCR 1333 (December 27, 1974), as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 3793 (April 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>