<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-342</num>
  <heading>OUTDOOR SPACE, EQUIPMENT AND SAFETY IN CENTERS (ยง 29-342)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>342.1.</num>
    <text>Each Child Development Facility serving infants, toddlers, and preschoolers shall provide suitable space for outdoor play. This play space shall be in an enclosed yard on the Facility premises, in a nearby park or playground, or in a rooftop play
      space that meets the requirements of this Chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>342.2.</num>
    <text>The Facility shall maintain the outdoor play space so that it is free of conditions that are, or might be, hazardous to the health and/or safety of children.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>342.3.</num>
    <text>Each Facility shall provide a minimum of sixty square feet (60 ft2) of outdoor play space per child, based on the maximum number of children scheduled to play outdoors at any one time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>342.4.</num>
    <text>All outdoor play spaces shall comply with the requirements of the District of Columbia Building Code, and with the Facility&amp;#8217;s Certificate of Occupancy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>342.5.</num>
    <text>The Facility shall comply with the adult/child ratios listed in section 343 of this Chapter at all times when children are going to, using, or leaving the outdoor play space.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>342.6.</num>
    <text>The Facility shall ensure that staff, while supervising a group of children in the outdoor play space, are able to summon another adult staff member if the need arises, without leaving the children unsupervised at any time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>342.7.</num>
    <text>The Facility shall ensure that the outdoor play space is supervised by adult staff in sufficient quantity and appropriate placement to ensure that all children are within sight and hearing of at least one staff member at all times.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 74-34 published at 21 DCR 1333 (December 27, 1974); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 3793 (April 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>