<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-306</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION FOR AN INITIAL LICENSE (§ 29-306)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>306.1.</num>
    <text>Each applicant, or person(s) designated by the applicant to represent the proposed Facility, shall attend an orientation program sponsored by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>306.2.</num>
    <text>Each application, accompanied by the appropriate fee(s), if any, shall be submitted on a form approved by the Director at least ninety (90) days prior to the date of proposed initiation of operations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>306.3.</num>
    <text>Each application shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Certificate of Occupancy, Home Occupation Permit, or other proof pursuant to subsection 304.1;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name(s) and address(es) of the person or persons making the application; or, in the case of a corporation or association, the tax identification number of the entity and the names and addresses of at least three primary officers, directors,
        or partners;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the individual designated by the applicant to be the Caregiver or Center Director of the Facility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The qualifications of the individual designated by the applicant to be the Caregiver or Center Director of the Facility, as described in sections 332 and 352 of this Chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Proof that the applicant, or in the case of an entity, all principal owners or operators thereof, and that the person designated by the applicant to be the Caregiver or Center Director of the Facility, have undergone the required background checks
        and obtained the required clearances pursuant to section 328 of this Chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The address of the premises to be used as the licensed Facility, plus a description of all structures and facilities making up the premises;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The name by which the Facility will be known;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The name(s) and address(es) of the owner(s) of the building(s) that will house the Facility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The proposed capacity, hours of operation, ages of children served and services to be provided;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>A program statement, which shall include the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A description of the educational and developmental philosophy to be followed at the Facility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A description of the curriculum to be implemented;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A description of the policy regarding discipline, including the policy regarding withdrawal and termination of children for disciplinary reasons;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A typical daily schedule of activities for each age group of children to be served;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A statement describing the provision of meals and snacks;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A general contingency plan for emergencies; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Proof of compliance with the Clean Hands Before Receiving a License or Permit Act of 1996, effective May 11, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-118, D.C. Official Code §§ 47-2861 et seq.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Certification that the Facility is free of lead-based paint hazards;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Proof of liability insurance, with additional coverage if the Facility provides transportation services to the enrolled children; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Such other reasonable information that the Director may require in order to determine whether the applicant is qualified to operate a Child Development Facility that conforms to the provisions of the Act and of this Chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 003793(April 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>