<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-417</num>
  <heading>PUBLIC HEARINGS (ยง 29-417)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>417.1.</num>
    <text>If requested by one (1) or more persons directly affected by the review, the SHPDA or SHCC shall conduct a public hearing in the course of the review.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>417.2.</num>
    <text>A request for a public hearing shall be made in writing and received by the SHPDA within five (5) calendar days after notification of the start of the review period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>417.3.</num>
    <text>No fees shall be imposed for holding a public hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>417.4.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, the definition of the phrase &amp;#8220;persons directly affected by the review&amp;#8221; shall be the same as the definition used in applicable federal regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>417.5.</num>
    <text>The SHPDA may elect to convene a public hearing on its own initiative during the review period to offer an opportunity for any person to provide information, opinion, or testimony. However, it shall not hold a separate hearing if an affected person
      makes a request on the same application. One (1) hearing shall suffice as long as proper notification is given in accordance with procedures set forth in this chapter and all persons have an opportunity to present testimony at the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>417.6.</num>
    <text>Notification to affected persons shall be made through written notice. Notification to the general public shall be placed in two (2) newspapers of general circulation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>417.7.</num>
    <text>Persons interested in presenting testimony shall notify the SHPDA in writing at least two (2) days prior to the scheduled hearing to register for the presentation of oral or written testimony. However, any person shall be allowed the opportunity to
      present testimony, regardless of pre-registration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>417.8.</num>
    <text>Written testimony and comments shall be received by SHPDA not later than the close of the hearing or by a later time established by the hearing officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>417.9.</num>
    <text>All comments and testimony presented at the public hearing shall become a part of the general record and shall be made available to the public for inspection and copying upon request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 1086 (March 13, 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>