<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4304</num>
  <heading>PROVIDER QUALIFICATIONS (ยง 29-4304)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4304.1.</num>
    <text>Each provider shall furnish the necessary personnel, facilities, equipment, material and supplies to perform comprehensive breast and cervical cancer treatment services as required pursuant to these rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4304.2.</num>
    <text>Each provider shall have a demonstrated ability to comply with all District and federal laws and rules governing participation of providers in the District of Columbia Medicaid Program, including the ability to meet all District and federal requirements
      for documentation, billing and audits.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4304.3.</num>
    <text>Each provider shall comply with the requirements set forth in the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revisions Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code ยง 3-1201 et seq) or comply with the licensure requirements
      to provide health or medical services in the jurisdiction where the services are rendered.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4304.4.</num>
    <text>Each provider shall establish and adhere to policies and procedures for selecting and hiring staff, including but not limited to requiring:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Evidence of licensure, certification or registration required by the job being performed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For unlicensed staff, evidence of completion of an appropriate degree, training program or credentials;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Appropriate references and background checks; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Evidence of completion of communicable disease testing and immunization as required by District laws and rules.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4304.5.</num>
    <text>Each provider shall comply with all applicable provisions of District and federal law and rules pertaining to Title XIX of the Social Security Act, and all District and federal law and rules applicable to the services or activity provided.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 997 (January 31, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>