<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-400</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 29-400)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>400.1.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this chapter, including procedures and criteria adopted in accordance with federal legislation and regulations (including regulations of the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (DHHS) issued August 10, 1979, Federal Register,
      Vol. 44, No. 156-Part II), shall govern the review and approval or disapproval of proposed uses of federal health funds in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>400.2.</num>
    <text>The review procedures and criteria set forth in this chapter shall also cover proposed uses of federal funds subject to Statewide Health Coordinating Council (also referred to in this chapter as the &amp;#8220;SHCC&amp;#8221;) review and approval
      or disapproval under §1524(c)(6) of Public Law 93-641, as amended, and specified in §401.3.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>400.3.</num>
    <text>The purpose of the review shall be to ensure that, to the greatest extent practicable, federal health funds shall be expended in the District in a manner consistent with local planning decisions and supportive of the D.C. State Health Plan developed
      under the authority of Titles XV and XVI of the Public Health Service Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>400.4.</num>
    <text>In accordance with the provisions of Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order No. 76-59, dated February 4, 1976, and consistent with the provisions of §1521 of the Public Health Service Act, the Department of Human Services (also referred to in this chapter as &amp;#8220;DHS&amp;#8221;)
      shall be the responsible agency for conducting health planning and resources development activities in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1979, 3 D.C. Code, 2001 Ed. at 338.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 1086 (March 13, 1981).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR’S NOTE</heading>
      <text>The Public Health Service Act referenced in this section is codified at 42 U.S.C. §§201 et seq.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>