<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4222</num>
  <heading>PROGRAM SERVICES[COLON] PERSONAL CARE AIDE SERVICES (ยง 29-4222)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4222.1.</num>
    <text>Personal care aide services shall be prescribed by a physician or Advanced Practice Nurse in accordance with the recipient&amp;#8217;s plan of treatment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4222.2.</num>
    <text>The physician&amp;#8217;s plan of care shall be developed initially, and the plan of care shall be re-certified by the physician or Advanced Practice Nurse every six (6) months thereafter. The plan must be signed by the physician or Advanced Practice
      Nurse within thirty (30) days of its prescription.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4222.3.</num>
    <text>Personal care aide services shall be initiated no later than forty-eight (48) hours after completion of the initial assessment unless the recipient or the recipient&amp;#8217;s representative agree to a later date to begin the services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4222.4.</num>
    <text>A waiver recipient may choose an individual or family member other than a spouse, or parent of a minor recipient or other legally responsible relative to provide personal care services. Each family member providing personal care services shall meet
      the requirements set forth in ยง 4221 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4222.5.</num>
    <text>Personal care services include, but are not limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Basic personal care including bathing, grooming, assistance with toileting, or bed pan use;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Changing urinary drainage bags;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Assisting recipients with range of motion exercises;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Assisting recipients with self-administered medications. The aide may remind the recipient to take the medication but cannot administer the medication to the recipient;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Reading and recording temperature, pulse, and respiration;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Observing and documenting the recipient&amp;#8217;s status and verbally reporting to the registered nurse or the case manager the findings immediately for emergency situations and within four (4) hours for other situations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Meal preparation in accordance with dietary guidelines and assistance with eating or feeding;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Tasks related to keeping the recipient&amp;#8217;s living areas in a condition that promotes the recipient&amp;#8217;s health, and comfort, and safety;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Accompanying the recipient to medically-related appointments or place of employment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Providing assistance at the recipient&amp;#8217;s place of employment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Shopping for items related to promoting the recipient&amp;#8217;s nutritional status and other health needs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Recording and reporting to the supervisory health professional and case manager any changes in the recipient&amp;#8217;s physical condition, behavior, or appearance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Infection control; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>Accompanying the recipient to approved recreational activities.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4222.6.</num>
    <text>Personal care aide services shall not include services that require the skills of a licensed professional, such as catheter insertion, procedures requiring the use of sterile techniques, and administration of medication.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4222.7.</num>
    <text>Personal care aide services shall not include tasks usually performed by chore workers, such as cleaning of areas not occupied by the recipient, laundry for family members, and shopping for items not used by the recipient.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4222.8.</num>
    <text>Personal care aide services shall be provided in the recipient&amp;#8217;s place of residence or other location such as the recipient&amp;#8217;s place of employment or assistance while in transit and shall be made available seven (7) days per week.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4222.9.</num>
    <text>Personal care aide services shall not be provided in a hospital, nursing facility, intermediate care facility for the mentally retarded, or institution for mental disease.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4222.10.</num>
    <text>When a recipient is receiving PCA services and homemaker services from two different staff persons who are employees of the same agency, all supervisory registered nurse (RN) visits shall be coordinated so that supervisory in-home RN visits are made
      in accordance with waiver standards and the supervisory in-home RN visits are made by the same supervising RN at the same time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 9025 (October 24, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>