<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4107</num>
  <heading>FISCAL ACCOUNTABILITY (§ 29-4107)
    <text>Beginning in FY 2014, except for the Administration cost center, each facilityhall spend at least ninety-five percent (95%) of the rate under each costenter on service delivery to Medicaid individuals. Facilities expending lesshan ninety-five percent
      (95%) of each cost center shall be subject to repaymentequirements.</text>
    <text>Beginning in FY 2014, each ICF/IID shall spend one hundred percent (100%) of theate for Active Treatment on service delivery to Medicaid individuals.</text>
    <text>Facilities expending less than one hundred percent (100%) of the rate for Activereatment shall be subject to repayment requirements.</text>
    <text>DHCF shall evaluate expenditures subject to the requirements in thisection through annual review of cost reports.</text>
    <text>The repayment amount described in § 4107.1 shall be the differenceetween ninety-five percent (95%) of the rate component and reported expenseslus the administrative percentage of thirteen percent (13%). The repaymentmount described in § 4107.2 shall
      be the difference between one hundredercent (100%) of the payments made for active treatment services and reportedxpenses for active treatment services.</text>
    <text>DHCF, or its designee, shall review each cost report forompleteness, accuracy, compliance, and reasonableness through a desk audit.</text>
    <text>On-site audits shall be conducted not less than once every three (3) years.</text>
    <text>Each ICF/IID shall allow access, during on-site audits or review by DHCF or U.S.epartment of Health and Human Services auditors, to relevant financial recordsnd statistical data to verify costs previously reported to DHCF.</text>
    <text>DHCF shall issue a notice to each ICF/IID that is required to repay as set forthn this section. The notice shall set forth the repayment amount and includeanguage describing the procedure and timeframes for requesting an appeal beforeAH. Filing an
      appeal with OAH shall not stay any action to recover the amountsrescribed in this section.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11590 (August 9, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>