<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4605</num>
  <heading>PHYSICAL PLANT REQUIREMENTS (ยง 29-4605)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4605.1.</num>
    <text>Each MCOTT Program office facility shall be either owned or leased by the Provider.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4605.2.</num>
    <text>Each MCOTT Program office facility shall include an accessible reception area for MCOTT clients and their families; a central team work/meeting room, and staff offices, as needed; a secure medication room; and a safe or other locked means of securing
      client funds and personal items, as needed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4605.3.</num>
    <text>Each MCOTT Program office facility shall be located within 15 minutes of public transportation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4605.4.</num>
    <text>Each MCOTT Program office facility shall conform to all applicable provisions of the District of Columbia Building Code and any other applicable District rules and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4605.5.</num>
    <text>The MCOTT Program office facility shall possess a current certificate of occupancy permit, appropriate District Fire Department Inspection Certificates and a Manual of Instructions and Plans which shall be followed in case of fire, explosion or other
      emergency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4605.6.</num>
    <text>The MCOTT Program office facility shall be located in a building of sound construction and shall be maintained in good repair.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4605.7.</num>
    <text>Curb cuts, handrails, steps, and ramps shall be designed or adapted to offer easy accessibility to the MCOTT Program office facility by the population being served.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4605.8.</num>
    <text>Each MCOTT Program office facility shall be accessible to persons with mobility limitations consistent with the Rehabilitation Act, P. L. 95-602, Section 504.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4605.9.</num>
    <text>There shall be at least two (2) toilet facilities at the site. At least one (1) toilet shall be designed or adapted to provide access and maneuverability for handicapped and wheelchair-bound individuals.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4605.10.</num>
    <text>A room with a bed with adequate provision for privacy shall be available at the MCOTT Program office facility in cases illness, individualized programming or instruction, or acting-out behavior. The MCOTT Program office facility shall have available
      an examination table for medical examinations and treatment in a private area.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4605.11.</num>
    <text>Drinking water shall be readily accessible to the clients and provided by either an angle jet drinking fountain with mouth guard or by a running water supply with individual drinking cups.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4605.12.</num>
    <text>Drinking water facilities shall not be located in toilet rooms.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4605.13.</num>
    <text>There shall be at least one (1) telephone in the MCOTT Program office facility to summon help immediately in case of fire or other emergencies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 6122 (July 23, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>