<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4405</num>
  <heading>GRANT AGREEMENT (ยง 29-4405)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4405.1.</num>
    <text>Each grant award shall be in the form of a written grant agreement between the Director and the awardee that is consistent with those statutes and regulations that apply to the grant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4405.2.</num>
    <text>The grant agreement shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A statement of the purpose of the grant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The amount of the grant award;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The term of the project;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Reference to provisions of statutes, rules, and regulations (including provisions of this chapter) particularly applicable to the grantee, as well as a statement that the grantee shall comply will all applicable Federal and District laws and regulations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The scope of work for the grant, a description of any service or products required to be delivered under the grant, and a schedule of expected performance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Reporting requirements, both program and financial;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A payment schedule;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The name, address and telephone number of the Grant Officer in the Department, and of the agent for the grantee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The address to which all written communications from the Department to the grantee may be sent, including periodic payments due under the grant; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>A provision that the grant may be modified by agreement of both parties.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 6246, 6249 (August 27, 1993).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>