<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4229</num>
  <heading>SPECIFIC PROVIDER REQUIREMENTS[COLON] HOMEMAKER SERVICES (ยง 29-4229)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4229.1.</num>
    <text>Supervisory staff employed by the provider shall develop an ISP for homemaker services, and the recipient&amp;#8217;s case manager shall approve the ISP before it is implemented.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4229.2.</num>
    <text>The homemaker provider shall document in-home visits and telephone contacts within the recipient&amp;#8217;s record at least within ninety (90) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4229.3.</num>
    <text>Each provider of homemaker services shall ensure that each homemaker staff obtains twelve (12) continuing in-service education hours per year. Continuing education shall be specifically designed to increase the staff&amp;#8217;s knowledge, ability,
      and skills related to the tasks to be performed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4229.4.</num>
    <text>Comprehensive records of each employee training shall be kept on file for a period of not less than six (6) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4229.5.</num>
    <text>In-home supervision of homemaker services shall be conducted at least once every three (3) months.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4229.6.</num>
    <text>A copy of the ISP shall be kept in the following locations:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Case management provider; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Home care agency, home health agency, or business.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4229.7.</num>
    <text>A waiver recipient may choose an individual or family member other than a spouse, or parent of a minor recipient or other legally responsible relative to provide homemaker services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4229.8.</num>
    <text>Each person providing homemaker services shall complete a 75-hour initial training course, hold a Home Health Aide/Homemaker certificate from a training institution approved by the District of Columbia Nursing Aide Training Program, and shall have
      successfully completed a competency evaluation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4229.9.</num>
    <text>Homemaker service providers shall require twelve (12) hours of continuing education annually. Continuing education shall be specifically designed to increase the staff&amp;#8217;s knowledge and understanding of the targeted population and to improve
      staff skills at tasks performed in the provision of homemaker service(s) in accordance with general and each applicable service standards.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4229.10.</num>
    <text>Homemaker service providers shall maintain comprehensive records in each employee&amp;#8217;s personnel file for a period of not less than six (6) years identifying dates of training and topics covered.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4229.11.</num>
    <text>Homemaker service providers shall develop and implement an individualized in- service training plan for each homemaker staff when performance evaluations indicate a need.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4229.12.</num>
    <text>Homemaker staff shall successfully complete initial cardiopulmonary resuscitation (&amp;#8220;CPR&amp;#8221;) training and annual re-certification. Homemaker staff shall complete the initial CPR training prior to the provision of homemaker services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4229.13.</num>
    <text>Each home care agency, home health agency, or business providing homemaker services shall conduct supervision of the homemaker by the supervisory RN at least on a quarterly basis.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4229.14.</num>
    <text>When a recipient is receiving homemaker services and Personal Care Aide (PCA) services from two different staff persons who are employees of the same agency, all supervisory Registered Nurse (RN) visits shall be coordinated so that supervisory in-home
      RN visits are made in accordance with waiver standards and the supervisory in-home RN visits are made by the same supervising RN at the same time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 9025 (October 24, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>