<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4231</num>
  <heading>SPECIFIC PROVIDER REQUIREMENTS[COLON] CHORE AIDE SERVICES (ยง 29-4231)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4231.1.</num>
    <text>A home care, home health agency, or business providing chore aide services shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Require that all persons providing chore services successfully complete a Homemaker or Health Aides Training and Certification Program. The training shall meet all the requirements of the D.C. Department of Health, Health Regulations Administration
        governing home health aides;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Require that chore aides complete a minimum of six (6) hours of continuing education on an annual basis. Initial training must be completed before a chore aide is assigned to a recipient&amp;#8217;s home;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Require continuing education for chore aide services that shall be specifically designed to increase the staff&amp;#8217;s knowledge and understanding of the population served and to improve the skill level of the staff regarding the tasks performed
        in the provision of service(s) in accordance with general service standards and each applicable service rule; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Maintain comprehensive records identifying dates of training and topics covered in each employee&amp;#8217;s personnel file for a period of not less than six (6) years. An individualized in-service training plan shall be developed and implemented
        for each staff person when performance evaluations indicate a need.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4231.2.</num>
    <text>A chore aide service provider shall provide a pre- and post-cleaning inspection of the home or place of residence with documentation indicating that the home environment has been placed in a state of readiness for ongoing, routine housekeeping.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4231.3.</num>
    <text>In the case of rental property and residential facilities, the case manager shall examine the existing responsibilities of the landlord or homeowner, pursuant to the lease agreement (or other applicable laws and regulations) prior to authorization
      of chore aide services. The case manager shall ensure that the requisite documents have been reviewed prior to ordering chore aide services on the ISP.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4231.4.</num>
    <text>Each home care, home health agency, or business providing chore aide services shall ensure that appropriate supervision of chore staff is conducted by an individual identified as one who is:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Trained to evaluate the activities of chore staff personnel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Has at least two (2) years of experience supervising chore staff activities; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Has been provided with training in basic supervision by the home care, home health agency, or business.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 9025 (October 24, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>