<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-406</num>
  <heading>SHPDA REVIEW PROCEDURES AND CRITERIA (ยง 29-406)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>406.1.</num>
    <text>The performance of any review by the SHPDA and SHCC shall be in accordance with and consistent with review procedures set forth in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>406.2.</num>
    <text>Before adopting or revising the review procedures and criteria, the SHPDA shall conduct a public hearing and establish a thirty (30) day public comment period to give interested persons an opportunity to offer written and or oral comments on materials
      it proposes to adopt.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>406.3.</num>
    <text>The SHPDA shall publish in the D.C. Register, and in one (1) or more newspapers of general circulation in the District, a notice stating that review procedures and criteria, or revisions, have been proposed for adoption and are available at a specified
      address for inspection and copying. The notice shall include detailed information about the public hearing and the public comment period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>406.4.</num>
    <text>The SHPDA shall distribute copies of the proposed review procedures and criteria, or revisions, to the Secretary of DHHS and to entities with which the SHPDA is required to coordinate its activities under ยง1513(d) of Public Law 93-641, as amended,
      including the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Any agency which establishes rates for health care facilities or health maintenance organizations (HMOs) in the District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The clearinghouse established under Office of Management and Budget Circular A-95;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Statewide Health Coordinating Council;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Professional Standards Review Organization; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The health systems agencies, SHPDAs, and Statewide Health Coordinating Councils designated for the areas contiguous to the District.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>406.5.</num>
    <text>The SHPDA shall not impose fees for distributing the proposed review procedures and criteria, or proposed revisions, to the agencies and organizations specified in ยง406.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>406.6.</num>
    <text>The SHPDA shall distribute copies of the adopted review procedures and criteria, and any revisions, upon request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 1086 (March 13, 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>