<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4205</num>
  <heading>RECORDS AND CONFIDENTIALITY OF INFORMATION[COLON] GENERAL (ยง 29-4205)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4205.1.</num>
    <text>Each provider of waiver services shall establish and implement a plan to protect the privacy and confidentiality of a recipient&amp;#8217;s records.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4205.2.</num>
    <text>The disclosure of treatment information by a provider of waiver services is subject to all the provisions of applicable District and Federal laws, for the purpose of confidentiality of information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4205.3.</num>
    <text>Each provider of waiver services shall maintain comprehensive records of the waiver services provided to each recipient and shall maintain each record for a period of not less than six (6) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4205.4.</num>
    <text>Each recipient&amp;#8217;s record shall include, but is not limited to, the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>General information including each recipient&amp;#8217;s name, Medicaid identification number, address, telephone number, age, sex, name and telephone number of emergency contact person, physician&amp;#8217;s name, address, and telephone number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A record of a Bill of Rights and Responsibilities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The initial and annual ISP developed by the case manager and approved by designated MAA staff;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A copy of the initial and annual ISP for other service providers as approved by the case manager;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A record of all service(s) provided, including description and dates of services rendered;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A record of staff person(s) providing the service(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A copy of the initial and annual level of care determinations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>A record of the initial and annual Beneficiary Freedom of Choice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>A record of all monthly in-home site visits and telephone contacts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>A record of all monthly system checks and telephone contacts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>A record of the initial and annual Pre-Admission Screening and Resident Review (PASRR) for mental illness or mental retardation and Psychiatric Evaluation, as necessary;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>A record of all quarterly reviews and narrative notes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>A record of the recipient&amp;#8217;s initial and annual health history;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>A record of all prior authorizations for services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>A record of all requests for change in services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(p)</num>
      <text>A discharge summary, if applicable; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(q)</num>
      <text>Any other records necessary to demonstrate compliance with all rules, regulations, requirements, guidelines, and standards for the implementation and administration of this waiver.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 9025 (October 24, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>