<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4609</num>
  <heading>DISCHARGE PROCEDURES (ยง 29-4609)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4609.1.</num>
    <text>Providers shall discharge a client from an MCOTT Program when a client, or his/her legal representative, if any, and MCOTT Program staff mutually agree to the termination of services. Circumstances giving rise to a consideration of termination include,
      but are not limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The client moves outside of the MCOTT Program&amp;#8217;s geographic area of responsibility. In such cases, the Provider shall arrange for transfer of mental health service responsibility to a provider within the area where the client relocates.
        The Provider shall maintain contact with the client until the service transfer has occurred; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Demonstration of the client&amp;#8217;s ability to function in all major role areas (work, social, self-care) without requiring assistance from the MCOTT Program and with high likelihood to maintain the functioning with less intensive intervention,
        with this determination to be made by both the client and MCOTT Program staff and with a reduced likelihood of returning to one of the treatment categories in 4607.2.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4609.2.</num>
    <text>A MCOTT Program shall document the discharge of each MCOTT client in the client&amp;#8217;s record. Such documentation shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The reason for the client&amp;#8217;s discharge;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The client&amp;#8217;s status and condition at the time of discharge;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A written final evaluation summary of the client&amp;#8217;s progress toward the goals set forth in the ITP;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A plan developed, in conjunction with the client, for care after discharge and for follow-up; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The signature of the Primary Case Manager, Program Director, the psychiatrist and the client.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 6122 (July 23, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>