<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4015</num>
  <heading>DECISION OF THE DIRECTOR (§ 29-4015)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4015.1.</num>
    <text>The Director may require informal, non-binding mediation between the parties before issuing a final decision if, due to the nature of the dispute, the Director considers it to be in the best interests of the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4015.2.</num>
    <text>The Director shall appoint one (1) or more individuals who have not participated substantially in the matter in dispute to conduct the mediation described in § 4014.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4015.3.</num>
    <text>The Director shall make a final written decision based upon the grant file, other documents filed by the parties, and the testimony and evidence presented at the hearing, in accordance with applicable laws and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4015.4.</num>
    <text>The final decision of the Director shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A description of the dispute;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Reference to the pertinent grant terms, regulations or statutes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A statement of the factual areas of agreement and disagreement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A determination sustaining or overruling the determination of the Grant Officer, in whole or in part, with the reason for the determination;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>If all or any part of the Grant Officer’s determination has been determined to be valid, a determination of any monetary settlement, the grant adjustment to be made, or other relief to be granted; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A written notice that the grantee may appeal the final decision to the Board of Appeals and Review.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4015.5.</num>
    <text>The Director shall deliver or send by certified mail, a copy of the final decision to the grantee, and shall provide a copy to the Grant Officer for inclusion in the grant file.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 38 DCR 6302, 6314 (October 11, 1991).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>