<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4703</num>
  <heading>PROGRAM SERVICES (ยง 29-4703)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4703.1.</num>
    <text>Each Provider shall have the capability to assist each client in gaining access to medical, social, educational or other services appropriate to the needs of the client.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4703.2.</num>
    <text>TCM services shall include, but are not limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Client Intake, through identifying programs appropriate for each client&amp;#8217;s needs and providing assistance to the client in accessing those programs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Assessment of each client&amp;#8217;s family and community circumstances, risks to the client, and service needs, in order to coordinate the identification and delivery of services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Case Planning with each client, the client&amp;#8217;s caregiver, and other parties, as appropriate to identify the care, services and resources required to meet the client&amp;#8217;s needs as identified in the assessment, and to identify how they
        might be most appropriately delivered;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Service Coordination and Monitoring, through linkage, referral, coordination, facilitation, documentation, and advocacy, to insure each client access to the care, services and resources identified in the case plan. This may be accomplished by oral,
        written or electronic contacts with the client, the client&amp;#8217;s caregiver, service providers, and other interested parties; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Case Plan Reassessments to determine and to document whether or not medical, social, educational, or other services continue to be adequate to meet the goals identified in the case plan. Activities shall include assisting each client in gaining
        access to different medical, social, educational, or other needed care and services beyond those previously identified and provided.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4703.3.</num>
    <text>In accordance with section 1902(a)(23) of the Social Security Act, CFSA shall ensure that each client shall have free choice of qualified providers of TCM services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4703.4.</num>
    <text>Case plan reassessments shall be conducted at least every six (6) months.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Emergency Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 5257 (June 23, 2000) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 7084 (September 1, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>