<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4112</num>
  <heading>DENIAL OF PAYMENT (§ 29-4112)
    <text>Pursuant to Section 1902(i) of the Act and 42 C.F.R. § 442.118, and in lieu ofermination in situations where residents are not in immediate jeopardy, DHCFay initiate a one-time denial of payment for claims associated with newdmissions at ICFs/IID
      that fail to comply with one (1) or more of the CoPs foredicaid enrollment.</text>
    <text>The denial of payment term shall be eleven (11) months in duration,eginning on the first day of the month after DHCF imposes the denial ofayments.</text>
    <text>DHCF shall also deny payment to ICFs/IID if DOH previously initiatednforcement actions due to immediate jeopardy, and the facility has failed toitigate the circumstances that caused immediate jeopardy.</text>
    <text>The ICF/IID has up to sixty (60) days to correct the cited deficiencies; and</text>
    <text>The procedures that shall commence once the sixty (60) days have lapsed,ursuant to § 4112.5.</text>
    <text>If the ICF/IID does not correct the violations within the sixty (60)ay timeframe, DHCF shall notify the facility of its intention to deny payment.</text>
    <text>This written notification shall include:</text>
    <text>Reasons for denial of payment;</text>
    <text>Information on the right to request a hearing though OAH, pursuant to 29 DCMR§ 1300 et seq.;</text>
    <text>Details of public notice; and</text>
    <text>The effective date for denial of payments.</text>
    <text>If an ICF/IID appeals DHCF’s decision to deny payment, DHCF shallotify the provider that the effective date of the sanction, established in 4112.2, shall be suspended until the appeal is resolved.</text>
    <text>If denial of payment is upheld at the appeal, the DHCF shall notifyhe facility and the public at least thirty (30) days before the newlystablished effective date of the sanction.</text>
    <text>DHCF, in coordination with other District agencies, shall monitorhe facility’s progress in improving cited violation(s) throughout the eleven11) month period.</text>
    <text>The Director of DHCF shall consider modifying or rescinding denial ofayment upon the occurrence of one of the following:</text>
    <text>Circumstances have changed and resulted in alterations of the CoPs violation(s)n such a manner as to immediately jeopardize patient health and safety; or</text>
    <text>The ICF/IID achieves full compliance with the CoPs in fewer than eleven (11)onths; or</text>
    <text>The ICF/IID makes significant progress in achieving compliance with the CoPshrough good faith efforts.</text>
    <text>DHCF shall terminate the provider agreement of an ICF/IID that haseen unable to achieve compliance with the CoPs during the full eleven (11)onth period of denial of payment. Termination shall be effective on the firstay following the last day of the
      denial payment period.</text>
    <text>An ICF/IID provider agreement that is subject to denial of paymenthall be automatically extended for the eleven (11) month period if the providergreement does not lapse on or before the effective date of denial of payments.</text>
    <text>ICF/IID provider agreements that are subject to denial of paymentay only be renewed when the denial period expires or is rescinded.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>DHCF, in coordination with DOH, shall notify the ICF/IID that it isubject to denial of payment. The written notification shall indicate theollowing</heading>
      <text />
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11590 (August 9, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>