<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4902</num>
  <heading>PROGRAM SERVICES (ยง 29-4902)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4902.1.</num>
    <text>Rehab services shall include the following services:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Evaluation, assessment and Plan of Care development;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Individual and group psychotherapy and counseling;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Medical evaluations, including developmental, psychological, speech/language, occupational therapy and physical therapy assessments;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Crisis intervention;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Health service coordination through activities to assist and enable the client to receive services authorized in the Plan of Care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Medication management to assist the client or the client&amp;#8217;s caregiver in understanding and adhering to a prescribed pharmacological routine;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Behavior management to assist the client who has a behavior problem in understanding the consequences of inappropriate behavior and to teach and reinforce appropriate behavior; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Plan of Care reassessment and revision.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4902.2.</num>
    <text>Each evaluation and assessment provided pursuant to ยง 4902.1(a) shall meet the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be based on an informed clinical opinion; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Include an evaluation of the client&amp;#8217;s cognitive, social, emotional and adaptive development.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4902.3.</num>
    <text>Healthcare professionals qualified to perform the evaluation and assessment and participate in the development and reassessment of the Plan of Care are as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Psychiatrist;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Psychologist;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Licensed Professional Counselor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Licenced Independent Clinical Social Worker (LICSW);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Advanced Practiced Registered Nurse; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Licensed Graduate Social Worker under the supervision of a psychiatrist, psychologist or LICSW.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4902.4.</num>
    <text>The Plan of Care shall be developed by a multi-disciplinary team in consultation with the client and his or her caregiver. Each Plan of Care shall be signed and dated by a psychiatrist and contain the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A written plan that contains and is based on the information derived from the evaluation and assessment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A statement of the client&amp;#8217;s present level of functioning in the domains examined in the evaluation and assessment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Treatment objectives in measurable terms, including discharge planning, long and short term goals with appropriate timelines;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A statement of the client&amp;#8217;s specific complaints, including the limitations and abilities, specific problems and specific needs of the patients;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A statement of the specific services and supports necessary to meet the unique needs of the client and the setting in which the services are to be delivered; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Names and titles of persons responsible for implementing the Plan of Care.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4902.5.</num>
    <text>Individual psychotherapy and counseling shall meet following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be provided in a face-to-face clinical intervention with an appropriate health care professional acting within the scope of their practice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be provided in accordance with the Plan of Care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Be provided at a ratio of one therapist to one client; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Be provided at a minimum of 30 minutes per session.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4902.6.</num>
    <text>Group psychotherapy and counseling shall meet the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be provided in a face-to-face clinical intervention with an appropriate health care professional acting within the scope of their practice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be provided in accordance with the Plan of Care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Be provided at a ratio of one therapist to no more than 12 clients; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Be provided at a minimum of 30 minutes per session.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4902.7.</num>
    <text>Healthcare professionals qualified to perform individual and group counseling are as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Psychiatrist;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Psychologist;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Licensed Professional Counselor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Licensed Independent Clinical Social Worker;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Licensed Graduate Social Worker under the supervision of a psychiatrist, psychologist or LICSW; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Advanced Practice Registered Nurse who is certified by the American Nurses Association to practice psychotherapy.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4902.8.</num>
    <text>Healthcare professionals qualified to perform psychotherapy are as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Psychiatrist;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Psychologist;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Licensed Independent Clinical Social Worker;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Licensed Graduate Social Worker under the supervision of a psychiatrist, psychologist or LICSW; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Advanced Practice Registered Nurse who is certified by the American Nurses Association to practice psychotherapy.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4902.9.</num>
    <text>Each medical evaluation shall be provided by a licensed health care professional acting within the scope of his or her practice, who has a contract with CFSA to provide medical evaluation services. Each medical evaluation shall meet the following
      requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be provided in a face-to-face clinical intervention; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Ensure that the client is assessed in all areas relating to a suspected disability including, when appropriate, health, vision, hearing, dental, social and emotional status, general intelligence, communicative status and motor abilities.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4902.10.</num>
    <text>Each medical evaluation shall be used in developing or modifying the Plan of Care.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4902.11.</num>
    <text>Reimbursement for a medical evaluation provided in a residential setting shall be allowed only when provided by a licensed health care professional who is not an employee of the residential facility and when necessary to supplement the capabilities
      of the facility&amp;#8217;s staff.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4902.12.</num>
    <text>Crisis intervention shall be provided as clinically appropriate by a psychiatrist, psychologist, licensed professional counselor or licensed independent clinical social worker or licensed graduate social worker under the supervision of a psychiatrist,
      psychologist or LICSW for the purpose of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Reducing the client&amp;#8217;s acute psychiatric and emotional symptoms;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Reducing the likelihood of the client harming himself or others; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Assisting the client in returning to his or her pre-crisis level of functioning.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4902.13.</num>
    <text>Crisis intervention shall be provided at a ratio of one therapist to one client.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4902.14.</num>
    <text>Health service coordination shall include the following activities:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Coordinating the performance of evaluations and assessments;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Facilitating and participating in the development, review and evaluation of the Plan of Care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Assisting and identifying available service providers; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Coordinating the provision of services with health care pracritioners.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4902.15.</num>
    <text>Health service coordination shall be provided by a licensed independent clinical social worker or registered nurse.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4902.16.</num>
    <text>Medication management shall be reimbursed only when provided by a lphysician or registered nurse who is authorized by the Provider to administer the Plan of Care. Medication management shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Educating the client/caregiver regarding the benefits and side effects of the medication;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Instructing and assisting the client/caregiver in the self-administration of the medication;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Reviewing with the client/caregiver the symptomatology of the illness; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Observing the client&amp;#8217;s vital signs and level of performance to ensure that adverse side effects are minimized.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4902.17.</num>
    <text>Behavior management shall be reimbursed only when provided by a psychiatrist, psychologist, licensed professional counselor, advanced practice registered nurse, licensed independent clinical social worker or licensed graduate social worker under the
      supervision of a psychiatrist, psychologist or LICSW who is authorized by the Provider to administer the Plan of Care. Behavior management shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Individual and group therapeutic interventions to improve or maintain the client&amp;#8217;s skills needed to interact safely and securely with other persons;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Symptom management to minimize the negative side effects of psychiatric or emotional symptoms which interfere with the client&amp;#8217;s personal development and community integration; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Supportive counseling with the client to develop, restore, manage and maintain the client&amp;#8217;s mental or emotional growth.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4902.18.</num>
    <text>The Plan of Care reassessment and revision shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A thorough review of the initial Plan of Care and any subsequent revisions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A review of any current evaluations or information pertaining to the client&amp;#8217;s condition;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A review of services authorized and delivered in the current Plan of Care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A determination of progress made or deficiencies arising from the current Plan of Care; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A re-authorization of current services that are determined to be beneficial, a discontinuation of services appearing to provide little or no benefit, and authorization of any additional services needed to meet the client&amp;#8217;s physical, mental
        or emotional needs.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4902.19.</num>
    <text>Each Plan of Care shall be reassessed and revised, at least once every six months by the multi-disciplinary team. The health care professions responsible for the client&amp;#8217;s case shall conduct an on-going review of the Plan of Care.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Emergency Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 8872 (September 21, 2001) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 247 (January 11, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>