<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4807</num>
  <heading>CALCULATION OF ADD-ON PAYMENTS (§ 29-4807)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4807.1.</num>
    <text>The final base payment rate calculated pursuant to Section 4801 shall be supplemented by additional payments for capital costs and direct medical education, as appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4807.2.</num>
    <text>Effective October 1, 2012, the capital cost add-on payment shall be calculated by dividing Medicaid capital costs applicable to hospital inpatient routine services costs, as reported on cost report Form HCFA 2552-10, Worksheet D, Part I, Line 200,
      Columns 1 and 3, or its successor, and capital costs applicable to hospital inpatient ancillary services, as determined pursuant to Subsection 4807.3, by the number of Medicaid discharges in the base year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4807.3.</num>
    <text>Capital costs applicable to hospital inpatient ancillary services, as reported on Worksheet D, Part II, Column 2, shall be allocated to inpatient capital by applying the facility ratio of ancillary inpatient charges to total ancillary charges for
      each ancillary line on the cost report.</text>
    <text>Direct medical education add-on shall be calculated by dividing the Medicaid direct medical education costs by the number of Medicaid discharges in the base year.</text>
    <text>Effective October 1, 2012, and annually thereafter, the base year payment rate for capital costs and direct medical education add-on payments for each participating hospital shall be based on costs from each hospital’s submitted or audited cost report
      for the fiscal year that ends prior to October 1 of the prior calendar year.</text>
    <text>If after an audit of the hospital’s cost report for the base year period an adjustment is made to the hospital’s reported costs which results in an increase or decrease of five percent (5%) or greater of the capital cost or direct medical education
      add-on payment, the add-on payment for capital or direct medical education add-on costs shall be adjusted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 4141, 4148 (June 26, 1998); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 2691 (March 26, 2010) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at
        57 DCR 6837 (July 10, 2010) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 4323, 4328 (May 20, 2011); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 15078 (December 28, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>