<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4233</num>
  <heading>SPECIFIC PROVIDER REQUIREMENTS[COLON] EAA[SLASH]HAIP (ยง 29-4233)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4233.1.</num>
    <text>The case manager shall ensure that a home assessment is conducted by a licensed physician or a licensed physical therapist prior to ordering EAA service(s) on the ISP.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4233.2.</num>
    <text>No EAA services shall be approved or reimbursed for a recipient who qualifies for the Handicap Accessibility Improvement Program (HAIP) administered by the District of Columbia Department of Housing and Community Development.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4233.3.</num>
    <text>The case management service provider shall assist all eligible recipients in gaining access to the Handicap Accessibility Improvement Program (HAIP) prior to including EAA/HAIP service in the ISP and shall provide documentation thereof to the MAA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4233.4.</num>
    <text>All necessary service(s) that exceed the maximum allowable costs provided by the District of Columbia Department of Housing and Community Development shall be subject to prior authorization by the MAA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4235.5.</num>
    <text>For rental property or leased property, no EAA services shall be approved or reimbursed unless the rental or lease agreement and all other relevant documents are thoroughly examined by the case manager to determine whether the services are prohibited
      or allowed with conditions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4233.6.</num>
    <text>In the case of rental property or leased property, no EAA services shall be approved or reimbursed unless:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The rental or lease agreement is thoroughly examined to determine that the services are not the responsibility of the property owner or manager; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A signed release was obtained from the management of the property.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4233.7.</num>
    <text>In the case of other residential facilities, no EAA services shall be approved or reimbursed unless:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The laws, rules, regulations, and agreements are thoroughly examined to determine whether the responsibility for the services(s) is not the responsibility of the owner and/or manager of the residential facility; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A signed release from the owner and/or management of the property is obtained.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4233.8.</num>
    <text>EAA service providers shall be exempt from the annual tuberculosis (TB) testing requirements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4233.9.</num>
    <text>Prior to initiating EAA services, the case manager shall obtain an evaluation from a Construction Analyst or Housing Inspector. The evaluation must substantiate that the home is in a condition that is structurally sound to accommodate each ordered
      service(s) and include any stipulation(s) or recommendation(s) on how the service(s) should be implemented.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4233.10.</num>
    <text>After receiving the evaluation by the Construction Analyst or Housing Inspector, the case manager must secure three bids (from among licensed contractors with valid provider agreements with the District of Columbia MAA) for necessary services that
      have been approved by MAA. Each bid submitted, in order to be considered acceptable, shall comply with each stipulation, limitation, or recommendation made by the Construction Analyst or Housing Inspector.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4233.11.</num>
    <text>Each building contractor licensed to conduct business in the District of Columbia shall ensure that all construction staff has the training and skill level required to make the allowable in-home modifications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4233.12.</num>
    <text>The case management service and EAA providers shall maintain a copy of the waiver recipient&amp;#8217;s ISP for a period not less than six (6) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 9025 (October 24, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>