<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4111</num>
  <heading>ALTERNATIVE SANCTIONS FOR ICFSIID-NON-IMMEDIATE JEOPARDY (§ 29-4111)
    <text>In accordance with Section 1902(i)(1)(B) of the Social Security Act, the District of Columbia may impose alternative sanctions against an ICF/IID when that facility fails to meet the CoPs, but the violation does not place beneficiary health or safety
      in immediate jeopardy.</text>
    <text>In lieu of terminating the provider agreement, DHCF may impose one (1) or more alternative sanctions against an ICF/IID as set forth below:</text>
    <text>Denial of payment, as described in § 4112;</text>
    <text>Directed Plan of Correction (DPoC), as described in § 4113;</text>
    <text>Directed In-Service Training (DIST), as described in § 4114; or</text>
    <text>State Monitoring, as described in § 4115.</text>
    <text>Seriousness of the violation(s);</text>
    <text>Number and nature of the violation(s);</text>
    <text>Potential for immediate and serious threat(s) to ICF/IID residents;</text>
    <text>Potential for serious harm to ICF/IID residents;</text>
    <text>Any history of prior violation(s) and/or sanction(s);</text>
    <text>Actions or recommendations of DDS, developmental disability advocacy groups, or health care entities;</text>
    <text>Mitigating circumstances; and</text>
    <text>Other relevant factors.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <num>4111.4.</num>
    <text>DHCF shall issue a written notice to each ICF/IID notifying the facility of termination of the Medicaid provider agreement or the imposition of an alternative sanction. The written notice shall comply with District and federal law and rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4111.5.</num>
    <text>All costs associated with the imposition of an alternative sanction against an ICF/IID pursuant to these rules shall be borne by the facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>DHCF shall determine the appropriateness of alternative sanctions against an ICF/IID upon notification by the Department of Health that an ICF/IID is not in compliance with any of the federal CoPs. A determination to terminate a provider from the
        Medicaid program, or to impose an alternative sanction shall be made based on the following factors</heading>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11590 (August 9, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>