<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4227</num>
  <heading>SPECIFIC PROVIDER REQUIREMENTS[COLON] RESPITE SERVICES (ยง 29-4227)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4227.1.</num>
    <text>A respite care service provider can be a home health agency or business licensed to do business in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4227.2.</num>
    <text>The home health agency or business providing respite care services to waiver recipients shall require the respite care staff to be certified as a home health aides or a personal care aides and complete twelve (12) hours of continuing education on
      an annual basis.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4227.3.</num>
    <text>The continuing education for respite services shall be specifically designed to increase the staff&amp;#8217;s knowledge and understanding of the recipient&amp;#8217;s needs or the target population and to improve the staff&amp;#8217;s skills at tasks
      performed in the provision of service(s) in accordance with applicable service standard.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4227.4.</num>
    <text>Comprehensive records identifying dates of training and topics covered shall be maintained in each employee&amp;#8217;s personnel file for a period of not less than six (6) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4227.5.</num>
    <text>The respite care service provider shall develop and implement an individualized in-service training plan for each staff person when performance evaluations indicate a need.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4227.6.</num>
    <text>If the recipient has a need for a respite care service provider, the case manager shall be notified immediately and shall order the service in the frequency and duration to meet the recipient&amp;#8217;s needs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4227.7.</num>
    <text>The respite care service provider shall develop and implement an initial intake assessment that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Assesses the recipient&amp;#8217;s respite needs; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The appropriate level of caregiver required to meet the identified needs.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4227.8.</num>
    <text>A Registered Nurse (RN) who possesses the following qualifications shall conduct the initial intake assessment:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Duly licensed to practice in the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Is employed by the personal care aide agency, home health agency, or business; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Have at least one year of experience working with the elderly and individuals with physical disabilities.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4227.9.</num>
    <text>In conducting the initial intake assessment, the RN shall also:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Establish a written emergency notification plan for each recipient receiving respite care services; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Document that the emergency plan has been reviewed with the recipient or representative and the individual staff person who will provide the respite care.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4227.10.</num>
    <text>A respite caregiver shall not leave the home or place of residence of the recipient during the period of time during which respite care is being provided unless the home care agency, home health agency, or business that is responsible for providing
      the services replaces the caregiver prior to the caregiver removing himself or herself from the recipient&amp;#8217;s home or primary place of residence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4227.11.</num>
    <text>Each provider of respite services shall keep all documentation related to an emergency notification plan on file with the home care agency, home health agency, or business for a period not less than six (6) years. The waiver recipient shall also receive
      a copy of the emergency notification plan and shall keep it at his or her home or place of residence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 9025 (October 24, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>