<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4215</num>
  <heading>PROVIDER REQUIREMENTS[COLON] GENERAL (ยง 29-4215)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4215.1.</num>
    <text>Each provider approved to provide one or more waiver services shall meet the following minimum requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Have a current provider agreement on file with the MAA before providing any waiver services; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be licensed to do business in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4215.2.</num>
    <text>Each provider of waiver services shall demonstrate a comprehensive knowledge and understanding of the MAA Program including:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Knowledge of State Plan services and limitations thereof;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Knowledge of linkages to community resources (legal, housing, rental, energy, food, transportation, and other medical and social assistance) and the methods of accessing these resources; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An understanding of the relationship between State Plan and waiver services, where applicable.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4215.3.</num>
    <text>Each provider of two (2) or more waiver services to the same recipient shall coordinate supervisory visits in order to avoid duplication of services and unnecessary cost to the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4215.4.</num>
    <text>Each provider of waiver services shall notify the District of any and all recipients who are hospitalized or who have had their waiver services placed &amp;#8220;On-Hold&amp;#8221; for any reason.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4215.5.</num>
    <text>Each provider of waiver services shall demonstrate a service history and current capacity to provide services to recipients who reside in all four (4) quadrants of the District of Columbia, and to assist recipients in accessing those services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4215.6.</num>
    <text>Each provider of waiver services shall demonstrate a service history and current capacity to assist recipients in accessing services provided through the District of Columbia Office on Aging or other agencies serving the elderly and individuals with
      physical disabilities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4215.7.</num>
    <text>Each provider of waiver services shall require and thoroughly check at least two (2) references on all staff that enter the home of a waiver recipient.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4215.8.</num>
    <text>Each provider of waiver services shall obtain a criminal background check on each direct care employee to be sent into a recipient&amp;#8217;s home or permanent place of residence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4215.9.</num>
    <text>No employee of a provider of waiver services who has been convicted of a felony, a crime involving abuse, neglect, or violence against the person of another, or crime involving theft or larceny under Federal or state law shall provide service(s) to
      a recipient.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4215.10.</num>
    <text>Each provider of waiver services shall conduct a performance evaluation of each case manager after the first three (3) months of employment and annually thereafter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4215.11.</num>
    <text>Each provider of waiver services that provides staff with hands-on responsibilities (for example, staff that has direct contact with recipient&amp;#8217;s bodily fluids) shall ensure that the service provider is trained in universal precautions prior
      to the provision of any service. Universal precautions training shall be included as part of one of the annual continuing education classes. Documentation of universal precautions training shall be maintained in the employee&amp;#8217;s file for
      a period of not less than six (6) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4215.12.</num>
    <text>Each provider of waiver services shall establish and implement a process to ensure that each recipient has:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Been informed of and given freedom of choice in the selection of all qualified providers of services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Been informed of his or her rights and responsibilities under the waiver program; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Exercised his or her choice and signed a &amp;#8220;Waiver Beneficiary Freedom of Choice&amp;#8221; form, either personally or through an authorized representative.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 9025 (October 24, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>