<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-5807</num>
  <heading>POST ELIGIBILITY ASSESSMENT AND INDIVIDUAL RESPONSIBILITY PLAN (ยง 29-5807)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5807.1.</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise exempt under subsection 5810.3, each TANF applicant or recipient shall be assessed in-depth as to their prior work experience, employability, barriers to employment and employment goals. Participants shall be advised of the location
      and time of the assessment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5807.2.</num>
    <text>Each TANF applicant or recipient may have a representative of his or her choosing present at the assessment and at all discussions related to the Individual Responsibility Plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5807.3.</num>
    <text>Based on the preliminary assessment identified in this section, each TANF recipient shall develop an Individual Responsibility Plan (&amp;#8220;IRP&amp;#8221;) with the Director or his or her designee which:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Sets forth the actions required of the recipient to achieve self-sufficiency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Identifies the resources, training, and other services that the Director or his or her designee may provide to the recipient to assist in attaining self-sufficiency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Recognizes individual preferences of the TANF applicant or recipient to the extent possible; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Ensures a TANF applicant&amp;#8217;s or recipient&amp;#8217;s safety, as required by Section 5811.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5807.4.</num>
    <text>Neither an applicant or recipient shall be required to participate in activities that are not designed to help him or her prepare for, find, or retain employment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5807.5.</num>
    <text>The Director or his or her designee and the applicant or recipient shall discuss the terms of the IRP and each shall sign it as evidence of their agreement. Each recipient shall be given a copy of the IRP and shall have the opportunity to have it
      reviewed periodically, but at least once a year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 10251 (November 9, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>