<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-5799</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 29-5799)
    <text>Capitation rate &amp;#8211; the fixed, monthly rate established by the Departmentayable to the managed care provider for providing covered services to annrolled child.</text>
    <text>Default &amp;#8211; the inability of the managed care provider to provide theervices described in the Medicaid managed care provider agreement; insolvencyf the provider; or, failure of the managed care provider to adhere to therovisions of the Medicaid
      managed care provider agreement.</text>
    <text>Department &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia Department of Human Services or itsgent.</text>
    <text>District &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Eligible child &amp;#8211; any individual, under twenty-two (22) years old, whoeceives Supplemental Security Income disability benefits.</text>
    <text>Emergency medical care &amp;#8211; care provided in response to the suddennexpected onset of a condition which may result in permanent physical injury or threat to life if care is not secured immediately after the onset of theondition or as soon thereafter
      as care can be made available.</text>
    <text>Emergency services &amp;#8211; covered inpatient or outpatient services that (1) areurnished by an appropriated source other than the managed care provider; (2)re needed immediately because of an injury or sudden illness; and (3) cannot beelayed for
      the time required to reach the managed care provider’s nearestvailable network provider without risk or permanent damage to the child’sealth.</text>
    <text>Enrolled child &amp;#8211; a Medicaid beneficiary whose family has elected to enrollhe child in the demonstration or who has been autoassigned to the demonstrationnd has not exercised the right to choose to remain in the current Medicaidee-for-service
      program.</text>
    <text>Evidence of coverage &amp;#8211; any certificate, agreement or contract issued to annrolled child that sets forth the responsibilities of the child and servicesvailable to the child.</text>
    <text>Federally qualified health center (FQHC) &amp;#8211; as defined in 42 C.F.R.405.2340 &amp;#8211; 2470.</text>
    <text>Federally qualified health maintenance organization (FQHMO) &amp;#8211; a healthaintenance organization (HMO) that has been determined by the U.S. Publicealth Service to be a qualified HMO under section 1310 (d) of the Public Healthervice Act, as
      amended, 42 U.S.C. §254c(d)(1) .</text>
    <text>Involuntary disenrollment &amp;#8211; termination of the membership of an enrolledhild by the managed care provider or the Department under conditions permittedy this chapter or the Medicaid managed care provider agreement.</text>
    <text>Lock in period &amp;#8211; the period between the first day of the second month andhe last day of the sixth month of enrollment, during which an eligible childnrolled in the managed care provider’s plan may disenroll only under theonditions prescribed
      in §5701 of these rules.</text>
    <text>Managed care provider &amp;#8211; the managed care organization selected by theepartment to provide for or arrange for health care services to eligiblehildren under the terms and conditions of the Section 1115 demonstration.</text>
    <text>Medicaid managed care provider agreement &amp;#8211; the agreement between theepartment and the managed care provider that sets forth the responsibilities ofhe District government and the provider for providing or arranging for therovision of, and
      making payment for all services that enrolled children arentitled to under the D.C. Medicaid Managed Care Program for Disabled Childrennd Youths.</text>
    <text>Primary care physician &amp;#8211; a qualified physician enrolled in theistrict’s Medicaid Managed Care Program whose specialty is pediatrics,nternal medicine, or family medicine. Specialty care providers qualified toeliver primary care services may
      also be included under this definition.</text>
    <text>Reinsurance &amp;#8211; the insurance protection to be obtained by the managed carerovider for costs over a certain level incurred by the provider for servicesendered to an enrolled child.</text>
    <text>Risk comprehensive contract &amp;#8211; a prepaid, capitated provider contract for acope of services specified in 42 C.F.R. §434.21(b), where the exposure toinancial loss is retained by the provider.</text>
    <text>Stop loss &amp;#8211; protection that limits the financial liability of the managedare provider for expenses incurred for rendering services to an enrolled childnder the Medicaid managed care provider agreement.</text>
    <text>Subcontract &amp;#8211; any written agreement between the managed care provider andnother party that requires the other party to provide services or benefits thathe managed care provider is required to provide, or provide for pursuant to aedicaid
      managed care provider agreement.</text>
    <text>Voluntary disenrollment &amp;#8211; the voluntary termination of membership in theanaged care provider’s plan by an enrolled child under conditions permittedy this chapter or the Medicaid managed care provider agreement.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 43 DCR 4833, 4857 (September 6, 1996).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>