<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-538</num>
  <heading>EMERGENCY MEDICAL RESPONDER INSTRUCTOR STANDARDS (§ 29-538)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>538.1</num>
    <text>538.1 Emergency Medical Responder (EMR) courses shall be taught by:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>District-certified EMR instructors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>EMR instructor trainees under the supervision of a District-certified EMR instructor; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>EMT or Advanced Emergency Medical Services instructors.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>538.2.</num>
    <text>In order to be certified as an EMR instructor, an individual shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Hold and maintain a valid District EMR or greater provider certificate or license, to include but not limited to Emergency Medical Technician, Advanced Emergency Medical Technician, Emergency Medical Technician-Intermediate, Paramedic, Nurse, or
        Physician;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Hold and maintain a valid instructor certification in a related discipline, such as CPR;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Successfully complete a competency-based evaluation based on current District policy; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Submit to the Director a completed EMR instructor application signed by the medical director of the EMS educational institution at which the applicant will teach, verifying competency evaluations and practice teaching dates.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>538.3.</num>
    <text>Certification as an EMR instructor shall be concurrent with the sponsoring EMS educational institution’s certification period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>538.4.</num>
    <text>In order to remain in good standing during his or her certification period, an EMR instructor shall:</text>
    <text>Maintain a current District EMS provider certification or license at the EMR level or greater, to include but not limited to Emergency Medical Technician, Advanced Emergency Medical Technician, Emergency Medical Technician-Intermediate, Paramedic,
      Nurse, or Physician;</text>
    <text>Successfully complete a competency-based evaluation based on current District policy;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Attend EMR instructor workshops as required; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Submit to the Director a completed EMR instructor application signed by the medical director verifying competency evaluations and teaching dates.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>538.5</num>
    <text>538.5 An EMR instructor may also function as the EMR program director if approved by the educational institution’s medical director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>538.6</num>
    <text>538.6 An EMR instructor whose certification has expired may apply to the Director for reinstatement within two (2) years of expiration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>538.7</num>
    <text>538.7 An EMR instructor reinstatement applicant shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Hold a District EMR or greater provider certificate, to include but not limited to Emergency Medical Technician, Advanced Emergency Medical Technician, Emergency Medical Technician-Intermediate, Paramedic, Nurse, or Physician;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Successfully complete a competency-based evaluation based on current District policy; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Submit to the Director a completed EMR instructor application signed by the medical director verifying successful evaluations from practice teaching.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>538.8</num>
    <text>538.8 An EMR instructor whose certification has lapsed for more than two (2) years shall be required to meet initial EMR instructor requirements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 16569 (December 6, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>