<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-556</num>
  <heading>CLINICAL QUALITY ASSURANCE AND IMPROVEMENT (§ 29-556)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>556.1.</num>
    <text>Each Emergency Medical Services Agency shall designate a quality improvement officer who is certified or licensed at or above the certification level of the Emergency Medical Services Agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>556.2</num>
    <text>556.2 The medical director may act in the role of the quality improvement officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>556.3</num>
    <text>556.3 Each Emergency Medical Services Agency shall compile and submit a written quality improvement plan, which the agency’s medical director shall approve. The quality improvement plan shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Require the review of data concerning patient care rendered by EMS providers affiliated with the Emergency Medical Services Agency operational program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Require the identification and analysis of trends in EMS care rendered by EMS providers affiliated with the Emergency Medical Services Agency’s operational program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Specify the method and manner to annually report to the Director on quality assurance issues;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Require the provision of remedial action to resolve any patient care issues involving EMS providers or the EMS system which should be addressed at the organizational level;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Identify violations of the District of Columbia Emergency Medical Services Protocols or Director approved organizational EMS protocols; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Require a review of oral or written allegations that:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An EMS provider failed to act in accordance with applicable law or protocols; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Pre-hospital patient care was below the applicable standard of care.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 16569 (December 6, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>