<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-599</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 29-599)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>599.1</num>
    <text>599.1 When used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have theeanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>ACEP &amp;#8211; the American College of Emergency Physicians.</text>
    <text>Act &amp;#8211; the Emergency Medical Services Act of 2008, effective March 25,009 (D.C. law 17-357; D.C. Official Code §§ 7-2341.01, et seq. (2012 Repl.)).</text>
    <text>ACS &amp;#8211; the American College of Surgeons.</text>
    <text>Administrative Law Judge &amp;#8211; a hearing examiner authorized to hear casesursuant to the Office of Administrative Hearings Establishment Act of 2001,ffective March 6, 2002 (D.C. Law 14-76; D.C. Official Code §§ 2-1831.02, eteq. (2007 Repl. and
      2012 Supp.)).</text>
    <text>Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS) &amp;#8211; the educational and certificationrogram operated that the American Heart Association operates.</text>
    <text>Advanced Emergency Medical Services (AEMS) instructor &amp;#8211; an individual whoeets the necessary educational requirements to teach Advanced EMT,MT-Intermediate, and Paramedic courses.</text>
    <text>Advanced Life Support (ALS) &amp;#8211; the level of care which may be rendered byn individual certified as an:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Advanced Emergency Medical Technician (AEMT);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Emergency Medical Technician – Intermediate (EMT-I); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Paramedic.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Advanced Life Support (ALS) education program &amp;#8211; an individual, agency,orporation, association, or other entity that prepares individuals for Districtmergency medical services (EMS) certification at the ALS level.</text>
    <text>Advertising &amp;#8211; information communicated by oral, electronic, written, orraphic means including handbills, newspapers, business cards, letterhead, otherusiness stationery, television, billboards, radio, and telephone directories,ncluding ambulance
      markings, but not including novelty items such as keyhains, pens, pencils, or mugs.</text>
    <text>Affiliated &amp;#8211; having employment or membership as an EMS provider with anmergency Medical Services Agency or EMS Educational Institution.</text>
    <text>AHA- the American Heart Association.</text>
    <text>Air ambulance &amp;#8211; any aircraft designed and constructed or modified andquipped to be used, maintained, or operated as an ambulance.</text>
    <text>Air medical &amp;#8211; an Emergency Medical Services Agency that responds toedical emergencies to offer care and provides transport to a hospital by an airmbulance.</text>
    <text>Ambulance &amp;#8211; any motor vehicle or aircraft designed and constructed orodified and equipped to be used, maintained, or operated for the transportationf individuals who are sick, injured, wounded, or incapacitated. The termambulance” does not
      include a motor vehicle or aircraft designed andonstructed or modified and equipped with a hydraulic lift which is used,aintained, or operated exclusively for transporting, in wheelchairs, patientsho do not require the use of equipment and trained
      personnel found in anmbulance.</text>
    <text>Automated External Defibrillator (AED) &amp;#8211; a portable electronic device thatutomatically diagnoses the potentially life threatening cardiac arrhythmias ofentricular fibrillation and ventricular tachycardia in a patient and is able toreat them
      through defibrillation.</text>
    <text>Base station &amp;#8211; a unit which has been approved by the Director to providenline medical direction to EMS providers.</text>
    <text>Basic Life Support (BLS) &amp;#8211; the level of care which may be rendered by anndividual certified as an:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Emergency Medical Responder (EMR); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Emergency Medical Technician (EMT).</text>
    </level>
    <text>Basic life support (BLS) education program- an individual, agency, corporation,ssociation, or other entity that prepares individuals for EMS certification athe BLS level.</text>
    <text>Candidate &amp;#8211; a person who has applied for initial certification or renewalf an existing certification as an EMS provider.</text>
    <text>CDC &amp;#8211; the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text>
    <text>CECBEMS &amp;#8211; the Continuing Education Coordinating Board for Emergencyedical Services, a national accrediting body for EMS continuing educationourses and course providers.</text>
    <text>Certification course &amp;#8211; a course of instruction designed to allow thearticipant to obtain certification as an EMS provider at the BLS or ALS level.</text>
    <text>CoAEMSP &amp;#8211; the Committee on Accreditation of Educational Programs for themergency Medical Services Professions which is a national committee thatccredits programs instructing EMS curricula.</text>
    <text>Continuing Education (CE) &amp;#8211; education used for renewal of EMS licensure orertification.</text>
    <text>Continuing Education Hour &amp;#8211; One (1) CE hour is any one (1) of theollowing:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Fifty (50) minutes of approved classroom or skills laboratory activity; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>One (1) hour of approved media-based or periodical-based CE (such as films,ideos, computer simulation, interactive computer modules, and magazinerticles).</text>
    </level>
    <text>Continuing education instructor &amp;#8211; an individual who meets necessaryducational requirements to teach only continuing education courses.</text>
    <text>Curriculum &amp;#8211; the required educational content of an EMS course that theOH approves for certification as an EMS provider.</text>
    <text>Day &amp;#8211; a calendar day.</text>
    <text>Department &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia Department of Health.</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; the Director of the District of Columbia Department of Healthr his or her designee.</text>
    <text>Distance education &amp;#8211; a method of acquiring knowledge and skills throughediated information and instruction, encompassing all technologies and forms ofearning at a distance.</text>
    <text>District EMS Officer – a physician in the District of Columbia Department ofealth who is appointed by the Director to oversee the District’s Emergencyedical Services.</text>
    <text>DOH &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia Department of Health.</text>
    <text>Education Licensure Commission (ELC) &amp;#8211; the Commission that licenses,pproves, or oversees all private postsecondary educational institutions in theistrict of Columbia.</text>
    <text>EMD &amp;#8211; an emergency medical dispatch program.</text>
    <text>Emergency &amp;#8211; a sudden or serious symptom in a patient which might indicate condition which:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Is threatening to the patient&amp;#8217;s physical or psychological well-being;nd</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Requires immediate medical attention to prevent possible deterioration,isability, or death of the patient.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Emergency Medical Response Vehicle &amp;#8211; a vehicle or conveyance used toespond to the scene of a medical emergency for the purpose of rendering medicalssistance, including the provision of medical assistance on the scene or theransportation
      of patients to a health care facility or other treatmentacility. The term &amp;#8220;emergency medical response vehicle&amp;#8221; includes:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Ambulances which operate as motor vehicles, watercraft, or aircraft; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Fire engines, motor vehicles, Segways, or other ground, water, or airehicles used to transport emergency medical services personnel, supplies, orquipment to the scene of an emergency.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Emergency Medical Services (EMS) &amp;#8211; medical services provided pre-hospitalo prevent imminent death or aggravation of illness or injury; transport fromhe scene of a medical emergency to a hospital or other appropriate facilityhether or not
      medical services are provided; medical inter-facility transportervices to an appropriate facility; or medical inter-facility critical careransport to an appropriate facility.</text>
    <text>Emergency Medical Services Agency (EMSA) &amp;#8211; a certified agency providingedical care at the Emergency Medical Responder (EMR), Emergency Medicalechnician (EMT), Advanced Emergency Medical Technician (AEMT), EMT-I, oraramedic level as a transport
      agency or non-transporting first respondergency.</text>
    <text>EMR instructor &amp;#8211; an individual who has met the necessary educationalequirements to teach Emergency Medical Responder courses.</text>
    <text>EMS provider &amp;#8211; an individual certified by DOH to provide emergency medicalervices.</text>
    <text>EMT instructor &amp;#8211; an individual who has met the necessary educationalequirements to teach Emergency Medical Technician courses.</text>
    <text>FAA &amp;#8211; the Federal Aviation Administration.</text>
    <text>First Responder Emergency Medical Services Agency &amp;#8211; an Emergency Medicalervices Agency that responds to medical emergencies to offer care but does notrovide transport to a hospital.</text>
    <text>Glasgow Coma Scale (GCS) &amp;#8211; a standardized system for assessing the degreef conscious impairment in the critically ill and for predicting the durationnd ultimate outcome of coma.</text>
    <text>Ground Transport EMR Agency &amp;#8211; an Emergency Medical Services Agency thatesponds to medical emergencies to offer care and provides transport to aospital by ambulance.</text>
    <text>Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) &amp;#8211; the federalaw that provides federal protections for personal health information held byovered entities and gives patients an array of rights with respect to thatnformation.</text>
    <text>HEPRA &amp;#8211; the Health Emergency Preparedness and Response Administration, andministration within the DOH.</text>
    <text>JCAHO &amp;#8211; the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations.</text>
    <text>Licensed physician &amp;#8211; an individual holding a current and valid license toractice medicine in the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Mass Casualty Incident (MCI) &amp;#8211; an incident in which emergency medicalervices personnel and equipment at a scene are unable to timely and adequatelyrovide emergency medical services, because of the large number and severity ofasualties.</text>
    <text>Medical aid station &amp;#8211; a temporary-use facility, such as a tent or a roomithin an existing building structure, designated to provide basic or advancedife support emergency medical care prior to arrival, treatment, or transport byn EMSA or
      its personnel during special events or emergencies.</text>
    <text>Medical control &amp;#8211; supervision by an EMS agency’s physician who isesponsible for the care of the patient by the agency’s medical providers.</text>
    <text>Medical control orders &amp;#8211; medical instructions that may be direct by two2)-way voice communications (on-line) or indirect by protocol (off-line).</text>
    <text>Medical director &amp;#8211; an agency’s licensed physician who has overallesponsibility for the EMS agency and who works with either the operational orducational section of the agency to provide medical oversight of EMSctivities.</text>
    <text>Medication – a substance taken by mouth; injected into the muscle, bloodessel, or cavity of the body; or applied topically to treat or prevent aisease or condition.</text>
    <text>NAEMSP &amp;#8211; the National Association of Emergency Medical Service Physicians.</text>
    <text>National Emergency Medical Services Information System (NEMSIS) – a nationalepository designed to store EMS data from every state in the nation.</text>
    <text>National Registry of Emergency Medical Technicians (NREMT) &amp;#8211; theot-for-profit independent non-governmental agency that provides standardizedational testing and registration for emergency medical technicians based onational training standards.</text>
    <text>NHTSA &amp;#8211; the United States National Highway Transportation Safetydministration.</text>
    <text>NIMS &amp;#8211; the National Incident Management System.</text>
    <text>Non-transport emergency medical response vehicle &amp;#8211; a vehicle certified toespond to a medical emergency that is not designated to transport a patient to hospital or other health care facility.</text>
    <text>On-line medical control physician &amp;#8211; the physician who directlyommunicates with the agency’s EMS providers regarding appropriate patientare procedures while on the scene of a medical emergency or en route to theospital.</text>
    <text>Operational CE programs &amp;#8211; a continuing education program that is sponsoredy an Emergency Medical Services Agency.</text>
    <text>Operational director &amp;#8211; a District-certified or licensed provider, who isertified or licensed at a level equal to that of the Emergency Medical Servicesgency by which he or she is employed, who is responsible for the operations,reatment,
      and transport of patients in the pre-hospital setting.</text>
    <text>OSSE &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia Office of the State Superintendent ofducation.</text>
    <text>Person – an individual, firm, corporation, association, or governmental agencyither as owner, agency, or otherwise.</text>
    <text>Preceptor hours &amp;#8211; the time spent on an emergency medical response vehicleo observe and assist with the training of EMS providers.</text>
    <text>Quality Assurance (QA) &amp;#8211; an organized method of auditing and evaluatingare provided within an EMS system.</text>
    <text>Quality Improvement (QI) &amp;#8211; a systematic review of pre-hospital careesigned to improve the overall delivery of care within the EMS system.</text>
    <text>Quality improvement officer – a District-certified or licensed provider, whos certified or licensed at a level equal to that of the EMR agency by which her she is employed, who is responsible for the quality improvement activitiesithin the agency.</text>
    <text>Refresher course &amp;#8211; a continuing education course which provides continuingducation requirements required for renewal of an EMS license or certificate.</text>
    <text>Representative – A person to whom authority for a particular act has beenelegated by the Director.</text>
    <text>Respondent &amp;#8211; a person against whom an adverse action is contemplated,roposed, or taken.</text>
    <text>Revocation &amp;#8211; action taken by the Department that permanently voids aertification such that the holder may no longer perform the function associatedith the certification.</text>
    <text>Sponsoring EMS agency – a District certified Emergency Medical Services Agencyr educational institution.</text>
    <text>Special Event – includes, but is not limited to, a circus, rodeo, carnival,air, concert, parade, flea market, marathon, walkathon, race, bicycle event,estival, celebration, performance, singing, playing of musical or othernstruments, dancing or amusement
      of any kind, preaching, exhorting, orecturing conducted or operating in a building, tent or temporary structure ofny kind, on vacant land, or in a yard or area appurtenant to any building, onublic or private space.</text>
    <text>Star-of-Life ambulance &amp;#8211; an ambulance which is constructed in complianceith Federal Specification KKK-A-1822.</text>
    <text>Suspension &amp;#8211; action taken by the Department that temporarily voids aertification such that the holder may no longer perform the function associatedith the certification until the holder has complied with the statutoryequirements and other
      conditions imposed by DOH.</text>
    <text>Time call is dispatched &amp;#8211; the date and time the responding unit wasotified by dispatch.</text>
    <text>Time call received &amp;#8211; the date and time the phone rings (911 call to publicafety answering point or other designated entity) requesting EMS services.</text>
    <text>Time patient was transported to the hospital &amp;#8211; the date and time theesponding unit left the scene (started moving) en route to the hospital.</text>
    <text>Time patient arrived at the hospital &amp;#8211; the date and time the respondingnit arrived with the patient at the hospital destination or transfer point.</text>
    <text>Time personnel arrive on the scene &amp;#8211; the date and time the responding unitrrived on the scene; that is, the time the vehicle stopped moving.</text>
    <text>Time personnel respond &amp;#8211; the date and time the unit responded; that is,he time the vehicle started moving.</text>
    <text>Time personnel returned to service &amp;#8211; the date and time the unit was backn service and available for response (finished with call, but not necessarilyack in home location).</text>
    <text>Time transport service was requested &amp;#8211; the date and time the non-transportMS agency initiated contact with another EMS agency for transport.</text>
    <text>Triage tag &amp;#8211; a tool for EMS providers to use during a mass casualtyncident to identify those patients that need immediate care (red tag), areotentially unstable (yellow tag), are stable patients and can reasonably waitor emergency medical
      service (green tag), and are deceased (black tag).</text>
    <text>Type of call &amp;#8211; the type of complaint dispatch reported to the respondingnit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Rules of the Board of Public Welfare issued July 28, 1950; as amended oneptember 29, 1950; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 16569December 6, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>