<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-57A00</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (ยง 29-57A00)
    <text>57A00.1 There is established in the District of Columbia (District) a program torovide medical assistance to any immigrant child who:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Resides in the District; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Has an annual family income of up to 200% of the federal poverty levelFPL).</text>
    </level>
    <text>57A00.2 Medical assistance provided pursuant to this chapter shall be providedy a health maintenance organization (HMO) that has a current contract with theistrict government to provide managed care health services on a capitated basisn accordance
      with subsections 57A00.4 and 57A00.5</text>
    <text>57A00.3 An application for medical assistance shall be submitted to the Incomeaintenance Administration, Department of Human Services.</text>
    <text>57A00.4 Each program enrollee shall select an HMO that satisfies the criteriaet forth in subsection 57A00.2 within thirty (30) days of the date of theotice that the enrollee&amp;#8217;s application has been approved.</text>
    <text>57A00.5 The Medical Assistance Administration (MAA), Department of Health, shallssign any enrollee who does not select an HMO that satisfies the criteria setorth in subsection 57A00.2 within the time frame set forth in subsection7A00.4.</text>
    <text>57A00.6 The cost of medical assistance provided pursuant to this chapter in anyiscal year shall not exceed the amount of local funds appropriated during thatiscal year for the purposes of this chapter.</text>
    <text>57A00.7 The number of persons enrolled in this program shall not exceed theumber authorized by statute.</text>
    <text>57A00.8 Nothing in this chapter shall be interpreted to create or constitute anntitlement or right to medical assistance for any person.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 8971 (September 28, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>