<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-5320</num>
  <heading>SANCTIONS FOR NON-COMPLIANCE (§ 29-5320)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5320.1.</num>
    <text>If the Department determines that a prepaid, capitated provider has failed to comply with the provisions of this chapter or other applicable federal or District law or regulations, the Department may:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Suspend further enrollment of Medicaid recipients by the prepaid, capitated provider;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Withhold part of the organization’s Medicaid payments;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Use all or part of the deposit detailed in §5303.2 and 5303.3; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Terminate the Medicaid managed care provider agreement within thirty (30) days from the date of notice of termination to the prepaid, capitated provider.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5320.2.</num>
    <text>Before taking any action described in §5320.1, the Department shall provide written notice which shall include at least the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A citation to the law or regulation that has been violated;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The sanction to be applied and the date the sanction will be imposed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The basis for the Department’s determination the sanction should be imposed; and,</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The time frame and procedure for the prepaid, capitated provider to appeal the Department’s determination.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5320.3.</num>
    <text>A provider’s appeal of action pursuant to §5320.1(a) and (b) shall not stay the effective date of the proposed action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5320.4.</num>
    <text>The Department shall provide reasonable written notice of a proposed sanction to AFDC and AFDC-related Medicaid recipients enrolled in the organization’s managed care plan and others who may be affected by the proposed sanction. Notice to AFDC and
      AFDC-related Medicaid recipients shall be by first -class mail, postage prepaid, at the address reflected in the Department’s records.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5320.5.</num>
    <text>Except as specifically provided in this section, 29 DCMR Chapter 13 shall apply to any administrative action taken with respect to a prepaid, capitated provider’s participation in the program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 42 DCR 1566, 1587 (March 31, 1995).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>