<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-5800</num>
  <heading>SCHOOL ATTENDANCE REQUIREMENTS FOR PREGNANT OR PARENTING TEENS (ยง 29-5800)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5800.1.</num>
    <text>Pregnant or parenting TANF recipients under the age of twenty (20) who have not completed high school shall attend high school or an approved alternate education or training program. This requirement is called the &amp;#8220;school attendance requirement&amp;#8221;.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5800.2.</num>
    <text>School attendance or participation in an alternative education or training program shall be verified. Verification may consist of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>DCPS or alternative education or training program attendance records;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Statements by collateral contacts; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Verification of school registration, if the teen is a recent registrant and attendance records are not available.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5800.3.</num>
    <text>If a teen fails without good cause as described in subsection 5800.4 to comply with the school attendance requirement, the teen&amp;#8217;s needs shall be excluded from the TANF benefit after adequate and timely notice has been provided. The teen&amp;#8217;s
      needs shall be excluded until he or she complies with school attendance requirements. After the teen has complied with school attendance requirements, he or she shall become eligible for assistance in the next available payment month but shall remain
      ineligible for the month in which compliance began.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5800.4.</num>
    <text>The Department may not sanction a pregnant or parenting teen for failing to comply with the school attendance requirement if the teen has good cause. The following constitute good cause reasons for failing to comply with school attendance requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The absence is deemed &amp;#8220;excused&amp;#8221; by the educational or training institution or program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The teen parent has a child under the age of six (6) years and no private, District-funded, or other publicly-funded child care resources are available to the teen that are determined by the Department of Human Services (DHS) to be suitable, affordable,
        and within a reasonable distance from the teen&amp;#8217;s home or school;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The teen&amp;#8217;s child has special health care needs that prevent the teen&amp;#8217;s regular attendance at school, which shall be verified by competent medical evidence, as determined by the Director of DHS or his or her designee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The teen&amp;#8217;s child is less than twelve (12) weeks of age; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>An extraordinary and unforseen circumstance determined by the Department to be beyond the control of the teen and prevent him or her from participating in the required activities.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5800.5.</num>
    <text>DHS may refer a pregnant or parenting teen in need of supportive services to the D.C. Public Schools for services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5800.6.</num>
    <text>A teen shall have the right to appeal a finding of non-attendance through the fair hearing process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 10251 (November 9, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>