<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-5829</num>
  <heading>SCREENING AND REFERRALS FOR THE POWER PROGRAM (ยง 29-5829)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5829.1.</num>
    <text>The Director or his or her designee shall screen TANF applicants and recipients at the point of application, recertification, or when incapacity or disability is raised by the applicant or recipient for the Program on Work, Employment and Responsibility
      (POWER) to determine if the head of the assistance unit has a physical or mental incapacity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5829.2.</num>
    <text>The Director or his or her designee may use a screening instrument that is filled out by each TANF applicant or recipient, which shall be designed to elicit basic information needed to determine potential POWER eligibility for the head of the assistance
      unit. The screening instrument shall be made available to the heads of the assistance units who self identify as having a physical or mental incapacity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5829.3.</num>
    <text>When the screening instrument indicates that the head of the assistance unit has a physical or mental incapacity, he or she shall be provided a medical examination form, to be completed by a physician to determine the extent of the physical or mental
      incapacity, if any.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5829.4.</num>
    <text>The head of the assistance unit who receives the medical examination form shall be responsible for ensuring that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>He or she is examined by a physician, mental health professional, or other appropriate professional;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The medical examination form is completed by the physician, or professional; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The medical examination form is returned to IMA as soon as possible, but no later than ninety (90) days after receipt of the medical examination form.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5829.5.</num>
    <text>Prior to the determination of POWER eligibility, the Director or his or her designee may determine Medicaid eligibility first, so that the head of the assistance unit may access his or her primary care physician for the required medical examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5829.6.</num>
    <text>The head of the assistance unit shall not be required to participate in TANF work programs pending a finding of POWER eligibility by the Medical Review Team (MRT).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5829.7.</num>
    <text>When the screening instrument indicates that the head of the assistance unit has a physical or mental incapacity, the Director or his or her designee shall provide him or her a social information form, which shall be designed to elicit basic information
      regarding his or her prior work experience, education, and other factors bearing on his or her ability to work.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5829.8.</num>
    <text>Pending resolution of POWER eligibility determination, the Director or his or her designee shall process the TANF application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5829.9.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of the completed medical examination form and the social information form from the head of the assistance unit, IMA shall send the application package to the MRT for:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Final disposition of the POWER application, assuming other eligibility criteria have been met; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Placement into self-sufficiency activities, if necessary.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5829.10.</num>
    <text>If the MRT determines that the head of the assistance unit is eligible for POWER, the eligibility start date shall be the first day of the month that IMA received the completed medical examination form from the head of the assistance unit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5829.11.</num>
    <text>The Director or his or her designee shall ensure that a reasonable plan for self-sufficiency is developed for the POWER-eligible head of the assistance unit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5829.12.</num>
    <text>The plan for self-sufficiency shall take into consideration the extent to which the head of the assistance unit has an incapacity and the social information provided by the head of the assistance unit. The amount of activities shall mirror, where
      possible, the work activities required in TANF.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5829.13.</num>
    <text>POWER eligibility and the plan for self-sufficiency shall be reviewed as set forth in the plan for self-sufficiency but not less than once every twelve (12) months.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5829.14.</num>
    <text>Each head of an assistance unit who receives a plan for self-sufficiency shall comply with the instructions contained in the plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 10251 (November 9, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>