<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-541</num>
  <heading>CONTINUING EDUCATION INSTRUCTOR STANDARDS (§ 29-541)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>541.1</num>
    <text>541.1 Continuing Education (CE) courses shall be taught by:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>District-certified EMR, EMT, or AEMS instructors consistent with the level of education being taught;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>District-certified CE instructors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>CE instructor trainees under the supervision of a District-certified EMS instructor; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>CE instructor trainees under the supervision of an Emergency Medical Services Agency’s training director.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>541.2</num>
    <text>541.2 A CE instructor who is not an EMS instructor shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Currently hold and maintain a District provider certification or license at or above the level of continuing education being taught, to include but not limited to Emergency Medical Responder, Emergency Medical Technician, Advanced Emergency Medical
        Technician, Emergency Medical Technician-Intermediate, Paramedic, Nurse, or Physician; and</text>
    </level>
    <text>Currently hold and maintain an instructor certification in a related discipline, such as CPR.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>541.3</num>
    <text>541.3 The EMS educational institution or the Emergency Medical Services Agency’s training director may authorize a CE Instructor to instruct in the following NREMT categories:</text>
    <text>Basic Life Support, which shall include the following NREMT topics:</text>
    <text>Preparatory;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Airway and Breathing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Patient Assessment;</text>
    </level>
    <text>Medical/Behavioral;</text>
    <text>Trauma;</text>
    <text>Infants and Children; and</text>
    <text>Obstetrics; or</text>
    <text>Advanced Life Support, which shall include the following NREMT topics:</text>
    <text>Operational Tasks;</text>
    <text>Airway and Breathing;</text>
    <text>Cardiology;</text>
    <text>Medical Emergencies;</text>
    <text>Trauma;</text>
    <text>Pediatrics; and</text>
    <text>Obstetrics.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>541.4.</num>
    <text>The medical director of the agency shall establish a CE Instructor approval process. The process shall be documented and the documentation shall be subject to inspection and verification by officials from the District EMS Officer or designee at any
      time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 16569 (December 6, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>