<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-512</num>
  <heading>EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES AGENCY VEHICLES[COLON] AIR AMBULANCES (§ 29-512)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>512.1</num>
    <text>512.1 An aircraft maintained and operated for response to the location of a medical emergency to provide immediate medical care at the basic or advanced life support level and for the transportation of patients shall be certified as an emergency medical
      response vehicle, operating as an air ambulance, pursuant to § 510.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>512.2</num>
    <text>512.2 An air ambulance shall be commercially constructed and certified to comply with the U.S. Federal Aviation Administration standards in effect on the date of its construction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>512.3.</num>
    <text>An air ambulance shall be constructed to provide sufficient space for safe storage of the equipment and supplies required by this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>512.4.</num>
    <text>Equipment and supplies as specified in the Emergency Medical Services Agency’s protocols shall be available for access and use from inside the patient compartment of the air ambulance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>512.5</num>
    <text>512.5 An air medical certificate shall be issued if all of the following conditions are met:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>All information contained in the application is complete;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The applicant is a certified District Emergency Medical Services Agency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The aircraft is registered with the Federal Aviation Administration; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The aircraft meets the minimum requirements as provided in this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>512.6</num>
    <text>512.6 An air ambulance certificate shall not be sold, transferred, or assigned without the approval of the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 16569 (December 6, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>