<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-5619</num>
  <heading>SANCTIONS FOR NON-COMPLIANCE (§ 29-5619)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5619.1.</num>
    <text>If the Department determines that the managed care provider has failed to comply with the provisions of this chapter or other applicable federal or District law or regulations, the Department may:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Suspend further enrollment of eligible children by the managed care provider;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Withhold part of the provider’s Medicaid payments;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Use all or part of the deposit detailed in §5602.2; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Terminate the Medicaid managed care provider agreement within thirty (30) days from the date of notice of termination to the managed care provider.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5619.2.</num>
    <text>Before taking any action described in §5619.1, the Department shall provide written notice which shall include at lease the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Citation of the law or regulation which has been violated;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Sanction to be applied and the date the sanction will be imposed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Basis for the Department’s determination that the sanction should be imposed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Timeframe and procedure for the managed care provider to appeal the District’s determination.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5619.3.</num>
    <text>A provider’s appeal of action pursuant to §5619.1(a) and (b) shall stay the effective date of the proposed action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5619.4.</num>
    <text>The Department shall provide reasonable written notice of a proposed sanction to eligible children enrolled in the managed care provider’s plan and others who may be affected by the proposed sanction. Notice to enrolled children shall be by first-class
      mail, postage prepaid, at the address reflected in the Department’s records.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5619.5.</num>
    <text>Except as specifically provided in this section, 29 DCMR Chapter 13 shall apply to any administrative action taken with respect to the managed care provider’s participation in the program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 43 DCR 4833, 4854 (September 6, 1996).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>