<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-5604</num>
  <heading>MARKETING (§ 29-5604)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5604.1.</num>
    <text>The managed care provider shall submit to the Department for its prior written approval all marketing plans, procedures, and materials including the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Marketing policies and manuals;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Written descriptions of proposed marketing approaches;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Marketing brochures and fliers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Advertising copy and public service announcements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Enrollment training guidelines; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Examples of any nominal value marketing gifts.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5604.2.</num>
    <text>The managed care provider shall not engage in any deceptive marketing practice that misleads, confuses, or defrauds an eligible child or the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5604.3.</num>
    <text>Marketing materials distributed to eligible children for use in selecting a primary care provider, as defined in §5799, shall be clear and shall include at least the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A statement that enrollment in the managed care provider’s plan is voluntary;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A statement that all necessary health care must be obtained through the managed care provider;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A description of the evidence of coverage, including excluded services and limitations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The days and hours of service;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The address of each facility or service site;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A description of the procedures to follow to receive services after hours;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A description of the procedures to follow to receive urgent care and emergency services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Telephone numbers to access emergency care services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>A statement that disenrollment from the managed care provider’s plan is subject to the limitations described in Chapter 57;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>A description of the managed care provider’s grievance process, including methods for filing grievances and the right of an enrolled child to receive assistance from a personal representative of the child’s or family’s choice; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>A statement of the enrolled child’s rights and responsibilities.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5604.4.</num>
    <text>The managed care provider shall not provide cash, gift incentives, or rebates to eligible children.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5604.5.</num>
    <text>The managed care provider shall not claim or assert superior medical care or provider skills or make untruthful, misleading or deceptive statements regarding the merits of its plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5604.6.</num>
    <text>The managed care provider shall not compensate marketing representatives based on commissions or other incentives that are based upon the number of eligible children enrolled in the provider’s plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5604.7.</num>
    <text>Each eligible child in the category or categories covered under the managed care provider agreement shall be considered a potential enrollee and may not be discriminated against on the basis of health status or need for health care services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5604.8.</num>
    <text>The managed care provider shall not represent to an eligible child that he or she is required to enroll in the provider’s plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 43 DCR 4833, 4839 (September 6, 1996).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>