<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-501</num>
  <heading>AMBULANCE SERVICES (ยง 29-501)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>501.1</num>
    <text>501.1 No person shall operate or hold itself out as operating an ambulance in the District unless the operator holds a currently valid certificate issued pursuant to this chapter for that ambulance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.2.</num>
    <text>No person shall advertise or disseminate information to the public that emergency medical technician ambulance service is offered unless that service is:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Provided by District-certified emergency medical technicians;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Operating District-certified basic life support ambulances, as defined by the Director pursuant to ยง 510 of this chapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Operating on a continuous twenty-four (24) hour per day basis except for those agencies providing special event coverage.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.3.</num>
    <text>No person shall advertise or disseminate information to the public that paramedic ambulance services are offered unless that service is:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Provided by District-certified paramedics;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Operating District-certified advanced life support ambulances, as defined by the Director pursuant to ยง 510; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Operating on a continuous twenty-four (24) hour per day basis.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.4.</num>
    <text>Advertising or information regarding ambulance services may only appear on emergency medical response vehicles, as defined in to ยง 510, used on a continuous twenty-four (24) hour per day basis to provide service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Rules of the Board of Public Welfare issued July 28, 1950; as amended on September 29, 1950; and by Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 8542 (December 4, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 16569 (December 6, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>