<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-5804</num>
  <heading>WORK PARTICIPATION STANDARDS (ยง 29-5804)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5804.1.</num>
    <text>Work participation standards governing the TANF Program shall be:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Work Participation Rates for all Families:</text>
    </level>
    <text>FY 1998&amp;#8211;30% FY 2001&amp;#8211;45%</text>
    <text>FY 1999&amp;#8211;35% FY 2002 and beyond&amp;#8211;50%</text>
    <text>FY 2000&amp;#8211;40%</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Work Participation Rates for Two-Parent Families:</text>
    </level>
    <text>FY 1998&amp;#8211;75%</text>
    <text>FY 1999 and beyond&amp;#8211;90%</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5804.2.</num>
    <text>Each TANF recipient shall participate in work activities the following minimum number of hours per week (averaged over a month):</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Single-Parent Families (including families with two parents, one of whom is incapacitated or disabled):</text>
    </level>
    <text>FY 1998 20 Hours</text>
    <text>FY 1999 25 Hours</text>
    <text>FY 2000 and beyond 30 Hours</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Two-Parent Families, who do not receive federally-funded child care and no adult in the family is disabled or caring for a child with a disability:</text>
    </level>
    <text>FY 1998 and beyond 35 Hours</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Two-Parent Families, who receive federally-funded child care and no adult in the family is incapacitated:</text>
    </level>
    <text>FY 1998 and beyond 55 Hours (both parents)</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5804.3.</num>
    <text>Single-parent families and two-parent families in which one parent is incapacitated or disabled shall participate in &amp;#8220;countable&amp;#8221; work activities, as defined in subsection 5804.4, for at least twenty (20) hours each week. Two-parent
      families (in which neither parent is incapacitated or disabled) shall participate in &amp;#8220;countable&amp;#8221; work activities, as defined in subsection 5804.4, for at least thirty (30) hours each week. Additional hours of participation needed
      to meet the hourly requirements as defined in subsection 5804.2 may consist of education, job training, or other approved employment-related activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5804.4.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, &amp;#8220;countable work activities&amp;#8221; are defined as unsubsidized employment, subsidized employment, on-the-job training, work experience, community service, job readiness, job search, and vocational educational
      training.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5804.5.</num>
    <text>Work participation standards shall comply with the requirements of Chapter 10 of Title 7 DCMR.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 10251 (November 9, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>