<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-5103</num>
  <heading>HOME HEALTH AIDES (ยง 29-5103)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5103.1.</num>
    <text>Each home health aide shall meet the following qualifications:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Be at least 18 years of age;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Be a citizen of the United States or an alien who is lawfully authorized to work in the United States;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Complete a home health aide training program that includes at least seventy- five (75) hours of classroom training with at least sixteen (16) hours devoted to supervised practical training and pass a competency evaluation for those services which
        the home health aide is required to perform consistent with the requirements set forth in 42 CFR 484.36;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Be certified in cardiopulmonary resuscitation (&amp;#8220;CPR&amp;#8221;) and thereafter obtain CPR certification annually;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Be able to read and write the English language at the fifth (5th) grade level and carry out instructions and directions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Be able to recognize an emergency and be knowledgeable about emergency procedures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Be knowledgeable about infection control procedures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Be acceptable to the patient;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>Demonstrate annually that he or she is free from communicable disease as confirmed by an annual PPD Skin Test or documentation from a physician stating that the person is free from communicable disease;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>Pass a criminal background check pursuant to the Health-Care Facility Unlicensed Personnel Criminal Background Check Act of 1998, effective April 20, 1999 (D.C. Law 12-238; D.C. Official Code, ยง 44-551 et seq.); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>Provide documentation of acceptance or declination of the Hepatitis vaccine.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5103.2.</num>
    <text>After the first year of service, each home health aide shall complete at least twelve hours of continuing education or in-service training annually. The in-service training may be furnished while the aide is furnishing care to the patient under the
      supervision of a registered nurse or other appropriate health care professional.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 3957 (May 23, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>