<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-5835</num>
  <heading>PAYMENT OF DIVERSION PAYMENTS (ยง 29-5835)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5835.1.</num>
    <text>In all possible circumstances, when an original bill is submitted and verified for the cost of the covered need, the Department shall issue the Diversion Payment directly to the entity to which the applicant owes money. If this entity refuses to accept
      a direct payment, the Department shall issue the Diversion Payment jointly to the entity and the applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5835.2.</num>
    <text>In all possible circumstances, when estimates are submitted and verified for the cost of the covered need, the Department shall issue the Diversion Payment directly to the entity which submitted the lowest cost estimate. If this entity refuses a direct
      payment, the Department shall issue the Diversion Payment jointly to the entity and the applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5835.3.</num>
    <text>In all cases, the Department shall within seven (7) days inform the entity that is being paid, either directly or jointly that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The amount of the Diversion Payment that will be made by the Department;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>It is preferred that the service or good be provided or delivered as soon as possible, with payment to follow; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>In any event, a confirmation letter providing the details of the Diversion Payment will be mailed to the entity.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5835.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant may not receive another payment for Diversion Assistance until twelve (12) months have elapsed since the authorization of the prior payment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5835.5.</num>
    <text>Whenever possible, payment to an entity shall be made within fourteen (14) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 10251 (November 9, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>