<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-542</num>
  <heading>EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICE EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTION CURRICULUM STANDARDS (ยง9-542)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>542.1.</num>
    <text>The Director shall approve all EMS course curricula that are intended to be used for certification, continuing education, and refresher courses that are taught in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>542.2</num>
    <text>542.2 Courses that are taught in the District of Columbia prior to the curriculum being approved will not be approved retroactively.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>542.3.</num>
    <text>Curricula shall conform to, and instruct according to, current national standards and guidelines, including current NREMT standards.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>542.4.</num>
    <text>In order to receive District approval of an EMS curriculum and to be eligible to use that curriculum in a certification, continuing education or refresher course, an EMS educational institution or Emergency Medical Services Agency shall file an application
      with the Director. The application shall include the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Program director;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Curriculum author;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Curriculum title; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Topic area (ALS or BLS).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>542.5.</num>
    <text>A curriculum application shall be filed at least forty-five (45) days before the educational institution or Emergency Medical Services Agency intends to use the curriculum in a course.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>542.6.</num>
    <text>All curricula submitted to the Director shall be assigned a curriculum tracking number. A tracking number shall be assigned regardless of whether the curriculum is approved or denied. The tracking number shall be used in all correspondence related
      to the curriculum.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>542.7.</num>
    <text>To maintain approval by the Director a course curriculum shall be updated to remain current with nationally accepted standards. Any updates to the curriculum shall be submitted to the Director as a new curriculum as outlined in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>542.8.</num>
    <text>Curricula that are currently approved by the Continuing Education Coordinating Board for Emergency Medical Services (CECBEMS) do not need to be submitted for District approval.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>542.9.</num>
    <text>The educational institution or Emergency Medical Services Agency shall submit a curriculum application along with a copy of the CECBEMS curriculum approval documentation to obtain a DOH curriculum number. The DOH curriculum number shall be used on
      the course application when used in a District course.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 16569 (December 6, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>