<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6019</num>
  <heading>HEALTH CARE (ยง 29-6019)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6019.1.</num>
    <text>A foster parent and the agency shall cooperate with the DC KIDS program in identifying and meeting the health care needs of the foster child.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6019.2.</num>
    <text>The foster child&amp;#8217;s health care shall include a medical screen within twenty-four (24) hours of placement and a full medical and dental examination within two (2) weeks, arranged by the child&amp;#8217;s social worker.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6019.3.</num>
    <text>A foster parent and the agency shall cooperate in planning to meet the health care needs of a foster child as identified through the DC KIDS program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6019.4.</num>
    <text>A foster parent may not consent to health care for a foster child. The foster parent shall notify the agency immediately of any situation requiring consent to health care.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6019.5.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall make and keep all health care appointments for the foster child, as identified through the DC KIDS program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6019.6.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall be responsible for transporting each foster child to all health care appointments. Assistance from the agency may be provided under special circumstances.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6019.7.</num>
    <text>Prescription medications shall be given to a foster child only on the instructions of a physician or other licensed medical practitioner. The foster parent shall supervise and administer the exact amount of the medication.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6019.8.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall inform CFSA and the agency within one (1) business day if a licensed medical practitioner prescribes any medication that is to be taken for more than five (5) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6019.9.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall provide a nutritionally balanced diet adequate for the foster child&amp;#8217;s growth and development.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 6617 (July 27, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>