<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6017</num>
  <heading>CLOTHING AND PERSONAL BELONGINGS (ยง 29-6017)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6017.1.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall provide each foster child with his or her own clean, well-fitting, attractive, and seasonal clothing appropriate to the foster child&amp;#8217;s age, gender, and individual needs, and comparable to community standards. The purchase
      of this clothing shall come from the money allotted within the foster care board and care payments.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6017.2.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall permit the foster child to choose her or his own clothing whenever possible.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6017.3.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall allow each foster child to bring and acquire personal belongings, and shall provide reasonable and private child-accessible space for storage.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6017.4.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall send all personal clothing and belongings with each foster child when the foster child leaves the foster home. A foster parent may not keep any clothing when a foster child leaves the foster home unless the clothing is clearly
      too small for the foster child and would not fit a sibling who is in placement with the foster child.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6017.5.</num>
    <text>Each foster child shall have sufficient suitcases, backpacks, or trunks for the transportation of the foster child&amp;#8217;s personal clothing and belongings. CFSA shall ensure that each foster child has sufficient containers to hold all of the
      foster child&amp;#8217;s clothes and belongings when the foster child is placed in the foster home. The foster parent shall ensure that the foster child leaves the foster home with sufficient containers to hold all of the foster child&amp;#8217;s
      clothes and belongings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6017.6.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall maintain an annual updated clothing inventory for each foster child in her or his care.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 6617 (July 27, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>