<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6232</num>
  <heading>BUILDINGS, GROUNDS AND EQUIPMENT (ยง 29-6232)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6232.1.</num>
    <text>All existing facilities and new facilities shall be constructed and maintained reasonably to protect and to ensure the safety of all present and future staff and residents.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6232.2.</num>
    <text>All existing and new facilities shall be constructed and maintained to promote a home-like environment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6232.3.</num>
    <text>All existing and new facilities shall comply with all local and federal laws, including but not limited to laws relating to construction, electrical, and lead paint standards.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6232.4.</num>
    <text>The facility shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Maintain all grounds, structures and equipment free from any hazard to the staff or residents&amp;#8217; health or safety;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Equip with a railing all stairways containing more than four steps that are accessible to residents and guard with a safety gate all stairways accessible to residents aged three (3) and under;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Assure that all locks on doors to any room or storage area in which a resident could be locked are of the type which permit the door to be unlocked from either side of the door;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Assure that all doors on toilet stalls and bathtub or shower stalls are of the type which permit the door to be unlatched from either side of the door unless the stall is of such construction as to permit emergency access by climbing over or crawling
        under the partitions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Maintain all exits, exit accesses and exit discharge areas free from obstructions or impediments and clearly marked to facilitate ingress and egress;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Assure that all areas accessible to residents aged three (3) and under shall be child-proofed appropriately, including but not limited to, covering electrical outlets, latching or locking cabinets, protecting sharp corners, and keeping poisonous
        plants, cosmetics, appliances and small items that could be swallowed outside a resident&amp;#8217;s reach; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Maintain for all windows operable screens in good repair.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 8675, 8712 (September 21, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>