<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6009</num>
  <heading>CHILD PROTECTION REGISTER CHECK (ยง 29-6009)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6009.1.</num>
    <text>As part of the home study process, an agency shall receive a clearance from the District&amp;#8217;s child protection register and from the child protection registers in every state in which any of the persons listed in ยง 6009.2 resided or worked
      from the time the person was eighteen (18) years of age or older.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6009.2.</num>
    <text>The following individuals shall apply for a child protection register clearance:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An applicant; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any other person eighteen (18) years of age or older residing in the prospective foster home.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6009.3.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in ยง 6009.4, CFSA may not license an individual as a foster parent if that individual or any person eighteen (18) years of age or older residing in the prospective foster home is:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Identified as a possible abuser or neglecter in an open child abuse or neglect case; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Identified as the abuser or neglecter in a supported case of child abuse or neglect.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6009.4.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding ยง 6009.3, CFSA may license an individual as a foster parent if it determines, after the individual&amp;#8217;s satisfactory completion of all other requirements of this chapter of the DCMR and a review of the child abuse or neglect
      case and current circumstances, that the individual would be able to provide care for foster children consistent with this chapter of the DCMR and the health, safety, and welfare of the children.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6009.5.</num>
    <text>A child protection register check shall be performed on any household member eighteen (18) years of age or older once every year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 6617 (July 27, 2001); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 8609 (September 3, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>