<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6029</num>
  <heading>DENIAL OF LICENSE OR RENEWAL (ยง 29-6029)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6029.1.</num>
    <text>CFSA shall deny an application for a license or a renewal if it determines that the applicant or foster parent cannot provide for the health, safety, or welfare of foster children. Factors to be considered in determining whether an applicant or foster
      parent can provide for the health, safety, or welfare of foster children include, but are not limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The applicant, foster parent, household member, prospective foster home or foster home violates or fails to comply with any provision of this chapter of the DCMR;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>CFSA&amp;#8217;s evaluation of the application reveals that the applicant or foster parent knowingly reported false information;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The applicant or foster parent has a history of regulatory violations which demonstrate an inability to provide for the health and safety of children;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A previous license or renewal was denied or revoked by CFSA;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The applicant prevents CFSA or the agency from completing the application or renewal process; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Abuse of alcohol or other controlled dangerous substances, mental instability, or ongoing health problems, by or of the applicant, foster parent, or a household member.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6029.2.</num>
    <text>CFSA may deny an application for a license or a renewal for other good cause.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 6617 (July 27, 2001); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 8609 (September 3, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>