<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6026</num>
  <heading>FOSTER PARENT TRAINING (§ 29-6026)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6026.1.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall participate in an orientation program offered by the agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6026.2.</num>
    <text>In addition to the orientation program required by § 6026.1, an applicant shall participate in thirty (30) hours of pre-service training offered by the agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6026.3.</num>
    <text>Pre-service training shall encompass the following areas:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Role and relationships in foster care between CFSA, agency personnel, the foster parent, the foster child, and the foster child&amp;#8217;s family;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The importance of the foster child&amp;#8217;s family and the foster child&amp;#8217;s relationship with them;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Developmental needs of children in foster care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Awareness of cultural and religious differences;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Child management and discipline techniques;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Child abuse and neglect, including prevention, reporting, investigation, and services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Supportive services available in the community for foster children and foster parents and their families;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Self-awareness;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Communication skills;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Problem solving;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>This chapter of the DCMR;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>The licensure process, including the agency&amp;#8217;s internal processes; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>The procedures and practices of the Family Division of the District of Columbia Superior Court related to children in foster care.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6026.4.</num>
    <text>In lieu of the training required by § 6026.2, an agency may accept training provided by another child-placing agency and completed satisfactorily by the applicant if the training and participation is properly documented and covers required areas.
      The agency may offer special sessions to cover any gaps in training.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6026.5</num>
    <text>6026.5 A foster parent shall participate in thirty (30) hours of in-service training to increase her or his skills and parenting abilities before the expiration of his or her license. This training shall be appropriate to the age and special needs
      of the foster children in the foster home, and may include formal seminars or workshops, support groups, or one-on-one training.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6026.6.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall obtain and maintain documentation of any training in which the foster parent participates in accordance with § 6026.5 and submit such documentation during the re-evaluation in accordance with § 6029.3.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6026.7.</num>
    <text>To meet the fifteen (15) hour requirement, in-service training shall be approved in advance by the agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 6617 (July 27, 2001); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 10669, 10670 (September 7, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>