<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6803</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION PROCESS (§ 29-6803)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6803.1.</num>
    <text>Each applicant shall submit a completed application packet.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6803.2.</num>
    <text>The application packet shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The application form, which shall include a signed statement, sworn under penalty of perjury, that all information provided in the application packet is true and accurate to the best belief of the applicant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Proof that the applicant is the grandparent, great-grandparent, great-aunt or great-uncle of the child;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Proof that the applicant is the primary caregiver as provided in § 6804;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The original results of a criminal background check, dated within one (1) year of the application;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A completed application for a Child Protection Register check;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Proof of application for TANF benefits on behalf of the child through the District of Columbia Department of Human Services, Income Maintenance Administration;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Proof that the child has resided with the applicant on a continuous basis for at least the most recent six (6) months. A sworn statement on the application is sufficient proof;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Proof that the child&amp;#8217;s parent has not resided in the applicant&amp;#8217;s home for at least the most recent six (6) months or proof of the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The parent has designated the applicant to be the child&amp;#8217;s standby guardian pursuant to Chapter 48 of Title 16 of the D.C. Official Code;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The parent is a minor enrolled in school; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The parent is a minor with a medically verifiable disability that prevents him or her from caring for the child;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Proof of household income; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Proof that the applicant resides in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6803.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall be ineligible for a subsidy if the application is not complete, if it is determined that the applicant made false statements in the application packet, or if any of the eligibility requirements set forth in § 6802 are not met. An
      application is incomplete if the requirements of §§ 6803.1 and 6803.2 are not met.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6803.4.</num>
    <text>CFSA shall complete its review of the application, determine the applicant&amp;#8217;s eligibility, and notify the applicant in writing of its decision within forty-five (45) days of receipt of a completed application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6803.5.</num>
    <text>Any statement under this section made with knowledge that the information set forth therein is false shall be subject to prosecution as a false statement under D.C. Official Code § 22-2405(a) and punishable by a fine of not more than $1,000 or imprisonment
      for not more than 180 days, or both.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 5837 (July 21, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12482 (December 12, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>