<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6808</num>
  <heading>RECERTIFICATION (ยง 29-6808)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6808.1.</num>
    <text>If the applicant seeks recertification of the subsidy, CFSA shall conduct a review of the subsidy to determine whether the recipient remains eligible in accordance with this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6808.2.</num>
    <text>The recipient shall establish continued eligibility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6808.3.</num>
    <text>The recipient shall submit a recertification application packet at least sixty (60) days but not more than ninety (90) days prior to the expiration of the subsidy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6808.4.</num>
    <text>The application packet shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A signed statement, sworn under penalty of perjury, that all information provided to establish continued eligibility is true and accurate to the best belief of the recipient and that there has been no material change in circumstance since the recipient
        was initially determined to be eligible for a subsidy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Updated criminal background check every two years from the date of the initial application;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Updated child protection register checks; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Current school attendance records for all school age children receiving the subsidy.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6808.5.</num>
    <text>If a recipient fails to submit an application for recertification or fails to cooperate with CFSA in its conduct of the review, CFSA may terminate the grandparent caretaker subsidy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 5837 (July 21, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12482 (December 12, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 5922 (July 9, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>