<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6024</num>
  <heading>ABUSE, NEGLECT, OR OTHER RISKS TO FOSTER CHILD&amp;#8217;S HEALTH OR SAFETY (§9-6024)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6024.1.</num>
    <text>CFSA shall conduct an investigation, in accordance with the time lines set forth by District law, to assess compliance with this chapter of the DCMR and the ability of a foster parent to provide for a foster child&amp;#8217;s health and safety after
      receiving information indicating:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Suspected abuse or neglect in a foster home; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any other information indicating a suspected risk to a foster child&amp;#8217;s health or safety from the foster parent or in the foster home.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6024.2.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, &amp;#8220;Hotline&amp;#8221; means the Child Abuse and Neglect Hotline.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6024.3.</num>
    <text>Any agency employee who receives information concerning or makes a personal observation of suspected abuse or neglect in a foster home, or who has any other information indicating a suspected risk to a foster child&amp;#8217;s health or safety from
      a foster parent or in a foster home, shall immediately notify:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Hotline (202-671-SAFE);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The social worker or supervisor for the foster child who is the subject of the report; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The social worker or supervisor for each foster child who was living in the foster home when the incident occurred.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6024.4.</num>
    <text>Any agency employee who observes that a child placed in a foster home is in serious and immediate danger shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Take immediate steps to protect the foster child including, as appropriate, removing the foster child from the foster home; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Immediately notify:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Hotline (202-671-SAFE);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The social worker or supervisor for the child who is the subject of the report; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The social worker or supervisor for each foster child who was living in the foster home when the incident occurred.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6024.5.</num>
    <text>The notification to the Hotline made pursuant to §§ 6024.3 or 6024.4 shall include informing the Hotline that the child is a foster child and providing the name, address, and telephone numbers of the foster parent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6024.6.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of notification pursuant to §§ 6024.3 or 6024.4 the Hotline shall immediately notify:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>CFSA monitoring and placement staff; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Director or designee.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6024.7.</num>
    <text>CFSA shall respond to the notification received pursuant to §§ 6024.3 or 6024.4 as required by District law and CFSA policy, including, but not limited to, by conducting an investigation and, as appropriate, suspending or revoking a license in accordance
      with § 6030.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6024.8.</num>
    <text>The investigator, social workers for all foster children in the foster home, and monitoring and placement staff shall remain in close communication throughout any investigation undertaken pursuant to this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6024.9.</num>
    <text>If an investigation is undertaken pursuant to this section:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Additional foster children may not be placed in the foster home until the investigation is completed and CFSA determines it will continue to license the home;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Children shall be removed from the home when and as required by District law and CFSA policy; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If any foster child remains in the foster home, the agency shall visit the foster home at least once a week as long as any foster child remains in the home and until a decision is rendered as to the continued use of the home.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6024.10.</num>
    <text>Within five (5) business days after completion of an investigation undertaken pursuant to this section, CFSA shall render a written decision as to the continued use of the foster home.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6024.11.</num>
    <text>A copy of the CFSA decision concerning the continued use of the foster home shall be:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Forwarded to the agency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Placed in the foster home record; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Placed in the record of any foster child living in the home when the incident occurred.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6024.12.</num>
    <text>Upon completion of an investigation undertaken pursuant to this section, CFSA shall send written notice of the outcome of the investigation to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The agency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Court;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The foster child&amp;#8217;s parent(s);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The foster child&amp;#8217;s guardian ad litem;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The parents and guardian ad litem of any other foster child residing in the home when the incident occurred; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The parent(s) and guardian ad litem of any other foster child involved in the suspected abuse or neglect.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6024.13.</num>
    <text>Upon completion of the investigation, CFSA shall make a decision as to the continued use of the home in accordance with § 6030. CFSA shall send a copy of its decision to the foster parent and to the parents and guardians ad litem for any foster child
      living in the foster home when the incident occurred.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6024.14.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the decision reached pursuant to § 6024.13, an agency other than CFSA may decide to close a foster home based on the investigation conducted pursuant to § 6024.1. The agency shall notify CFSA in writing of a decision to close a foster
      home at least ten (10) business days prior to the effective date of the decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6024.15.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section are in addition to the requirements of law for the reporting and investigation of suspected child abuse and neglect in the District of Columbia and, if different, in the jurisdiction in which the foster home is located.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6024.16.</num>
    <text>CFSA shall discuss its findings from the investigation required by § 6024.1 with the foster parent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6024.17.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter of the DCMR, CFSA may remove a foster child from a foster home whenever such a removal would, in the judgement of CFSA, be in the best interest of the foster child&amp;#8217;s health, safety and
      welfare, or would promote the achievement of the child&amp;#8217;s case plan or permanency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 6617 (July 27, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>