<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6327</num>
  <heading>PERSONNEL POLICIES (§ 29-6327)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6327.1.</num>
    <text>At the time of her or his employment, an independent living program shall give a staff member a written description of his or her position that defines the qualifications, duties, and responsibilities of the position and his or her salary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6327.2.</num>
    <text>An independent living program shall have a written statement of personnel policies that shall be given to a staff member at the time of employment. The personnel policies shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Provisions for paid vacation, sick leave, and policy regarding holidays;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A description of any other employment benefits; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Provisions for periodic evaluations of work performance.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6327.3.</num>
    <text>An independent living program shall maintain an accurate personnel record on each staff member which shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A written application showing qualifications and experience;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Reports of medical examinations as required by §§ 6323.21 and 6323.22;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Reports of criminal records checks as required by § 6324;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Reports of child protection register checks as required by § 6325;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Dates of employment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Date of separation from employment with reason for separation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Documentation of training received pursuant to § 6326, including the type, duration, and date of training and the person or agency conducting the training;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Annual performance evaluations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Documentation of all certifications and licenses required under this Chapter in accordance with §§ 6323 and § 6343.3.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 1591 (February 22, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>