<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6007</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PHYSICAL ENVIRONMENT (ยง 29-6007)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6007.1.</num>
    <text>A foster home shall be free from all safety hazards, including fire, sanitation, and health hazards.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.2.</num>
    <text>A foster home shall be properly ventilated and heated.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.3.</num>
    <text>A foster home shall have and use protective devices on all windows to prevent a child from falling out of the window.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.4.</num>
    <text>A foster home shall have and use screens on all windows that are opened.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.5.</num>
    <text>A foster home shall have and use safety locks on all windows and doors on or above the second floor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.6.</num>
    <text>A foster home shall have a working, non-coin operated, telephone.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.7.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall store all medications, poisonous chemicals, and hazardous materials in locked storage out of the reach of children.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.8.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall store alcoholic beverages safely out of the reach of children.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.9.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall be in compliance with all laws concerning firearms in the jurisdiction in which the foster home is located. Notwithstanding the law in the jurisdictions, all firearms shall be:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Stored unloaded and in a locked container that is inaccessible to children;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Equipped with and use properly a tamper-resistant mechanical lock or other safety device, that, when properly engaged will render the firearm inoperable by any person other than the owner or other lawfully authorized user; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Stored separately from any ammunition, which shall be stored in locked storage that is inaccessible to children.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.10.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall have comprehensive first aid supplies, including at a minimum, syrup of ipecac, Band-Aids, rubbing alcohol, peroxide, and the phone number for poison control.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.11.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall monitor foster children&amp;#8217;s safety around animals and shall restrict foster children&amp;#8217;s access to potentially dangerous animals. All foster home pets shall be properly vaccinated and licensed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.12.</num>
    <text>A foster home shall have no more pets than can be cared for appropriately, consistent with the health, safely, and welfare of the children, and the size and location of the foster home.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.13.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall maintain a kitchen with the necessary equipment for safe food preparation, food storage, serving, and cleanup of meals.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.14.</num>
    <text>A foster home shall have living room or family room space that is adequately furnished and accessible to all members of the household, including foster children.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.15.</num>
    <text>A foster home shall have a designated dining area.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.16.</num>
    <text>A foster child&amp;#8217;s bedroom shall have at least two (2) means of egress, each on a different side of the room.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.17.</num>
    <text>A foster child under fourteen (14) years of age may not sleep in a bedroom located in the basement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.18.</num>
    <text>A foster child&amp;#8217;s bedroom shall be sufficient in size to provide for the safety, privacy, and comfort of the foster child. The following bedroom sizes shall be used as general guidelines for adequate square footage:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Seventy (70) square feet for one (1) foster child;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>One hundred (100) square feet for two (2) foster children; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>One hundred fifty (150) square feet for three (3) foster children.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.19.</num>
    <text>CFSA may license a foster home with bedrooms that do not meet the general guidelines in ยง 6007.18 if CFSA finds and has documented that the available space is adequate to provide for safety, privacy, and comfort of each foster child.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.20.</num>
    <text>No more than three (3) children may share a room regardless of the room&amp;#8217;s size.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.21.</num>
    <text>No foster child over the age of five (5) may share a room with a child of the opposite gender.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.22.</num>
    <text>No foster child over eighteen (18) months of age may share a bedroom with an adult.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.23.</num>
    <text>A foster parent or a responsible adult shall sleep within call of each foster child as appropriate to the foster child&amp;#8217;s age, capabilities, and individual needs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.24.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall provide each foster child with his or her own individual bed and each infant foster child with his or her own individual crib which meets Consumer Product Safety Commission standards. The bed may not be a cot, sofa, or any type
      of portable bed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.25.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall provide each foster child with a clean non-toxic mattress, waterproof cover (as necessary), clean bed linens, and sufficient blankets and pillows.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.26.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall provide sufficient individual storage space for each foster child&amp;#8217;s clothing and other personal belongings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.27.</num>
    <text>A foster home shall have a minimum of one (1) flush toilet, one (1) wash basin with running water, and one (1) bath or shower with hot and cold water for every eight (8) residents.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6007.28.</num>
    <text>A foster parent who lives in an apartment building shall obtain evidence from the building manager or landlord that the building has been approved for fire safety within the last two (2) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 6617 (July 27, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>