<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6307</num>
  <heading>ORIGINAL ANNUAL LICENSE (§ 29-6307)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6307.1.</num>
    <text>An original annual license:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Permits the operation of an independent living program pursuant to the terms of this Chapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Is valid for no more than one (1) year from the date it is issued.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6307.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant for an original annual license shall submit the following with the application:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A statement of the ownership of the independent living program, including the names and addresses of all owners or, in the case of corporations, the officers and board members;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Copies of all certificates of approval, authority, occupancy, or need that are required as a precondition to lawful operation in the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A projected one (1) year operating budget;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Documentation of sufficient funds on hand to operate the independent program for at least three (3) months;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Financial statements (including, without limitation, cash flow statement, income statement, and balance sheet), independently audited, prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles for each of the immediately preceding two
        (2) years, or the duration of the applicant&amp;#8217;s existence, whichever is shorter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Copies of insurance information required under § 6316;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A written plan for satisfying the requirements of the fire safety law in the jurisdiction in which the main facility and residences are located, including a fire evacuation plan and exit drills;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>A written plan for meeting residents&amp;#8217; emergency medical needs, including access to emergency mental health services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Documentation of compliance with § 6324 concerning criminal records checks;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Documentation of compliance with § 6325 concerning child protection register checks;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Documentation of compliance with §§ 6323.20 &amp;#8211; 6323.22 concerning the health of and medical examinations for prospective and existing staff; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>A written plan for compliance with the requirements set forth in this Chapter concerning:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Abuse, neglect, or other risks to residents&amp;#8217; health and safety pursuant to § 6304;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Grievance procedure pursuant to § 6305;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Unusual incidents pursuant to § 6319;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Personnel pursuant to § 6323;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Personnel policies pursuant to § 6327;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Emergency plan pursuant to § 6335;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Prohibited and illegal devices and substances pursuant to § 6337;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Health care pursuant to § 6342;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Recreational activities pursuant to § 6344;</text>
    </level>
    <text>(10) Behavior management and discipline pursuant to § 6347; and</text>
    <text>(11) Discharge pursuant to § 6348.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6307.3.</num>
    <text>CFSA shall review an application for an original annual license and either grant or deny the application or grant a provisional or restricted license, within sixty (60) days of receipt of the completed application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6307.4.</num>
    <text>CFSA shall notify an applicant in writing of the decision to grant or deny an original annual license application, or to grant a provisional or restricted license. The notice shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A statement of the grounds for the decision; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An explanation of the right to and the method of requesting a fair hearing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6307.5.</num>
    <text>If CFSA decides to grant the application, it shall issue the license within two (2) business days of its decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 1591 (February 22, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>