<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6499</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 29-6499)
    <text>For the purposes of this Chapter, the following terms shall have the meaningscribed:</text>
    <text>AIDS &amp;#8211; acquired immune deficiency syndrome.</text>
    <text>COBRA- Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1986. This programdministered by the United States Department of Labor and the United Statesension and Welfare Benefits Administration allows an employee who voluntarilyesigns from employment
      or is terminated for any reason other than &amp;#8220;grossisconduct&amp;#8221; to continue their former employer&amp;#8217;s group health planboth for individual and family coverage) coverage for a period up to eighteen18) months from the effective
      date of employment termination or resignation.</text>
    <text>Demonstration Project &amp;#8211; as authorized under Section 1115 of the Socialecurity Act.</text>
    <text>DOH &amp;#8211; Department of Health.</text>
    <text>DOH HIV Pharmacy Network &amp;#8211; group of participating pharmacies thatistribute anti-retrovirals and other HIV-related medications for theemonstration Project, Medicaid, and the ADAP.</text>
    <text>Enrollment ceiling &amp;#8211; the limit on the number of recipients in theemonstration Project.</text>
    <text>Gross income &amp;#8211; total pre-tax income for a household; this amount includesll income that the Income Maintenance Administration and other agencies mayisregard in their eligibility determinations for other programs (includingurrent law Medicaid).</text>
    <text>HAART &amp;#8211; Highly Active Anti-Retroviral Therapy. A broad category ofreatment regimens for individuals with HIV usually comprised of three (3) orore anti-retroviral drugs that, in previously untreated HIV-1-infectedatients, are expected to
      reduce plasma virus levels below the limits ofetection. Most HAART regimens include drugs from at least two (2) of the three3) classes of anti-retroviral therapy (nucleoside analog reverse transcriptaseRT) inhibitors, non-nucleoside analog RT inhibitors,
      and protease inhibitors).</text>
    <text>HIV &amp;#8211; human immunodeficiency virus. A retrovirus that causes AIDS,ormerly known as HTLV-III.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Emergency Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 5605 (May 28, 2004) [EXPIRED];s amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 7435 (July 30, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>