<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6001</num>
  <heading>FOSTER PARENT REQUIREMENTS (§ 29-6001)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6001.1.</num>
    <text>An agency shall select and maintain as foster parents individuals who have the following characteristics:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Knowledge of, interest in, and regard for the principles of good child care and understanding of the foster parent&amp;#8217;s responsibility in providing care for a foster child;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The willingness to work with CFSA and agency personnel in the best interest of the foster child;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Maturity and personality characteristics which:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Make it possible to provide an emotional climate in which a foster child can benefit during temporary care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Create an atmosphere in which social skills can be enriched;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Help a foster child to understand placement in foster care and the child&amp;#8217;s own feelings about the placement; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Help maintain family ties through regular and consistent family contact in accordance with a foster child&amp;#8217;s case plan;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The flexibility to understand and work with lifestyles different from the foster parent&amp;#8217;s;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The capacity to value, respect, appreciate, and educate a foster child regarding the child&amp;#8217;s racial, ethnic, religious, and cultural heritage;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The capacity to understand that it is in the best interest of a foster child of mixed racial parentage to have healthy multiracial experiences;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The suitability and stamina to meet the demands of caring for growing foster children;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The willingness to support and encourage a foster child&amp;#8217;s educational progress, and take an active role by attending school conferences and similar activities whenever possible;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The ability to give a foster child the needed care and attention;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>The ability to provide a nurturing family life and meet the needs of a foster child, notwithstanding any employment outside the home; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>Awareness of the way in which a child needs family life to grow and learn, and the ability to provide a foster child with the skills and values which a parent customarily provides.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6001.2.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall be at least twenty-one (21) years of age.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6001.3.</num>
    <text>A foster parent and all household members shall be in good health as documented by a health examination within the previous twenty-four (24) months.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6001.4.</num>
    <text>If a foster parent or household member has symptoms or a history of physical or mental health problems or has recently been under the care of a physician for either of the above, CFSA or the agency may require the individual to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Undergo additional medical examinations of a general or specific nature; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Provide a written statement by the examining or treating physician to the effect that the health problem poses no threat to the foster child.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6001.5.</num>
    <text>A foster parent and all household members shall be free of disease in communicable form, as certified by a physician. Each child in the household shall be in compliance with the immunization requirements of the jurisdiction in which the foster home
      is located.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6001.6.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall have sufficient family income to meet the reasonable living needs of his or her own family without relying on foster care board and care payments.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6001.7.</num>
    <text>A criminal records check and a child protection register clearance shall be performed as set forth in §§ 6008 and 6009.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6001.8</num>
    <text>6001.8 A foster parent shall possess current American Red Cross Standard First Aid and infant, adult, and child Cardio-Pulmonary Resuscitation (CPR) certifications before being licensed to care for a foster child.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6001.9</num>
    <text>6001.9 The CPR and American Red Cross Standard First Aid certification training shall be approved by the American Red Cross, American Heart Association or the District of Columbia Department of Health.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 6617 (July 27, 2001); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 10669 (September 7, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>