<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6399</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 29-6399)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6399.1.</num>
    <text>The following terms and phrases shall have the meanings described:</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Adolescents and young adults&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; Persons age sixteen (16) to twenty-one (21) years of age.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Administrator&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; The independent living program staff member responsible for the operation of the independent living program or that person&amp;#8217;s designee.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Admission&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; The administrative process by which an adolescent or young adult becomes a resident of an independent living program.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Aftercare&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; Control, supervision, and care exercised over an adolescent or young adult after discharge from an independent living program;</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Annual license&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; Permission granted to an applicant to operate an independent living program under this chapter of the DCMR.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Apartment&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; A self-contained dwelling unit located in a building containing at least one other self-contained dwelling unit, and also containing a bedroom, kitchen, and bathroom facilities.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Audit&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; An examination of records or accounts to check their accuracy, that is conducted by a person or persons not directly involved in the creation and maintenance of the records or accounts.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Business day&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; Monday through Friday excluding legal holidays.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Case record&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; Information about a resident&amp;#8217;s situation and services that is documented by the independent living program and retained in the independent living program&amp;#8217;s files.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;CFSA&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; The District of Columbia Child and Family Services Agency.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Contracting entity&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; A public or private entity or individual that places or offers to place an adolescent or young adult in an independent living program.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;DCMR&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; District of Columbia Municipal Regulations.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Independent living program&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; A residential program for persons who:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Are sixteen (16) to twenty-one (21) years of age;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Have sufficient maturity to live without regular and continuous supervision and monitoring;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Reside in apartments; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Are provided with monitoring and services that reflect and support the person&amp;#8217;s ability to reside in the community without regular and continuous supervision and monitoring.</text>
    </level>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Initial ITILP&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; Initial Individual Transitional Independent Living Plan.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;ITILP&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; Individual Transitional Independent Living Plan.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;License&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; A license to operate an independent living program, and including, as appropriate, an original annual license, an annual license, a provisional license, and a restricted license.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Main facility&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; The central independent living program edifice that provides onsite staff supervision and which has more than one residence.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;OLM&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; The CFSA Office of Licensing and Monitoring.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Person&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; An individual, corporation, trustee, receiver, guardian, representative, firm, partnership, society, school, agency or other entity.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Planning team&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; The persons who plan a resident&amp;#8217;s initial ITILP, ITILP, or discharge plan and consisting of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A representative from the contracting entity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Staff who have direct responsibility for implementing the initial ITILP or the ITILP, as appropriate, on a daily basis;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The resident;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>To the extent that they participate, the resident&amp;#8217;s parent(s) or guardian(s) and the resident&amp;#8217;s guardian ad litem; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>To the extent that they participate, representatives of service providers including health, mental health, and education representatives.</text>
    </level>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Provisional license&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; A license that may be issued if the applicant is temporarily unable to comply with all of the requirements of this Chapter and under the condition that the requirements will be met within a specific
      length of time.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Residence&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; An apartment or single dwelling unit in which one or more residents lives.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Resident&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; A person age sixteen (16) to twenty-one (21) years of age participating in an independent living program.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Restricted license&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; A license that is issued to an independent living program that is not in compliance with these regulations that prohibits the independent living program from accepting new residents or providing
      certain specified services that it otherwise would be authorized to provide.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Staff or staff member&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; A person employed by an independent living program, including administrative staff, professional staff, support staff, consultants, and volunteers.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Variance&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; Permission given by a licensing agency to an independent living program to deviate from a requirement of this Chapter.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;YSA&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; The Youth Services Administration of the D.C. Department of Human Services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 1591 (February 22, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>