<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6212</num>
  <heading>VARIANCES (ยง 29-6212)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6212.1.</num>
    <text>The facility may submit a written request for a variance to the applicable licensing agency. The facility shall include documentation sufficient to establish that the facility&amp;#8217;s procedures comply with the intent of this Chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6212.2.</num>
    <text>The applicable licensing agency may approve a variance to any requirement contained in this Chapter upon showing of hardship and manifest public need, provided that the variance is not deleterious to the residents&amp;#8217; health, safety, or welfare.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6212.3.</num>
    <text>A variance shall remain in effect for no longer than the duration of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6212.4.</num>
    <text>The applicable licensing agency shall review and either grant or deny an application for a variance. The applicable licensing agency shall notify the facility in writing of the decision to grant or deny an application for a variance, including a statement
      of the grounds for the decision and notification of the facility&amp;#8217;s right to a fair hearing in accordance with 29 DCMR Chapter 59.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6212.5.</num>
    <text>The applicable licensing agency shall issue no variances to facilities owned or operated by the District of Columbia government.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6212.6.</num>
    <text>Upon approval of a request for a variance, the licensing agency shall mail the applicant a copy of the variance. The licensing agency shall keep copies of the variance on file.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6212.7.</num>
    <text>Variances shall be made available to the public, upon request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 8675, 8691 (September 21, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>