<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6509</num>
  <heading>VENTILATOR CARE (ยง 29-6509)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6509.1.</num>
    <text>In addition to the facility-specific base year per diem rate calculated in accordance with subsection 6508.1 (a) through (c), MAA shall pay an additional per diem amount for any day that a resident qualifies for and receives ventilator care pursuant
      to the requirements set forth in sections 6509 through 6511.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6509.2.</num>
    <text>Each resident receiving ventilator care shall meet all of the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be ventilator dependent and not able to breathe without mechanical ventilation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Use the ventilator for life support, 16 hours per day, 7 days per week;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Have a tracheostomy or endotracheal tube;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>At the time of placement the resident has been ventilator dependent during a single stay or continuous stay at a hospital, skilled nursing facility or intermediate care facility for the mentally retarded;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Have a determination by the resident&amp;#8217;s physician and respiratory care team that the service is medically necessary, as well as documentation which describes the type of mechanical ventilation, technique and equipment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Be medically stable, without infections or extreme changes in ventilatory settings and/or duration (increase in respiratory rate by 5 breaths per minute, increase in F102 of 25% or more, and/or increase in tidal volume of 200 mls or more) at time
        of placement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Require services on a daily basis which cannot be provided at a lower level of care; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Require services be provided under the supervision of a licensed health care professional.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6509.3.</num>
    <text>Each nursing facility shall comply with all of the standards governing ventilator care services set forth in section 3215 of Title 22 DCMR.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6509.4.</num>
    <text>Ventilator care shall be prior-authorized by the Department of Health, Medical Assistance Administration (MAA). The following documents shall be required for each authorization:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Level of Care determination;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Pre-admission Screening and Annual Resident Review (PASARR) forms;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Admission history;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Physical examination reports;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Surgical reports; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Consultation reports and ventilator dependent addendum.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6509.5.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section the term &amp;#8220;medically necessary&amp;#8221; shall mean a service that is required to prevent, identify, or treat a resident&amp;#8217;s illness, injury or disability and meets the following standards:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Consistency with the resident&amp;#8217;s symptoms, or with prevention, diagnosis, or treatment of the resident&amp;#8217;s illness or injury;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Consistency with standards of acceptable quality of care applicable to the type of service, the type of provider, and the setting in which the service is provided;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Appropriateness with regard to generally accepted standards of medical practice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Is not medically contraindicated with regard to the resident&amp;#8217;s diagnosis, symptoms, or other medically necessary services being provided to the resident;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Is of proven medical value or usefulness, and is not experimental in nature;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Is not duplicative with respect to other services being provided to the resident;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Is not solely for the convenience of the resident;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Is cost-effective compared to an alternative medically necessary service which is reasonably acceptable to the resident based on coverage determinations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Is the most appropriate supply or level of service that can safely and effectively be provided to the resident.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 1370 (February 24, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>