<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6199</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 29-6199)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6199.1.</num>
    <text>The following terms and phrases shall have the meanings described:</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Applicant&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; A kinship caregiver who is applying for a permanent guardianship subsidy.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Application&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; A written request to be approved for a permanent guardianship subsidy submitted pursuant to this chapter of the DCMR.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;CFSA&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; The D.C. Child and Family Services Agency.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Child&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; A person under eighteen (18) years of age.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Court&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; The Family Division of the District of Columbia Superior Court.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;DCMR&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; The District of Columbia Municipal Regulations.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Foster care board and care payment&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; Payment provided by CFSA for the provision of basic and routine care to a foster child in a foster home.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Kinship caregiver&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; A person who is licensed or approved by CFSA as a foster parent who provides full-time parenting and protection of a kin foster child.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Permanent guardianship&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; A legal status awarded by the court.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Permanent guardianship subsidy&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; Monies provided by CFSA to a permanent guardian to financially support the care of a child in a permanent guardianship home in accordance with this chapter of the DCMR.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Permanent guardianship subsidy agreement&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; An agreement entered into between CFSA and a permanent guardian concerning the provision of a guardianship subsidy to the permanent guardian.</text>
    <text>&amp;#8220;Recipient&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; A permanent guardian who receives a permanent guardianship subsidy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 3671 (April 27, 2001) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 10740 (November 23, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>