<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6238</num>
  <heading>NUTRITION (ยง 29-6238)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6238.1.</num>
    <text>The facility shall develop and follow a written plan for nutritional services including planning and budgeting for the resident&amp;#8217;s dietary needs, and purchasing, storing, preparing and serving food.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6238.2.</num>
    <text>The plan shall identify one (1) staff person who is responsible for implementing the nutritional service plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6238.3.</num>
    <text>The facility shall provide each resident at least three (3) regularly-scheduled meals per day and snacks that meet the National Research Council&amp;#8217;s recommended dietary allowance (RDA) as adjusted for the age and sex of each resident.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6238.4.</num>
    <text>The facility shall provide food to residents who miss regularly-scheduled meals.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6238.5.</num>
    <text>The facility shall provide food in accordance with a residents&amp;#8217; religious beliefs, reasonable dietary preferences, including vegetarianism, or medical or specially prescribed dietary needs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6238.6.</num>
    <text>The facility shall not deny food for any reason other than as medically directed, and shall not force-feed or otherwise coerce a resident to eat against his or her will except where medically prescribed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6238.7.</num>
    <text>For facilities that serve food to staff, the facility shall serve to residents food that is substantially the same as that served to staff, unless religious beliefs, dietary preferences, or medical or special dietary needs require differences in diet.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6238.8.</num>
    <text>The facility shall store, prepare, and serve all food in a manner that is clean, wholesome, free from spoilage or pest infestation, and safe for human consumption.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6238.9.</num>
    <text>The facility shall maintain copies of menus for thirty (30) calendar days and records of food purchased for ninety (90) calendar days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 8675, 8716 (September 21, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>