<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6802</num>
  <heading>ELIGIBILITY (§ 29-6802)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6802.1.</num>
    <text>To the extent that funds are specifically appropriated for the Pilot Program, an applicant shall be eligible to receive a subsidy under the Pilot Program if each of the following criteria is met:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The applicant has submitted a completed application packet in accordance with § 6803;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The applicant is the grandparent, great-grandparent, great-aunt, or great uncle of the child or was the grandparent, great-grandparent, great-aunt, or great-uncle of the child prior to adopting the child.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The applicant has been the child&amp;#8217;s primary caregiver for at least the previous six (6) months;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The child has resided with the applicant on a continuous basis for at least the most recent six (6) months;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The child&amp;#8217;s parent has not resided in the applicant&amp;#8217;s home for at least the most recent six (6) continuous months; provided that a parent may reside in the home without disqualifying the applicant from receiving a subsidy if:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The parent has designated the applicant to be the child&amp;#8217;s standby guardian pursuant to Chapter 48 of Title 16 of the D.C. Official Code;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The parent is a minor enrolled in school; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The parent is a minor with a medically verifiable disability that prevents him or her from caring for the child;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The applicant and all adults residing in the applicant&amp;#8217;s home have obtained a criminal background check in accordance with § 6805;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The applicant and all adults residing in the applicant&amp;#8217;s home have obtained a child protection register check in accordance with § 6805;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The household income is under two hundred percent (200%) of the federally-defined poverty level;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The applicant has applied for Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF) benefits for the child through the Department of Human Services, and an eligibility determination has been made;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>The applicant is a resident of the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>The applicant has entered into a subsidy agreement in accordance with § 6807.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>The applicant is not currently receiving a guardianship or adoption subsidy for the child.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 5837 (July 21, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12482 (December 12, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>