<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6508</num>
  <heading>FINAL PER DIEM RATE CALULATION (ยง 29-6508)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6508.1.</num>
    <text>Each nursing facility&amp;#8217;s per diem rate effective January 1, 2006 shall be the sum of (a), (b) and (c) as set forth below:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>the nursing and resident care base year cost per diem established pursuant to subsection 6505.6 adjusted for inflation to March 30, 2003 using the CMS Prospective Payment System Skilled Nursing Facility Input Price Index;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>the routine and support cost base year cost per diem established pursuant to subsection 6506.3, or subsection 6506.4 if applicable, adjusted for inflation to March 30, 2003 using the CMS Prospective Payment System Skilled Nursing Facility Input
        Price Index; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>the capital related base year cost per diem established pursuant to section 6507 adjusted for inflation to March 30, 2003 using the CMS Prospective Payment System Skilled Nursing Facility Input Price Index. The inflation adjustment in this subsection
        shall not be applied to depreciation, amortization and interest on capital related expenditures.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6508.2.</num>
    <text>Effective April 1, 2006 and every six months thereafter, the nursing and resident care costs per diem shall be re-calculated in accordance with section 6505. The per diem rates established for routine and support costs and capital-related costs established
      pursuant to subsection 6508.1 shall be carried forward until costs are rebased.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6508.3.</num>
    <text>When necessary, each facility&amp;#8217;s per diem rate will be reduced by the same percentage to maintain compliance with the Medicare upper payment limit requirement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6508.4.</num>
    <text>MAA may approve an adjustment to the facility&amp;#8217;s per diem rate if the facility demonstrates that it incurred higher costs due to extraordinary circumstances beyond its control including but not limited to strikes, fire flood, earthquake,
      or similar unusual occurrences with substantial cost effects.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6508.5.</num>
    <text>Each adjustment pursuant to subsection 6508.4 shall be made only to the extent the costs are reasonable, attributable to the circumstances specified, separately identified by the facility, and verified by MAA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 1370 (February 24, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>