<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6807</num>
  <heading>SUBSIDY AGREEMENT (§ 29-6807)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6807.1.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall enter into a subsidy agreement with CFSA prior to receiving a subsidy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6807.2.</num>
    <text>The amount of the subsidy stated in the subsidy agreement shall be the sole and complete amount of funds an individual shall receive under the Pilot Program for a child named in the subsidy agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6807.3.</num>
    <text>A subsidy agreement shall include at least:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The amount of the subsidy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A statement that the subsidy shall expire after one (1) year unless the recipient is recertified in accordance with § 6808;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A statement that the receipt of the subsidy is contingent upon the availability of funds specifically appropriated for this Pilot Program, and that if funds are exhausted during the period covered by the subsidy agreement, the subsidy will terminate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A statement that subject to availability of funds specifically appropriated for this Pilot Program, the recipient may reapply annually to be recertified in accordance with § 6808; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A statement of the circumstances under which the subsidy shall terminate.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6807.4.</num>
    <text>A subsidy agreement shall terminate:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If funds specifically appropriated for this Pilot Program are not available to pay the subsidy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>At the end of one (1) year if the recipient fails to reapply and be recertified for the succeeding year;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If the recipient dies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>If the recipient is no longer the child&amp;#8217;s legal custodian or standby guardian;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Upon the earlier of the child&amp;#8217;s:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Eighteenth (18th) birthday;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Residence outside recipient&amp;#8217;s the home, unless the recipient can demonstrate that he or she retains financial responsibility for the child and the child is attending a residential school;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Marriage;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Death; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Enlistment in the military;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>If there is a substantiated finding of child abuse or neglect resulting in the child&amp;#8217;s removal from the household;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>If the recipient no longer meets the eligibility criteria set out in § 6802; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>In accordance with any additional terms contained in the subsidy agreement or otherwise in accordance with this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6807.5.</num>
    <text>The recipient shall notify CFSA within two (2) weeks of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Any circumstances that may result in the recipient no longer meeting the eligibility criteria set out in § 6802;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any circumstances that may result in the termination of the agreement pursuant to § 6807.4; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any change of address.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 5837 (July 21, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12482 (December 12, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>