<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6608</num>
  <heading>RECERTIFICATION FOR BENEFITS; REINSTATEMENT (ยง 29-6608)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6608.1.</num>
    <text>An IDA recipient shall recertify for benefits within twelve (12) months of the month of the individual&amp;#8217;s approval and every twelve (12) months thereafter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6608.2.</num>
    <text>The following eligibility requirements shall be redetermined and reverified at the IDA interview:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Residency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Income;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Resources; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Status of the SSI claim.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6608.3.</num>
    <text>No IDA recipient shall be required to submit new medical information to continue IDA eligibility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6608.4.</num>
    <text>If the IDA recipient provides all information needed to redetermine eligibility, confirming that he or she continues to meet all financial and non-financial requirements, the SSR shall recertify IDA benefits for an additional twelve (12) months.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6608.5.</num>
    <text>An IDA recipient shall report, within ten (10) days, any changes that affect his or her eligibility for benefits.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If any change results in an increase in the recipient&amp;#8217;s benefits, the SSR shall make the change for the following month; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If any change results in a decrease in the recipient benefits, the SSR shall make the change for the month following the fifteen (15) days notice of the intended reduction in benefits, except that if the recipient reports the approval of SSI benefits,
        the recipient&amp;#8217;s benefits may be changed for the following month.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6608.6.</num>
    <text>An IDA recipient may be reinstated for benefits if he or she provides by the effective date of closing, all information needed to re-establish eligibility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6608.7.</num>
    <text>An individual who does not provide all needed information by the effective date of closing shall re-apply for IDA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6608.8.</num>
    <text>At reapplication, the applicant shall verify all eligibility requirements and he or she shall provide current medical information if the Medical Review period has expired. Representation and reimbursement agreements shall also be resigned.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6608.9.</num>
    <text>If, at re-application, the applicant re-establishes eligibility but IDA funds are exhausted, the applicant shall be added to the waiting list, effective the date of reapplication.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 4948 (June 20, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>