<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6404</num>
  <heading>ENROLLMENT PROCESS (ยง 29-6404)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6404.1.</num>
    <text>Each applicant shall complete a single application that shall be signed and dated. Application forms shall be made available and submitted to the District&amp;#8217;s HIV/AIDS Administration (HAA) for review and approval.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6404.2.</num>
    <text>Each applicant shall obtain and present to HAA one (1) piece of documentation to support proof or residency within the District of Columbia. Documents needed to prove residency include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Copy of a utility bill or a letter from a government agency with the applicant&amp;#8217;s District of Columbia address listed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Voter registration card;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>District of Columbia driver&amp;#8217;s license, or non-driver&amp;#8217;s identification; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Lease or mortgage agreement.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6404.3.</num>
    <text>Each applicant shall obtain one (1) of the following signatures on the application form to verify his or her HIV status:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Physician&amp;#8217;s signature; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Case manager&amp;#8217;s signature.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6404.4.</num>
    <text>Each applicant shall provide evidence of receipt of other health insurance coverage from the following sources, if applicable:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Health insurance card;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Letter from the health insurance company;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1986 (COBRA) coverage;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Retirement health benefit coverage;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Medicare coverage; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Any other health plan.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6404.5.</num>
    <text>Each applicant shall complete, sign, and date an informed consent form as part of the application process during the initial enrollment. Each applicant shall certify by signing the informed consent form that each applicant understands the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Participation in the Demonstration Project is voluntary; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Enrollment in the Demonstration Project is limited, and if the programs are already full at the time of application, the applicant will be placed on a waiting list;</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6404.6.</num>
    <text>The applicant shall complete, sign to acknowledge receipt of a copy of the form, and date the informed consent form in order to be placed on a waiting list.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6404.7.</num>
    <text>Each applicant shall be screened to determine if he or she is eligible for Medicaid benefits under other Medicaid eligibility groups.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6404.8.</num>
    <text>A recipient&amp;#8217;s eligibility shall be subject to re-determination annually. The re-determination date shall be one (1) calendar year from the date of enrollment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6404.9.</num>
    <text>A recipient and the case manager, when appropriate, shall receive a notice of re-determination from the District&amp;#8217;s HIV/AIDS Administration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6404.10.</num>
    <text>A recipient shall respond to a request for information or to resubmit re-determination forms within thirty (30) days from the date of notice of re-determination. The HIV/AIDS Administration may extend the thirty (30) day requirement in cases involving
      extraordinary circumstances.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Emergency Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 5605 (May 28, 2004) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 7435 (July 30, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>