<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6263</num>
  <heading>ADMINISTRATION OF PRESCRIPTION MEDICATION (ยง 29-6263)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6263.1.</num>
    <text>The facility shall develop and follow a written plan governing the use and administration of prescription medication to residents.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6263.2.</num>
    <text>Prescription medications shall be administered only by a dentist, physician, physician&amp;#8217;s assistant, registered nurse, or practical nurse who is a licensed health professional pursuant to the Health Occupations Revision Act, effective March
      25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, D.C. Code ยง 2-3301, et seq., as amended.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6263.3.</num>
    <text>When specifically authorized by a physician, the facility may allow a staff person (excluding volunteers and staff not providing direct care and supervision of residents) to administer medications to a resident. In such cases, the facility shall ensure
      that the staff person is able responsibly to administer medications, shall train the staff person concerning administration procedures, and shall provide supervision and monitoring. The facility shall obtain the consent of the resident and the resident&amp;#8217;s
      parent(s) or guardian(s) prior to allowing a staff person to administer medications to a resident.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6263.4.</num>
    <text>When specifically authorized by a physician, the facility may allow a resident to administer or self-administer medications or allow a resident to administer medications to his or her child. In such cases, the facility shall ensure that the resident
      is able responsibly to medicate or self-medicate, shall train the resident concerning administration procedures, and shall provide supervision and monitoring. The facility shall obtain the consent of the resident&amp;#8217;s parent(s) or guardian(s)
      prior to allowing the resident to self-administer medications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6263.5.</num>
    <text>The facility shall document the prescription and administration of medication, and notify attending physicians of, and record, significant changes in a resident&amp;#8217;s behavior or health.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 8675, 8729 (September 21, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>