<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6299</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 29-6299)
    <text>Act &amp;#8211; The Youth Residential Facilities Licensure Act of 1986, effectiveugust 13, 1986, D.C. Law 6-139, D.C. Code § 3-801 et seq.</text>
    <text>Administrator &amp;#8211; The person responsible for the operation of the facilityr that person&amp;#8217;s designee.</text>
    <text>Admission &amp;#8211; The administrative process of a child&amp;#8217;s entry into aacility.</text>
    <text>Aftercare &amp;#8211; Control, supervision, and care exercised over childreneleased from facilities.</text>
    <text>Annual license &amp;#8211; A license that is granted to a facility whose program,acilities, and operations meet the standards of this Chapter.</text>
    <text>Applicable licensing agency &amp;#8211; For youth residential facilities intendedrimarily for detained or delinquent youth or children in need of supervision,he applicable licensing agency is the Youth Services Administration. For allther facilities,
      the applicable licensing agency is the Child and Familyervices Agency.</text>
    <text>Audit &amp;#8211; An examination of records or accounts to check their accuracy,hich is conducted by a person or persons not directly involved in the creationnd maintenance of these records or accounts. An independent audit results in anpinion based
      on generally accepted accounting principals (GAAP) that eitherffirms or disaffirms the accuracy of the records or accounts audited.</text>
    <text>Business day &amp;#8211; All days excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays.</text>
    <text>Case record &amp;#8211; All information maintained by a facility concerning aesident.</text>
    <text>CFSA &amp;#8211; Child and Family Services Agency.</text>
    <text>Child or Children &amp;#8211; Any individual who is:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Under 18 years of age;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>18 to 20 years of age and the subject of a consent decree or dispositionalrder entered pursuant to proceedings of the Family Division of the Superiorourt of the District of Columbia, D.C. Code § 16-2301 et seq.; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>18 to 21 years of age and has an individualized education program pursuanto the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, approved April 13, 1970,ub.L. 91-230, 84 Stat. 175, 20 U.S.C. § 1400 et seq.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Children in need of supervision&amp;#8211;A child who is in need of care andehabilitation and who:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Is subject to compulsory school attendance and is habitually truant fromchool without justification;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Has committed an offense committable only by children; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Is habitually disobedient of the reasonable and lawful commands of hisarent(s), guardian(s), or other custodian and is ungovernable.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Continuing care &amp;#8211; Ongoing supervision and care designed to nurture aesident&amp;#8217;s growth and development, meet basic health needs, and monitorpplicable school or work attendance.</text>
    <text>Contracting entity &amp;#8211; Any public or private entity or individual thatlaces or offers to place a child in a youth residential facility. The termncludes, but is not limited to, the Child and Family Services Agency, the Youthervices Administration,
      and their successors. Where the contracting entity isot also the child&amp;#8217;s legal custodian, the term shall be read to include,n addition to the contracting entity, the child&amp;#8217;s legal custodian.</text>
    <text>CSSD &amp;#8211; Court Social Services Division of the District of Columbia Superiorourt.</text>
    <text>DCMR &amp;#8211; District of Columbia Municipal Regulations.</text>
    <text>Emergency care facility(ies) &amp;#8211; Facilities that provide temporaryupervision and care, usually not exceeding ninety (90) calendar days androvided as a result of an individual or family crisis, that includes monitoringf applicable school or
      work attendance and an assessment of a resident&amp;#8217;shysical, psychosocial, and educational needs.</text>
    <text>Facility &amp;#8211; See youth residential facility.</text>
    <text>Independent living programs&amp;#8211;Programs for adolescent and young adults thatrovide monitored residences in apartments or single dwelling units and servicedround preparing the adolescent or young adult to live successfully, on his orer own,
      in the community. Residents can include teen mothers and theirhildren. Also known as a supervised apartment.</text>
    <text>Individual Service Plan (ISP)&amp;#8211;A document that sets forth aacility&amp;#8217;s plan for the resident&amp;#8217;s health, safety, welfare, andeneral well-being. The ISP includes the individualized treatment plan, asrovided in section 7 of
      the Act (D.C. Code § 3-806).</text>
    <text>Licensing agency &amp;#8211; Child and Family Services Agency or Youth Servicesdministration.</text>
    <text>Person &amp;#8211; An individual, corporation, trustee, receiver, guardian,epresentative, firm, partnership, society, school, agency or other entity.</text>
    <text>Provisional license &amp;#8211; A license that may be issued if the applicant isemporarily unable to comply with all of the requirements of this Chapter andnder the condition that the requirements will be met within a specific lengthf time.</text>
    <text>Resident &amp;#8211; A child residing in a youth residential facility.</text>
    <text>Residential treatment center(s) &amp;#8211; Facilities that are characterized by anmphasis on therapeutic intervention for residents who cannot or do not functionatisfactorily in their own home or community. Staff provide twenty-four (24)our supervision
      and a variety of professional services, such as individual orroup psychotherapy, formal schooling, social skills training, recreation, andarious other forms of therapy. Usually these facilities are located on a campusetting and utilize dormitory-type
      housing. These facilities may be locked ortaff secure.</text>
    <text>Restricted license &amp;#8211; A license that is issued to a facility not inompliance with these regulations that prohibits the facility from accepting newesidents or providing certain specified services that it otherwise would beuthorized to provide.</text>
    <text>Runaway shelters &amp;#8211; Short-term facilities that house minor children whoave departed the parental or legal guardian home, contrary to the wishes of thearent or guardian. Runaway shelters provide safety, twenty-four (24) hourupervision, physical
      and emotional nourishment and counseling to help resolvehe difficulties between the children and their parent(s), so that the childrenan return to the parental home.</text>
    <text>Staff or Staff person or Staff member &amp;#8211; All employees of the facility andny other person (including, without limitation, volunteers, independentontractors, and vendors) regularly providing services at the facility. A personegularly provides
      services at the facility if the person:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Visits the facility on at least a weekly basis;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Visits the facility for at least ten (10) hours per month; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Provides direct care and supervision of residents.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Therapeutic care &amp;#8211; An intensive, professionally supervised program ofducation and treatment designed to meet a resident&amp;#8217;s physical,sychosocial, and educational needs as identified in an individualized treatmentlan and if applicable,
      an individualized education program.</text>
    <text>Youth group homes &amp;#8211; Facilities that provide twenty-four (24) hour care foresidents. Youth group homes maintain staff to meet the physical, emotional andevelopmental needs of their residents and provide supervision, guidance andecreation
      to their residents.</text>
    <text>Youth residential facility &amp;#8211; A residential placement providing adultupervision and care for one (1) or more children who are not related by blood,arriage, guardianship, or adoption (including both final and nonfinal adoptivelacements) to
      any of the facility&amp;#8217;s adult caregivers and who were foundo be in need of a specialized living arrangement as the result of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A detention or shelter care hearing held pursuant to D.C. Code § 16-2312;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A dispositional hearing held pursuant to D.C. Code § 16-2317;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Family crisis, homelessness, runaway status, or other circumstances creating need for out-of-home supervision and care; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A mental or physical disability that requires, in accordance with 20 U.S.C. 1401, et seq., more services than can be provided by nonresidential programs.</text>
    </level>
    <text>For purposes of this Chapter, the term &amp;#8220;youth residential facility&amp;#8221;nly includes youth shelters, runaway shelters, emergency care facilities, andouth group homes.</text>
    <text>Youth shelter-Facilities that provide temporary residential placement forlleged or adjudicated juvenile offenders prior to disposition by a court.</text>
    <text>YSA &amp;#8211; Department of Human Services, Youth Services Administration.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 8675, 8740 (September 21, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>