<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6218</num>
  <heading>LOCAL ADVISORY COMMITTEE (ยง 29-6218)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6218.1.</num>
    <text>Each facility shall have a local advisory committee made up of no less than three (3) members, including at least one (1) representative of the neighborhood in which the facility is located who is otherwise unaffiliated with the facility and who is
      not employed by the contracting entity or licensing agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6218.2.</num>
    <text>Multiple facilities operated by the same person may have one (1) local advisory committee for all of the facilities so long as the local advisory committee includes at least one (1) representative of each neighborhood in which a facility is located.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6218.3.</num>
    <text>The local advisory committee shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Meet with the facility administrator at the facility at least quarterly to review programs, policies, citizen complaints, and police contacts;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Inform the contracting entity and licensing agency in writing of any situation that a majority of the committee believes warrants correction and that the facility has failed to correct within a reasonable period of time after being notified by the
        committee; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Report annually to the contracting entity and licensing agency on the number of admissions, the number, outcome, and length of stay of planned and unplanned discharges, staff turnover rate and efforts to reduce it, and program effectiveness in meeting
        the needs of residents.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6218.4.</num>
    <text>The facility shall provide the local advisory committee the information necessary to prepare the report required under ยง 6218.3(c). The local advisory committee shall not have access to identifying information regarding individual residents.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6218.5.</num>
    <text>The administrator and the local advisory committee shall biannually conduct an open community meeting to facilitate communication between the facility and the community.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6218.6.</num>
    <text>The facility shall maintain copies of the minutes of the local advisory committee meetings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 8675, 8694 (September 21, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>