<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6510</num>
  <heading>VENTILATOR CARE DISCHARGE (ยง 29-6510)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6510.1.</num>
    <text>Each provider shall ensure that residents are weaned from the ventilator when weaning is determined to be medically appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6510.2.</num>
    <text>A provider shall discontinue weaning and resume mechanical ventilation if the resident experiences any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Blood pressure elevation of more than 20 mmHg Systolic or more than 10 mmHg diastolic;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Heart rate of more than 10% above the baseline or a heart rate of 120 beats per minute;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Respiratory rate increase of more than 10 breaths per minute or a rate above 30 breaths per minute;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Arrhythmias;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Reduced tidal volume;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Elevated partial pressure of arterial carbon dioxide;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Extreme anxiety;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Dyspnea; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Accessory muscle use in breathing or an otherwise deteriorating breathing pattern.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6510.3.</num>
    <text>Each nursing facility shall have an appropriate program for discharge and weaning from the ventilator.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6510.4.</num>
    <text>The nursing facility shall ensure that the resident and all caregivers be trained in all aspects of mechanical ventilation and demonstrate proficiency in ventilator care techniques before a ventilator-dependent resident can be discharged home on a
      mechanical ventilator.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6510.5.</num>
    <text>The physician and respiratory team shall arrange a schedule for follow-up visits, as indicated by the needs of the resident.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6510.6.</num>
    <text>A written discharge plan shall be provided to and reviewed with the resident and resident&amp;#8217;s caregiver and shall include at a minimum the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Name, address and telephone number of the primary physician;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Address and telephone number of the local hospital emergency department;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Name, address and telephone number of the physician for regular respiratory check-ups, if different from the physician identified in 6510.4(a);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The responsibilities of the resident and caregiver in daily ventilator care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Identification of financial resources for long-term care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Identification of community resources for health, social, educational and vocational needs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>An itemized list of all equipment and supplies needed for mechanical ventilation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Names, addresses and telephone numbers of mechanical ventilation equipment dealers and a list of services that they provide; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Contingency plans for emergency situations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6510.7.</num>
    <text>The nursing facility shall notify MAA of the date of discharge from the facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 1370 (February 24, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>