<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6326</num>
  <heading>STAFF TRAINING (§ 29-6326)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6326.1.</num>
    <text>All staff training shall be specific to the ages and characteristics of the residents served by the independent living program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6326.2.</num>
    <text>A new staff member of an independent living program shall receive pre-service training.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6326.3</num>
    <text>6326.3 The pre-service training required by § 6326.2 for new staff shall be for at least twenty (20) hours and include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The independent living program&amp;#8217;s administrative structure, procedures, and overall program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The independent living program&amp;#8217;s emergency plan as required by § 6335;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Communicable diseases and universal precautions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Conflict resolution; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>An introduction to daily living skills for adolescents and young adults.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6326.4.</num>
    <text>A staff member shall receive at least forty (40) hours of annual in-service training.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6326.5.</num>
    <text>Annual in-service training shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The independent living program&amp;#8217;s emergency plan as required by § 6335;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The principles and practices of resident care, including appropriate training on age-specific and special physical, emotional, and medical needs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Life skills as set forth in § 6330;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The independent living program&amp;#8217;s administrative structure;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The independent living program&amp;#8217;s policies and procedures as set forth in § 6307.2(n);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>For the administrator, clinical director, social workers, and counselors appropriate techniques of behavior management and discipline pursuant to § 6347;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>For the administrator, clinical director, social workers, and counselors techniques and methodologies of crisis management;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Child development;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Methods of working with adolescents and young adults that take into account their culture and interests;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Manifestation of and techniques for working with abused, neglected, and traumatized residents;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>The independent living program&amp;#8217;s discipline policy, including acceptable methods of discipline;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Recognition and prevention of abuse, neglect, and risks to the resident&amp;#8217;s health or safety;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>The independent living program&amp;#8217;s procedures for reporting actual or alleged resident abuse or neglect, and actual or alleged risk to a resident&amp;#8217;s health or safety, as set forth in § 6304, including training on mandatory reporting,
        and policies and procedures relating to child abuse or neglect and risks to residents&amp;#8217; health or safety;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>Recognition of substance abuse symptoms and treatment resources;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>Universal precautions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(p)</num>
      <text>Recognition of mental heath disorders and treatment resources;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(q)</num>
      <text>Suicide prevention;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(r)</num>
      <text>Depression; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(s)</num>
      <text>Topics determined jointly by the independent living program and CFSA.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6326.6.</num>
    <text>An independent living program shall maintain records of attendance at training.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 1591 (February 22, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>