<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6027</num>
  <heading>TEMPORARY LICENSE FOR KIN (§ 29-6027)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6027.1.</num>
    <text>CFSA may issue a temporary license to operate a foster home only if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The applicant is kin to each foster child who would be placed in her or his home;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The applicant has submitted an application for a license to operate a foster home;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The applicant has:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Received a satisfactory criminal records check from the Interstate Identification Index System of the National Crime Information Center (III);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Applied for a criminal records check in accordance with § 6008 of this Chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Complied with the requirements of § 6009 of this Chapter concerning the Child Protection Register check;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Received a satisfactory safety assessment of the prospective foster home; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Demonstrated the willingness and ability to provide a safe and secure environment for a foster child;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>All individuals eighteen (18) years of age or older residing in the prospective foster home have:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Received a satisfactory criminal records check from the III;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Applied for a criminal records check in accordance with § 6008 of this Chapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Complied with the requirements of § 6009 of this Chapter concerning the Child Protection Register check;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>There exist exigent circumstances as set forth in § 6027.2 of this Chapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A lead-based paint certificate has been obtained indicating no risk from lead-based paint for a home built before March 1, 1978, in which a foster child under six (6) years of age may be placed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6027.2.</num>
    <text>Exigent circumstances exist if a child who would be placed in the home if it had a temporary license:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Must be removed from her or his home immediately because of suspected or supported child abuse or neglect;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Is in CFSA&amp;#8217;s custody and must be removed from her or his placement immediately; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Has been removed from her or his home because of child abuse and neglect; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A petition alleging neglect of the child has been filed before the Family Division of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 16-2305; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A disposition of the neglect petition pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 16-2320 has not yet occurred.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6027.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant is kin to a foster child if the applicant is:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>At least 21 years of age; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Either:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A relative of the foster child by blood, marriage, or adoption; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Identified by a relative of the foster child by blood, marriage, or adoption, in a sworn affidavit, to have close personal or emotional ties with the foster child or the foster child&amp;#8217;s family, which pre-dated the foster child&amp;#8217;s
        placement with the individual.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6027.4.</num>
    <text>A temporary license:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Permits a foster home to operate prior to issuance of an annual license and while the foster parent(s) attempts to satisfy the requirements for a license; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Expires in one hundred fifty (150) days from the date of the temporary license.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6027.5.</num>
    <text>A temporary license may be renewed once and for no more than ninety (90) days if the:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Applicant is making a good faith effort to comply with all elements of the foster home licensing process as set forth in this Chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Renewal is needed to complete the licensing process;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Licensing process is not completed for a reason that is beyond the control of the applicant; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Applicant has otherwise complied with the requirements of this Chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6027.6.</num>
    <text>A temporary licensee under this section shall actively and promptly take all steps required for full licensure under this Chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6027.7.</num>
    <text>A foster child who is not kin to the applicant may not be placed in a foster home that has a temporary license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6027.8.</num>
    <text>Except as specifically set forth in § 6027, all sections of this Chapter shall apply to a foster parent or foster home that has a temporary license except that the denial of a temporary license shall not be grounds for an appeal pursuant to § 6032
      of a temporary license shall not be grounds for an appeal pursuant to § 6032 of this Chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 6830 (July 22, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 10669, 10670 (September 7, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>