<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6266</num>
  <heading>MENTAL HEALTH SERVICES (ยง 29-6266)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6266.1.</num>
    <text>For residents who are in their initial placement in a facility, the facility shall cooperate with the contracting entity and, where applicable, the CSSD to develop and follow a written plan for providing effective mental health services, including
      but not limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Crisis intervention;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A preliminary mental health screen by a qualified mental health practitioner within three (3) business days of admission; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Evaluation and assessment, including a standardized diagnostic mental health assessment completed within fifteen (15) calendar days of admission by a qualified mental health practitioner, unless the parent(s) or guardian(s), contracting entity,
        CSSD, or other governmental entity provides a written report of such examination conducted no more than thirty (30) calendar days prior to admission.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6266.2.</num>
    <text>For residents who the contracting entity previously placed in another facility, the facility shall cooperate with the contracting entity and, where applicable, the CSSD to develop and follow a written plan for providing effective mental health services,
      including but not limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Crisis intervention;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An evaluation within seven (7) calendar days of admission by the resident&amp;#8217;s ISP planning team, as established by ยง 6258.4, to determine whether another mental health screen or evaluation and assessment is required, including written documentation
        of the ISP planning team&amp;#8217;s determination;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If the planning team determines that another mental health screen is required, a mental health screen by a qualified mental health practitioner within seven (7) business days of this determination; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>If the planning team determines that another mental health evaluation and assessment is required, an evaluation and assessment, including a standardized diagnostic mental health assessment, shall be completed within thirty (30) calendar days of
        admission by a qualified mental health practitioner, unless the parent(s) or guardian(s), contracting entity, CSSD, or other governmental entity provides a written report of such examination conducted no more than thirty (30) calendar days prior
        to admission.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6266.3.</num>
    <text>The facility shall cooperate with the contracting entity and, where applicable, the CSSD to develop and follow a written plan for providing effective mental health services to all residents, including but not limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Individualized treatment, including therapy and counseling for individuals and groups;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Substance abuse prevention, intervention, and treatment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Clinical consultation with residents, parent(s) or guardian(s), and staff;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Access to emergency mental health services on a twenty-four (24) hour per day, seven (7) day per week basis;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A standardized system for collecting, recording, and conveying each resident&amp;#8217;s essential mental health information; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A standardized system for collecting and reviewing the resident&amp;#8217;s historical mental health records.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 8675, 8730 (September 21, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>