<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6804</num>
  <heading>DOCUMENTATION OF STATUS AS PRIMARY CAREGIVER (§ 29-6804)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6804.1.</num>
    <text>The applicant shall demonstrate that he or she is the primary caretaker of the child by providing at least one of the following documents:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A court order granting custody of the child to the applicant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A court order granting the applicant standby guardianship of the child, pursuant to D.C. Official Code §§ 16-4801 &amp;#8211; 4810; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A decree stating that the applicant has adopted the child.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6804.2.</num>
    <text>If the applicant is unable to provide any of the documents listed in 29 DCMR § 6804.1(a) through (c), the applicant may demonstrate that he or she has been the primary caretaker of the child by providing documentation required in § 6804.3 and at least
      one of the following documents:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Records showing that the applicant enrolled the child in school the current or previous school year or is the primary educational contact for the child;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Immunization or medical records indicating that the applicant is tending to the medical needs of the child. The records provided must be no older than two years old;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Proof that the applicant has received either Supplemental Security Income or TANF for the child; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A letter from any legal, medical, military, law enforcement, social service or similar professional, or the applicant&amp;#8217;s landlord describing the applicant&amp;#8217;s status relevant to the child.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6804.3.</num>
    <text>If the Applicant is establishing eligibility under § 6804.2, the applicant shall provide a signed, written statement that he or she has become the primary caregiver of the child because both parents are unable to fulfill the duties of a primary caretaker
      due to at least one of the following situations:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Death;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Incarceration;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Lack of Involvement or Abandonment or Voluntary relinquishment of physical custody;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Separation due to abuse or neglect;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Active military assignment; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Serious illness.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6804.4.</num>
    <text>The Agency reserves the right to request a home visit if probable cause exists to suspect the documents being provided are fraudulent or that the applicant has misrepresented himself or herself for the purpose of receiving the subsidy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6804.5.</num>
    <text>If a home visit is requested, the applicant will be informed that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Agency representative visiting the home is a mandated reporter of child abuse or neglect and that any evidence of abuse or neglect will be reported to the child abuse hotline;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any substantiated fraud will be reported to the Office of the Inspector General;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Upon completion of the home visit, the Agency representative will complete a report stating whether the suspicion of fraud is substantiated by a preponderance of the evidence known to the Agency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>If the suspicion is not so substantiated, the suspicion may not affect the Agency&amp;#8217;s decision regarding the application;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>If the suspicion is so substantiated, the Agency may deny the application;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>If the applicant does not submit to a home visit, the Agency may deny the application; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The applicant may withdraw their application without repercussion at any time.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 5837 (July 21, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12482 (December 12, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>