<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6323</num>
  <heading>PERSONNEL (§ 29-6323)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6323.1.</num>
    <text>An independent living program shall recruit and hire staff members who have the specialized knowledge, skills, and cultural competency necessary to provide for the residents&amp;#8217; safety and developmental needs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.2.</num>
    <text>An independent living program shall appoint an administrator who is responsible for the overall management and fiscal operation of the independent living program. Whenever this Chapter requires that an independent living program undertake or perform
      any act or obligation, the administrator shall be responsible for the performance of such act or obligation, unless otherwise specified.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.3.</num>
    <text>Except as provided by § 6323.26, the person appointed as the administrator shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Have a master&amp;#8217;s degree in social work or a related area of study from an accredited college or university and at least two (2) years of experience in the management or supervision of child welfare personnel and programs; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Have a bachelor&amp;#8217;s degree in social work or a related area of study from an accredited college or university and at least four (4) years of experience in the management or supervision of child welfare personnel and programs.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.4.</num>
    <text>The administrator shall be available to residents, CFSA, the contracting entity, staff and residents&amp;#8217; parents and guardians by telephone at all times.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.5.</num>
    <text>An independent living program shall designate a clinical director who is responsible for the development, implementation, and supervision of programmatic services provided by or through the independent living program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.6.</num>
    <text>The clinical director shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Have a master&amp;#8217;s degree in social work or a related field; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Have at least three (3) years of post-graduate experience working with adolescents and young adults.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.7.</num>
    <text>An independent living program shall employ at least one (1) social worker for every twenty (20) residents. The social worker is responsible for the daily implementation of the social services provided to residents.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.8.</num>
    <text>A social worker shall have a master&amp;#8217;s degree in social work or a related field.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.9.</num>
    <text>An independent living program shall employ or have a contract for the provision of services by a certified or licensed addictions counselor who is responsible for providing education and treatment regarding substance abuse to residents of the program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.10.</num>
    <text>An independent living program shall employ or have a contract for the provision of services by an educational coordinator, whose responsibility is to identify residents&amp;#8217; educational needs and arrange for the provision of appropriate educational
      services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.11.</num>
    <text>An educational coordinator shall have:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A master&amp;#8217;s degree in education or a related field; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A bachelor&amp;#8217;s degree in education and five (5) years experience in counseling and guidance of high school students.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.12.</num>
    <text>An independent living program shall employ or have a contract for the provision of services by a licensed practical nurse who is responsible for medication administration and attendance to the medical needs of the residents of the program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.13.</num>
    <text>A licensed practical nurse shall be licensed as a practical nurse in the jurisdiction in which the service is provided.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.14.</num>
    <text>A staff member or independent contractor responsible for performing professional services, including psychological, psychiatric, medical, social work, nursing, dental, or education, shall have a professional degree in his or her respective field from
      an accredited college or university and any licensure or certification required by law in the jurisdiction in which the service is performed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.15.</num>
    <text>An independent living program shall employ counselors who are responsible for day-to-day monitoring of the resident and her or his activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.16.</num>
    <text>A counselor shall have:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A high school or general equivalency diploma; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>At least five (5) years experience in human services delivery preferably working with adolescents and young adults.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.17.</num>
    <text>A degree in social work, psychology, or a related field may be substituted for the experience required by § 6323.16(b).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.18.</num>
    <text>An independent living program shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If it operates a main facility, have a minimum resident to counselor ratio of 10:1 during the daytime, 6:1 at evenings, and 15:1 at night; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If it does not operate a main facility, have a minimum resident to counselor ratio of 15:1.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.19.</num>
    <text>A counselor on duty pursuant to § 6323.18 shall be awake and available at all times to all staff and residents through a pager whose number is conspicuously posted in the main facility and each residence and provided to the contracting entity and
      licensing agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.20.</num>
    <text>A staff member shall be in general physical condition that permits her or him to perform the duties of her or his position, be free from disease in a communicable form, and be able to work closely with residents without danger to the residents.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.21.</num>
    <text>A prospective staff member shall undergo a pre-employment medical examination and provide a physician&amp;#8217;s opinion concerning her or his general physical condition, freedom from disease in a communicable form, and ability to work closely with
      residents without danger to the residents. A staff member employed by an operating independent living program on the effective date of this Chapter shall provide such a physician&amp;#8217;s opinion when the program is licensed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.22.</num>
    <text>A staff member shall undergo a follow-up medical examination every two (2) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.23.</num>
    <text>An independent living program may not permit a staff member to provide transportation services to residents unless the independent living program has:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Verified that the staff member has a current operator&amp;#8217;s permit; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Reviewed the staff member&amp;#8217;s driving record for at least the last five (5) years and verified the absence of any serious moving violation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.24.</num>
    <text>A staff member preparing food shall have a Food Handler&amp;#8217;s Certificate from the District of Columbia Department of Health.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.25.</num>
    <text>An independent living program may not hire a prospective staff without receiving and confirming sufficient documentation to establish the individual&amp;#8217;s identity, qualifications, and experience. The documentation shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>At least three (3) work references;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Proof of educational degrees or certificates; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Proof of any required current professional licensure or certification.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.26.</num>
    <text>A staff member employed by an operating independent living program on the effective date of this Chapter:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If employed as the administrator, is exempt from the requirements of § 6323.3; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If employed as a counselor, is exempt from the requirements of § 6323.16.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6323.27.</num>
    <text>All staff shall possess current American Red Cross Standard First Aid and CPR certifications or the equivalent prior to commencing work at the independent living program, and shall continue to possess current certifications throughout their employment.
      A staff member employed by an operating independent living program on the effective date of this Chapter shall possess such certification when the program is licensed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 1591 (February 22, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>