<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6324</num>
  <heading>CRIMINAL RECORDS CHECK (ยง 29-6324)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6324.1.</num>
    <text>A prospective staff member shall undergo a criminal records check in accordance with ยง 6324 prior to commencing work.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6324.2.</num>
    <text>An independent living program may not employ any individual who has a conviction for any of the following offenses or their equivalents:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Fraud; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A drug-related offense.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6324.3.</num>
    <text>An independent living program may not employ any individual who has a conviction for any of the following offenses or their equivalents:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Child abuse;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Child neglect;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Spousal abuse;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A crime against children, including child pornography; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A crime involving violence, including but not limited to, rape, sexual assault, homicide and assault.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6324.4.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding a conviction as set forth in ยง 6324.2 or ยง 6324.3, CFSA may permit the employment of an individual if it determines, after the individual&amp;#8217;s satisfactory completion of all other applicable requirements of this Chapter and
      a review of the conviction and current circumstances, that the individual would be able to provide care for adolescents or young adults consistent with this Chapter and the health, safety, and welfare of the residents.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6324.5.</num>
    <text>A criminal records check shall be performed on each staff member once every two (2) years as part of the annual license renewal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6324.6.</num>
    <text>An independent living program shall keep confidential the results of all criminal records checks, except that the results shall be available to CFSA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 1591 (February 22, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>