<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6262</num>
  <heading>HEALTH CARE PLAN (ยง 29-6262)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6262.1.</num>
    <text>The facility shall cooperate with the contracting entity and, where applicable, the CSSD to meet the residents&amp;#8217; preventative, routine and emergency health needs, including:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An initial medical screen of each resident by a licensed physician within twenty-four (24) hours of admission into a facility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A comprehensive medical and dental examination of each resident by a licensed physician within fourteen (14) calendar days of admission into a facility unless the parent(s) or guardian(s), contracting entity or CSSD provides a written report of
        such examination conducted within the timeframes recommended by the American Academy of Pediatrics. The American Academy of Pediatrics recommends that children receive such examinations at the ages of two (2) days, four (4) days, one (1) month,
        two (2) months, four (4) months, nine (9) months, twelve (12) months, fifteen (15) months, eighteen (18) months, two (2) years, and annually thereafter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Routine medical and dental examinations at intervals recommended by the American Academy of Pediatrics, as specified in ยง 6262.1(b);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Maintenance of required immunizations and booster shots recommended by the American Academy of Pediatrics;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Vision and hearing examinations and provisions for obtaining eye glasses and hearing aids as medically recommended;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Provision of prosthetic and corrective devices prescribed by a physician;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Provision of health and sex education as appropriate to the resident&amp;#8217;s age and level of development;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Explanation of all medical and/or psychiatric treatments in language as appropriate to the resident&amp;#8217;s age and level of development;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Maintenance, storage and supervision of health records; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Maintenance, storage, supervision and administration of prescription medications.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6262.2.</num>
    <text>The facility shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Prohibit the use and possession of alcohol and tobacco products by residents or staff, while on the premises of the facility;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Cooperate with the contracting entity and, where applicable, the CSSD to involve the resident&amp;#8217;s parent(s) or guardian(s) in the resident&amp;#8217;s health and medical care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Cooperate with the contracting entity and, where applicable, the CSSD to obtain a general written consent upon admission from the resident&amp;#8217;s parent(s) or legal guardian(s), or by court order, for the provision of preventative and routine
        health care; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Cooperate with the contracting entity and, where applicable, the CSSD to obtain a separate written consent prior to treatment from the resident&amp;#8217;s parent(s) or guardian(s), or by court order, for each incidence of non-routine health care.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 8675, 8727 (September 21, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>