<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6033</num>
  <heading>BACK-UP CAREGIVER (§ 29-6033)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6033.1.</num>
    <text>The foster parent shall identify a back-up caregiver to provide short-term overnight care for the child in the event of an emergency requiring the foster parent to be away from the foster home.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6033.2.</num>
    <text>Unless the back-up caregiver is licensed to provide care to a foster child by the District of Columbia or Maryland, the back-up caregiver shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be twenty-one (21) years of age or older;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Have knowledge of, interest in, and regard for the principles of good child care and understanding of the back-up caregiver’s responsibility in providing care for a foster child; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Have the suitability, stamina, and physical and mental health to meet the demands of serving as the back-up caregiver for a foster child.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6033.3</num>
    <text>6033.3 The back-up caregiver and all adults residing in the back-up caregiver’s home shall obtain a child protection register check.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6033.4</num>
    <text>6033.4 If a child protection register check reveals that a back-up caregiver or an adult residing in the back-up caregiver’s home is identified as the abuser or neglector in a substantiated child abuse or neglect case, CFSA shall review the results
      and determine whether the back-up caregiver is able to provide for the health, safety, and welfare of the child.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6033.5</num>
    <text>6033.5 The back-up caregiver and all adults residing in the individual’s home shall obtain a criminal record check that is performed by the Federal Bureau of Investigation and by:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Metropolitan Police Department, if the individual as an adult resided, worked, or attended school in the District at any time in the past five (5) years; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The state’s law enforcement agency, if the individual as an adult resided, worked, or attended school outside of the District at any time in the past five (5) years.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6033.6.</num>
    <text>If a criminal record check reveals that an individual has a felony criminal conviction, CFSA shall review the results and determine whether the back-up caregiver is able to provide for the health, safety, and welfare of the child.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 10669, 10672 (September 7, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>