<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6030</num>
  <heading>ANNUAL RE-EVALUATION AND LICENSE RENEWAL (§ 29-6030)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6030.1.</num>
    <text>The agency shall re-evaluate every two (2) years the ability of each foster parent and foster home to meet the requirements of this chapter of the DCMR.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6030.2.</num>
    <text>Re-evaluation shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A thorough inspection of the foster home to assure continued compliance with this chapter of the DCMR;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>At least one (1) interview with the foster parent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Collection and review of all documentation required pursuant to § 6029.3;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Interviews with all social workers assigned to children placed in the foster home during the licensing period. The interviews shall include, but are not limited to:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The appropriateness of the individual as a foster parent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The safety and well-being of each foster child in the home;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Attachment and bonding among household members;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The willingness and ability of the foster parent to comply with CFSA and agency directives;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The foster parent&amp;#8217;s compliance with this chapter of the DCMR;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The willingness and ability of the foster parent to meet the foster child&amp;#8217;s needs; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Engagement of the foster child with the community as measured by school, church, clubs, or civic group activity.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Review of:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The results of any investigation conducted pursuant to this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any complaints concerning the provision of care; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Cooperation with assigned social workers, teachers, therapists, police, and others involved in the foster child&amp;#8217;s case; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Identification of any additional supports that may be needed by the foster parent.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6030.3</num>
    <text>6030.3 The documentation required for the re-evaluation and renewal shall be provided by the foster parent to the agency at least thirty (30) calendar days before the expiration of the current license and shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Documentation of completed in-service training in accordance with § 6026.5;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A criminal records check for each resident of the foster home who is eighteen (18) years of age or older in accordance with § 6008;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A child protection register check for each resident of the foster home who is eighteen (18) years of age or older in accordance with § 6009;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A clean hands certification signed by the foster parent within ninety (90) days preceding the expiration date of the current license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Documentation from a physician that the foster parent and any other household member eighteen (18) years of age or older has had a complete medical examination within twenty-four (24) months (including a tuberculosis screening) and has no medical
        conditions that would contraindicate the foster parent&amp;#8217;s appropriateness to serve as a foster parent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Documentation from a physician, for every household member under eighteen (18) years of age who is not a foster child, that the household member has had a complete medical examination consistent with the standards for the Early Periodic Screening
        and Diagnostic Testing (EPSDT) schedule (including up- to-date immunizations, a tuberculosis screening, and, if the household member is under six (6) years of age, a blood lead screening); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A current vaccination records for every pet in the foster home.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6030.4.</num>
    <text>If the agency is not CFSA, the agency&amp;#8217;s recommendation as to whether to renew the license shall be completed and received by CFSA at least forty-five (45) days before the anniversary date of the foster home&amp;#8217;s initial license. CFSA
      shall complete its review and determine whether to renew the license no more than fifteen (15) days after receipt of the agency&amp;#8217;s recommendation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6030.5.</num>
    <text>If the agency is CFSA, CFSA shall complete the re-evaluation and determine whether to renew the license at least thirty (30) days prior to the anniversary date of the initial license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6030.6.</num>
    <text>CFSA shall issue a renewal within three (3) business days of its decision to renew the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 6617 (July 27, 2001); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 8609 (September 3, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 10669, 10672 (September 7, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>