<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-7300</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (ยง 29-7300)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7300.1.</num>
    <text>There is established in the District of Columbia (District) a program to provide medical assistance to any immigrant child who:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Resides in the District; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Has an annual family income of up to 200% of the federal poverty level (FPL).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7300.2.</num>
    <text>Medical assistance provided pursuant to this chapter shall be provided by a health maintenance organization (HMO) that has a current contract with the District government to provide managed care health services on a capitated basis in accordance with
      subsections 7300.4 and 7300.5</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7300.3.</num>
    <text>An application for medical assistance shall be submitted to the Income Maintenance Administration, Department of Human Services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7300.4.</num>
    <text>Each program enrollee shall select an HMO that satisfies the criteria set forth in subsection 7300.2 within thirty (30) days of the date of the notice that the enrollee&amp;#8217;s application has been approved.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7300.5.</num>
    <text>The Medical Assistance Administration (MAA), Department of Health, shall assign any enrollee who does not select an HMO that satisfies the criteria set forth in subsection 7300.2 within the time frame set forth in subsection 7300.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7300.6.</num>
    <text>The cost of medical assistance provided pursuant to this chapter in any fiscal year shall not exceed the amount of local funds appropriated during that fiscal year for the purposes of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7300.7.</num>
    <text>The number of persons enrolled in this program shall not exceed the number authorized by statute.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7300.8.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this chapter shall be interpreted to create or constitute an entitlement or right to medical assistance for any person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 8971 (September 28, 2001); Errata Notice published at 57 DCR 5049 (June 11, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>