<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-707</num>
  <heading>PHYSICAL PLANT REQUIREMENTS (ยง 29-707)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>707.1.</num>
    <text>The day treatment program site shall offer easy accessibility by the specialized population being served to public transportation, and easy accessibility to emergency vehicles.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.2.</num>
    <text>The building that houses the program shall meet the requirements set forth in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.3.</num>
    <text>The building shall be of sound construction and shall be maintained in good repair.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.4.</num>
    <text>Curb cuts, handrails, steps, and ramps shall be designed or adapted to offer easy accessibility to the building by the population being served.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.5.</num>
    <text>Illumination shall be adequate in all areas and commensurate with the type of activity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.6.</num>
    <text>The relevant sections of the American National Standards Institute (ANSI) &amp;#8220;Specifications for Making Buildings and Facilities Accessible To, and Usable By, the Physically Handicapped&amp;#8221; shall be the specifications for constructing
      new facilities or renovating old facilities to accommodate day treatment programs for the elderly or the handicapped.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.7.</num>
    <text>Where appropriate to the population served, light switches, control panels, counters, sinks, and door handles shall be within easy reach of a wheelchair-bound person, and door frames shall be wide enough for easy entering of wheelchairs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.8.</num>
    <text>There shall be at least two (2) toilet facilities at each day care site. Where appropriate, one (1) toilet shall be designed or adapted to provide access and maneuverability for handicapped and wheelchair-bound individuals.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.9.</num>
    <text>Each day treatment site program shall have a large room where all participants can gather as well as rooms or divided areas for small group activities including a quiet area for rest.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.10.</num>
    <text>A room with a bed and with adequate provision for privacy shall be available at each site for medical examination, treatment, illness, individualized programming or instruction, or acting-out behavior.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.11.</num>
    <text>Drinking water shall be easily accssible to the participants and provided by either an angle jet drinking fountain with mouth guard or by a running water supply with individual services drinking cups.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.12.</num>
    <text>Drinking facilities shall not be located in toilet rooms.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.13.</num>
    <text>There shall be at least one (1) telephone in the building that is not a pay station or locked telephone.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.14.</num>
    <text>Additional telephones or extensions as may be required to summon help immediately in case of fire or other emergencies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.15.</num>
    <text>The minimum space requirements for the building shall be as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>One hundred square feet (100 ft.2) for each of the first five (5) persons;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Eighty square feet (80 ft.2) for each of the next ten (10) persons;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Sixty square feet (60 ft.2) for each of the next ten (10) persons;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>One-thousand six hundred square feet (1,600 ft.2) for twenty (20) persons; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Two-thousand square feet (2,000 ft.2) for thirty (30) persons.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>707.16.</num>
    <text>Space requirements outlined in ยง707.15 do not include office space, bathrooms, storage, examination room, or dining room unless these rooms are also used for activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 326 (January 27, 1984).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>