<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-713</num>
  <heading>DISCHARGE AND REFERRAL (ยง 29-713)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>713.1.</num>
    <text>A participant shall be discharged from the day treatment program under one (1) of the following conditions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If the participant demonstrates improvement sufficient to enable him or her to live more independently;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If the participant requires institutional care due to illness;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If the participant develops extreme behavior problems that require referral to a more appropriate environment for assistance before returning to the program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>If the participant wishes to discontinue participation in the program; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>If the participant&amp;#8217;s needs can be better met in another type of program.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>713.2.</num>
    <text>The provider shall establish, in writing, the following procedures for discharge and referral:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A discharge or referral summary;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Post discharge or referral goals;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Recommendations for sources of continuing care; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Referral to community service agencies, if indicated, if the participant is returning to a more independent living situation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>713.3.</num>
    <text>The day treatment program staff shall discuss the discharge plan with the participant and his or her family or guardian as far in advance of discharge as possible.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>713.4.</num>
    <text>The day treatment program provider shall submit to the D.C. Office of Health Care Financing (OHCF) a form that indicates the discharge plan within one (1) week after discharge.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 326 (January 27, 1984).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>