<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-7599</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 29-7599)
    <text>The following terms shall have the meaning ascribed:</text>
    <text>Applicant Unit &amp;#8211; The individual who is applying for emergency assistanceor his or her own needs or the needs of those with whom he or she lives, andhose persons described in section 7502 of these rules.</text>
    <text>Authorized Representative &amp;#8211; An individual who is at least eighteen (18)ears of age, who is acting responsibly on behalf of the applicant, and hasufficient knowledge of the circumstances of the applicant to provide or obtainecessary information
      about the applicant, or a person who has legaluthorization to act on behalf of the applicant.</text>
    <text>Budget Month &amp;#8211; The thirty (30) day period immediately prior to the day ofpplication.</text>
    <text>Department &amp;#8211; The District of Columbia Department of Human Services or itsesignated agent.</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; The Director of the Department of Human Services.</text>
    <text>Emergency &amp;#8211; A situation in which immediate action is necessary to avoidomelessness or eviction, to re-establish a home, or prevent displacement from aome.</text>
    <text>Equity &amp;#8211; Current market value of property less any lien indebtedness onhe property and less reasonable expenses necessary to liquidate the property.</text>
    <text>Household Member with a Disability &amp;#8211; A member of the applicant unit who isisabled, as documented by medical evidence provided by a qualified professionalr by participation in a program which conditions its eligibility on theocumentation
      of disability.</text>
    <text>Income from a Boarder &amp;#8211; Any money paid to the applicant by a person livingn the same household as the applicant, but who is not related to the applicant.</text>
    <text>Joint Legal Responsibility &amp;#8211; The individual household members are named onhe deed (as tenants in common or joint tenants), or rental lease.</text>
    <text>Minor child &amp;#8211; A child, including those by adoption, eighteen (18) years ofge or younger.</text>
    <text>SSI &amp;#8211; The Supplemental Security Income for the Aged, Blind, and Disabledash assistance program authorized by Title XVI of the Social Security Act of935, as amended (42 U.S.C. §§ 1381 to 1383f).</text>
    <text>Provider &amp;#8211; An organization that receives Emergency Rental Assistancerogram funds and is authorized to administer the Emergency Rental Assistancerogram.</text>
    <text>Rental Payment &amp;#8211; A regular payment made by a tenant to an owner orandlord for the right to occupy or use property.</text>
    <text>Security Deposit (also Damage Deposit) &amp;#8211; A sum of money paid in advancehat is required by the owner or landlord for leasing property as securitygainst the tenant&amp;#8217;s failure to fulfill the lease or security to coveramage to the rental
      premises.</text>
    <text>TANF &amp;#8211; Temporary Assistance for Needy Families.</text>
    <text>Vendor &amp;#8211; Provider of a service or product, including but not limited toandlords.</text>
    <text>Verification &amp;#8211; Documentation or collateral proof used to confirm thealidity of an applicant&amp;#8217;s circumstances.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 12622 (December 28, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>