<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-703</num>
  <heading>ACTIVITIES COORDINATOR (ยง 29-703)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>703.1.</num>
    <text>An Activities Coordinator shall have a minimum of one (1) or more years of experience working in an adult or elderly social or recreational program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>703.2.</num>
    <text>An Activities Coordinator shall have the ability to develop and implement therapeutic activity programming both for specific individuals and for groups.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>703.3.</num>
    <text>For the developmentally disabled or for those with maladaptive behavior, the Activities Coordinator shall have had one (1) year of experience working in the specialty services being provided in the day care treatment program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>703.4.</num>
    <text>The Activities Coordinator shall implement, in concert with plan of care goals and with other day treatment program staff, activity programs to meet the individual needs of each participant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>703.5.</num>
    <text>The Activities Coordinator shall not serve as the Program Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>703.6.</num>
    <text>The Activities Coordinator shall also be responsible for the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Developing and scheduling educational events;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Supervising activity program assistants; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Participating in the monthly review of each participant&amp;#8217;s care plan.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>703.7.</num>
    <text>The Activities Coordinator shall enter in each participant&amp;#8217;s record, at least monthly and more often if indicated, notations regarding the participant&amp;#8217;s involvement and progress in activities as a part of his or her care plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 326 (January 27, 1984).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>