<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-7699</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 29-7699)
    <text>The following terms shall have the meaning ascribed:</text>
    <text>Authorized Representative – an individual who is at least eighteen (18) yearsf age, who is acting responsibly on behalf of the applicant, and has sufficientnowledge of the circumstances of the applicant to provide or obtain necessarynformation about
      the applicant, or a person who has legal authorization to actn behalf of the applicant.</text>
    <text>Department – the District of Columbia Department of Human Services or itsesignated agent.</text>
    <text>Equity – current market value of property less any lien indebtedness on theroperty and less reasonable expenses necessary to liquidate the property.</text>
    <text>Household Member with a Disability – a member of the applicant unit who isisabled, as documented by medical evidence provided by a qualified professionalr by participation in a program which conditions its eligibility on theocumentation of disability.</text>
    <text>Housing Stability – the ability to pay housing costs, including rent andtilities, necessary to retain housing without HPRP assistance.</text>
    <text>Joint Legal Responsibility – the individual household members are named on theeed (as tenants in common or joint tenants), or rental lease.</text>
    <text>Minor child – a child, including those by adoption, eighteen (18) years of ager younger.</text>
    <text>SSI – the Supplemental Security Income for the Aged, Blind, and Disabled cashssistance program authorized by Title XVI of the Social Security Act of 1935,s amended (42 U.S.C. §§ 1381 to 1383f).</text>
    <text>Provider – an organization that receives Homelessness Prevention and Rapide-Housing funds and is authorized to administer and deliver Homelessnessrevention and Rapid Re-Housing services.</text>
    <text>Rent Reasonableness Standard – Rent Reasonableness is defined by the Unitedtates Department of Housing and Urban Development to mean that the total rentharged for a unit must be reasonable in relation to the rents being chargeduring the same time
      period for comparable units in the private unassistedarket and must not be in excess of rents being charged by the owner during theame time period for comparable non-luxury unassisted units.</text>
    <text>Rental Arrearages – amount due in unpaid rent, which may include reasonableate fees.</text>
    <text>Rental Payment – a regular payment made by a tenant to an owner or landlord for the right to occupy or use property.</text>
    <text>Security Deposit (also Damage Deposit) – a sum of money paid in advance thatis required by the owner or landlord for leasing property as security againsthe tenant’s failure to fulfill the lease or security to cover damage to theental premises.</text>
    <text>Vendor – provider of a service or product, including but not limited toandlords.</text>
    <text>Verification – documentation or collateral proof used to confirm the validityf an applicant’s circumstances.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 2116March 12, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposedulemaking published at 57 DCR 5973 (July 9, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended byotice of Final Rulemaking
      published at 58 DCR 1566, 1586 (February 25, 2011).</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>