<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-7010</num>
  <heading>REQUIREMENTS FOR INSTITUTIONAL PARTICIPATION &amp;#8211; CASH MANAGEMENT ANDCCOUNTING (§ 29-7010)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7010.1.</num>
    <text>Each payment period, the Mayor shall provide the institution a roster of eligible students who have expressed an interest in attending the institution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7010.2.</num>
    <text>Each payment period, the institution shall submit to the Mayor a roster of eligible students for payment:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The roster shall contain the institution’s Tax Information Number (TIN) and the Dun and Bradstreet Number (DUN);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The roster shall also contain the social security number, name, and permanent address of each eligible student enrolled at the institution, his or her enrollment status, the amount of tuition specific aid (grant money, scholarship, tuition or fee
        waivers, or tuition remission) the student received, the amount of tuition and fees charged the student for the payment period, the amount of tuition and fees that would be charged to an in-State student (if a public institution) for that payment
        period; the award amount that should be paid to the institution on behalf of the student for that payment period;</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7010.3.</num>
    <text>A private institution shall determine the amount to request for each payment period by dividing the total amount of the annual award by the number of payment periods the institution expects the student will attend in that award year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7010.4.</num>
    <text>The institution shall submit the roster to the Mayor after the institution’s drop/add period in order to account for the most accurate information with respect to the student’s enrollment status.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7010.5.</num>
    <text>If the student registers for an additional course after the institution has submitted its roster to the Mayor for payment, the institution may submit a supplemental roster for payment, except that the amount of payment requested may not result in
      the institution receiving on behalf of the student more money than is authorized under the College Access Act and this Chapter for the award year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7010.6.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of the institutional roster, the Mayor shall review the information on the roster to determine that each student listed as eligible for the grant has filed an application for the grant and is eligible to receive the grant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7010.7.</num>
    <text>If the Mayor determines that a student on the roster has not submitted the appropriate documents and/or is not eligible for a grant, the Mayor shall notify the institution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7010.8.</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall determine the aggregate amount of funds to be paid to the institution on behalf of all eligible students attending the institution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7010.9.</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall transmit funds to the institution’s account by use of the Automated Clearing House/Electronic Funds Transfer (ACH/EFT) or check within 30 days of receipt of the roster for payment of funds from the institution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7010.10.</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall provide to the institution a roster reflecting the names, social security numbers, and amounts of payment for each student transmitted to the institution’s account.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7010.11.</num>
    <text>The Mayor may require the institution to maintain the tuition assistance program funds in a separate bank or investment account that contains no other funds if the Mayor determines that the institution failed to comply with:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The requirements of this section;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The recordkeeping and reporting requirements in §7012.2 through 7012.8; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any other requirements of this Chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7010.12.</num>
    <text>The institution shall maintain accounting and internal control systems that identify the cash balance of the tuition assistance funds that are included in the institution’s bank or investment account as readily as if those program funds were maintained
      in a separate account.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7010.13.</num>
    <text>The institution shall maintain its financial records in accordance with the requirements contained in §7012.2 through 7012.8.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7010.14.</num>
    <text>The institution shall exercise the level of care and diligence required of a fiduciary with regard to administering tuition assistance program funds.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 5013, 5026 (June 1, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>