<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-8212</num>
  <heading>CLOSE-OUT (ยง 29-8212)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8212.1.</num>
    <text>The Grant Officer shall close-out the grant when he or she determines that all applicable administrative actions and all required work of the grant have been completed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8212.2.</num>
    <text>Upon termination or close-out of the grant, the Grant Officer shall promptly provide an accounting of the funds expended, obligated, and remaining under the grant to the Child and Family Services Agency Chief Financial Officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8212.3.</num>
    <text>Within ninety (90) days after expiration or termination of the grant, the grantee shall submit all financial, performance, and other reports required as a condition of the grant. The Grant Officer may extend this deadline upon request of the grantee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8212.4.</num>
    <text>The District shall make prompt payment to the grantee for allowable reimbursable costs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8212.5.</num>
    <text>The grantee shall immediately refund to the District any balance of unobligated cash advanced that is not authorized to be retained for use on other grants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8212.6.</num>
    <text>The close-out of a grant shall not affect the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Grant Officer&amp;#8217;s authority to disallow costs and recover funds on the basis of a later audit or other review;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The grantee&amp;#8217;s obligation to return any funds due as a result of later refunds, correction or other transactions; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The grantee&amp;#8217;s duty under section 8213 to retain and make records available to the District for review</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking at 53 DCR 7448 (September 8, 2006) [EXPIRED]; and as amended by Final Rulemaking at 54 DCR 120 (January 5, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>