<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-8999</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 29-8999)
    <text>Acute care hospital: A health care facility: (1) where the average length ofatient stay is twenty-five (25) days or fewer; and (2) with a Centers foredicare and Medicaid Services (CMS) certification number (previously known ashe Medicare provider
      number) that has the last four (4) digits in the series001–0879 or 1300–1399 pursuant to 42 C.F.R. § 495.302.</text>
    <text>Children’s hospital: A separately certified children&amp;#8217;s hospital, eitherreestanding or hospital-within-hospital that (1) has a CMS certification numberCCN), (previously known as the Medicare provider number), that has the lastour (4) digits
      in the series 3300–3399; or (2) does not have a CCN but haseen provided an alternative number by CMS for purposes of enrollment in MEIP as children&amp;#8217;s hospital; and; (3) predominantly treats individuals underwenty-one (21) years of age,
      pursuant to 42 C.F.R. § 495.302.</text>
    <text>Hospital based professional: As defined in 42 C.F.R. § 495.4, a professionalho furnishes ninety (90) percent or more of covered professional services inites of service identified by the codes used in the Health Insuranceortability and Accountability
      Act of 1996, enacted August 21, 1996 (Pub.L.04–191, 110 Stat. 1936) (HIPAA) standard transaction as an inpatient hospitalr emergency room setting in the year preceding the payment year, or in the casef a payment adjustment year, in either of the
      two (2) years before such paymentdjustment year.</text>
    <text>Federally Qualified Health Center (FQHC): An entity that meets the definitionet forth in § 1905(l)(2)(B) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. §396d(l)(2)(B)).</text>
    <text>Medicaid encounter: Services rendered in accordance with 42 C.F.R. §95.306(e).</text>
    <text>Needy individuals: As defined at 42 C.F.R. § 495.302, individuals who: receivededical assistance from Medicaid or the Children&amp;#8217;s Health Insurancerogram (or a Medicaid or CHIP demonstration project approved under § 1115 ofhe Social Security
      Act); were furnished uncompensated care by the provider; orere furnished services at either no cost or reduced cost based on a slidingcale determined by the individuals&amp;#8217; ability to pay.</text>
    <text>Patient Encounter: Services rendered to an individual pursuant to 42 C.F.R. §95.306(e).</text>
    <text>Patient Volume: The minimum participation threshold pursuant to 42 C.F.R. §95.304(c)-(e), § 495.306, and the District of Columbia State Medicaid Healthnformation Technology Plan.</text>
    <text>Payment year: For an eligible professional, a calendar year (CY) beginning withY 2011 and for an eligible hospital, a federal fiscal year (FFY) beginning withFY 2011.</text>
    <text>Provider: For the purposes of this section, the term “provider” shallnclude both health care professionals and hospitals.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 61 DCR 237 (January 10, 2014).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>