<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-8901</num>
  <heading>METHODOLOGY FOR VOLUME REQUIREMENTS (§ 29-8901)
    <text>An eligible professional shall establish and demonstrate, based on individualnd group practice methodology, compliance with the following volumeequirements:</text>
    <text>An eligible professional shall have at least thirty percent (30%) of therofessional&amp;#8217;s patient volume covered by Medicaid, except that:</text>
    <text>A board-certified pediatrician who does not practice at a FQHC shall have ainimum of twenty percent (20%) of patient encounters; and</text>
    <text>Any eligible professional predominately practicing at a FQHC shall have at leasthirty percent (30%) of patient volume attributable to needy individuals.</text>
    <text>An eligible professional shall calculate individual Medicaid patient volume byividing the total Medicaid patient encounters (in and out of the District) inny continuous ninety (90) day period in the calendar year (CY) preceding theligible professional’s
      payment year, or in the twelve (12) months before theligible professional’s attestation; by the total patient encounters in theame ninety (90) day period;</text>
    <text>Subject to 42 C.F.R. § 495.306(h), an eligible professional shall calculateroup Medicaid patient volume by dividing the total Medicaid patient encountersin and out of the District across the entire group or clinic) in any continuousinety (90) day
      period in the CY preceding the eligible professional’s paymentear, or in the twelve (12) months before the eligible professional’sttestation; by the total patient encounters (in and out of the District acrosshe entire group or clinic); and</text>
    <text>An eligible professional practicing in a FQHC shall calculate needy individualatient volume by dividing the total needy individual patient encounters in anyontinuous ninety day period in the CY preceding the eligible professional’sttestation; by the
      total patient encounters in the same ninety (90) day period.</text>
    <text>An eligible acute care hospital shall have at least ten percent (10%) Medicaidatient volume based on individual methodology as calculated below:</text>
    <text>An eligible hospital shall divide the total Medicaid patient encounters (in andut of the District) in any continuous ninety (90) day period in the precedingiscal year (FY), or in the twelve (12) months before the eligible hospital’sttestation; by</text>
    <text>The total patient encounters in the same ninety (90) day period to calculatendividual Medicaid patient volume.</text>
    <text>An eligible children’s hospital shall be exempt from volume requirements ofubsections 8901.1 through 8901.2.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 61 DCR 237 (January 10, 2014).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>