<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-804</num>
  <heading>PROGRAM MANUAL (ยง 29-804)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>804.1.</num>
    <text>Each participating FSMHC shall have a current program manual that outlines all of its policies and procedures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>804.2.</num>
    <text>The program manual shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A mission statement reflecting the goals and missions of the DHS Mental Health Services Administration;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The range or services to be provided;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Fee schedules;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The population to be served;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Operational schedules;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Staff policies, personnel policies, clinic policies, and quality assurance standards;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Financial and record-keeping procedures; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Patient&amp;#8217;s rights.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>804.3.</num>
    <text>The personnel policies shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Written job descriptions of all staff positions, procedures for employee hiring, evaluations, grievances, and in-service training;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>In-service training of meaningful nature for all non-professional staff and identification of the supervisor(s) responsible for providing and facilitating that training;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A minimum of one (1) hour per week of supervision for all non-professionals, student trainees, staff-in-training, and volunteers, furnished by a mental health professional designated as the supervisor. Supervision shall cover patient related and
        other activities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>An up-to-date listing of professional staff licensure and registration information; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Written policies and procedures for emergency care.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>804.4.</num>
    <text>All personnel policies shall be reviewed at least annually, revised as indicated, and the date of review and revisions shall be noted in the program manual.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking adopted at 29 DCR 264 (January 15, 1982).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>