<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-8903</num>
  <heading>PROGRAM INTEGRITY (§ 29-8903)
    <text>An eligible provider shall retain documentation that verifies its eligibilityor MEIP for a minimum of ten (10) years and cooperate with DHCF and any otheruly authorized agent of a governmental agency seeking to audit compliance withEIP requirements.</text>
    <text>An eligible provider’s cooperation shall include, but is not limited to, theollowing:</text>
    <text>Making available to DHCF, or its designee, upon request, all necessary andomplete records and other documentation for audit purposes as specified in theequest;</text>
    <text>Permitting DHCF, or its designee, to audit, inspect, examine, excerpt, copynd/or transcribe the records related to this incentive program; and</text>
    <text>Permitting DHCF, or its designee, to access its premises to inspect and monitorts compliance with program requirements.</text>
    <text>Conduct a full investigation or refer the case to the State Medicaid fraudontrol unit upon suspicion or detection of fraud or abuse by an eligiblerovider;</text>
    <text>Refer the case to the appropriate law enforcement agency upon suspicion oretection of fraud by a beneficiary; and</text>
    <text>Comply with all other laws and regulations designed to prevent fraud, waste, andbuse, including, but not limited to applicable provisions of federal criminalaw, the False Claims Act (31 U.S.C. § 3729 et seq.), the Anti-Kickback Statute42 U.S.C. §
      1320a-7b), § 1128B(b) of the Social Security Act, and 42 C.F.R.§95.368.</text>
    <text>Suspend an incentive payment until the eligible provider has removed theeficiency to the satisfaction of DHCF;</text>
    <text>Require full repayment of all or a portion of an incentive payment; or</text>
    <text>Terminate the eligible provider’s MEIP participation.</text>
    <text>DHCF shall issue a written notice when any action is taken pursuant toubsection 8903.3 in accordance with the requirements set forth in Chapter 13 ofitle 29 DCMR.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>DHCF shall prevent fraud, waste, and abuse by employing the following actions</heading>
      <text />
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>DHCF may take the following actions with respect to an eligible provider foundeficient or in violation of this rule</heading>
      <text />
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 61 DCR 237 (January 10, 2014).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>