<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-8208</num>
  <heading>FINANCIAL MANAGEMENT BY GRANTEES (ยง 29-8208)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8208.1.</num>
    <text>Each grantee shall make accurate, current, and complete disclosure of the financial results of each project or program in accordance with the financial reporting requirements of the grant agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8208.2.</num>
    <text>Each grantee shall maintain records which identify adequately the source and application of funds for grant supported activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8208.3.</num>
    <text>The grantee&amp;#8217;s records shall contain information identifying the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Any grant awards received;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any subgrant awards, if authorized by the grant agreement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any authorizations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any obligations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any unobligated balances;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>All assets;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>All outlays; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>All income.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8208.4.</num>
    <text>Each grantee shall maintain effective control and accountability for all grant or subgrant assets, including cash and real personal property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8208.5.</num>
    <text>Each grantee shall adequately safeguard all property and shall assure that it is used solely for authorized purposes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8208.6.</num>
    <text>Each grantee&amp;#8217;s records shall compare the actual and budgeted amounts of expenditures for each grant or subgrant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8208.7.</num>
    <text>If required by the grant officer, the grantee shall correlate financial information to performance or productivity data, including the production of unit cost information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8208.8.</num>
    <text>The grantee shall establish procedures to minimize the time elapsing between the advance of District grant funds and their disbursement by the grantee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8208.9.</num>
    <text>Grantees advancing cash to subgrantees shall conform substantially to the same standards of timing and amount of advances as apply to advances by the District to grantees, including requirements for timely reporting of cash disbursements and balances.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8208.10.</num>
    <text>Each grantee shall establish procedures for determining the reasonableness, allowability, and allocability of costs in accordance with the applicable cost principles prescribed in the Office of Management and Budget Circular A-122.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8208.11.</num>
    <text>Grantee accounting records shall be supported by source documentation such as canceled checks, paid bills, payrolls, contract and subgrant award documents.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8208.12.</num>
    <text>Each grantee shall follow a systematic method to assure timely and appropriate resolution of audit findings and recommendations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking at 53 DCR 7448 (September 8, 2006) [EXPIRED]; and as amended by Final Rulemaking at 54 DCR 120 (January 5, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>