<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-9410</num>
  <heading>PROVIDER AND SUPPLIER TERMINATION OR DENIAL OF ENROLLMENT (§ 29-9410)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>9410.1.</num>
    <text>In accordance with 42 C.F.R. §§ 455.416(a)-(f), DHCF shall initiate termination of the Provider Agreement, or deny the Application, of any provider or supplier when any of the following occurs:</text>
    <text>Termination of a provider or supplier on or after January 1, 2011, under Title XVIII of the Social Security Act, or under the Medicaid program or Children’s Health Insurance Program (CHIP) in any state;</text>
    <text>Failure to cooperate with screening methods and submit timely and accurate information by any individual with a five percent (5%) or greater direct or indirect ownership interest in a provider or supplier;</text>
    <text>Conviction of a criminal offense related to Medicare, Medicaid, or CHIP in the last ten (10) years related to any individual with a five percent (5%) or greater direct or indirect ownership interest in a provider or supplier, unless DHCF determines
      that denial or termination is not in the best interests of the District’s Medicaid program and documents this determination in writing;</text>
    <text>Failure to submit timely and accurate information by any individual with an ownership or control interest, or who is an agent or managing employee of the provider or supplier, unless DHCF determines that denial or termination is not in the best interests
      of the District’s Medicaid program and documents this determination in writing;</text>
    <text>Failure of individuals with a five percent (5%) or greater direct or indirect ownership interest in a provider or supplier to submit fingerprints upon request, in a form and manner determined by DHCF, within thirty (30) days from the date of the request,
      unless DHCF determines that denial or termination is not in the best interests of the District’s Medicaid program and documents this determination in writing; or</text>
    <text>Failure to permit access to provider or supplier’s locations for any site visit required pursuant to 42 C.F.R. § 455.432, unless DHCF determines that denial or termination is not in the best interests of the District’s Medicaid program and documents
      this determination in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9410.2.</num>
    <text>In accordance with 42 C.F.R. § 455.416(g), DHCF may terminate the enrollment, or deny an Application, of any provider or supplier if CMS or DHCF finds either of the following:</text>
    <text>The Applicant falsified any information provided on the Application; or</text>
    <text>The Applicant’s identity cannot be verified.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9410.3.</num>
    <text>DHCF shall enforce all terminations that result from the Secretary of the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services mandatorily excluding individuals or entities from participating in any Federal or state health care program, pursuant to 42 U.S.C.
      § 1320a-7(a), for the any of the following:</text>
    <text>Conviction of program-related crimes;</text>
    <text>Conviction relating to patient abuse;</text>
    <text>Felony conviction relating to health care fraud; or</text>
    <text>Felony conviction relating to a controlled substance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9410.4.</num>
    <text>DHCF shall enforce all terminations that result from the Secretary of the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services permissively excluding individuals and entities from participating in any Federal or state health care program, pursuant to 42 U.S.C.
      § 1320a-7(b), for any of the following:</text>
    <text>Conviction relating to fraud, theft, embezzlement, breach of fiduciary responsibility, or other financial misconduct;</text>
    <text>Conviction in connection with the interference with, or obstruction of, any investigation or audit related to the use of funds received, directly or indirectly, from any Federally funded health care program;</text>
    <text>Misdemeanor conviction relating to a controlled substance;</text>
    <text>License revocation or suspension by a State licensing authority, including surrendering of such a license held while formal disciplinary proceeding is pending;</text>
    <text>Exclusion, suspension, or sanction from any Federal or State program involving the provision of health care, including programs administered by the Department of Defense and Department of Veterans Affairs;</text>
    <text>Submission of claims reflecting excessive charges and/or unnecessary services;</text>
    <text>Failure to provide medically necessary services, and thereby adversely impacting covered individuals;</text>
    <text>Committing acts that constitute fraud, facilitate kickbacks, and/or support other prohibited activities, pursuant to 42 U.S.C. §§ 1320a-7a, 1320a-7b, or 1320a-8;</text>
    <text>Allowing a sanctioned individual to hold a five percent (5%) or more direct or indirect ownership or control interest, serve as an officer, director, agent, or managing employee;</text>
    <text>Allowing an individual to hold a direct or indirect ownership or control interest in a sanctioned entity when the individual knows, or should know, of the action that resulted in conviction or exclusion from Medicare or a state health care program;</text>
    <text>Failure to disclose information required to process an Application or revalidate enrollment, including requested information on subcontractors and/or suppliers;</text>
    <text>Failure to permit examination of records supporting payment;</text>
    <text>Failure to grant immediate access, upon reasonable request, to the Secretary, or designee; the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services; or representatives of DHCF or the Medicaid Fraud Control Unit;</text>
    <text>Failure of a hospital to comply substantially with corrective action commenced in accordance with 42 U.S.C. § 1395ww(f)(2)(B);</text>
    <text>Default on health education loan or scholarship obligations by an individual, except physicians who provide unique services to the community serviced; and</text>
    <text>Making false statements or misrepresentation of material facts in any application, agreement, bid, or contract to participate or enroll as a provider or supplier under a Federal health care program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9410.5.</num>
    <text>As set forth in 42 U.S.C. §§ 1320a-7(c)-(g), DHCF shall adhere to Federal guidelines governing terminations that occur pursuant to Subsections 9410.4 and 9410.5.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9410.6.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall supersede or lessen the force of any other laws or regulations that govern provider participation in the Medicaid program, including the False Claims Act, effective February 21, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-85; D.C. Official Code
      § 2-381.02 (2008 Repl.)).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10041 (July 12, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>