<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-938</num>
  <heading>INCREASED REIMBURSEMENT FOR ELIGIBLE PRIMARY CARE SERVICES (§ 29-938)
    <text>Except as provided in Subsection 938.2, primary care services eligible forncreased reimbursement under the Healthcare Common Procedure Coding SystemHCPCS) shall include evaluation and management (E&amp;#038;M) services billednder codes 99201 through
      99499; and Current Procedural Terminology (CPT)accine administration codes 90460, 90461, 90471, 90472, 90473, and 90474, orheir successor codes. DHCF shall publish a list of all eligible codes on itsrovider website at www.dc-medicaid.com.</text>
    <text>Services billed under codes that were not reimbursable under the DHCF feechedule as of January 1, 2013 shall be ineligible for reimbursement. DHCF shallublish a list of ineligible codes on its provider website atww.dc-medicaid.com.</text>
    <text>An eligible primary care physician shall receive increased reimbursement forligible primary care services, provided the following requirements are met:</text>
    <text>A physician provides a written self-attestation that the physician has apecialty designation of family medicine, general internal medicine, orediatric medicine; and</text>
    <text>A primary care physician provides a written self-attestation of theollowing:</text>
    <text>That he or she has Board-certification in family medicine, general internaledicine, pediatric medicine, or in a subspecialty of family medicine; generalnternal medicine or pediatric medicine as designated by the American Board ofedical Specialties
      (ABMS); the American Board of Physician Specialties (ABPS);r the American Osteopathic Association (AOA); or</text>
    <text>He or she has provided E&amp;#038;M and vaccine administration services under theodes described in Subsection 938.1 that equal at least sixty percent (60%) ofll the Medicaid services that the physician bills during either of theollowing:</text>
    <text>The most recently completed calendar year; or</text>
    <text>The month prior to the month that DHCF receives the self-attestation formeferenced in Subsections 938.4 through 938.9, for a physician enrolled inedicaid for less than a full calendar year.</text>
    <text>An Advanced Practice Registered Nurse (APRN) shall receive increasedeimbursement for eligible primary care services billed pursuant to the FPS feechedule, provided the APRN provides eligible primary care services under theirect supervision of a physician
      who:</text>
    <text>Meets the eligibility requirements of Subsection 938.3;</text>
    <text>Assumes professional responsibility for the services provided by the APRN; and</text>
    <text>Has submitted a self-attestation form, as described in Subsections 938.3 through38.9, which identifies the APRN as a practitioner under the physician&amp;#8217;sirect supervision.</text>
    <text>To receive reimbursement under this rule for calendar year (CY) 2013 and CY014, an eligible physician shall provide the DHCF with a self-attestation thathe physician meets the requirements of Subsection 938.3 using a form prescribedy DHCF.</text>
    <text>Except as provided in Subsection 938.7, reimbursement under this rule shallommence from the date that DHCF receives the self-attestation form from anligible provider, as described in Subsections 938.3 through 938.9.</text>
    <text>Reimbursement shall be made in accordance with the corresponding State Planmendment as approved by the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS),rovided an eligible physician who is participating in Medicaid on the effectiveate of these rules
      shall submit the self-attestation form, as described byubsections 938.3 through 938.6, to DHCF no later than July 1, 2013.</text>
    <text>An eligible physician, who has submitted a self-attestation form as required byubsection 938.3, is obligated to inform DHCF in writing of any changes thatlter the physician’s eligibility for reimbursement under this rule.</text>
    <text>An APRN who provides eligible primary care services under the direct supervisionf an eligible physician shall be exempt from the self-attestation formequirement.</text>
    <text>For eligible primary care services rendered by an eligible physician, FPSedicaid reimbursement shall be made at the lower of the physician&amp;#8217;silled charges or the applicable reimbursement rate, as defined in Subsection38.13.</text>
    <text>For eligible primary care services rendered by an APRN, FFS Medicaideimbursement shall be made in accordance with the approved State Plan using thepplicable rate, as defined in Subsection 938.13.</text>
    <text>Reimbursement rates established pursuant to this section apply to eligiblerimary care services billed as fee-for-service that are furnished on and afterhe effective date of the corresponding State Plan Amendment as approved by CMSnd ending on December
      31, 2014.</text>
    <text>The applicable rates for eligible primary care services shall be as follows:</text>
    <text>For eligible E&amp;#038;M services:</text>
    <text>The applicable rate for services furnished for the period beginning with theffective date of the corresponding State Plan Amendment as approved by theenters for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS) through December 31, 2013 shalle the higher of the
      Medicare Part B fee schedule rate that is applicable to theon-­ facility site of service in effect on January 1, 2013 or the rate thatould be derived using the CY 2009 conversion factor and the CY 2013 Medicareelative value units (RVUs); and</text>
    <text>The applicable rate for services furnished for the period beginning January 1,014 through December 31, 2014 shall be the higher of the Medicare Part B feechedule rate that is applicable to the Medicare Part B fee schedule rate thats applicable to
      the non-facility site of service in effect on January 1, 2014r the rate that would be derived using the CY 2009 conversion factor and the CY014 Medicare relative value units (RVUs).</text>
    <text>For eligible vaccine administration services:</text>
    <text>The applicable rate for services furnished for the period beginning with theffective date of the corresponding State Plan Amendment as approved by theenters for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS) through December 31, 2013 shalle the Regional Maximum
      Administration Fee in effect in CY 2013; and</text>
    <text>The applicable rate for services furnished for the period beginning January 1,014 through December 31, 2014 shall be the Regional Maximum Administration Feen effect in CY 2014.</text>
    <text>DHCF shall publish the applicable rates for eligible primary care services eachalendar year on its provider website at www.dc-medicaid.com/.</text>
    <text>The eligibility of each physician or APRN shall be subject to verification thathe physician or APRN has complied with the requirements set forth in this rule.</text>
    <text>Any administrative action with respect to an eligible physician or APRN found iniolation of the rule, shall comply with the requirements set forth in Chapter3 of Title 29 DCMR.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <num>938.99</num>
    <text>938.99 For the purposes of this section, the following terms shall havehe meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Advanced Practice Registered Nurse (APRN): A licensed registered nurse withdvanced education, knowledge, skills, and scope of practice who has beenertified to perform advanced­ level nursing actions by a national certifyingody acceptable to the Board
      of Nursing; and pursuant to District of Columbiaealth Occupations Revisions Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law-99; D.C. Official Code §§ 3-1201 et seq. (2007 Repl. &amp;#038; 2011 Supp.)).dvanced practice registered nursing shall include
      the categories of nurseidwife and nurse­ practitioner. (D.C. Official Code§ 3-1202.04 (2007 Repl.#038; 2011 Supp.)).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 2042 (March 7, 2003); as amended byinal Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 6703 (August 15, 2003); as amended by Finalulemaking published at 50 DCR 7832 (September 19, 2003); as amended by Finalulemaking published
        at 55 DCR 2858 (March 21, 2008); as amended by Finalulemaking published at 61 DCR 225 (January 10, 2014).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>