<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-9104</num>
  <heading>CLINICAL CARE COORDINATION (§ 29-9104)
    <text>Each Medicaid beneficiary receiving ASARS treatment shall be assigned a Clinicalare Coordinator.</text>
    <text>Clinical Care Coordinators shall participate in a beneficiary’snterdisciplinary team meetings in order to identify opportunities to furtherevelop or update the treatment plan. The interdisciplinary team shall meet theequirements set forth in 29 DCMR
      § 2334.4.</text>
    <text>A unit of clinical care coordination service shall be one (1) fifteen (15)inute increment, pursuant to DHCF’s billing criteria.</text>
    <text>Clinical care coordination service shall be subject to limitations on scope,requency, and duration. Beneficiaries who require services in excess ofstablished limits shall require prior authorization from DHCF.</text>
    <text>Limitations for clinical care coordination services, by level of care, perreatment episode are as follows:</text>
    <text>Level IV shall not exceed sixteen (16) units;</text>
    <text>Level III shall not exceed sixty-four (64) units;</text>
    <text>Level II shall not exceed ninety-six (96) units; and</text>
    <text>Level I shall not exceed one hundred ninety-two (192) units. Beneficiaries atevel I and receiving long-term Medication Assisted Treatment shall be allowedn additional sixteen (16) units.</text>
    <text>Beneficiaries entering ASARS treatment at Level IV shall have clinical careoordination services provided by either qualified physicians or psychologists.</text>
    <text>Beneficiaries entering ASARS treatment at Level III shall have clinical careoordination services provided by qualified physicians, psychologists, licensedndependent clinical social workers, or advanced practice registered nurse.</text>
    <text>Beneficiaries entering ASARS treatment at Levels II and I shall have clinicalare coordination services provided by any of the following qualifiedractitioners:</text>
    <text>Licensed Independent Clinical Social Worker;</text>
    <text>Advanced Practice Registered Nurse;</text>
    <text>Registered Nurse;</text>
    <text>Licensed Independent Social Worker;</text>
    <text>Licensed Professional Counselor; or</text>
    <text>Certified Addiction Counselor II.</text>
    <text>Clinical care coordinators, except physicians and psychologists, shall providelinical care coordination services under the supervision of the followingractitioners:</text>
    <text>Licensed Independent Clinical Social Worker;</text>
    <text>Advanced Practice Registered Nurse;</text>
    <text>Registered Nurse certified in chemical dependency;</text>
    <text>Supervisory Certified Addiction Counselor II as defined in 17 DCMR § 8715; or</text>
    <text>An individual with a Bachelor’s degree from an accredited college orniversity in social work, counseling, psychology, or a closely related field,nd at least two (2) full years of experience.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 11144 (September 28, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>