<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-9102</num>
  <heading>TREATMENT FRAMEWORK (§ 29-9102)
    <text>The ASARS treatment framework shall be based on four (4) levels of carestablished by the American Society for Addiction Medicine (ASAM). Treatmentnder the ASARS Program shall also support continuity of services acrossultiple levels of care. Delivery
      of ASARS shall be based on theeneficiary’s level of care and length of the treatment episode.</text>
    <text>Levels of care under the ASARS program are as follows:</text>
    <text>Level IV shall represent beneficiaries who are at high risk of experiencingithdrawal due to a diagnosed substance use disorder. Beneficiaries who presentor Level IV treatment shall require twenty-four (24) hour psychiatric care withelated addiction
      treatment;</text>
    <text>Level III shall represent beneficiaries who are at risk of experiencingithdrawal due to a diagnosed substance use disorder, but who do not require theull resources of a licensed hospital. Beneficiaries who present for Level IIIreatment shall require
      placement in facilities that offer twenty-four (24)tructured settings;</text>
    <text>Level II shall represent beneficiaries who are at minimal or moderate risk ofevere withdrawal. Beneficiaries who present for Level II treatment shallequire near-daily programs offering intensive engagement in order to progressfter exhibiting signs
      of readiness to change; and</text>
    <text>Level I shall represent beneficiaries who experience minimal or no risk ofignificant or severe withdrawal. Beneficiaries who present for Level Ireatment shall be able to maintain abstinence from substances while pursuingecovery goals with minimal
      support.</text>
    <text>The average lengths of ASARS treatment episodes, by level of care, shall be asollows:</text>
    <text>Level IV: Three (3) to five (5) days;</text>
    <text>Level III: Approximately twenty-eight (28) days;</text>
    <text>Level II: Thirty (30) to forty-five (45) days; and</text>
    <text>Level I: Approximately one hundred twenty (120) days (excluding Medicationssisted Treatment).</text>
    <text>Prior authorization shall be required if a beneficiary experiences a relapsehat requires him or her to repeat treatment at a level of care that wasreviously received during the same twelve (12)-month period.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 11144 (September 28, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>