<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-9103</num>
  <heading>ASSESSMENT AND DIAGNOSTIC SERVICES (§ 29-9103)
    <text>Assessment and diagnostic services shall include the initial evaluation, initialnd ongoing collection of relevant information, and subsequent monitoring ofnformation about a beneficiary who needs access to ASARS treatment.</text>
    <text>Assessment and diagnostic services shall include the following categories:</text>
    <text>Initial assessment and diagnostic services;</text>
    <text>Comprehensive assessment and diagnostic services;</text>
    <text>Ongoing assessment and diagnostic services; and</text>
    <text>Brief assessment and diagnostic services.</text>
    <text>The assessment instruments shall incorporate American Society for Addictionedicine (ASAM) patient placement criteria.</text>
    <text>The initial assessment and diagnostic services shall be required to determine anndividual’s need for substance treatment.</text>
    <text>The comprehensive assessment and diagnostic services shall be required tonitiate a treatment episode.</text>
    <text>Initial, comprehensive, and ongoing assessment and diagnostic services shallnclude referrals, as well as development and refinement of treatment plans.</text>
    <text>Brief assessment and diagnostic services shall be used to incorporate updates to beneficiary’s diagnosis or treatment plan prior to transfer into a differentevel of care. Brief assessment and diagnostic services shall also be used tore-screen for
      hospitalization and prior to a beneficiary’s discharge fromSARS treatment.</text>
    <text>Initial and comprehensive assessment and diagnostic services shall be performednce per treatment episode.</text>
    <text>Clinical care coordinators shall determine the frequency of ongoing and briefssessment and diagnostic services and note this information in theeneficiary’s treatment plan.</text>
    <text>A unit of assessment and diagnostic service shall be one (1) fifteen (15) minutencrement, pursuant to Department of Health Care Finance’s (DHCF) billingriteria.</text>
    <text>Assessment and diagnostic services shall be subject to limitations on scope,requency, and duration. Beneficiaries who require services in excess ofstablished limits shall require prior authorization from DHCF.</text>
    <text>Limitations for assessment and diagnostic services, per treatment episode are asollows:</text>
    <text>Initial assessment and diagnostic services shall not exceed four (4) units;</text>
    <text>Comprehensive assessment and diagnostic services shall not exceed sixteen (16)nits;</text>
    <text>Ongoing assessment and diagnostic services shall not exceed ninety-two (92)nits; and</text>
    <text>Brief assessment and diagnostic services shall not exceed eight (8) units.</text>
    <text>Initial assessment and diagnostic services shall be delivered by the followingualified practitioners:</text>
    <text>Registered nurses;</text>
    <text>Licensed Independent Social Workers;</text>
    <text>Licensed Professional Counselors; and</text>
    <text>Certified Addiction Counselors I and II.</text>
    <text>Comprehensive, ongoing, and brief assessment and diagnostic services shall beelivered by the following qualified practitioners:</text>
    <text>Physicians;</text>
    <text>Psychologists;</text>
    <text>Licensed Independent Clinical Social Workers; and</text>
    <text>Advanced Practice Registered Nurses.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 11144 (September 28, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>