<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-951</num>
  <heading>MONTHLY REPORTING REQUIREMENTS FOR RESERVED BED DAYS (ยง 29-951)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>951.1.</num>
    <text>Each provider shall submit to MAA on a monthly basis a status report reflecting the total number of reserved bed days used for each resident during the month and the cumulative total for the fiscal year, including the additional hospitalization days
      authorized pursuant to these rules. The report shall include the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Resident&amp;#8217;s name;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Medicaid identification number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Number of hospitalization reserved bed days used in previous months;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Number of therapeutic leave reserved bed days used in previous months;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Number of hospitalization reserved bed days used in the current month;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Number of therapeutic leave reserved bed days used in the current month;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Cumulative hospitalization reserved bed days used to date in the fiscal year; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Cumulative therapeutic leave reserved bed days used to date in the fiscal year.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>951.2.</num>
    <text>The monthly status report shall be submitted to MAA no later than the 10th day of each month unless the 10th day is on a weekend or a District of Columbia government holiday. In the case of a weekend or holiday, the report shall be submitted the first
      business day following the weekend or holiday.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>951.3.</num>
    <text>The Medicaid Program shall seek repayment from the provider for any reserved bed days in excess of the limitations set forth in section 950.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>951.99.</num>
    <text>DEFINITIONS</text>
    <text>When used in sections 950 and 951 of this Chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Fiscal Year (FY) &amp;#8211; Shall have the same meaning as the District of Columbia government fiscal year, October 1 through September 30.</text>
    <text>Therapeutic Leave &amp;#8211; Includes visits with relatives and friends as well as leave to participate in State-approved therapeutic and rehabilitative programs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 1370 (February 24, 2006); as Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 3879 (April 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>