<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-950</num>
  <heading>PAYMENT FOR RESERVED BEDS (§ 29-950)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>950.1.</num>
    <text>Vendor payment for reserved bed days for hospitalization or therapeutic leaves of absence, for a resident of a nursing facility, when provided in the resident&amp;#8217;s plan of care, shall not exceed eighteen (18) days during any fiscal year, if
      there is a reasonable expectation that the resident will return to the nursing facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>950.2.</num>
    <text>Vendor payment for reserved bed days for hospitalization, for a resident of an intermediate care facility for persons with mental retardation (ICFs/MR) shall not exceed fifteen (15) days during any fiscal year, if there is a reasonable expectation
      that the resident will return to the facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>950.3.</num>
    <text>Vendor payment for reserved bed days for therapeutic leaves of absence, for a resident of an ICF/MR, when provided in the resident&amp;#8217;s plan of care shall not exceed forty-five (45) days during any fiscal year, if there is a reasonable expectation
      that the resident will return to the facility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>950.4.</num>
    <text>Payment for reserved bed days authorized in accordance with section 950.1 shall equal 100 percent of the facility&amp;#8217;s per diem rate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>950.5.</num>
    <text>Payment for reserved bed days authorized in accordance with sections 950.2 and 950.3 shall equal the facility&amp;#8217;s per diem rate and shall not include reimbursement for one to one services. A reserved bed day for purposes of this section is
      a day in which an ICF/MR resident receives fewer than eight of hours of supports in an ICF/MR beginning at midnight (12:00 am) and ending at 11:59 p.m.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>950.6.</num>
    <text>Each resident shall reside in the nursing facility or ICF/MR for at least one day as a condition of vendor payment for reserved bed days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>950.7.</num>
    <text>Each provider shall require the family member or caregiver to sign a leave and request form upon exit and return to the facility. The provider shall ensure that each family member or caregiver provide contact information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>950.8.</num>
    <text>Each provider shall discuss the resident&amp;#8217;s medical regimen with the family member or caregiver. The provider shall ensure that each family member or caregiver is provided a sufficient quantity of the resident&amp;#8217;s medication for the
      leave period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>950.9.</num>
    <text>Each provider shall report to MAA any unusual incident that occurred during any therapeutic leave of absence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>The authority for §§950 &amp;#8211; 960 is D.C. Code, 2001 Ed. §1-307.02; Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1996, 3 D.C. Code, 2001 Ed. at 413; and Mayor’s Order 97-42 (February 18, 1997).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 1370 (February 24, 2006); as Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 3879 (April 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>