<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-1007</num>
  <heading>REGISTRATION VERIFICATION OF THE PETITION (§ 3-1007)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1007.1.</num>
    <text>Upon the acceptance of an initiative or referendum petition for filing, whether in the normal course or at the direction of the court, the Board shall certify within thirty (30) calendar days whether the initiative or referendum petition contains
      the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A sufficient number of valid signatures which meet the qualifying percentage and ward distribution requirements; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The necessary number of names and signatures of registered qualified electors of the District of Columbia, properly distributed by ward.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1007.2.</num>
    <text>In evaluating the sufficiency of the petition, the Board shall first verify the registration of each petition signer and determine the number of registered voters whose names and apparent signatures appear on the petition, and who are registered to
      vote at the address listed on the petition on the date signed. The Board shall include in this number any petition signer whose name appears on the voter registry at a different address, if the Board’s records indicate that the voter filed a change
      of address after the date on which the petition was signed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1007.3.</num>
    <text>The number of verified registrants determined pursuant to § 1007.2 shall establish the universe of apparent registered voter signatures to be verified for authenticity by random sample pursuant to § 1008 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1007.4.</num>
    <text>The Board shall exclude from the random sample universe a signature if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The signer’s voter registration was designated &amp;#8220;inactive&amp;#8221; on the voter roll pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 1-1001.07(j)(2) (2011 Repl.), at the time the petition was signed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The signer, according to the Board’s records, was not registered to vote at the address listed on the petition at the time the petition was signed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The signer is not a &amp;#8220;duly registered voter&amp;#8221;;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The signature is not dated;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The petition does not include the printed or typed current address of the signer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The petition does not include the printed or typed name of the signer and, in the judgment of the Board, the signature is illegible; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The circulator of the petition sheet did not meet the petition circulator requirements set forth in § 1005.1 at the time the petition was signed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1007.5.</num>
    <text>Registered voters who are unable to sign their names may make their marks in the space provided for signatures. These marks shall not be counted as valid signatures unless the person(s) witnessing the marks has attached an affidavit to the petition,
      wherein it is stated that the contents of the petition were explained to the signatory and that the affiant witnessed their marks.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1007.6.</num>
    <text>If a person has signed an initiative or referendum petition more than once, only one (1) signature shall be counted for that person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1007.7.</num>
    <text>If a person who has signed a petition is a duly registered voter on the date signed in a ward other than that which was indicated on the petition sheet, that person’s signature shall be counted from the proper ward in which he or she was duly registered
      to vote at the time the petition was signed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1007.8.</num>
    <text>When some but not all signatures on a petition have been signed outside the presence of the circulator, only those signatures signed outside the circulator’s presence shall be invalid, and the remaining signatures on the sheet shall be deemed valid
      if there are no other defects in the signatures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1007.9.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, a &amp;#8220;duly registered voter&amp;#8221; shall be a registered qualified elector who is registered to vote at the address listed on the petition as shown on the Board’s voter registration records at the time
      the petition was signed and whose registration is not designated &amp;#8220;inactive&amp;#8221; on the voter roll at the time the petition is signed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1007.10.</num>
    <text>A registered voter may submit a written notarized request to the Board to disallow the voter’s signature from being counted on the petition; Provided, that the request shall be received by the Board prior to the time the petition is filed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1007.11.</num>
    <text>If the number of apparent signatures determined pursuant to § 1007.2 does not meet or exceed the established ward and District-wide requirements, the Board shall reject the petition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1007.12.</num>
    <text>If the number of apparent signatures of registered voters determined pursuant to § 1007.2 meets or exceeds the established minimum ward and District-wide requirements, the Board shall verify the apparent voter signatures appearing on the initiative
      or referendum petition by performing a bona fide random, statistical sampling pursuant to § 1008 of this chapter under the guidance of the Data Management Division of the Office of Planning.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 43 D.C. Reg. 103, 111 (January 12, 1996); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 D.C. Reg. 6977 (August 27, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 5582 (April 12, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>