<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-1001</num>
  <heading>COMMENCEMENT OF INITIATIVE OR REFERENDUM PROCESS (§ 3-1001)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1001.1.</num>
    <text>In order to commence the initiative or referendum process, a registered qualified elector(s) shall file the following documents with the Board:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Five (5) printed or typewritten copies of the full text of the initiative or referendum measure;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A summary statement of the measure not exceeding one hundred (100) words in length, as defined in § 1002.8;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A short title of the measure to be proposed by initiative or of the act or part of the act to be referred; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>An affidavit under oath containing the name, telephone number, and residence address of the proposer, and a statement that the proposer is a registered qualified elector of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1001.2.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt, the Board shall immediately transmit a copy of the measure to its General Counsel, who shall prepare for publication in the D.C. Register a &amp;#8220;Notice of Public Hearing: Receipt and Intent to Review&amp;#8221; the proposed initiative
      or referendum measure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1001.3.</num>
    <text>Following publication of the &amp;#8220;Notice of Public Hearing: Receipt and Intent to Review&amp;#8221; in the D.C. Register, the Board, at a public hearing, shall determine whether to approve the measure as proper subject matter for an initiative
      or referendum measure, or to reject it based on the following reasons:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The measure presented is not a proper subject for an initiative or referendum under Title IV of the Self-Government Act;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The statement of organization and the report(s) of receipts and expenditures have not been filed with the Office of Campaign Finance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The form of the measure does not comply with the requirements set forth in §1001.1;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The measure authorizes or would have the effect of authorizing discrimination prohibited under the Human Rights Act of 1977; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The measure would negate or limit an act of the Council enacted pursuant to § 446 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1001.4.</num>
    <text>In the event of a refusal to accept the measure as a proper subject matter, the Board shall endorse on the measure the words &amp;#8220;received but not accepted,&amp;#8221; and the date, and retain the measure pending appeal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1001.5.</num>
    <text>The proposer(s) of a rejected initiative or referendum measure may, under D.C. Code § 1-1001.16(b)(3) (2006 Repl.), as amended, petition the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, within ten (10) days after the refusal, for a writ in the nature
      of mandamus to compel the Board to accept the measure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1001.6.</num>
    <text>If none of the grounds for refusal specified in § 1001.3 exist, the Board shall accept the initiative or referendum measure as a proper subject matter and shall assign a serial number to the measure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1001.7.</num>
    <text>The first initiative measure shall be numbered one (1) in numerals. Succeeding measures shall be numbered consecutively 2, 3, 4, and so on ad infinitum.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1001.8.</num>
    <text>The first referendum measure shall be numbered 001 in numerals. Succeeding measures shall be numbered 002, 003, 004, and so on ad infinitum.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1001.9.</num>
    <text>Once assigned a serial number, an initiative or referendum measure shall be known and designated on all petitions, election ballots, and proceedings as &amp;#8220;Initiative Measure No. &amp;#8220;or&amp;#8221; Referendum Measure No. .&amp;#8221;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 43 D.C. Reg. 103, 104-05 (January 12, 1996).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR’S NOTE</heading>
      <text>Section 11717 of Title XI of the National Capital Revitalization and Self Government Improvement Act of 1997 amended section 101 of the District of Columbia Self-Government Reorganization Act by striking &amp;#8220;District of Columbia Self Government
        and Governmental Reorganization Act&amp;#8221; and inserting &amp;#8220;District of Columbia Home Rule Act.&amp;#8221; Therefore, all reference, to the &amp;#8220;District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act&amp;#8221;
        shall mean the &amp;#8220;District of Columbia Home Rule Act.&amp;#8221;</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>