<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-1600</num>
  <heading>NOMINATING PETITIONS[COLON] PRIMARY ELECTION (§ 3-1600)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1600.1.</num>
    <text>A nominating petition shall be separately prepared and issued by the Board for each candidate seeking nomination in the Primary Election to the office of Delegate, Mayor, Chairman of the Council, Member of the Council, U.S. Senator and U.S. Representative.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.2.</num>
    <text>The requirements for the Primary Election nominating petition for the offices of Delegate, Mayor, and Chairman of the Council, Member of the Council, U.S. Senator and U.S. Representative are as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The front page of each petition sheet shall contain the name, address, party affiliation, registration number and the office to which the candidate seeks election;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The front page shall also state that the signers of the petition shall be of the same political party as the candidate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If the candidate is running from a ward, school district or single-member district, the front page shall also state that all signatories shall be registered and be residents of the ward, school district or single-member district from which the candidate
        seeks election;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The back page of each petition sheet shall contain the name, address (telephone number optional) of the person circulating the petition sheet and the affidavit of circulator required pursuant to § 1600.5 of this chapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The back page of each petition sheet shall inform the circulator of the penalties for conviction of providing false information in the affidavit of the circulator required pursuant to § 1600.5 of this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.3.</num>
    <text>No nominating petition for any of the offices covered by this chapter shall be issued by the Board until the information required pursuant to § 1600.2 of this chapter has been placed in all appropriate spaces on each petition page.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.4.</num>
    <text>The individual who files the petition shall execute an affidavit attesting that to the best of his or her knowledge and belief the petition being filed is complete and contains the legally required number of valid signatures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.5.</num>
    <text>Each candidate shall file a Declaration of Candidacy and Affidavit of Qualifications, pursuant to Chapter 6 of this title, by no later than the deadline for the filing of nominating petitions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.6.</num>
    <text>The Board may reject the nominating petition of any individual who fails to submit the required Declaration of Candidacy and Affidavit of Qualifications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.7.</num>
    <text>No nominating petition shall be issued to any person other than the candidate unless the Board receives written notice from the candidate which authorizes the Board to release petitions in his or her name.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.8.</num>
    <text>The authorization shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Candidate’s name;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Office which the candidate seeks; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Candidate’s signature.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.9.</num>
    <text>A candidate may electronically submit the authorization to the Board by telefacsimile, the original of which shall be filed with the Board no later than the deadline for the filing of the nominating petition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 8364 (December 15, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 43 DCR 1078, 1108-09 (March 1, 1996); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 689 (February 7, 1997); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 60 DCR 5582 (April 12, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>