<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-1604</num>
  <heading>CIRCULATION OF PETITIONS (§ 3-1604)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1604.1.</num>
    <text>In order to circulate petitions pursuant to this chapter, a person shall:</text>
    <text>Be at least 18 years of age;</text>
    <text>Be a citizen of the United States;</text>
    <text>Not be incarcerated for a crime that is a felony in the District;</text>
    <text>Not have been found by a court of law to be legally incompetent to vote; and</text>
    <text>Either be a resident in the District of Columbia or, if not a resident in the District of Columbia, have registered as a non-resident petition circulator prior to circulating a petition in accordance with Sections 1604.2 and 1604.3.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1604.2.</num>
    <text>Each petition circulator who is not a resident of the District of Columbia shall, prior to circulating a petition under this chapter, complete and file with the Board a Non-Resident Petition Circulator Registration Form in which he or she:</text>
    <text>Provides the name of (and office sought by) the candidate or ballot measure in support of which he or she will circulate the petition;</text>
    <text>Provides his or her name, residential address, telephone number, and email address;</text>
    <text>Swears or affirms that he or she, while not a resident of the District of Columbia, is otherwise eligible to vote in the District of Columbia;</text>
    <text>Acknowledges that he or she has received from the Board information regarding</text>
    <text>the rules and regulations governing the applicable petition circulation process, and that he or she will adhere to such rules and regulations;</text>
    <text>Consents to submit to the Board’s subpoena power and to the jurisdiction of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for the enforcement of Board subpoenas.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1604.3.</num>
    <text>Each non-resident petition circulator shall present proof of residence to the Board at the time he or she files the Non-Resident Petition Circulator Registration Form. Valid proof of residence is any official document showing the circulator’s name
      and residence address. Acceptable forms of proof of residence include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A copy of a current and valid government-issued photo identification;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A copy of a current utility bill, bank statement, government check, paycheck;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A copy of a government-issued document; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A copy of any other official document, including leases or residential rental agreements, occupancy statements from homeless shelters, or tuition or housing bills from colleges or universities.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1604.4.</num>
    <text>Each circulator shall swear or affirm under oath that he or she:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Has personally circulated the petition;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Has personally witnessed the signing of each signature on the</text>
    </level>
    <text>petition;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Has determined from each signer that he or she is a registered voter, in the same party as the candidate and, where applicable, that the signer is registered in and a resident of the ward, school district or single-member district from which the
        candidate seeks election; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Meets the petition circulator requirements set forth in § 1604.1.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 8364, 8367 (December 15, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 5582 (April 12, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>