<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-1607</num>
  <heading>VALIDITY OF SIGNATURES ON PETITIONS (§ 3-1607)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1607.1.</num>
    <text>Signatures for a person seeking direct nomination for office in a primary election or direct access nomination in a general election shall be valid only if the signatures are on the form prescribed by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1607.2.</num>
    <text>The signature on a petition shall be made by the person whose signature it purports to be and not by any other person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1607.3.</num>
    <text>Registered voters who are unable to sign their names may make their marks in the space for signature. These marks shall not be counted as valid signatures unless the persons witnessing the marks shall attach to the petition affidavits that they explained
      the contents of the petitions to the signatories and witnessed their marks.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1607.4.</num>
    <text>In addition to the signature of the registered voter, the petition shall contain the voter’s current residence address and the date the petition was signed by the voter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1607.5.</num>
    <text>A signature shall not be counted as valid in any of the following circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The signer’s voter registration was designated as inactive on the voter roll pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 1-1001.07(j)(2) (2011 Repl.) at the time the petition was signed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The signer, according to the Board’s records, is not registered to vote at the address listed on the petition at the time the petition was signed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The signer is not a duly registered voter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The signature is not dated;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>On a petition to nominate a candidate in a primary election, the signer is not registered to vote in the same party as the candidate at the time the petition is signed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>On a petition to nominate a candidate from a ward, school district or single-member district, the signer is not duly registered in the ward, school district or single-member district from which the candidate seeks election at the time the petition
        is signed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The petition does not include the printed or typed address of the signer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The petition does not include the printed or typed name of the signer where the signature is not sufficiently legible for identification; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The circulator of the petition page did not meet the petition circulator requirements set forth in § 1604.1 at the time the petition was signed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1607.6.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, a &amp;#8220;duly registered voter&amp;#8221; shall be a registered qualified elector who is registered to vote at the address listed on the petition as shown on the Board’s voter registration records, and whose registration
      is not designated as inactive on the voter roll at the time the petition is signed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1607.7.</num>
    <text>A registered voter may submit a written notarized request to the Board to disallow the voter’s signature from being counted on the petition; provided, that the request shall be received by the Board prior to the time the petition is filed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1607.8.</num>
    <text>An address on a petition which is different than the address which appears on the Board&amp;#8217;s records shall be deemed valid if the signer&amp;#8217;s current address is within the school district for a district-wide school board election, within
      the ward for a ward-wide election, or within the District of Columbia for an at-large election, and the signer files a change of address form with the Board during the first 10 days of the period designated for resolving challenges to petitions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 8364, 8368 (December 15, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 2467, 2511 (April 10, 1992); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 43 DCR 1078, 1109 (March 1, 1996); as amended by Final
        Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 11725 (December 28, 2001); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 2740 (March 22, 2002); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 5072 (May 14, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published
        at 51 DCR 7434 (July 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 5582 (April 12, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>