<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-1601</num>
  <heading>NOMINATING PETITIONS[COLON] GENERAL ELECTION (§ 3-1601)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1601.1.</num>
    <text>The Board shall require every candidate seeking direct nomination for election to the office of Delegate, Mayor, Chairman of the Council, Member of the Council, U. S. Senator or U.S. Representative to indicate whether he or she is seeking direct nomination
      as an independent candidate or as a candidate affiliated with a political party not qualified to conduct a primary election.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1601.2.</num>
    <text>No petition form shall be issued by the Board to a candidate seeking direct access nomination as a candidate, affiliated with a political party not qualified to conduct a primary election, who is not registered as affiliated with such party in the
      official voter registration records of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1601.3.</num>
    <text>No person who is registered as a member of a political party may seek direct access nomination as a non-affiliated (independent) candidate; nor may any person who is registered as a member of a political party which has qualified to hold primary elections
      seek direct access nomination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1601.4.</num>
    <text>For direct access nomination to the offices of Delegate, Mayor, Chairman of the Council, Member of the Council, U.S. Senator and U. S. Representative, Member of the Board of Education, and Advisory Neighborhood Commissioner, the Board shall separately
      prepare and issue nominating petitions for the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Each candidate who seeks nomination as an independent candidate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Each candidate who seeks nomination as a candidate affiliated with a political party not qualified to conduct a primary; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Each candidate who seeks nomination to the non-partisan offices of Member of the Board of Education and Advisory Neighborhood Commissioner.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1601.5.</num>
    <text>No nominating petition shall be issued to any person other than the candidate unless the Board receives written notice from the candidate which authorizes the Board to release petitions in his or her name.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1601.6.</num>
    <text>The authorization shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Candidate’s name;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Office which the candidate seeks; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Candidate’s signature.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1601.7.</num>
    <text>A candidate may electronically submit the authorization to the Board by telefacsimile, the original of which must be filed with the Board by not later than the deadline for the filing of the nominating petition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 D.C. Reg. 8364, 8365-66 (December 15, 1989); and further amended by Final Rulemaking published at 43 D.C. Reg. 1078, 1109 (March 1, 1996).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL NOTE</heading>
      <text>Prior to December 15, 1989, the Board of Elections and Ethics published Final Rulemaking notice at 27 D.C. Reg. 2763 (June 27, 1980), incorporating the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 27 D.C. Reg. 1929, 1947-48 (May 9,1980).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>