<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-1804</num>
  <heading>CERTIFICATION OF PROPOSED AMENDMENT FOR THE BALLOT (ยง 3-1804)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1804.1.</num>
    <text>Following the expiration of the ten (10) day review period or the resolution of any objections to the proposed formulations, the Board shall hold a public meeting to:</text>
    <text>Certify the formulations for the proposed Charter amendment(s); and</text>
    <text>Announce that the proposed Charter amendment(s) will be brought before voters in an election conducted under ยง 1805.1 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1804.2.</num>
    <text>The formulations certified by the Board under ยง 1804.1 shall be printed on the ballot and used in all Board proceedings relating to the proposed Charter amendment(s).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1804.3.</num>
    <text>Within thirty (30) days of the certification, the Board shall publish the following in the D.C. Register, and in at least two (2) newspapers of general circulation:</text>
    <text>The entire Act, or the provision(s) of the Act that would amend the Charter;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The formulations for the proposed Charter amendment(s) as certified by the Board; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A statement that the proposed Charter amendment(s) will be presented to voters in an election conducted under ยง 1805 of this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1804.4.</num>
    <text>The Board shall make copies of the formulations, and either the entire Act or the provisions of the Act that would amend the Charter, available to the public at no charge.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 D.C. Reg. 7083, 7086-87 (October 8, 1993); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published 59 DCR 627 (January 27, 2012)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published 59 DCR 4780,
        3783 (May 11, 2012).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL NOTE</heading>
      <text>Prior to October 8, 1993, the Board of Elections and Ethics published a Final Rulemaking notice at 35 D.C. Reg. 5454, 5460-61 (July 15, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>