<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-1906</num>
  <heading>CERTIFICATION OF LANGUAGE FORMULATED BY THE BOARD OF ELECTIONS (ยง 3-1906)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1906.1.</num>
    <text>Following the expiration of the ten (10) day review period or the resolution of any objections to the proposed short title or summary statement, the Board shall hold a public meeting for the following purposes:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>To certify the summary statement and short title of the Advisory Referendum; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>To announce that the Advisory Referendum will be brought before voters in an election scheduled in accordance with ยง 1907 of this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1906.2.</num>
    <text>The short title and summary statement certified by the Board pursuant to ยง 1906.1 shall be the short title and summary statement printed on the ballot and used in all proceedings of the Board relating to this Advisory Referendum.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1906.3.</num>
    <text>Within thirty (30) days of the certification, the Board of Elections and Ethics shall publish the following in the D.C. Register, and in at least two (2) newspapers of general circulation:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Resolution passed by the Council in its entirety;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The short title of the Advisory Referendum as certified by the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The summary statement as certified by the Board; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A statement that the Advisory Referendum will be presented to voters in an election conducted pursuant to ยง 1907 of this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1906.4.</num>
    <text>Copies of the following shall be made available to the public at no expense:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Resolution passed by the Council in its entirety;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The short title as certified by the Board; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The summary statement as certified by the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 D.C. Reg. 7083, 7091-92 (October 8, 1993).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>