<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-203</num>
  <heading>ETHICAL CONDUCT (§ 3-203)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>203.1.</num>
    <text>A member or employee of the Board shall not directly or indirectly give any person who is not a member or employee of the Board access to official information obtained through or in connection with his or her employment which has not been released
      to the general public or which is not a matter of public record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>203.2.</num>
    <text>A member or employee of the Board shall not solicit or accept, either directly or through the intercession of others, any fee, gift, gratuity, favor, loan, entertainment, or other thing of monetary value from any person, organization or entity which
      has done or is doing any of the following:</text>
    <text>Has obtained, or is seeking to obtain, contractual or other business or</text>
    <text>financial relations with the Board.</text>
    <text>Conducts operations or activities that are regulated or examined by the</text>
    <text>Board; or</text>
    <text>Has interests that may be favorably affected by the action or inaction of</text>
    <text>the member employee in the performance of his or her official duties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>203.3.</num>
    <text>The restrictions set forth in § 203.2 of this section shall not apply to any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Obvious personal relationships, such as those that exist between an employee or member and his or her parents, children, or spouse;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The acceptance of food and refreshment of nominal value on infrequent occasions in the ordinary course of a luncheon or dinner meeting;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The acceptance of loans from financial institutions on customary terms to finance the acquisition of a car, home, appliance, or other personal items;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The acceptance of unsolicited advertising or promotional materials such as pens, pencils, note pads, calendars, and like items of nominal intrinsic value; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The acceptance of a voluntary gift of nominal value of a cash donation in a nominal amount which is presented on a special occasion such as marriage, illness, or retirement.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>203.4.</num>
    <text>A member or employee of the Board shall not directly or indirectly use or allow the use of government property of any kind, including office machines, motor vehicles, materials, supplies or funds, for other than officially approved activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>203.5.</num>
    <text>Without prior approval of the Board, a member or employee of the Board shall not accept any reimbursement for expenses or receive any other honorarium or fee for any service, speech, or other activity which is rendered as a result of his or her official
      duties with the Board, whether or not such activities were performed during official working hours.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>203.6.</num>
    <text>Board members and employees shall not engage in any employment which is incompatible with the full and proper discharge of their government responsibilities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>203.7.</num>
    <text>No Board member or employee shall do indirectly (by, through, or with other persons) those acts or actions which the Board member or employee are prohibited from doing directly under the restrictions set forth in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>203.8.</num>
    <text>An employee shall promptly report to his or her immediate supervisor any attempt to direct or otherwise unlawfully influence the discharge of that employee’s official duties.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 7686 (August 20, 2010) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11107, 11109 (November 26, 2010).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>