<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-2013</num>
  <heading>RECORDS MAINTAINED BY THE BOARD (ยง 3-2013)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2013.1.</num>
    <text>The Board shall make and maintain records pertaining to each request for information, including copies or correspondence. The material shall be filed by individual request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2013.2.</num>
    <text>The Board shall maintain a file, open to the public, which shall contain copies of all letters of denial.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2013.3.</num>
    <text>Where the release of the identity of the requester or other identifying details related to the request would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy, the Board shall delete identifying details from the copies of the documents
      maintained in the public files.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2013.4.</num>
    <text>The Board shall also maintain records permitting annual reporting of the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Total number of requests made to the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The number of requests granted and denied, in whole or in part;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The number of times each exemption was invoked as the basis for non- disclosure;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The names and titles or positions of each person responsible for the denial of records and the number of instances each person was involved in a denial; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The amount of fees collected, and the amount of fees for duplication and search waived by the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2013.5.</num>
    <text>On or before the 31st day of March of each calendar year, the Board shall compile and submit to the Secretary its report pursuant to the provisions of this section and on other matters relating to Board compliance with the terms of the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2013.6.</num>
    <text>With respect to appeals taken pursuant to ยง 2012, the Secretary shall maintain records reflecting the number of appeals taken, the results of the appeals, and the number of times each exemption was invoked as a basis for non-disclosure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 D.C. Reg. 1191, 1197-98 (February 12, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>