<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-3005</num>
  <heading>PRINCIPAL CAMPAIGN COMMITTEE (§ 3-3005)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3005.1.</num>
    <text>With the exception of persons who make independent expenditures under the Act, only a candidate’s designated principal campaign committee and its authorized committees shall accept contributions or make expenditures on behalf of that candidate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3005.2.</num>
    <text>An individual who is a candidate for more than one (1) office shall designate a separate principal campaign committee for each office sought.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3005.3.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding § 3005.2, a principal campaign committee supporting the nomination or election of a candidate as an official of a political party may support the nomination or election of more than one (1) candidate as an official of a political party.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3005.4.</num>
    <text>The principal campaign committee shall process contributions in the following manner:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Contributions received by check, money order, or other written instrument shall be consigned directly to the principal campaign committee; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The proceeds of any monetary instruments listed in Subsection (a) that have been cashed or redeemed by the candidate pursuant to § 3004.2 shall be disallowed by the principal campaign committee and returned by the candidate to the donor.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3005.5.</num>
    <text>No contributions shall be commingled with the candidate’s personal funds or accounts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 3161, 3166-67 (May 22, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 2731 (March 22, 2002); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 2229, 2236 (March 19, 2010); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 60 DCR 1402 (February 8, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11864 (August 16, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>