<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-3006</num>
  <heading>DESIGNATION OF EXISTING POLITICAL COMMITTEE (§ 3-3006)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3006.1.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § 3006.2, an existing political committee may be designated as the principal campaign committee of a candidate if such existing political committee meets the following conditions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Statement of Organization of the existing political committee indicates that the existing political committee is an unauthorized committee, pursuant to § 3000.7, including any independent or political action committee; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>R&amp;#038;E Reports of the existing political committee are current.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3006.2.</num>
    <text>An existing political committee that has been previously designated as the principal campaign committee of a candidate, or of a slate of candidates for election as officials of a political party, shall not be designated as the principal campaign committee
      of a candidate in any future election.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3006.3.</num>
    <text>Upon designation of an existing political committee as a principal campaign committee of a candidate, the committee shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Amend its Statement of Organization, pursuant to § 3000.19, to report the designation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Determine whether persons making contributions previously received by or on behalf of the candidate or by the political committee before designation may have exceeded the relevant limits, pursuant to § 3011; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Refund any contributions to donors who may have exceeded the contribution limitations by no later than 30 days after such determination is made.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3006.4.</num>
    <text>To ascertain individual donor compliance with the contribution limitations, contributions to a candidate and to a committee, prior to designation, shall be attributed in aggregate by donor name.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 3161, 3167-68 (May 22, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 3222 (April 21, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 1402 (February 8, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 60 DCR 11864 (August 16, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>