<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-3011</num>
  <heading>LIMITATIONS ON CONTRIBUTIONS (§ 3-3011)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3011.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall make any contribution, and no person shall receive any contribution, which, when totaled with all other contributions from the same person, pertaining to an individual’s campaign for nomination as a candidate or election to public
      office, including both the primary and general elections, or special elections, exceeds the limitations enumerated for each office, under § 3011.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.2.</num>
    <text>Contributions in support of either individual candidates or their authorized committees, or for the recall of an incumbent, shall be limited to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Mayor, U. S. Senator, and U.S. Representative to Congress – two thousand dollars ($2,000);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Chairman of the Council – one thousand five hundred dollars ($1,500);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Member of the Council at-large – one thousand dollars ($1,000);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Member of the Council elected from a ward and Member of the State Board of Education at-large – five hundred dollars ($500);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Member of the State Board of Education elected from a ward – two hundred dollars ($200);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Official of a Political party – two hundred dollars ($200); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Member of an Advisory Neighborhood Commission – twenty-five dollars ($25).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.3.</num>
    <text>With the exception of special elections, no person shall make any contribution in any one primary or general election that, when totaled, exceeds five thousand dollars ($5,000), to any one (1) unauthorized committee, under § 3000.10.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.4.</num>
    <text>With the exception of special elections, no person shall make any contribution in any one (1) primary or general election per elective office for Mayor, U.S. Senator, U.S. Representative to Congress, Chairman of the Council, and each member of the
      Council and Board of Education which, when totaled with all other contributions made by that person in any one (1) election (primary and general) to candidates and political committees per elective office, exceeds eight thousand five hundred dollars
      ($8,500); provided, that contributions to individual candidates and political committees shall not exceed those listed under §§ 3011.2 and 3011.3.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.5.</num>
    <text>No person shall receive or make any cash contribution of twenty-five dollars ($25) or more in legal tender.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.6.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, expenditures for candidates for office shall not be considered contributions or expenditures by or on behalf of a candidate when derived from:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Personal funds belonging to candidates; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Funds from any person or independent expenditure committee advocating the election or defeat of any candidate for office; provided, that the person was not requested or suggested to do so by the candidate, any agent of the candidate, or any authorized
        committee of the candidate.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.7.</num>
    <text>Each loan or advance from a candidate or member of the immediate family of a candidate shall be evidenced by a written instruction that fully discloses:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The terms of the loan or advance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The conditions of the loan or advance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The parties to the loan or advance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Documentation regarding the source of the funds when the loan or advance is from the candidate.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.8.</num>
    <text>The amount of each loan or advance from a member of the candidate’s immediate family shall be included in computing and applying the limitations on contributions under § 3011, upon receipt by the authorized committee of the loan or advance from an
      immediate family members; provided, that the standards for repayment are consistent with repayment policies of lending institutions in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.9.</num>
    <text>Contributions to a candidate or political committee shall be attributed to the person actually making the contribution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.10.</num>
    <text>Contributions from minor children (under eighteen (18) years old) shall be attributed to their parents or legal guardians except under the following circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The decision to contribute is made knowingly and voluntarily by the minor child; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The funds, goods, or services contributed are owned or controlled exclusively by the minor child.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.11.</num>
    <text>A connected organization, under § 3000.9(a), and each political committee established, financed, maintained, or controlled by the connected organization share a single contribution limitation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.12.</num>
    <text>Corporations may make contributions in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.13.</num>
    <text>A corporation, its subsidiaries, and each political committee established, financed, maintained, or controlled by the corporation and its subsidiaries share a single contribution limitation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.14.</num>
    <text>A corporation is deemed to be a separate entity; provided, that a corporation (corporation B) which is established, financed, maintained, or controlled (51% or more) by another corporation (corporation A) is considered, for the purposes of the contribution
      limitations, a subsidiary of the other corporation (corporation A).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.15.</num>
    <text>Partnerships may make contributions in the District of Columbia; provided, that all contributions by a partnership shall be subject to each contributing partner’s individual contribution limitations, under § 3011.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.16.</num>
    <text>Contributions by a partnership shall be attributed to each partner, only by one (1) of the following methods:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Instructions from the partnership to the political committee or the candidate; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Agreement of the partners; provided, that the profits of non-contributing partners are not affected.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.17.</num>
    <text>No portion of any contribution under § 3011.15 shall derive from the profits of a corporation that is a partner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.18.</num>
    <text>Limitations on contributions under § 3011 apply to a limited liability company depending on whether it is established as a corporation or partnership.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.19.</num>
    <text>Limitations on contributions under § 3011 shall not apply to initiative or referendum measures, or to fundraising engaged in by independent expenditure committees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.20.</num>
    <text>With the exception of contributions received to retire debt, a political committee or a candidate shall not receive or accept contributions after the election or defeat of the candidate for office, or after the candidate notifies the Office of Campaign
      Finance of the intent to terminate the candidacy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3011.21.</num>
    <text>Limitations on contributions under § 3011 shall not apply to unauthorized political committees during any calendar year in which the committee is not supporting candidates in either a primary or general election.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 3161, 3172-74 (May 20, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 2171, 2177-79 (March 24, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 2731 (March 22, 2002); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 53 DCR 3229 (April 21, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 2229, 2241 (March 19, 2010); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 1402 (February 8, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at
        60 DCR 11864 (August 16, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>