<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-3003</num>
  <heading>EXEMPTION FROM FILING AND REPORTING REQUIREMENTS (ยง 3-3003)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3003.1.</num>
    <text>To invoke the exemption from filing and reporting requirements, a candidate must anticipate spending less than five hundred dollars ($500) in any one election.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3003.2.</num>
    <text>A candidate shall be exempt from the filing and reporting requirements of the Act if, on the Statement of Candidacy form, he or she:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Certifies that he or she anticipates spending less than five hundred dollars ($500) in any one election; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Excludes the designation of a principal campaign committee.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3003.3.</num>
    <text>Each exempt candidate shall notify the Director in writing within forty-eight (48) hours from the time he or she spends, or anticipates spending, five hundred dollars ($500) or more.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3003.4.</num>
    <text>Each exempt candidate shall certify in writing to the Director, on a Report of Exemption for a Candidate Spending Less than Five Hundred Dollars ($500), that he or she has not spent more than five hundred dollars ($500).</text>
    <text>Such certification shall be filed with the Director by no later than:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The fifteenth (15th) day before the date of the election in which the candidate seeks office; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The thirtieth (30th) day following the election.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 3161, 3165-66 (May 22, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 5919-20 (July 28, 2000) ; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 1402 (February 8, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 60 DCR 11864 (August 16, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>