<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-3502</num>
  <heading>PROCEDURES FOR INFORMAL HEARING (§ 3-3502)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3502.1.</num>
    <text>Notice of an informal hearing shall be issued in writing at least seven (7) days prior to the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3502.2.</num>
    <text>In the notice, the requester shall be informed of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The authority upon which the hearing is based;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The time and place of the hearing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The right to be represented by legal counsel; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The fact that the requester’s failure to appear may result in a dismissal of the matter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3502.3.</num>
    <text>The Director shall regulate the course of the informal hearing and the conduct of the parties and their counsel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3502.4.</num>
    <text>The requester, or counsel for the requester, shall present the requester’s case and evidence to the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3502.5.</num>
    <text>The Director may wait a reasonable period of time for the requester to appear before beginning the informal hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3502.6.</num>
    <text>If the requester fails to appear after a reasonable period of time, the Director shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Reschedule the informal hearing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Issue notice of the rescheduled hearing; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Serve the requester both by certified and regular mail.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3502.7.</num>
    <text>If the requester fails to appear after an informal hearing has been rescheduled, the Director may proceed with the informal hearing; provided, that the requester has received notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3502.8.</num>
    <text>Following the conduct of each informal hearing, the Director shall issue a written order with findings of facts and conclusions of law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 3161, 3199-00 (May 22, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 1402 (February 8, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>