<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-3709</num>
  <heading>INFORMAL HEARING FOR ALLEGED VIOLATIONS OF REPORTING REQUIREMENTS (§ 3-3709)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3709.1.</num>
    <text>The Director may institute or conduct an informal hearing on alleged violations of the reporting and disclosure requirements, prescribed by the Act and Chapters 30-41 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3709.2.</num>
    <text>The reporting and disclosure requirements shall apply to the following documents:</text>
    <text>Statement of Acceptance of Position of Chairperson;</text>
    <text>Statement of Acceptance of Position of Treasurer;</text>
    <text>Identification of Campaign Literature;</text>
    <text>Notice of Not Receiving Contributions or Expenditures;</text>
    <text>Notification of Non-Support;</text>
    <text>Report of Exemption for a Candidate Expending Less Than $500;</text>
    <text>Report of Receipts and Expenditures;</text>
    <text>Request for Candidate Waiver;</text>
    <text>Request for Additional Information;</text>
    <text>Statement of Candidacy;</text>
    <text>Statement of Candidate Withdrawal;</text>
    <text>Statement of Committee Termination;</text>
    <text>Statement of Information;</text>
    <text>Statement of Organization;</text>
    <text>Summary Financial Statement for Advisory Neighborhood Commission (ANC);</text>
    <text>Verified Statement of Contribution Report;</text>
    <text>Withdrawal of Chairperson;</text>
    <text>Withdrawal of Treasurer; and</text>
    <text>24-Hour Report of Receipts for Candidates and Political Committees</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3709.3.</num>
    <text>Notice of an informal hearing shall be issued in writing at least ten (10) days prior to the hearing; provided that the ten (10) day period may be waived for good cause shown as long as the party is given a sufficient opportunity to prepare for the
      hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3709.4.</num>
    <text>In the notice, an alleged violator of the reporting requirements shall be informed of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The nature of the alleged violation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The authority on which the hearing is based;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The time and place of the hearing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The right to be represented by legal counsel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The fact that the alleged violator’s failure to appear may be considered an admission of the allegation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The fact that service of process shall be by regular mail.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3709.5.</num>
    <text>The Director shall regulate the course of the informal hearing and the conduct of the parties and their counsel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3709.6.</num>
    <text>The respondent, or his or her counsel, may present the respondent’s case and evidence to the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3709.7.</num>
    <text>The Director may wait a reasonable period of time for the respondent to appear before beginning the informal hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3709.8.</num>
    <text>If the respondent fails to appear after a reasonable period of time, the Director shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Reschedule the informal hearing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Issue notice of the rescheduled informal hearing; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Serve the respondent both by certified and regular mail.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3709.9.</num>
    <text>If the respondent fails to appear after an informal hearing has been rescheduled under § 3709.8, the Director may proceed with the informal hearing by making a record of the proceeding.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3709.10.</num>
    <text>Following the conduct of each informal hearing, the Director shall:</text>
    <text>Determine whether a violation has occurred; and</text>
    <text>Issue a written order with findings of facts and conclusions of law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3709.11.</num>
    <text>Any party adversely affected by any order of the Director may obtain review of the order by filing, with the Board of Elections, a request for a hearing de novo.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3709.12.</num>
    <text>The request for a hearing de novo pursuant to § 3709.12 shall be filed:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Within fifteen (15) days from the issuance by the Director of an order; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>In accordance with Chapter 4 of this title.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3709.13.</num>
    <text>Within five (5) days after receipt of an order of the Director where a fine has been imposed, a respondent may file a Motion for Reconsideration to address issues considered mitigating that were not presented during the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3709.14.</num>
    <text>The Motion shall not address issues that were not the subject of the alleged violation for which the penalty was assessed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3709.15.</num>
    <text>The Director shall respond to the Motion within five (5) days after its receipt by issuing a new order which either:</text>
    <text>Modifies or vacates the original order, providing clearly articulated reasons; or</text>
    <text>Denies the Motion and affirms the original order, providing clearly articulated reasons.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3709.16.</num>
    <text>The filing of the Motion shall toll the appeal period for requesting a hearing de novo before the Board of Elections, or the payment of the fine.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3709.17.</num>
    <text>The appeal period shall be recalculated from the date of issuance of the subsequent order of the Director in the matter, if appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 3161, 3208-10 (May 22, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 2171, 2187 (March 24, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 2272, 2274 (March 19, 2010), as corrected by Errata
        Notice published at 57 DCR 5737 (July 2, 2010); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 10612, 10613 (December 16, 2011); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 1402 (February 8, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking published
        at 60 DCR 11864 (August 16, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>