<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-3707</num>
  <heading>SUBPOENAS AND DEPOSITIONS (ยง 3-3707)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3707.1.</num>
    <text>The Director shall have the power to require, by subpoena, the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of documentary evidence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3707.2.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in ยง 3704.7, each subpoena issued by the Director shall be approved by the Board, and shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name of the respondent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The title of the action;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A specification of the time allowed for compliance with the subpoena; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A command to the person to whom it is directed to:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Attend and give testimony at a time and place specified in the subpoena; and/or</text>
    <text>Produce and permit inspection and copying of the books, papers, documents, or tangible things designated in the subpoena.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3707.3.</num>
    <text>A complainant may request the Director to subpoena particular persons or evidence; provided, that the subpoena shall not be obtained as a matter of right to the complainant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3707.4.</num>
    <text>Any person to whom a subpoena is directed may, prior to the time specified in the subpoena for compliance, file a motion to request that the Board quash or modify the subpoena.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3707.5.</num>
    <text>Any application to quash a subpoena shall be accompanied by a brief statement of the reasons supporting the motion to quash.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3707.6.</num>
    <text>The Board may quash or modify the subpoena upon a showing of good cause.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3707.7.</num>
    <text>Upon written notice, the Director may, in any proceeding or investigation, order testimony to be taken by deposition, under oath, before any person who is designated by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3707.8.</num>
    <text>A deposition may be scheduled at a time and place convenient to the parties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3707.9.</num>
    <text>A respondent or witness may be represented by counsel at a deposition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3707.10.</num>
    <text>A transcript of a deposition may be requested and furnished at reasonable cost to the requestor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 3161, 3207 (May 22, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 1402 (February 8, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11864 (August 16, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>