<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-406</num>
  <heading>MEETINGS AND HEARINGS (ยง 3-406)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>406.1.</num>
    <text>The meetings and hearings of the Board shall be open to the public, with the exception of executive sessions, as that term is defined and explained in Section 103 in Chapter 1 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>406.2.</num>
    <text>The proposed agenda for each Board meeting and the minutes from the previous regular Board meeting shall be posted in the office of the Board and on its website at least twenty-four (24) hours prior to a regular Board meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>406.3.</num>
    <text>Copies of the agenda and the minutes from the previous regular Board meeting shall be available to the public at the meeting or hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>406.4.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall preclude the Board from amending the agenda at the meeting or hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>406.5.</num>
    <text>A meeting of the Board shall be held once each month in accordance with a schedule to be established by the Board, and additional meetings may be called as needed by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>406.6.</num>
    <text>Hearings shall be scheduled as needed for the purpose of receiving evidence and testimony on specific complaints or petitions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>406.7.</num>
    <text>Meetings and hearings shall be held at the time and place the Board or the Chairperson designates.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>406.8.</num>
    <text>Meetings and hearings may be adjourned from time-to-time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>406.9.</num>
    <text>If the time and place of resumption is publicly announced when the adjournment is ordered, no further notice shall be required.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>406.10.</num>
    <text>A majority of the Board shall constitute a quorum. However, the Board is authorized to utilize the use of one-member panels pursuant to D.C. Code ยง 1-1001.05(g) (2006 Repl.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>406.11.</num>
    <text>A member absent at the decision meeting may cast an absentee vote only if the member attended all of the hearings on the complaint or petition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>406.12.</num>
    <text>A member attending the decision meeting and having read the transcript and reviewed the complete record may vote even though that member may not have attended any or all of the prior meetings or hearings on the complaint or petition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 D.C. Reg. 432, 437-38 (January 23, 1998); and as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 D.C. Reg. 4738-39 (June 19, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>