<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-4101</num>
  <heading>DESIGNATION OF AN EXPLORATORY COMMITTEE AS A PRINCIPAL CAMPAIGN COMMITTEE (§-4101)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4101.1.</num>
    <text>In the event that an individual on whose behalf an exploratory committee was organized becomes a candidate, that exploratory committee may be designated as that candidate’s principal campaign committee, pursuant to § 3005 of Chapter 30 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4101.2.</num>
    <text>If an exploratory committee is designated as a principal campaign committee:</text>
    <text>All funds previously raised and spent by the exploratory committee shall be reported as contributions and expenditures, pursuant to § 3008 of Chapter 30 of this title;</text>
    <text>The exploratory committee shall account for all financial transactions including, but not limited to, contributions, expenditures, and loans, retroactive to the formation of the exploratory committee as defined in Chapter 99 of this title; and</text>
    <text>The exploratory committee shall:</text>
    <text>Determine whether persons making contributions previously received by or on behalf of the candidate or by the principal campaign committee before designation may have exceeded the relevant limits, pursuant to § 3011 of Chapter 30 of this title; and</text>
    <text>Refund any contributions to donors who may have exceeded the contribution limitations by no later than 30 days after such determination is made.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4101.3.</num>
    <text>To ascertain individual donor compliance with the contribution limitations, contributions to an exploratory committee, or to a pre-designated principal campaign committee, shall be attributed in aggregate by donor name.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 1402 (February 8, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11864 (August 16, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>