<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-510</num>
  <heading>VOTER REGISTRATION APPLICATION PROCESSING[COLON] IN-PERSON AT THE BOARD OFLECTIONS AND ETHICS OR A VOTER REGISTRATION AGENCY (VRA) (§ 3-510)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>510.1.</num>
    <text>Prior to the thirtieth (30th) day preceding an election, a qualified elector (pursuant to § 500.2), or a person who is qualified to pre-register (pursuant to § 500.4), may appear in-person at the Board’s office, and by extension, a voter registration
      agency (VRA), and do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Submit a voter registration application; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Submit a notice of a change of name, address, or party affiliation status.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>510.2.</num>
    <text>On or after the thirtieth (30th) day preceding an election, a qualified elector may submit a voter registration application or a notice of change of name or address at the Board’s office or a VRA. On or after the thirtieth (30th) day preceding a primary
      election, a qualified elector shall not change his or her party affiliation status. Requests for change of party affiliation status received during the thirty (30) days that precede a primary election shall be held and processed after the election.
      A change in party affiliation status occurs when a voter:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Changes his or her party registration from one political party to another;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Changes his or her party registration from “no party (independent)” to a political party; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Changes his or her party registration from a political party to “no party (independent).”</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>510.3.</num>
    <text>A qualified elector may appear in person at the Board’s office to complete and sign the Board’s official Voter Registration Application between the hours of 8:30 a.m. and 4:45 p.m., Monday through Friday. The Executive Director, or his or her designee,
      may expand the weekly hours, and may specify other days on which the Board may accept voter registration applications, based on the level of registration activity. Public notice of the expansion of weekly hours shall be provided at least twenty-four
      (24) hours in advance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>510.4</num>
    <text>510.4 A voter registration application or a notice of a change of name, address, or party affiliation status that is submitted in-person at the Board’s office or a VRA shall be considered to be received by the Board on the date that it is submitted
      at the Board’s office or the voter registration agency. The effective date of registration or a registration update pursuant to this section shall be the date it was received by the Board</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 43 D.C. Reg. 1078, 1086-87 (March 1, 1996); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 48 D.C. Reg. 11722 (December 28, 2001); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 49 D.C. Reg. 2737 (March 22, 2002); as amended
        by Final Rulemaking published at 50 D.C. Reg. 11074 (December 26, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 D.C. Reg. 4738, 4740 (June 19, 2009); and as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 D.C. Reg. 3267, 3279 (April 16, 2010);
        as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 7 DCR 7690 (August 20, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 111111, 111117 (November 26, 2010); as amended by Notice of Emergency and
        Federal Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 10752 (December 16, 2012)[EXPIRED];as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 941, 949 (February 10, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>