<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-514</num>
  <heading>NOTIFICATION OF ACCEPTANCE OF REGISTRATION OR CHANGE OF REGISTRATION (§ 3-514)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>514.1</num>
    <text>514.1   Within nineteen (19) calendar days after the receipt of a voter registration application, the Registrar shall mail a non-forwardable voter registration notification to the applicant advising him or her of the acceptance or rejection of the
      registration application. If the application is rejected, the notification shall include the reason or reasons for the rejection and shall inform the voter of his or her right to either submit additional information as requested by the Board, or
      appeal the rejection pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 1-1001.07(f) (2011 Repl.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>514.2.</num>
    <text>In the event that the notification advising the applicant of acceptance of his or her voter registration is returned to the Board as undeliverable, the Registrar shall mail the notice provided in D.C. Official Code §</text>
    <text>1-1001.07(j)(1)(B) (2011Repl.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>514.3.</num>
    <text>As soon as practicable after the election, the Board shall mail each registered voter who filed a change of address at the polls on Election Day a non-forwardable address confirmation notice to the address provided in the written affirmation on the
      Special Ballot Envelope. If the United States Postal Service returns the address confirmation notification as &amp;#8220;undeliverable&amp;#8221; or indicating that the registrant does not live at the address provided in the written affirmation
      on the Special Ballot Envelope, the Board shall notify the Attorney General of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>514.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall not be registered until the date the Board determines that the applicant is a qualified elector and eligible to register to vote in the District of Columbia. Once the Board determines a registrant’s eligibility, the effective date
      of the registration or registration update shall be the date of receipt of the voter registration application or registration update, or as otherwise provided in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 43 D.C. Reg. 1078, 1088-89 (March 1, 1996); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 D.C. Reg. 4738, 4741 (June 19, 2009); and as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 D.C. Reg. 3267, 3283 (April 16, 2010);
        as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 7 DCR 7690 (August 20, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11111, 11119 (November 26, 2010); as amended by Notice of Emergency and
        Federal Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 10752 (December 16, 2012)[EXPIRED];as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 941, 952 (February 10, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>