<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-5102</num>
  <heading>BOARD MEETINGS (§ 3-5102)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5102.1.</num>
    <text>Except as provided otherwise by the Act, a quorum of the Board shall consist of no less than two (2) members of the Board and shall be necessary to conduct official Board business.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.2.</num>
    <text>At the beginning of each calendar year, a preliminary schedule of regular meetings for the year, which the Board has discretion to change, shall be published in the D.C. Register.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.3.</num>
    <text>Regularly scheduled Board meetings shall be held on the first Thursday of each month, or at least once each month, at a time to be determined by the Board. Additional meetings may be called as needed by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.4.</num>
    <text>Notice of all regular and additional meetings of the Board shall be published on the Board&amp;#8217;s web site at least forty-eight (48) hours, or two (2) business days, in advance, whichever is greater, except in the case of emergency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.5.</num>
    <text>The Board may exercise its discretion and reschedule a regular meeting or call special meetings when necessary with reasonable notice to the public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.6.</num>
    <text>The Board encourages comments on any issue under the jurisdiction of the Board that is considered at its regular meetings. The Board shall permit the submission of written comments either in advance or within a time set after the regular meeting.
      The Board may also provide the public with a reasonable opportunity to appear before the Board and offer such comments. No public comment will be accepted when the Board is considering enforcement actions or is conducting an adversarial hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.7.</num>
    <text>To ensure the orderly conduct of public Board meetings, public comments may be limited with respect to the number of speakers permitted and the amount of time allotted to each speaker; however, the Board shall not discriminate against any speaker
      on the basis of his or her position on a particular matter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.8.</num>
    <text>Any member of the public who intends to comment regarding any agenda item or any issue under the jurisdiction of the Board is encouraged to notify the Board in advance of his or her intent to do so, providing his or her name and the topic on which
      he or she wishes to speak. Such notification may be provided by e-mail to the Board’s email address, by telephone, or by mail or in person at the Board’s office. No person shall be prevented from speaking at a Board meeting simply because he or
      she has not provided advance notice of his or her intent to do so.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.9.</num>
    <text>Members of the public who wish to submit items for consideration by the Board shall do so in writing one (1) week in advance and the Board may in its discretion include the submitted items on the agenda if it determines that the items’ subject matter
      is within the Board’s jurisdiction and there is sufficient time to address the item at the meeting Any item that was properly submitted to the Board but was not included on the agenda shall be included on the agenda of the next regularly scheduled
      meeting. Failure to submit an item in advance as required may, within the Board’s discretion, result in the matter being continued until the next regularly scheduled meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.10.</num>
    <text>The Chairperson shall conduct the meetings of the Board. In the absence of the Chairperson, the senior member of the Board shall conduct the meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.11.</num>
    <text>Each meeting shall begin with the adoption of the agenda, followed by the adoption of any outstanding minutes of previously conducted Board meetings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.12.</num>
    <text>The Director of Government Ethics shall present a report of the activities of that position at each regularly scheduled meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.13.</num>
    <text>Each Board member may properly make any and all motions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.14.</num>
    <text>All meetings of the Board shall be open to the public and conducted in compliance with the Open Meetings Act (Open Meetings Act), effective March 31, 2011 (D.C. Law 18-350; D.C. Official Code § 2-571 et seq.) (2011 Repl.), unless governed by Sections
      405(b) and 406 of the Open Meetings Act (permissible closed meetings).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.15.</num>
    <text>The proposed agenda for each Board meeting shall be posted and made available for public inspection in the Board’s office and on its website at least twenty-four (24) hours prior to a meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.16.</num>
    <text>Copies of the agenda shall be available to the public at the meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.17.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall preclude the Board from amending the agenda at the meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.18.</num>
    <text>Meetings may be adjourned from time to time and resumed at the Board’s discretion so long as the time of resumption is announced to the public. Where the meeting is adjourned and resumed in less than forty-eight (48) hours or two (2) business days,
      the Board will provide notice of the date and time of its resumption on its website and by posting notice in the Board’s office. Where a meeting is adjourned to a time longer than forty-eight (48) hours or two (2) business days, the Board shall
      provide notice of the new day and time as required by the Open Meetings Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5102.19.</num>
    <text>Any individual who is deemed by the Board Chairman to be disruptive to the meeting may be removed therefrom.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 739 (January 25, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>