<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-5301</num>
  <heading>PRELIMINARY INVESTIGATIONS (ยง 3-5301)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5301.1.</num>
    <text>The Director shall conduct a preliminary investigation of a possible violation of the Code of Conduct or of the Act brought to the attention of the Director by any source including but not limited to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The media;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A tip received through the hotline; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Documents filed with the Ethics Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5301.2.</num>
    <text>If during or after the preliminary investigation, the Director of Government Ethics has reason to believe that a violation of the Code of Conduct or of the Act may have occurred, the Director shall present evidence of the violation to the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5301.3.</num>
    <text>Upon presentation of evidence, the Ethics Board may authorize a formal investigation and the issuance of subpoenas if it finds reason to believe a violation has occurred.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5301.4.</num>
    <text>A preliminary investigation may be dismissed at any time by the Director or Board if insufficient evidence exists to support a reasonable belief that a violation has occurred.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5301.5.</num>
    <text>The identity of an individual who is the subject of the preliminary investigation shall not be disclosed without the individual&amp;#8217;s consent unless or until the Board finds reason to believe that the individual has committed a violation and
      that disclosure would not harm the investigation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5301.6.</num>
    <text>In conducting a preliminary investigation, the Director shall have the authority to gather evidence using any of the powers and procedures described in ยง 5303.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 747 (January 25, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>