<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-5405</num>
  <heading>ADVISORY OPINIONS (§ 3-5405)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5405.1.</num>
    <text>Upon application made by an employee or public official subject to the Code of Conduct, the Board or the Director shall, within a reasonable period of time, provide an advisory opinion as to whether a specific transaction or activity inquired of would
      constitute a violation of a provision of the Code of Conduct over which the Board has primary jurisdiction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5405.2.</num>
    <text>An advisory opinion shall be published in the District of Columbia Register within thirty (30) days of its issuance; provided, that the identity of a person requesting an advisory opinion shall not be disclosed in the District of Columbia Register
      without the person’s prior consent in writing. Where consent is not obtained, the name of the requester shall be removed prior to publication.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5405.3.</num>
    <text>If issued by the Director or an individual Board member, an advisory opinion may be appealed for consideration by the full Board. There shall be no enforcement of a violation of the Code of Conduct taken against an employee or public official who
      relied in good faith upon an advisory opinion requested by that employee or public official and substantially complied with the advice or recommendation given in the advisory opinion; provided, that the employee or public official, in seeking the
      advisory opinion, made full and accurate disclosure of all relevant circumstances and information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5405.4.</num>
    <text>A request for an advisory opinion shall be in writing, signed by the requestor, and filed with the Director. The Director may accept email requests for advisory opinions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5405.5.</num>
    <text>A request for an advisory opinion shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The full name, residence address, and telephone number of the requestor; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A clear and concise statement of the facts relating to the specific transaction or activity which is the subject of the inquiry.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5405.6.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this Chapter shall prevent the Director from providing informal advice or guidance to an employee or public official by referring that employee or official to a published advisory opinion or established guidance contained in the District’s
      Ethics Manual or other reference source. Such informal advice or guidance need not be published in the District of Columbia Register and does not provide the employee with protections described in § 5405.3.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 747 (January 25, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>