<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-5517</num>
  <heading>SPECIFIC RULES OF HEARING PROCEDURE (§ 3-5517)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5517.1.</num>
    <text>All parties shall have the right to produce evidence and witnesses on their behalf and to rebut or explain testimony or evidence against them.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5517.2.</num>
    <text>All parties have the right to cross-examine other parties and witnesses and to offer argument or explanation in support of their positions or contentions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5517.3.</num>
    <text>A party may cross-examine any other party or person, except that the Board, through the Chairman, may rule a question out of order when it is irrelevant, immaterial, or unduly repetitious.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5517.4.</num>
    <text>Witnesses shall be examined and cross-examined orally under oath or affirmation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5517.5.</num>
    <text>The order of procedure for presenting evidence at the hearing shall be as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Call to order and opening statements by the Chairperson and members of the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Introductory statement by Director or staff;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Consideration of pending motions and procedural matters;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Director’s case;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The respondent’s case; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Any rebuttal offered by the Director.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5517.6.</num>
    <text>If there is more than one respondent, the respondents shall stipulate their order of presentation. If the respondents are unable to agree, the Chairperson shall set the order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5517.7.</num>
    <text>In an adversarial hearing no decision or order of the Board shall be made except upon the exclusive record of the proceedings before the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 747 (January 25, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>