<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-5505</num>
  <heading>RECORD OF MEETINGS AND HEARINGS (§ 3-5505)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5505.1.</num>
    <text>All meetings whether open or closed shall be recorded by electronic means; provided, that if a recording is not feasible, detailed minutes of the meeting shall be kept.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5505.2.</num>
    <text>For all open meetings or hearings, copies of records shall be made available for public inspection according to the following schedule:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>For a meeting, a copy of the minutes of a meeting shall be made available for public inspection as soon as practicable, but no later than 3 business days after the meeting.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For an adversarial hearing, a copy of the full record, including any recording or transcript, shall be made available for public inspection as soon as practicable, but no later than 7 business days after the meeting.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>At the discretion of the Board, electronic recordings of the hearing may be posted on the Board’s website.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5505.3.</num>
    <text>The minutes of Board meetings shall include the vote of each member of any ruling of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5505.4.</num>
    <text>Copies of the official transcript shall be available to parties and to the public upon payment to the Board of the charges fixed for the copies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5505.5.</num>
    <text>Changes in the official transcript may be made only when they involve errors affecting substance and upon the filing of a motion by a party to correct a transcript with the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5505.6.</num>
    <text>Copies of the motion to correct a transcript shall be served simultaneously on all opposing parties or legal representatives.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5505.7.</num>
    <text>Objections to the motion to correct a transcript shall be filed with the Board within five (5) days and served upon the parties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5505.8.</num>
    <text>The transcript may be changed by the Board at a public meeting to reflect any corrections.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 747 (January 25, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>