<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-5800</num>
  <heading>REGISTRATION REQUIREMENTS (§ 3-5800)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5800.1.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this chapter shall establish the procedures for the filing of registration forms for lobbyists pursuant to the authority set forth in the Subtitle E of the Government Ethics Act of 2011 (Ethics Act), Title II of the Board of Ethics
      and Government Accountability Establishment and Comprehensive Ethics Reform Amendment Act of 2011, effective April 27, 2012 (D.C. Law 19-124; D.C. Official Code § 1-1161.01 et seq. (2012 Supp.)).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5800.2.</num>
    <text>A person shall register as a lobbyist with the Director of Government Ethics (the Director) by filing the Lobbyist Registration Form if that person, under the following circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Receives compensation of two hundred fifty dollars ($250) or more in any three (3) consecutive calendar month period for lobbying;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Receives compensation from more than one (1) source which totals two hundred fifty dollars ($250) or more in any three (3) consecutive month period for lobbying; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Expends funds of two hundred fifty dollars ($250) or more in any three (3) consecutive calendar month period for lobbying.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5800.3.</num>
    <text>The registration for lobbyists shall be two hundred fifty dollars ($250).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5800.4.</num>
    <text>The registration for lobbyists who lobby solely for nonprofit organizations shall be fifty dollars ($50).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5800.5.</num>
    <text>The Lobbyist Registration Form shall include the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Registrant’s name, permanent address and temporary address, if any, while lobbying;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Name and address of each person designated to lobby on behalf of the registrant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Name, address, and nature of the business of any person who compensates the registrant and the terms of the compensation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Identification, by formal designation if known, of matters on which the registrant expects to lobby; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Registrant’s verification under oath of the required information; provided, that if the registrant is not an individual, an authorized officer or agent of the registrant (other than the lobbyist retained by contract to provide lobbying services)
        shall sign the form.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5800.6.</num>
    <text>A lobbyist shall file a separate registration form for each person from whom he or she receives compensation for lobbying.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 2852 (March 8, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11954 (August 16, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>