<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-5801</num>
  <heading>EXEMPTION FROM REGISTRATION REQUIREMENTS (§ 3-5801)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5801.1.</num>
    <text>A person shall be exempt from the registration requirements of § 5800 if that person is any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A public official, or an employee of the United States acting in an official capacity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A publisher or working member of the press, radio, or television who, in the ordinary course of business, disseminates news or editorial comment to the general public;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any candidate, member or member-elect of an Advisory Neighborhood Commission; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any entity specified in D.C. Official Code § 47-1802.01(4) whose activities do not include lobbying, the result of which shall inure to the financial gain or benefit of the entity.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5801.2.</num>
    <text>Lobbying activities shall not include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Appears or presents written testimony, on his or her own behalf, or is represented by an attorney, in an informal or formal rule-making, rate making or adjudicatory hearing before an executive agency or the Tax Assessor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Supplies information in response to written inquiries by an executive agency, the Council of the District of Columbia or any public official;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Inquires only as to the status of specific actions by an executive agency or the Council of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Testifies before, or submits written testimony to, a committee of the Council of the District of Columbia, or the Council, in a proceeding for which there is a public record or testimony submitted for inclusion in the public record;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Communicates through a newspaper, television, or radio of general circulation or a publication whose primary audience is the organization&amp;#8217;s membership; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Conveys communications, indirectly or directly, by a bona fide political party, as defined in Section 101 of the Board of Ethics and Government Accountability Establishment and Comprehensive Ethics Reform Amendment Act of 2011, effective April 27,
        2012 (D.C. Law 19-124; D.C. Official Code § 1-1161.01 et seq. (2012 Supp.)).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5801.3.</num>
    <text>A person, who may be exempt from the registration requirements of this chapter, may be a registrant for other purposes pursuant to the Act; provided, that the activity of the person shall not constitute a conflict of interest as described in Section
      223 of the Board of Ethics and Government Accountability Establishment and Comprehensive Ethics Reform Amendment Act of 2011, effective April 27, 2012 (D.C. Law 19-124; D.C. Official Code § 1-1162.23 (2012 Supp.)).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 2852 (March 8, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>