<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-700</num>
  <heading>BALLOT FORM AND CONTENT (ยง 3-700)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>700.1.</num>
    <text>The Board shall provide official ballots to absentee voters and to voters on election day and at early voting centers to be used by the voter for indicating candidate or measure preference in any contest.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>700.2.</num>
    <text>Official primary elections ballots (PRIMARY BALLOTS) shall be separate and color-coded for the candidates of each political party qualified to participate in the election.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>700.3.</num>
    <text>Official city-wide general election ballots (GENERAL ELECTION BALLOTS) shall list the offices to be filled and the candidates for each office to be filled.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>700.4.</num>
    <text>Official special election ballots shall list:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Any offices to be filled and candidates for each office to be filled;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The short title and summary statement of each proposed initiative, referendum or recall measure, if any; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any proposed Charter amendment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>700.5</num>
    <text>700.5 Official Federal Ballots (FEDERAL BALLOTS) shall list only the offices of President of the United States, Vice President of the United States, and Delegate to the House of Representatives and the candidates for each office, and shall be provided
      in any primary, general or special election in which those offices appear on primary, general election, or special election ballots. Federal Ballots shall be restricted to qualified federal electors as defined in ยง 501.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>700.6.</num>
    <text>Initiative, Referendum and Recall measures and proposed Charter amendments may appear on a separate ballot in any election.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 D.C. Reg. 2478-79 (April 10, 1992); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 D.C. Reg. 7401 (July 30, 2004); and as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 D.C. Reg. 4245 (May 14, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>