<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-703</num>
  <heading>EARLY VOTING CENTERS (§ 3-703)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>703.1.</num>
    <text>For each primary and general election, qualified electors may choose to cast a full ballot for their precinct at early voting centers according to procedures established by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>703.2.</num>
    <text>The Board shall designate no fewer than four (4) early voting centers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>703.3.</num>
    <text>Early voting centers shall be equitably distributed geographically throughout the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>703.4.</num>
    <text>Satellite early voting centers shall be open for no fewer than seven (7) days prior to Election Day, from the hours of 8:30 a.m. to 7 p.m., Monday through Saturday. The Board’s office shall serve as the early voting center for the in-person absentee
      voting period for the hours specified in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>703.5.</num>
    <text>All persons standing in line at an early voting center at the time the early voting center closes shall be permitted to vote, if otherwise qualified.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>703.6.</num>
    <text>Votes recorded at an early voting center will not be tallied until Election Day. Election results from early voting shall not be released until the polls close on Election Day.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 D.C. Reg. 2467, 2480 (April 10, 1992); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 D.C. Reg. 11074-11075 (December 26, 2003); incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 5041
        (May 14, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 D.C. Reg. 7403 (July 30, 2004); and as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 D.C. Reg. 4245, 4247 (May 14, 2010); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published
        at 57 DCR 57 DCR 7081 (August 6, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11123 (November 26, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>