<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-712</num>
  <heading>SECRECY OF THE BALLOT (§ 3-712)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>712.1.</num>
    <text>Before any optical scan voting equipment (“OSVE”) is used for deposit of voted ballots, the Precinct Captain shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Inspect the interior of the OSVE to show any voters and/or watchers that all ballot receiving areas are empty;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Secure and lock the ballot receiving areas of the OSVE;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Produce a zero-printout and, after ascertaining that vote totals opposite all voting positions are set at zero (0000), sign said printout; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Inspect OSVE counter display to insure that it reads zero (0000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>712.2.</num>
    <text>From the time of the procedure specified in § 712.1 until the close of the polls, the polling official attending the OSVE shall ascertain that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Only official ballots are deposited in the OSVE;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Nothing is removed from the OSVE; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The secrecy of each voter’s ballot is preserved.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>712.3.</num>
    <text>Each voter shall pass his or her voted paper ballot through the OSVE before leaving the early voting center or polling place.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>712.4.</num>
    <text>Provision shall be made for maintaining the secrecy of the voted ballot while the voter carries it from voting booth to OSVE.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>712.5.</num>
    <text>The OSVE’s shall be attended by a polling place official at all times, from the opening of the polls until the ballots, memory cards, or other electronic media are returned to the counting center.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 D.C. Reg. 2467, 2488-89 (April 10, 1992); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 D.C. Reg. 7412-7413 (July 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 D.C. Reg. 5753, 5755-56 (July 17, 2009);
        and as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 D.C. Reg. 4245, 4259 (May 14, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>