<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-817</num>
  <heading>POST GENERAL ELECTION SUMMARY REPORT (§ 3-817)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>817.1.</num>
    <text>Within ninety (90) days following every general election, the Board shall publish on its website a report (“post general election summary report”) containing the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The total number of ballots cast and counted, with subtotals for each type of ballot;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The total number of spoiled and special ballots not counted;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The total number of persons registered to vote more than thirty (30) days preceding the election, broken down by party, ward, and precinct;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The number of persons who registered to vote between thirty (30) days preceding the election and the date of the election;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The number of persons who registered to vote at an early voting center;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The number of persons who registered to vote on Election Day;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The number of polling place officials at each precinct, broken down by position title;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Copies of any unofficial summary reports generated by the Board on election night;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>A summary of issues identified in Precinct Captain or Area Representative reports;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Performance measurement data of polling place officials;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>A description of any irregularities experienced on Election Day; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Any other relevant information.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 D.C. Reg. 7433 (July 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 D.C. Reg. 5071 (May 14, 2004); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 7705 (August 20, 2010)[EXPIRED];
        as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11149, 11167 (November 26, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>