<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-905</num>
  <heading>VACANCY IN THE OFFICE OF ELECTED MEMBER OF THE STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION (ยง-905)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>905.1.</num>
    <text>When a member of the State Board of Education resigns his or her office prior to expiration of the term, the resignation shall be in writing and in duplicate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>905.2.</num>
    <text>The resigning member of the State Board of Education shall forward one (1) duplicate original of the resignation to the Mayor and one (1) duplicate original to the Chairperson of the D.C. Board of Elections and Ethics.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>905.3.</num>
    <text>Within five (5) working days of receipt of the duplicate resignation, the Board shall certify the seat vacant, effective as provided by the resignation, and issue the appropriate notification as provided in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>905.4.</num>
    <text>When a member of the State Board of Education dies while still serving his or her term of office, the Board shall, within five (5) working days of notice of the death of the member of the State Board of Education, certify the seat vacant and issue
      the appropriate notification as provided in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>905.5.</num>
    <text>When a vacancy in the office of Member of the State Board of Education is declared by court order, the Board shall, as soon as practicable after the court declaration, notify the President of the State Board of Education of the vacancy by registered
      mail.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>905.6.</num>
    <text>When a vacancy in the office of Member of the State Board of Education occurs as a result of a recall election, the Board shall, as soon as practicable after certification of the election results, do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Certify the seat vacant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Notify the State Board of Education; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Issue the appropriate notification as provided in this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 28 D.C. Reg. 1726 (April 17, 1981), incorporating the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 28 D.C. Reg. 403, 406-07 (January 23, 1981); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 8058, 8062 (September
        16, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>