<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-1414</num>
  <heading>MULTIHALL BINGO LICENSE (ยง 30-1414)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1414.1.</num>
    <text>Subject to the provisions of Chapter 12, the Board may issue a special multihall bingo game license to any organization holding a Class A, Class B or Class C regular bingo license or a Class A, Class B or Class C limited period bingo license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1414.2.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this title shall preclude organizations eligible for a regular or limited period bingo license from co-sponsoring bingo, including multihall bingo.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1414.3.</num>
    <text>The Board shall require a non-refundable application fee for a special multihall bingo game license in the following amounts:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Class A regular multihall bingo license S500;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Class B regular multihall bingo license $250;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Class C regular multihall bingo license S 50;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Class A limited period multihall bingo license $200;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Class B limited period multihall bingo license S 100; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Class C limited period multihall bingo license $ 25.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1414.4.</num>
    <text>If the books, records and operations of a provider of services are located outside the District of Columbia, the Agency may assess additional licensing fees to review, inspect and audit the books, records and operations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1414.5.</num>
    <text>The fee shall be equal to the Agency&amp;#8217;s cost for conducting a review, divided by the number of licensees using the services of the provider of services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1414.6.</num>
    <text>In no event shall the Agency&amp;#8217;s cost include any expenditure by Agency personnel which is inconsistent with the Travel Regulations contained in Title 1 DCMR, Chapter 8.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1414.7.</num>
    <text>A special multihall bingo game license shall not extend beyond the expiration date of the bingo license held by the licensed organization. The Agency may reduce the fees specified in ยง1414.3 on a pro rata basis pursuant to this subsection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1414.8.</num>
    <text>A licensed organization holding a Class A, Class B, or Class C regular bingo license or a Class A, Class B or Class C limited period bingo license may apply for a multihall bingo game license on a form provided by the Agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1414.9.</num>
    <text>A licensed organization may satisfy the bonding requirements of ยง1205.3 by providing a bond in an amount equal to the cost to pay the highest prize offered plus fifteen percent (15%).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1414.10.</num>
    <text>The Agency may limit the number of multihall bingo games that are offered in any bingo operation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 38 DCR 2048, 2049 (April 5, 1991).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>