<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-1400</num>
  <heading>PREMISES (§ 30-1400)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1400.1.</num>
    <text>The premises where any game of bingo is conducted or where it is intended to be conducted or where any bingo equipment is used or intended to be used shall be open at reasonable times to inspection by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1400.2.</num>
    <text>A licensed organization shall lease a premise for any bingo operation only by means of a fixed rental payment; Provided, that the fixed rental payment is not based on a percentage of gross receipts or net proceeds from a bingo operation and reflects
      a fair rental value.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1400.3.</num>
    <text>Any lease entered into in accordance with §1400.2 shall be set forth in writing and filed with the application for a license and reviewed by the Board to determine compliance with §§1400.2 and 1400.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1400.4.</num>
    <text>The lease shall separately state the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The rental amount;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A detailed breakdown of any other charges;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The purpose for which the premises will be used;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Duration of the rental term;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Execution date;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Names, addresses, and identification of the parties; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Other information as may be required by the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1400.5.</num>
    <text>No more than two (2) bingo operations per week shall be conducted on any one (1) premise.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1400.6.</num>
    <text>A licensed organization shall conduct no more than two (2) bingo operations per week on any one (1) premise.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1400.7.</num>
    <text>A licensed organization shall conduct bingo only on premises listed on the face of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1400.8.</num>
    <text>A licensed organization shall not conduct bingo in a building which does not have a current occupancy permit required by the District&amp;#8217;s Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1400.9.</num>
    <text>Each licensed organization shall post at a place where the bingo cards are sold the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The bingo license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For a multihall bingo game, a license issued pursuant to § 1414 of this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Notices required by the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A valid occupancy permit;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A sheet listing the approximate percentage of the handle to be paid out in prizes, the percentage to be used for the lawful purpose, and the percentage to be used for expenses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The sheet required by § 1405.1; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The list of names required by § 1401.1.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1400.10.</num>
    <text>Each player shall be furnished a chair and place with sufficient room to play at no extra charge.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1400.11.</num>
    <text>The playing area shall be free of hazards to safety with means of egress clearly designated.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1400.12.</num>
    <text>The licensed organization shall provide at least one (1) security person, either a District police officer or a person licensed by the District as a security guard.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is §4 of the Law to Legalize Lotteries, Daily Numbers Games, and Bingo and Raffles for Charitable Purposes in the District of Columbia, D.C. Law 3-172, D.C. Official Code §3-1301 et seq.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3788, 3802 (May 20, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 38 DCR 2048, 2051 (April 5, 1991).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL NOTE</heading>
      <text>Prior to May 20, 1988, the D.C. Lottery and Charitable Games Control Board published Final Rulemaking at 29 DCR 5018, 5028 (November 12, 1982).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>