<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-104</num>
  <heading>REGULAR MEETINGS (ยง 30-104)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>104.1.</num>
    <text>Regular meetings of the Board shall be held monthly.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.2.</num>
    <text>The regular meetings shall be held at 6:30 p.m. on the first Wednesday of each month; Provided, that a meeting may be changed by the Chairperson, with the concurrence of the majority of the Board members.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.3.</num>
    <text>In the event that the first Wednesday of the month is a legal holiday, then the regular meeting shall be held on the next business day at 6:30 p.m., or at a time and date approved by the Board,</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.4.</num>
    <text>Public notice shall be posted for each regular meeting in a public access area at the office of the Board and in the D.C. Register.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.5.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director shall inform the press and the media of all regular meetings as soon as possible after the Board has determined that a meeting will be held.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.6.</num>
    <text>Prior to any meetings of the Board, the Executive Director shall, after consulting the Chairperson, prepare an agenda for the meeting</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.7.</num>
    <text>The agenda of the regular meeting of the Board shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A report of the Chairperson of the Board, which may include, but is not limited to, any item for the information of the Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Approval of the minutes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A report of the Executive Director which may include, but shall not be limited to, items for the information of the Board, items for referral to Board committees, items recommended by the Committee of the Whole, and items requiring a vote by the
        Board;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Comments by any Board member which may include items for information or items requiring a vote by the Board; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Comments from the public.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.8.</num>
    <text>Three (3) Board members shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, except that where the Board may issue, revoke or suspend a license authorized by the Act, then four (4) Board members shall constitute a quorum.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.9.</num>
    <text>The affirmative vote of three (3) Board members shall be the action of the Board, except as provided in ยง 104.10.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.10.</num>
    <text>The affirmative vote of four (4) Board members shall be required to issue, revoke or suspend a license in accordance with D.C. Official Code ยง3-1302.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>104.11.</num>
    <text>The Board may sit and consider matters in the absence of a quorum, but no action shall be taken in the absence of a quorum.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 3704, 3706 (June 20, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>