<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-2326</num>
  <heading>PRICE AND COST ANALYSIS (ยง 30-2326)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2326.1.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall be responsible for selecting and using whatever price analysis techniques will ensure a fair and reasonable price.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2326.2.</num>
    <text>One (1) or more of the following techniques may be used to perform price analysis:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Comparison of proposed prices received in response to the solicitation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Comparison of prior proposed prices and contract prices with current proposed prices for the same or similar items;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Application of rough yardsticks (such as dollars per pound or per horsepower, or other units) to highlight significant inconsistencies that warrant additional pricing inquiry;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Comparison with competitive published price lists, published market prices of commodities, similar indexes, and discount or rebate arrangements; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Comparison of proposed price-s with independent Agency cost estimates.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2326.3.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall be required to perform a cost analysis in either of the following circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The award of any contract in excess of one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The modification of any contract when the modification exceeds one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2326.4.</num>
    <text>If cost analysis is required, the contracting officer shall perform cost analysis by using the techniques and procedures set forth in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2326.5.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall verify cost or pricing data and evaluate the cost elements, including the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The necessity for and reasonableness of the proposed cost, including allowances for contingencies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A projection of the offeror&amp;#8217;s cost trends on the basis of current and historical cost or pricing data;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A technical appraisal of the estimated labor, material, tooling and facilities requirements and of the reasonableness of scrap and spoilage factors; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The application of audited or negotiated indirect cost rates, labor rates, and other factors.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2326.6.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall evaluate the effect of the offeror&amp;#8217;s current practices on future costs. In conducting this evaluation, the contracting officer shall ensure that the effects of inefficient or uneconomical past practices are
      not projected into the future.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2326.7.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall compare the costs proposed by the offeror for individual cost elements with the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Actual costs previously incurred by the same offeror;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Previous cost estimates from the offeror or from other offerors for the same or similar items;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Other cost estimates received in response to the Agency request;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Independent Agency cost estimates; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Forecasts or planned expenditures.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2326.8.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall verify that the offeror&amp;#8217;s cost submissions are in accordance with the contract cost principles and procedures set forth in Chapter 33 of Title 27, Contracts and Procurements (hereafter &amp;#8220;Title 27 DCMR&amp;#8221;).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2326.9.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall review each proposal to determine whether any cost or pricing data necessary to make the contractor&amp;#8217;s proposal accurate, complete, and current have been submitted or identified In writing by the contractor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6681, 6756 (September 22, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>