<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-2508</num>
  <heading>IMPREST FUNDS (ยง 30-2508)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2508.1.</num>
    <text>A cash purchase using imprest funds may be made when the transaction does not exceed two hundred fifty dollars ($250).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.2.</num>
    <text>A contracting officer shall specifically designate in writing persons authorized to make purchases using imprest funds.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.3.</num>
    <text>Each purchase using imprest funds shall be recorded on an imprest fund purchase form, approved by the Director, which shall include a discreet imprest fund purchase number, accounting data identifying the specific imprest fund account, the items or
      services purchased, the name of the person making the purchase, the purchase date, and other information required by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.4.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall further document each purchase using imprest funds by including a record of receipt and acceptance of supplies and services by the Agency, receipt of cash payment by the supplier, and the cash advances and reimbursements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.5.</num>
    <text>When using imprest funds, the contracting officer may place orders to suppliers orally and without soliciting competition if prices are determined to be reasonable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.6.</num>
    <text>When using imprest funds, the contracting officer shall attempt to distribute purchases equitably among suppliers, and shall solicit prompt payment discounts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.7.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer, or other employee authorized under ยง 2508.2, shall furnish a copy of the imprest fund purchase form to the imprest fund cashier with the following information annotated:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That an imprest fund purchase has been made;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The unit and extended prices;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The supplier&amp;#8217;s name and address; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The anticipated delivery date.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.8.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall require that the supplier include the following with each delivery:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An invoice, packing slip, or other sales instrument;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The supplier&amp;#8217;s name and address;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A list and quantity of items;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The unit and extended prices; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The trade discount, if any.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6681, 6776 (September 22, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>