<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-2407</num>
  <heading>PROCUREMENT OF MEDIA TIME AND SPACE (ยง 30-2407)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2407.1.</num>
    <text>The Director and each contracting officer engaged in the procurement of media time and space may make individual purchases of media time and space on a sole source basis, in accordance with the procedures set forth in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2407.2.</num>
    <text>When there is only a single source for a particular type of media time or space (such as mass transit or display advertising space), the contracting officer shall purchase the time or space in accordance with the applicable marketing budget and marketing
      plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2407.3.</num>
    <text>When there are multiple sources for the purchase of media time or space (such as newspapers or broadcast media), the contracting officer shall use the following to allocate purchases among available media sources and to determine the amount of time
      or space to be purchased from each source selected:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The strategic marketing plan developed for the specific media buying activity, including demographic and targeting variables, as well as the overall goals of the particular media campaign;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Marketing surveys, including information obtained from various media sources and market analysis sources;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Rates available from media sources, including rate variations based on factors such as broadcast time, audience demographics and market share, the availability of targeted time slots, and other relevant factors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The overall budget for purchase of media time and space; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Results obtained from prior advertising or promotion programs using particular media sources, targeting approaches, and other relevant factors affecting the effectiveness of media buying.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2407.4.</num>
    <text>To the extent that purchases of media time and space from local media sources are in the best interests of the Agency, a contracting officer may allocate media purchases to local media sources even though the allocations do not meet all of the requirements
      set forth in ยง2407.3.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2407.5.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall attempt to obtain the best price possible from each media source through price negotiation and other appropriate methods, such as obtaining rate discounts for package purchases, when in the best interests of the Agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2407.6.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer may use special contracting methods to obtain the best possible combination of media exposure and price, including blanket purchase agreements and indefinite quantity term contracts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2407.7.</num>
    <text>The Director shall establish a quality control program for media purchases to ensure that the allocation of media purchases meet the goals of the Agency&amp;#8217;s marketing plan and that media advertisements and promotions are placed or broadcast
      in accordance with the specific contract or purchase order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6681, 6765 (September 22, 1989)</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>