<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-2020</num>
  <heading>BONDS, OTHER SECURITY, AND INSURANCE (ยง 30-2020)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2020.1.</num>
    <text>A form of bid security, performance bond, and payment bond shall be required for all construction contracts estimated to exceed one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000). The Director of Procurement may require any of these types of security for construction
      projects that are less than one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2020.2.</num>
    <text>Bonds or other security shall be payable to the Agency and shall be executed on forms prescribed by the Director of Procurement, and shall be filed with the Director of Procurement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2020.3.</num>
    <text>The Director of Procurement shall furnish a certified copy of a payment bond or other security to any person making application who submits an affidavit that the person has supplied labor or materials for which payment has not been made, or that the
      person is being sued on any bond or other security.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2020.4.</num>
    <text>A certified copy of the bond or other security shall be prima facie evidence of the contents, execution, and delivery of the bond or other security as applicable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2020.5.</num>
    <text>Applicants shall pay for the certified copies and the fees set by the Director of Procurement to cover the costs of preparation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2020.6.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall prohibit the Director of Procurement from requiring a performance bond or any other type of security, in addition to the types of security described in this section, in circumstances other than those set forth in this
      section and Title 27 DCMR.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2020.7.</num>
    <text>The provisions of Chapter 27 of Title 27 DCMR shall apply to procurement by the Agency, except as provided in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6681, 6695 (September 22, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>