<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-2500</num>
  <heading>USE OF SMALL PURCHASE PROCEDURES (ยง 30-2500)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2500.1.</num>
    <text>The small purchase procedures set forth in this chapter may only be used for the procurement of supplies, services, and other items when the total amount of the procurement does not exceed ten thousand dollars ($10,000), in accordance with D.C. Code
      ยง 1-1110 (1992 Repl. Vol.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.2.</num>
    <text>A contracting officer shall not use small purchase procedures when the requirement can be met by using one of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A requirements term contract;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An indefinite quantity term contract;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A federal or District supply schedule; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Another source of supply, other than sealed bids or proposals, which would result in a lower price for the same or comparable supplies or services.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.3.</num>
    <text>A contracting officer shall not use small purchase procedures when the procurement requirement is initially estimated to exceed ten thousand dollars ($10,000), even though the resulting award does not exceed that limit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.4.</num>
    <text>If a procurement requirement totals more than ten thousand dollars ($10,000), a contracting officer shall not split the procurement into several purchases that are each less than the limit in order to permit the use of the small purchase procedures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.5.</num>
    <text>A procurement requirement shall not be parceled, split, divided, or purchased over a period of time in order to avoid the ten thousand dollar ($10,000) limitation for use of small purchase procedures. However, this shall not preclude the use of small
      purchase procedures for different requirements for the same or similar items which arise independently and for which the contracting officer cannot reasonably plan or execute a single procurement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2500.6.</num>
    <text>A contracting officer shall use the small purchase procedure that is most suitable, efficient, and economical based on the circumstances of each procurement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is ยง 4 of the Law to Legalize Lotteries, Daily Numbers Games, and Bingo and Raffles for Charitable Purposes in the District of Columbia, D.C. Law 3-172, D.C. Code ยง 2-2501 et seq. (1994 Repl.
        Vol.).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6681, 6769 (September 22, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>