<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-2110</num>
  <heading>USE OF THE D.C. PROCUREMENT HOTLINE (ยง 30-2110)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2110.1.</num>
    <text>The Director of Procurement (the &amp;#8220;Director&amp;#8221;) shall use the contract information hotline established by the Department of Administrative Services (&amp;#8220;DAS&amp;#8221;) under an agreement for use of the hotline made with the
      Director, DAS.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2110.2.</num>
    <text>If the Agency is unable to enter into an agreement with the Director, DAS, for use of the D.C. Procurement Hotline, or if the Procurement Hotline is discontinued, the Director of Procurement may establish a contract information hotline.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2110.3.</num>
    <text>The following information shall be provided by prerecorded message to callers on the hotline:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The title of the invitation for bid, or other identifying information on the contract;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The nature of the procurement, including whether the procurement is for supplies or services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A brief description of the type of supplies or services being sought and whether the offer is for spot acquisition or term contract;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The amount of deposit required, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Whether the contract is restricted to the sheltered market or is available to the open market;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The date and time by which bids or requests for proposals must be submitted and the place for submission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Where and when further information on the contracts may be obtained; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Any other information that the Director of Procurement considers appropriate and practicable.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2110.4.</num>
    <text>The information described in ยง 2110.3 shall be updated once per week, or at intervals that the Director considers more appropriate and practicable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6681, 6713 (September 22, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>