<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-203</num>
  <heading>EVALUATION OF AN APPLICATION FOR A LICENSE AND AN ASSIGNMENT OF ON-LINE COMPUTERERMINAL (§ 30-203)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>203.1.</num>
    <text>The Agency shall consider all relevant information in evaluating an application in accordance with the criteria specified in §§201.2 and 205.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>203.2.</num>
    <text>The Agency may conduct pre-licensing and pre-assignment surveys in order to evaluate the performance capability of the prospective agent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>203.3.</num>
    <text>The pre-licensing or preassignment survey shall be based on information submitted by the applicant, data in the possession of the Agency or other District or Federal agencies, and on-site inspections of the location.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>203.4.</num>
    <text>By filing an application, the applicant shall consent to have his or her name referred to the Metropolitan Police Department and the police department of the jurisdiction of his or her residence for a criminal history report and to undergo any procedures
      which may be required for that purpose, including fingerprinting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>203.5.</num>
    <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s partners, directors, officers, managers, supervisors and key employees shall also consent to have their names referred to the Metropolitan Police Department and the police department of the jurisdiction of residence for a
      criminal history report and to undergo any procedure which may be required for that purpose, including fingerprinting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>203.6.</num>
    <text>A criminal history report shall not be required from the jurisdiction of residence if that jurisdiction does not permit the use of the reports for licensing purposes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>203.7.</num>
    <text>The Agency shall not accept an application for a license from an applicant, or any of its owners, directors, or officers, within one (1) year of a denial or revocation of a license, if the denial was based on the submission of false, misleading or
      fraudulent information, or if the revocation was for cause.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>203.8.</num>
    <text>On-line lottery terminals shall be assigned only to agents who provide a physically secure location and space which is adequate to serve on-line ticket purchasers efficiently.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>203.9.</num>
    <text>The Board may deny the assignment of an on-line terminal in a particular area if it determines that the area is adequately served.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 8665, 8668 (December 29, 1989); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 7488 (August 3, 2007).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL NOTE</heading>
      <text>Prior to December 29, 1989, the D.C. Lottery and Charitable Games Control Board published Final Rulemaking published at 29 DCR 2202 (May 28, 1982).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>