<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-2225</num>
  <heading>RECEIPT AND SAFEGUARDING OF BIDS (ยง 30-2225)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2225.1.</num>
    <text>All bids and modifications received before the time set for the opening of bids shall be kept secure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2225.2.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in ยง2225.8, all bids shall remain unopened in a locked box or safe.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2225.3.</num>
    <text>Necessary precautions shall be taken to ensure the security of the bid box or safe.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2225.4.</num>
    <text>If an IFB is cancelled, the bids shall be returned to the bidders.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2225.5.</num>
    <text>Before bid opening, information concerning the identity and number of bids received shall be made available only to Agency employees, and then only as required in the execution of their duties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2225.6.</num>
    <text>When bid samples are submitted, they shall be handled with sufficient care to prevent disclosure of characteristics before bid opening.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2225.7.</num>
    <text>Each bid shall be marked with the date and time of receipt.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2225.8.</num>
    <text>Envelopes marked as bids which do not identify the bidder or the solicitation may be opened solely for the purpose of identification or to determine whether a bidder is eligible to bid, and then only by an official designated for this purpose.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2225.9.</num>
    <text>A person who opens a sealed bid by mistake, or for the reasons set forth in ยง2225.8, shall sign the envelope opened, indicate the person&amp;#8217;s position, and deliver it to the contracting officer. The contracting officer shall immediately write
      the following on the envelope and then sign and reseal the envelope:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An explanation of the opening;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The date and time opened; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The IFB number.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6681, 6725 (September 22, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>