<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-2307</num>
  <heading>RECEIPT AND SAFEGUARDING OF PROPOSALS (ยง 30-2307)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2307.1.</num>
    <text>All proposals and modifications received before the time set for the opening of proposals shall be kept secure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2307.2.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in ยง 2307.6, all proposals shall remain unopened in a locked box or safe. Necessary precautions shall be taken to ensure the security of the locked box or safe.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2307.3.</num>
    <text>If an RFP is cancelled, proposals shall be returned to the offerors.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2307.4.</num>
    <text>Before opening the proposals, information concerning the identity and number of proposals received shall be made available only to Agency employees, and then only as required in the execution of their duties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2307.5.</num>
    <text>Each proposal shall be marked with the date and time of receipt.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2307.6.</num>
    <text>Envelopes marked as proposals which do not identify the offeror or the solicitation may be opened solely for purposes of identification or to determine whether an offeror is eligible to submit a proposal and then only by an Agency official designated
      for this purpose.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2307.7.</num>
    <text>A person who opens a sealed proposal by mistake, or for the reasons set forth in ยง2307.6, shall sign the envelope opened, indicate the person&amp;#8217;s position, and deliver it to the contracting officer. The contracting officer shall immediately
      write the following on the envelope and then sign and reseal the envelope:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An explanation of the opening;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The date and time opened; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The RFP number.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6681, 6743 (September 22, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>