<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-305</num>
  <heading>COLLECTION OF ON-LINE SALES FUNDS (ยง 30-305)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>305.1.</num>
    <text>Each agent shall maintain a separate bank account in a federally-insured bank located within the District for the deposit of all on-line revenues received by the agent from the agent&amp;#8217;s on-line lottery operations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.2.</num>
    <text>Collections of funds from the sale of on-line tickets shall be accomplished by electronic transfer of funds from the agent&amp;#8217;s bank account to the Agency&amp;#8217;s bank account.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.3.</num>
    <text>The agent shall be responsible for all monies collected from on-line tickets sales until such monies have been deposited and accepted by the bank in the agent&amp;#8217;s bank account required by this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.4.</num>
    <text>Funds deposited in this account shall constitute a trust fund for the Agency and withdrawals shall be made only in accordance with instructions issued by the Agency. No other funds shall be deposited in this account.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.5.</num>
    <text>Each agent shall permit the Agency, representatives of the Agency and others authorized by the Agency, to inspect the bank records and accounts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.6.</num>
    <text>The agent&amp;#8217;s agreement with the bank shall provide that upon the change of principals, death, legal disability, incompetency, insolvency, or bankruptcy of the agent, all funds remaining in the account shall be paid over to the Agency as the
      lawful and true owner of the funds.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.7.</num>
    <text>The proper amount of funds due the Agency shall be accessed by the Agency weekly.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.8.</num>
    <text>The agent shall deposit funds promptly in the bank account to be available on the designated day of collection, but not later than the next banking day.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.9.</num>
    <text>In the event there is a change in the agent&amp;#8217;s bank or bank account, the agent shall notify the Agency of the change within five (5) working days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.10.</num>
    <text>The Agency may assess a monetary penalty not to exceed one thousand dollars ($1,000) for failure to comply with the requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.11.</num>
    <text>Funds deposited in an account pursuant to ยง305.4 shall not be assigned, pledged or used as collateral for any security interest. The transfer of any security interest in the funds shall be void.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 8665, 8675 (December 29, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 6959 (October 1, 1993).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL NOTE</heading>
      <text>Prior to December 29, 1989, the D.C. Lottery and Charitable Games Control Board published Final Rulemaking at 29 DCR 2202, 2207 (May 29, 1982).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>