<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-307</num>
  <heading>TIMES AND PLACE OF SALE (ยง 30-307)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>307.1.</num>
    <text>Each agent shall make all current lottery tickets available for sale to the public at all times during normal hours of operation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>307.2.</num>
    <text>Each Distribution Center shall make current lottery tickets available for distribution to agents at all times during normal business hours.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>307.3.</num>
    <text>An agent shall sell lottery tickets only at the location set forth in the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>307.4.</num>
    <text>A Distribution Center shall distribute lottery tickets only at the location set forth in the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>307.5.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director may waive the requirements of ยง307.1, upon a determination that the waiver is in the best interests of the agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>307.6.</num>
    <text>The waiver contemplated by ยง307.5 shall only be granted upon a written determination by the Executive Director that it is likely to do one of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Enhance ticket sales;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Increase the agent&amp;#8217;s overall performance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Target sales;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Increase the efficiency of the lottery; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Generate lottery sales which otherwise would not occur.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>307.7.</num>
    <text>A waiver may also be granted for similar good cause, and shall also effect a waiver of ยง308.1(b).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 8665, 8676 (December 29, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 5588 (July 30, 1993); as amended by NOTICE OF EMERGENCY AND PROPOSED RULEMAKING published at 46 DCR 1023 (February 5, 1999);
        as amended by NOTICE OF FINAL RULEMAKING published at 46 DCR 2814 (March 19, 1999).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL NOTE</heading>
      <text>Prior to December 29, 1989, the D.C. Lottery and Charitable Games Control Board published Final Rulemaking at 29 DCR 2202, 2207 (May 29, 1982).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>