<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-600</num>
  <heading>PROCESSING OF CLAIMS (ยง 30-600)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>600.1.</num>
    <text>Claims for prizes of less than six hundred dollars ($600) may be presented to a licensed agent for payment. The agent shall validate the ticket and pay all prize amounts due, if any, in accordance with the provisions of this title and procedures adopted
      by the Executive Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.2.</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in section 924.2, prizes of six hundred dollars ($ 600) or more shall be claimed at the Claim Center beginning on the first day following the drawing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.3.</num>
    <text>To claim a prize at a Claim Center, a claimant shall present a winning ticket and a completed and signed claim form to the Agency for payment. A claim shall be presented or paid only in accordance with this Title and procedures adopted by the Executive
      Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.4.</num>
    <text>A prize shall be claimed within one hundred eighty (180) days after the drawing in which the prize was won commencing with the day following the drawing, unless a shorter period of time has been authorized by the Executive Director for that particular
      game.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.5.</num>
    <text>A prize for a bonus game shall be claimed within the period of time authorized by the Executive Director for that particular game.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.6.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any requirement in sections 308.1(m) or 600 relating to the processing of claims by an agent, the Executive Director may designate a claiming period after which no instant ticket prize may be paid by a licensed agent. The time period
      shall be announced to licensed agents and the public. For the purpose of this section, the term &amp;#8220;claiming period&amp;#8221; shall mean the period of time in which a player may be paid an instant ticket prize by a licensed agent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.7.</num>
    <text>After the close of the claiming period, all instant ticket game prize claims shall be made at the Claim Center.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 7439, 7442 (October 2, 1992); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 6959, 6960 (October 1, 1993), 49 DCR 872 (February 1, 2002) and 49 DCR 11241 (December 13, 2002); as amended by BOARDS, COMMISSIONS,
        AND AGENCIES published at 50 DCR 10654 (December 12, 2003); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 9841 (November 18, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>