<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-602</num>
  <heading>CLAIM FORM (ยง 30-602)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>602.1</num>
    <text>602.1 Each claimant presenting a prize claim at the Claim Center shall either complete paper claim form or verify all information contained on an electronic claim form designated by the Executive Director and shall provide all information required
      by the Executive Director, including but not limited to, the prize claimant&amp;#8217;s:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Name;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Address, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Social Security number or FEIN;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Driver&amp;#8217;s license, non-driver identification or other acceptable photographic</text>
    </level>
    <text>identification; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Other applicable certifying documents required by the Executive Director.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.2.</num>
    <text>All claim forms paper or electronic shall be completed and signed by the claimant or his or her duly authorized representative as provided in this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.3.</num>
    <text>If the owner of a prize winning ticket is unable to complete a claim form due to a legal, physical, or other disability, a duly authorized representative, guardian, conservator, custodian, or fiduciary shall complete and sign a claim form on his or
      her behalf. The claim form shall indicate the name of the lawful payee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.4.</num>
    <text>If the person signing the claim form is a personal representative of the estate of a deceased winner, that person shall submit his or her letter of administration or its legal equivalent showing the appointment from the court having jurisdiction over
      the estate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.5.</num>
    <text>A person who signs either a paper or electronic claim form shall be considered to have verified and represented that all the information contained therein is accurate and complete.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.6.</num>
    <text>No incomplete claim form shall be processed for payment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.7.</num>
    <text>Any person who willfully submits a false or fraudulent claim form may be prosecuted for the offense of making a false statement in accordance with D.C. Code ยง 22-2514 (1996 Repl. Vol.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>D.C. Official Code ยง3-1306, District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority Order issued September 21, 1996, and Office of the Chief Financial Officer Financial Management Control Order No. 96-22 issued November
        18, 1996</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 7837,7438 (October 2, 2009), 39 DCR 7439,7443 (October 2, 1992).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORY NOTE</heading>
      <text>Prior to October 2, 1992, the D.C. Lottery and Charitable Games Control Board published Final Rulemaking at 29 DCR 2202, 2211 (May 28, 1982).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>