<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-614</num>
  <heading>RELEASE OF INFORMATION ABOUT WINNERS (§ 30-614)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>614.1.</num>
    <text>Pursuant to D.C. Code § 2-536(6), a prizewinner&amp;#8217;s name, city, county and state of residence, winnings, and all associated game, play and prize information are records, or a portion of records, required to be made available to the public.
      Information about or concerning prizewinners or participants in Agency activities authorized at Chapter 10 of this title may also be contained in records, or a portion of records, required to be made available to the public pursuant to D.C. Official
      Code § 2-531 through § 2-539.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>614.2.</num>
    <text>The Agency shall not release the street address or telephone number of a prize winner, except as may be required pursuant to lawful authority or urgent necessity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>614.3.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director may direct that prizewinners, or participants in Agency activities authorized at Chapter 10 of this title, be photographed or videotaped to complete the Agency&amp;#8217;s records and for the purposes identified in § 614.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>614.4.</num>
    <text>A prizewinner, or participant in Agency activities authorized at Chapter 10 of this title, consents, without further consideration or expectation of payment, to the Agency&amp;#8217;s use of the prizewinner&amp;#8217;s name, county, city and state
      of residence, the games played, the amount of the prize and any photographic or video-graphic replication of the prizewinner&amp;#8217;s likeness or image for promotional purposes. &amp;#8220;Promotional purposes&amp;#8221; shall include, without
      limitation, advertising, publication and promotion of the Agency, its games, programs, contests and other activities in any print, broadcast, electronic, Internet or other form or media whatsoever.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>614.5.</num>
    <text>Each prizewinner, or participant in Agency activities authorized at Chapter 10 of this title, releases the District of Columbia, the Agency, Multi-State Lottery Association, and their respective game groups, members, officers, employees, agents and
      attorneys, representatives, and contractors from all claims and liability arising out of, or related to, the promotional purposes, and use of the information and likenesses, set out in § 614.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>614.6.</num>
    <text>The provisions of § 614.4 and § 614.5, which are applicable to prizewinners shall also apply to any person who presents a prize claim that is later denied or forfeited for any reason.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 7439, 7949 (October 2, 1992), 50 DCR 8816 (October 17, 2003).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL NOTE</heading>
      <text>Prior to October 2, 1992, the D.C. Lottery and Charitable Games Control Board published Final Rulemaking at 29 DCR 2202, 2211 (May 28, 1982).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>