<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-900</num>
  <heading>DESCRIPTION OF THE DC DAILY 6™ GAME (§ 30-900)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>900.1.</num>
    <text>The Agency may offer a game known as DC Daily 6TM</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>900.2.</num>
    <text>The DC Daily 6TM game is a six (6) out of thirty-nine (39) on-line lottery game. A bonus ball shall be drawn from the remaining thirty-three (33) numbers after the initial six (6) winning numbers are drawn. DC Daily 6TM pays the top prize in accordance
      with these rules. To play the DC Daily 6TM game, a player shall select six (6) numbers from 1 to 39 for input into a terminal. The holder of a winning DC Daily 6TM game ticket may win in only one prize category per game board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>900.3.</num>
    <text>The price of a DC Daily 6TM game ticket shall be two (2) boards for one dollar ($ 1) or any other price designated by the Executive Director from a price schedule adopted by the Agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>900.4.</num>
    <text>The bonus ball, which is chosen after the initial six (6) winning numbers are drawn may not be used to claim the top prize and shall only pay according to the prize structure in § 901.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>900.5.</num>
    <text>If a single ticket contains more than one (1) winning play on separate game boards, the prize amounts shall be added together and shall be paid in accordance with the prize payment limits set forth in §§ 900.6 and 901.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>900.6.</num>
    <text>The holder of a winning DC Daily 6TM ticket may win in only one prize category per board in connection with the winning numbers drawn, and shall be entitled only to the prize for the highest prize category won by those numbers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>900.7.</num>
    <text>A ticket subject to the validations requirements of this title shall be the only proof of a wager.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is §4 of the Law to Legalize Lotteries, Daily Numbers Games, and Bingo and Raffles for Charitable Purposes in the District of Columbia, D.0 Law 3-172, D.C. Official Code §3-1301 et seq..</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 7439, 7452 (October 2, 1992) and 53 DCR 295 (January 13, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>