<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-922</num>
  <heading>DESCRIPTION OF EXTRA GAME ENHANCEMENT (ยง 30-922)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>922.1.</num>
    <text>The Agency may offer a game enhancement known as EXTRA to the public. A player who places a wager on Lucky Numbers or DC-4 may place an additional wager on a Lucky Numbers or DC-4 ticket by indicating to the agent that he wants to play EXTRA. Selection
      slips may not be used to place an EXTRA wager.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>922.2.</num>
    <text>A player who places a Lucky Numbers EXTRA wager will receive a Lucky Numbers EXTRA ticket containing three (3) additional electronically generated numbers, and a player who places a DC-4 EXTRA wager will receive a DC-4 EXTRA ticket containing four
      (4) additional electronically generated numbers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>922.3.</num>
    <text>EXTRA numbers are randomly selected with the aid of a computer program which determines EXTRA instant winners.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>922.4.</num>
    <text>The EXTRA numbers and/or prize amounts appearing on a valid Lucky Numbers or DC-4 ticket shall be the only proof of an EXTRA wager or prize.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>922.5.</num>
    <text>An EXTRA prize may be claimed at an agent location immediately upon generation of a winning EXTRA ticket or at any time within one year of the date of the EXTRA wager.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>922.6.</num>
    <text>The price of an EXTRA wager shall be one dollar ($ 1). The price of a ticket containing an EXTRA wager shall be one of the following amounts: (a) the sum of the price of the Lucky Numbers and EXTRA wagers; or (b) the sum of the price of the DC-4 and
      EXTRA wagers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>922.7.</num>
    <text>The EXTRA option is not available to players who use Quick Pick to make a Lucky Numbers or DC-4 wager using the Quick Pick selection method.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>922.8.</num>
    <text>An EXTRA winning ticket is a ticket that displays one (1) or more EXTRA prizes on the ticket. This occurs when there is an exact match by position and number between the EXTRA numbers and Lucky Numbers on the ticket, or between the EXTRA numbers and
      DC-4 numbers on the ticket, and a prize amount is displayed under the matching number(s). The amount of an EXTRA prize is the sum of the EXTRA prize amount(s) displayed on a valid winning ticket.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>922.9.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to repeal, amend or modify any provision of this Title concerning Lucky Numbers or DC-4 except as provided in sections 503.4 and 503.5.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 11241 (December 13, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>