<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-100</num>
  <heading>OFFICERS (§ 31-100)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>100.1.</num>
    <text>The officers of the Commission shall be the Chairperson, the Vice-Chairperson, and the Secretary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>100.2.</num>
    <text>The Chairperson shall perform the following duties:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Preside at regular meetings of the Commission and at meetings of the Panel on Rates and Rules and the Panel on Adjudication;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Preside at all other meetings called by the Commission, or designate the Vice-Chairperson or any other Commissioner to preside;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Serve as the spokesperson for the Commission on all matters, or designate the Vice-Chairperson or another Commissioner to serve in that capacity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Issue or sign notices and correspondence in accordance with § 109;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Appoint committees and their chairs, and chairs of panels as required;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Serve as chief administrative officer of the Commission and as its personnel authority; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Perform other duties of the Commission as the Commission may delegate.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>100.3.</num>
    <text>The Vice-Chairperson shall act as Chairperson when the Chairperson is absent, or when requested by the Chairperson, and shall perform other duties assigned by the Chairperson or the Commission to the extent permitted by law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>100.4.</num>
    <text>The Secretary shall perform the following duties:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Oversee the recording of the taped transcription of Commission meetings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Call the roll at Commission meetings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Announce that a quorum is or is not present;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Maintain a record of the attendance of commissioners at Commission meetings; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Perform such ministerial and other duties assigned by the Commission.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is the &amp;#8220;District of Columbia Taxicab Commission Establishment Act of 1985&amp;#8243;, codified at D.C. Official Code §§ 50-301 to 50-320 (2001).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 6707 (October 23, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>