<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-1102</num>
  <heading>PUBLIC VEHICLE FOR HIRE CONSUMER SERVICE FUND USES (§ 31-1102)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1102.1.</num>
    <text>Monies in the Public Vehicle for Hire Consumer Service Fund shall be used by the Commission to pay costs incurred by the Commission, including, but not limited to, the costs of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Operating and administering programs, investigations, proceedings, and inspections;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Improving the District’s taxicab fleet;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Administering the Fund;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Establishing a program to provide taxicab fare discounts for low-income senior citizens aged 65 and older and persons with disabilities; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Providing grants, loans, incentives and other financial assistance to owners of licensed taxicabs legally operating and incorporated in the District to incentivize the purchase and use of alternative-fuel vehicles and wheelchair-accessible vehicles,
        directing licensed taxicabs to underserved areas, and to offset costs associated with meeting the mandates of the Act.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1102.2.</num>
    <text>A proceeding, as referenced in Section 1102.1(a), includes, but is not limited to, any administrative action, process, adjudication, or rulemaking pending before, or initiated by, the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1102.3.</num>
    <text>A Commission investigation may include, but is not limited to, an investigation into any of the following subjects:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Rate studies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Review of the taximeter or Taxi Smart Meter System;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Public education and awareness;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Education of taxicab operators and owners;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Enforcement activities; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Discrimination in the taxicab industry.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 8528, 8529 (December 28, 1990); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 3831 (April 11, 2008); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 3173, 3174 (April 20, 2012); as amended by
        Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 14015 (December 7, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>