<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-1405</num>
  <heading>PROHIBITIONS (§ 31-1405)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1405.1.</num>
    <text>No LCS owner or operator shall provide sedan service in the District except as required by this chapter, Chapter 12 of this title, and other applicable laws.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1405.2.</num>
    <text>No DDS shall provide dispatch or payment services for sedan class service in the District except as required by this chapter, Chapter 16 of this title, and other applicable laws.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1405.3.</num>
    <text>No person shall provide sedan service in the District unless the fare, including all rates and charges, comply with § 1402 and all other applicable provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1405.4.</num>
    <text>No person providing sedan service in the District shall charge a gratuity, regardless of how such amount is styled, that does not comply with § 1402.1(f).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1405.5.</num>
    <text>No person shall participate in providing sedan service in the District unless the passenger surcharge is collected from the passenger and received by the District as required by § 1403.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1405.6.</num>
    <text>No person shall provide sedan service if the vehicle or the operator is not on the DDS vehicle inventory at the time the digital dispatch was initiated by the passenger.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1405.7.</num>
    <text>No owner or operator may alter or tamper with a component of a DPS unit or make any change in the vehicle that prevents the DPS unit from operating as required by this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1405.8.</num>
    <text>No operator may provide service using a DPS unit that has been tampered with, broken, or altered. The operation of a sedan with a tampered, broken, or altered DPS shall give rise to a rebuttable presumption that the operator knew of the tampering,
      breaking, or alteration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1405.9.</num>
    <text>Sedan class service shall not be booked except through a digital dispatch transmitted to the operator by a DDS using a digital payment system with current operating authority to operate such system.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1405.10.</num>
    <text>No DDS shall allow its associated operators to access a passenger’s payment information after the payment has been processed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1405.11.</num>
    <text>Each operator shall pick up a passenger at the time and location provided in the digital dispatch.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1405.12.</num>
    <text>No operator shall provide sedan service using a vehicle that does not comply with all applicable provisions of Chapter 12.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 12410 (August 30, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>