<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-1520</num>
  <heading>DOME LIGHT INSTALLATION BUSINESS – LIABILITY FOR CONDUCT OF EMPLOYEES (§1-1520)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1520.1.</num>
    <text>A dome light installation business owner shall supervise and be responsible for the conduct of all of its employees, contractors, or agents, for the activities including, but not limited to, the sale, installation, inspection and testing of dome lights.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1520.2.</num>
    <text>A dome light installation business owner shall ensure that all employees are fully familiar with the rules and regulations contained herein, as well as any other pertinent regulatory agency rules and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1520.3.</num>
    <text>A dome light installation business shall employ only such persons who have been certified as dome light installation technicians by a dome light installation manufacturer to perform any installation, testing, or repair of the dome light on which work
      is being performed:</text>
    <text>Any work involving a dome light, including, but not limited to, installation, inspection, or repair shall be performed by a technician certified by the dome light installation manufacturer; and</text>
    <text>The certified technician shall be responsible for maintaining all records required by the Commission and shall place that technician’s signature on all inspection, testing, repair, or other reports.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1520.4.</num>
    <text>A dome light installation business owner shall ensure that all employees perform their duties in compliance with all relevant federal and District laws, rules, and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1520.5.</num>
    <text>A dome light installation business shall furnish to the Commission, upon licensure or renewal, the names of all certified dome light installation technicians employed by it and shall notify the Commission in writing of any changes in the employment
      of certified dome light installation technicians.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 14019 (December 7, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>