<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-1530</num>
  <heading>DOME LIGHT INSTALLATION BUSINESS – RECORD KEEPING AND REPORTING (§ 31-1530)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1530.1.</num>
    <text>A dome light installation business owner shall comply with all record-keeping procedures established by the Office of Taxicabs. All records required to be kept by the Commission shall be in the form and manner prescribed by the Commission and must
      be maintained for a period of five (5) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1530.2.</num>
    <text>All record-keeping entries must be made by a technician certified in accordance with § 1520.3 of these rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1530.3.</num>
    <text>A dome light installation business owner shall account for all certification stickers procured and issued by the dome light installation business licensee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1530.4.</num>
    <text>A dome light installation business owner shall account for all new or used dome lights that the dome light installation business licensee buys, loans, rents, exchanges, or accepts in trade.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1530.5.</num>
    <text>A dome light installation business owner shall keep records of all sales, installations, inspections, re-inspections, calibrations, and repairs and the results thereof.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1530.6.</num>
    <text>At any and all times, a dome light installation business owner shall make available for examination, to any agent of the Commission or any other properly authorized law enforcement officer, all the records the official dome light installation business
      is required to keep.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1530.7.</num>
    <text>A dome light installation business owner shall permit any agent of the Commission or any law enforcement official to inspect any portion of its business premises at any time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 14019 (December 7, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>