<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-102</num>
  <heading>MEETINGS (ยง 31-102)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>102.1.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall hold regular meetings on the second Wednesday of January, March, May, July, September and November at 10:00 a.m., at the official offices of the Commission, or at any other place as the Chairperson may designate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.2.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall hold work sessions, as necessary, to engage in briefings and to consider matters before the Commission on the first Tuesday of February, April, June, September, October and December at the official offices of the Commission, or
      at any other place as the chairperson may designate. The Commission may hold additional work sessions to carry out its statutory authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.3.</num>
    <text>The Panel on Adjudication shall hold regular meetings on the first and third Wednesday of each month from September to July inclusive, at 9:00 a.m., at the official offices of the Commission, or at any other place as the Chairperson may designate.
      The Panel on Adjudication may schedule additional meetings necessary to carry out its functions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.4.</num>
    <text>The Panel on Rates and Rules shall hold regular meetings, on the first and third Wednesday of each month from September to July, inclusive, at 9:00 a.m., at the official offices of the Commission, or at any other place as the Chairperson may designate.
      The Panel on Rates and Rules may schedule additional meetings necessary to carry out its functions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.5.</num>
    <text>The Committee on Education shall hold regular meetings on the second Tuesday of January, April, July, and October at 9:00 a.m., at the official offices of the Commission, or at any other place the Chairperson may designate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.6.</num>
    <text>The Commission, its panels, and committees shall not meet on holidays, during the last two (2) weeks in December, or on snow emergency days as declared by the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.7.</num>
    <text>The Chairperson may call special meetings of the Commission or its panels, and shall call additional meetings at the direction of the Commission or its Panels, by sending notice of the special or additional meeting not less than seven (7) days in
      advance. The notice shall state the matters to be considered. No other matter may be considered at the special or additional meeting except with the consent of all members of the Commission or panel present.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.8.</num>
    <text>By affirmative vote of a majority of Commissioners in office, the Commission may schedule or hold a closed executive session to discuss personnel, litigation, or other matters of a private or confidential nature. No official action may be taken in
      an executive session, and no records shall be kept of the session other than a record of the vote to schedule or hold the session.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.9.</num>
    <text>The Chairperson may have published in any newspaper of general circulation notice of any Commission meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 6707, 6709 (October 23, 1987); as amended by Final Rulemaking published 52 DCR 9711 (October 28, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published 53 DCR 1175 (February 17, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>