<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-1320</num>
  <heading>TAXIMETER BUSINESS &amp;#8211; LIABILITY FOR CONDUCT OF EMPLOYEES (ยง 31-1320)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1320.1.</num>
    <text>A taximeter business owner shall supervise and be responsible for the conduct of all its employees, contractors or agents, for the activities including, but not limited to, the sale, installation, inspection, testing, and calibration of taximeters.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1320.2.</num>
    <text>A taximeter business owner shall ensure that all employees are fully familiar with the rules and regulations contained herein, as well as any other pertinent regulatory agency rules and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1320.3.</num>
    <text>To this end, a taximeter business shall employ only such persons who have been certified as taximeter technicians by a taximeter manufacturer to perform any installation, testing, repair or calibration of the taximeter on which work is being performed:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Any work involving a taximeter, including, but not limited to, installation, inspection, calibration, and repair shall be performed by a technician certified by the taximeter manufacturer; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The certified technician shall be responsible for maintaining all records required by the Commission and shall place his signature on all inspection, testing, repair or other reports prepared by him.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1320.4.</num>
    <text>A taximeter business owner shall ensure that all employees perform their duties in compliance with all relevant federal and District laws, rules, and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1320.5.</num>
    <text>A taximeter business shall furnish to the Commission, upon licensure or renewal, the names of all certified taximeter technicians employed by it and shall notify the Commission in writing of any changes in the employment of certified taximeter technicians.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 3831 (April 11, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>