<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-1205</num>
  <heading>LICENSING OF LCS VEHICLE OPERATORS &amp;#8211; ELIGIBILITY REQUIREMENTS (§ 31-1205)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1205.1</num>
    <text>1205.1 Each applicant for a license to operate an LCS vehicle (“applicant”) shall be at least eighteen (18) years of age.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1205.2.</num>
    <text>No license shall be issued under the provisions of this chapter to any person who is unable to read, write, and speak the English language.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1205.3.</num>
    <text>No license shall be issued under the provisions of this chapter to any person who is covered by diplomatic immunity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1205.4.</num>
    <text>No license shall be issued under the provisions of this chapter to any person who does not possess a valid District of Columbia motor vehicle operator&amp;#8217;s permit or, for non- District residents or persons exempt from obtaining a District motor
      vehicle operator&amp;#8217;s permit, a valid motor vehicle operator&amp;#8217;s permit issued by a state that is a party to the Driver License Compact.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1205.5.</num>
    <text>No license shall be issued under the provisions of this chapter to any person who has been adjudged to be afflicted with or suffering from any mental disability or disease and who has not at the time of application been restored to competency by the
      methods provided by law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1205.6</num>
    <text>1205.6 No operator’s license shall be issued by the Office to any person who is required by this chapter to take and pass an examination unless that person has successfully passed an examination that shall include testing of the applicant’s ability
      to read, write, and speak the English language.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1205.7.</num>
    <text>No license shall be issued under the provisions of this chapter to any person employed by a federal or District agency with a policy that forbids the employee from operating a public vehicle for hire.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1205.8.</num>
    <text>No license shall be issued under the provisions of this chapter to any employee of the District government whose employment is concerned directly or indirectly with the issuance of licenses to operate public vehicles for hire, or the enforcement of
      applicable rules and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1205.9.</num>
    <text>No license shall be issued to any person who is delinquent in paying a fine or, within the last three (3) years, has committed one or more serious traffic offenses in the District or elsewhere that indicate a disrespect for traffic laws or the safety
      of other persons.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1205.10.</num>
    <text>No license shall be issued under this chapter to any person who is not of good moral character under the standards delineated in §§ 1205.11 through 1205.13.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1205.11.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall not be considered of good moral character if he or she is any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A habitual drunkard;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Addicted to the use of drugs; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>On parole or probation at the time of the filing of the application for a license, except as provided in § 1205.12.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1205.12</num>
    <text>1205.12 Notwithstanding the provisions of § 1205.11, if the parole or the probation arose out of a conviction other than those listed in § 1205.13, the parolee’s or probationer’s application may be considered for approval if a letter from the appropriate
      parole or probation officer is submitted with the application stating that there is no objection to the issuance of a limousine or sedan operator&amp;#8217;s license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1205.13</num>
    <text>1205.13 An applicant shall not be considered of good moral character if the applicant has been convicted of or has served any part of a sentence for the following crimes, or an attempt to commit any of the following crimes, within the three (3) year
      period immediately preceding the filing of the application:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Murder, manslaughter, mayhem, malicious disfiguring of another, arson, kidnapping, burglary, housebreaking, robbery, theft, fraud, or unlawful possession of a firearm;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Assault with the intent to commit any offense punishable by imprisonment in the penitentiary;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A sexual offense proscribed by D.C. Official Code § 22-1901 (incest), §§ 22-3101 to 22-3103 (sexual performances using minors), §§ 22-2701 to 22-2722 (prostitution and pandering), §§ 22-3002 to 22-3020 (sexual abuse) or, an act committed outside
        the District that, if committed in the District, would constitute an offense under the foregoing statutes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A violation of the D.C. Uniformed Controlled Substances Act of 1981 or the Drug Paraphernalia Act of 1982, (D.C. Official Code §§ 48-901.01 et seq. and §§ 48-1101 et seq.) or, an act committed outside the District that, if committed in the District,
        would constitute an offense under the foregoing statutes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any criminal offense committed against a passenger; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Any criminal offense committed against any person that involves the use of a public vehicle-for-hire in a wanton, reckless, depraved, or malicious manner.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 2812, 2816 (May 20, 1994); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 12394 (August 30, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>