<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-1216</num>
  <heading>INTERJURISDICTIONAL LIMOUSINE OPERATION &amp;#8211; PERMIT REQUIRED (§ 31-1216)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1216.1.</num>
    <text>Any person who would be required to obtain a limousine for hire vehicle permit pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 50-313 and rules promulgated pursuant thereto may, in place of the permit, be issued an interjurisdictional limousine permit; provided
      that the person satisfies the conditions for the issuance of an interjurisdictional permit and the transportation provided by such person complies with the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1216.2.</num>
    <text>An interjurisdictional limousine permit only authorizes a person to pick-up passengers for hire in the District on a pre-arranged basis for destinations outside the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1216.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant for an interjurisdictional vehicle permit shall satisfy the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Possess a valid vehicle registration which is valid for the transportation of persons by limousine within that state;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Neither the applicant nor any person or business engaged in transporting passengers by motor vehicle for hire that is affiliated with the applicant has a place of business, a telephone number, or solicits business or specifically advertises in the
        District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The vehicle shall be driven only by the holder of a driver&amp;#8217;s license that is valid for the for-hire operation of the vehicle;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The vehicle shall be driven only by the holder of a for-hire vehicle driver&amp;#8217;s license where the driver has submitted proof satisfactory to the Commission that the driver possesses a license or permit that was granted by a state or political
        subdivision and for which the driver has been fingerprinted for the purpose of securing and reviewing the driver&amp;#8217;s criminal history records;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The applicant has not had an interjurisdictional vehicle permit revoked or has not been refused renewal of an interjurisdictional vehicle permit; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A driver of a vehicle for which an interjurisdictional limousine permit has been obtained must be licensed by the Commission, unless the driver has been issued a certificate by the Commission indicating that the driver possesses a license or permit
        that was granted by a state or political subdivision and for which the driver has been fingerprinted for the purpose of securing and reviewing the driver&amp;#8217;s criminal records.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1216.4.</num>
    <text>The annual fee for an interjurisdictional permit, including any permit for any limousine operating within the District of Columbia under an authorization issued by the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Commission, shall be four hundred dollars
      ($400) per vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1216.5.</num>
    <text>A fee of one hundred dollars ($100) shall be paid for each interjurisdictional limousine permit issued to replace a lost or mutilated permit, or a permit which has become obsolete as a result of the acquisition of new license plates.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1216.6.</num>
    <text>If the Commission, after reviewing an application for an inter-jurisdictional limousine permit and after appropriate investigation and a hearing affording the applicant an opportunity to be heard, finds that the applicant made a material false statement
      or concealed a material fact in connection with the application, the Commission may deny issuance of the permit, refuse to renew, suspend or revoke any such permit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1216.7.</num>
    <text>A vehicle owner issued a permit pursuant to this section shall maintain the conditions of issuance of the permit as provided in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1216.8.</num>
    <text>A vehicle owner shall ensure that a valid Commission decal, evidencing an interjurisdictional limousine permit, is affixed to the front right side of the windshield of a vehicle so as to be plainly visible. Interjurisdictional limousine permits for
      vehicles registered outside of the District shall be affixed to the front right side window so as to be plainly visible.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1216.9.</num>
    <text>No unauthorized entry shall be made on the interjurisdictional limousine permit or decal, nor shall any entry on any such vehicle permit or decal be changed or de faced.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1216.10.</num>
    <text>An unreadable interjurisdictional limousine permit or decal shall immediately be surrendered to the Commission for replacement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1216.11.</num>
    <text>A vehicle owner who holds an interjurisdictional limousine permit shall pick up passengers on a prearranged basis only. Street hails and the use of stands are not permitted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1216.12.</num>
    <text>A vehicle owner who holds an inter-jurisdictional limousine permit shall not pick-up and discharge the same passenger(s) within the District unless the following occurs:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>As part of pre-arranged transportation which begins with the pick-up of the passenger(s) in the District and ends with the discharge of the passenger(s) outside of the District, temporary discharge and subsequent pick-up of the passenger(s) within
        the District occurs during the course of performing the pre-arranged transportation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>There is no unauthorized intra-District transportation provided to any other person who is not covered by the pre-arranged transportation agreement during any such period of discharge.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1216.13.</num>
    <text>A vehicle owner shall ensure that a record of each transport authorized solely by an inter-jurisdictional limousine permit issued pursuant to § 1216.1 is entered prior to the commencement of the transport in a log carried in the vehicle. The record
      shall be kept for a period of one year after the transport. The record of each transport shall be written legibly in ink and include the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Passenger&amp;#8217;s name;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Time of scheduled pick up of passenger;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Location of one temporary discharge, if applicable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Final destination of passenger; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The time of completion of the transport.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1216.14.</num>
    <text>The log required by § 1216.13 shall be kept in the vehicle during inter-jurisdiction transport and shall be subject to inspection by any police officer, hack inspector, law enforcement official or other person authorized by the Commission. Failure
      to present a log maintained in the manner prescribed in § 1216.13 when requested by any such authorized person shall be presumptive evidence of intra-District operation in violation of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1216.15.</num>
    <text>A vehicle registered outside the District shall meet the inspection requirements provided by the state of registration. Authorized personnel of the Commission may conduct an on-street inspection of the vehicle. The Commission may order the vehicle
      owner to repair or replace the vehicle when it appears that it no longer meets the safety requirements prescribed by this chapter and the applicable state law or the safety requirements of the state of registration, as applicable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1216.16.</num>
    <text>A vehicle owner who holds an interjurisdictional limousine permit shall not permit the vehicle to be operated without daily personal inspection and reasonable determination that all equipment, including brakes, lights, and signals are in good working
      order and meet all the requirements of the applicable state law and this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1216.17.</num>
    <text>A vehicle owner who holds an interjurisdictional limousine permit shall not permit the vehicle to be operated when the Commission or the District&amp;#8217;s Bureau of Motor Vehicle Services has determined that the vehicle is unsafe or unfit for use
      as a for-hire vehicle and the vehicle owner has been directed to remove the vehicle from service.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1216.18.</num>
    <text>A vehicle owner who holds an interjurisdictional limousine permit shall ensure that he or she promptly complies with all Commission notices and directives to correct observable defects in a vehicle which would result in the inability of the vehicle
      to pass a District inspection or an inspection in the state of registration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1216.19.</num>
    <text>A vehicle owner who holds an interjurisdictional limousine permit shall designate each and every driver who operates the vehicle as his or her agent for accepting service by Commission personnel of summonses or notices to correct defects in the vehicle.
      Delivery of the summons or notice to a driver shall be considered proper service of the summons or notice on the vehicle owner. The Commission shall send a copy of any summons or notice to the vehicle owner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1216.20.</num>
    <text>A for-hire limousine vehicle owner shall immediately notify the Commission of the theft, loss, or destruction of an interjurisdictional limousine permit or decal and furnish the Commission with an affidavit or such information as may be required,
      and shall replace the permit or decal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1216.21.</num>
    <text>The transfer of an interjurisdictional limousine permit between vehicles shall be prohibited.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1216.22.</num>
    <text>Two hundred dollars ($200) of the annual fee in subsection 1216.4 shall be used to increase enforcement of this section, including providing a list of approved limousine services to District hotels for service within District boundaries with a copy
      of applicable regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 2812, 2826 (May 20, 1994); as amended by Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Act of 2009, effective March 3, 2010 (D.C. Law 18-111), at 57 DCR 181, 295 (January 8, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>