<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-1526</num>
  <heading>DOME LIGHT INSTALLATION BUSINESS – RECORD OF DOME LIGHT INSTALLATION TESTS (§1-1526)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1526.1.</num>
    <text>The dome light installation business owner shall record the results of any inspections or tests, and the dome light make, model, and serial number on a form prescribed by the Office of Taxicabs, which the dome light installation business licensee
      shall submit to the Commission within seven (7) days of such inspection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1526.2.</num>
    <text>Upon a determination that a dome light installation has passed an inspection, the dome light installation business owner, in addition to complying with § 1526.1, shall affix a certification sticker, prescribed and approved by the Office of Taxicabs,
      to the dome light. Any certification sticker shall not be re-affixed to the dome light installation if removed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1526.3.</num>
    <text>A dome light installation business owner shall provide for the safekeeping of certification stickers, shall control their sequence of issuance, and shall ensure that such stickers are placed only on dome lights in accordance with these regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1526.4.</num>
    <text>When a dome light is installed in preparation for “hack-up,” the dome light installation business owner, in addition to complying with §§ 1526.1 and 1526.2, shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Prepare a vehicle “hack-up” certification form approved by the Office of Taxicabs at the completion of the preparatory work for vehicle “hack-up”;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Submit to the Commission, within twenty-four (24) hours, all documents relating to the installation and inspection of such dome light; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Provide the vehicle owner with an itemized list of all work performed in preparation for “hack-up.”</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 14019 (December 7, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>