<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-237</num>
  <heading>SUBPOENAS (§ 31-237)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>237.1.</num>
    <text>Subpoenas requiring the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary or tangible evidence for the purpose of hearings or reviews may be issued by the Chairperson in substantially the same form as shown in Appendix 2-1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>237.2.</num>
    <text>Applications shall be in writing and in the form of a motion.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>237.3.</num>
    <text>If application is made two (2) or more days prior to the hearing, the motion shall be acted upon prior to the hearing, unless all parties agree that it will be acted upon at the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>237.4.</num>
    <text>If made during a hearing, the application may be made orally on the record with the consent of the Chairperson.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>237.5.</num>
    <text>Motions for issuance of subpoenas shall contain a statement or showing of general relevance and reasonable scope of the evidence sought, and shall be accompanied by a description of any documentary or tangible evidence to be subpoenaed with as much
      particularity as is feasible.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>237.6.</num>
    <text>Where it appears at a hearing that the testimony of a witness or the production of documentary evidence is relevant to the issues in a proceeding, the Chairperson or the Panel may issue on his or her or its own motion a subpoena requiring such witness
      to attend and testify or requiring the production of such documentary evidence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>237.7.</num>
    <text>Proceedings of the Panel shall be considered investigations or examinations of municipal matters within the meaning of the Act of July 1, 1902 (D.C. Official Code § 1-301.21 (2001)). The provisions of D.C. Official Code §§ 5-1001 through 5-1003 (2001),
      shall be applicable with respect to enforcement of subpoenas issued under this section, and with respect to witness fees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>237.8.</num>
    <text>Any person upon whom a subpoena has been served may, within ten (10) days after service, but in any event prior to the return date thereof, file with the Chairperson a motion to quash or to modify the subpoena and such filing shall stay the subpoena
      pending final action by the Chairperson or the Panel on the motion.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 6715, 6735 (October 23, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>