<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-228</num>
  <heading>CONDUCT DURING PROCEEDINGS (ยง 31-228)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>228.1.</num>
    <text>In addition to the requirements of ยง 225 any attorney who participates in any proceeding before the Panel shall comply with the rules of the Panel and shall adhere to the standards of ethical conduct required of attorneys before the courts of the
      District of Columbia and the District of Columbia Code of Professional Responsibility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>228.2.</num>
    <text>No restrictions in this section shall preclude an attorney from replying to charges of misconduct publicly made against him or her, or from participating in the proceedings of legislative, administrative, or other investigative bodies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>228.3.</num>
    <text>In all proceedings before the Panel, no attorney, other than the Commission&amp;#8217;s General Counsel, shall communicate, or cause another to communicate as to the merits of the case with any Commissioner before whom the proceeding is pending, except
      as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>In the course of official proceedings in the case; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>In writing directed to the Secretary with copies served upon all other parties.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>228.4.</num>
    <text>It is improper for any party, or person representing a party, in a case before the Panel to attempt to sway the judgment of the Panel in that case by undertaking directly or indirectly, through a third party outside the hearing process, to bring pressure
      or influence to bear upon the Panel or its staff.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>228.5.</num>
    <text>Requests for expeditious treatment of matters pending with the Panel are improper except when filed with the Secretary with copies served upon all parties or unless made before the Panel at a hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>228.6.</num>
    <text>No member of the Commission, Panel, or Office shall invite or knowingly entertain any prohibited ex parte communication, or make any communication to any party, counsel or agent of a party, or any other person who he or she has reason to know may
      transmit that communication to a party or a party&amp;#8217;s agent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>228.7.</num>
    <text>The Panel may disqualify and deny temporarily or permanently, the privilege of appearing or practicing before it in any way to any individual who, after a hearing, is found to have violated the requirements of this section. Violations of the requirements
      of this section by attorneys shall be referred to the appropriate District of Columbia Bar Committee for investigation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>228.8.</num>
    <text>Conduct amounting to contempt at any hearing before the Panel shall be grounds for exclusion from the hearing and for summary suspension without a hearing for the duration of the hearing or of the proceeding, or any part thereof.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 6715, 6729 (October 23, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>