<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-248</num>
  <heading>ADMISSION OF EVIDENCE (ยง 31-248)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>248.1.</num>
    <text>The Federal Rules of Evidence as they have been construed by the courts of the District of Columbia shall be applied in hearings; provided, that the Panel may, after informing the parties of an intention to do so, relax those rules in any hearing
      when, in its judgment, the ends of justice would be better served by so doing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>248.2.</num>
    <text>Formal exceptions to rulings of the Panel are unnecessary. It is sufficient that a party, at the time the ruling is made or sought, makes known the action which he or she desires to be taken, or his or her objection to an action taken, and his or
      her grounds for such action or objection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>248.3.</num>
    <text>The Panel may, in its discretion, limit the cross cross-examination of any witness.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>248.4.</num>
    <text>Where written matter offered in evidence is embraced in a document containing another matter which is not intended to be offered in evidence, the offering party shall present the original document for inspection at the hearing, and shall offer an
      exact copy of the matter which is to be introduced, unless the presiding officer, or the Panel, determines that the matter is short enough to be read into the record. Other parties shall be afforded opportunity to introduce in evidence, in like
      manner, other portions of the original document.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>248.5.</num>
    <text>When any portion of the record before the Panel in any proceeding other than the one being heard, or any portion of any other official record of the Commission or of the Panel, is offered in evidence, true copies of that portion shall be presented
      for the record in the form of an exhibit, or that portion may, without objection, be incorporated in the record by reference.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 6715, 6744 (October 23, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>