<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-234</num>
  <heading>COMPUTATION OF TIME (§ 31-234)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>234.1.</num>
    <text>When, by notice given under §§ 220 to 256, and 299, or by order or decision of the Panel, an act is required or allowed to be done at or within a specified time, the Panel for cause shown may, at any time in its discretion, do either of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>With or without motion or notice, order the period enlarged if request therefor is made before the expiration of the period originally prescribed or as extended by a previous order; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Upon motion made after expiration of the specified period, permit the act to be done where the failure to act was the result of excusable neglect and only then in extraordinary cases where the denial of an enlargement of time would operate to deny
        a person adversely affected thereby any opportunity to notice and hearing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>234.2.</num>
    <text>In computing any period of time prescribed or allowed by §§ 220 to 256 and 299, by notice, order, rule, of the Commission, Panel, Office, by statute, the day of the act, event, or default after which the designated period of time begins to run is
      not to be included.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>234.3.</num>
    <text>The last day of the period so computed shall be included unless it is a Saturday, Sunday, or during the period of time described in § 202.2, in which event the period runs until the end of the next day which is not a Saturday, Sunday, or during the
      period of time described in § 202.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>234.4.</num>
    <text>Whenever a party has the right or is required to take action within the period prescribed by §§ 220 to 256 and 299, by a notice given thereunder, or by an order or regulation, the Panel may, before the expiration of the prescribed period, with or
      without notice, extend the period; or, upon motion, permit the act to be done after the expiration of the specified period, where the failure to act is clearly shown to have been the result of excusable neglect.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 6715, 6732 (October 23, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>