<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-503</num>
  <heading>TAXICAB COLORINGS AND MARKINGS (§ 31-503)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>503.1.</num>
    <text>Uniform color scheme. Effective October 1, 2013, each vehicle in the District intended for use as a taxicab shall comply with the uniform color scheme in</text>
    <text>§ 503.3 if;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>It is entering service as a new vehicle; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For any reason it is repainted in whole or in part, or is required to be repainted in whole or in part by any provision of this title or by any other District of Columbia law or regulation; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>It is a replacement vehicle, including a vehicle entering service according to the gradual removal schedule of § 609 of this title.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>503.2.</num>
    <text>A taxicab that fails to comply with this section shall not be operated. Each taxicab operated in violation of this section shall subject the owner and operator to the civil penalties set forth in this chapter, including impoundment of the vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>503.3.</num>
    <text>The uniform color scheme for District taxicabs is established as provided in this subsection. Each vehicle shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be painted red in color to match the D.C. Circulator: 3M Controltac Graphic Film color Geranium 180C-63;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Bear a vehicle model specific stripe decal on both sides that: aligns with the bottom of the taxicab tail light at the rear of the vehicle, is made of 3M Controltac Plus Film (or equivalent), and matches Pantone Warm Gray 2 in color;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Bear decal letters of the name of the taxicab company, association, or fleet name, or the name of the owner for an independently operated taxicab, and a customer service telephone number on both front side doors (driver and passenger). The decal
        letters shall be the color black, in Calibri font, using capital letters that are two and fifteen sixteenths inches (2-15/16″) in height measured from the X height and manufactured of 3M Controltac Plus Film (or equivalent);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Bear decal letters of the taxicab company, association, or fleet name and fleet vehicle number, if applicable, or the name of the owner and independent taxicab number, if applicable, which shall be on the rear of the body so as to be clearly visible
        from the rear, on either side of and in alignment with the center of the vehicle manufacturer placed logo. The decal letters shall be the color black, in Calibri font, using capital letters that are one and one half (1-1/2) inches in height measured
        from the X height and manufactured of 3M Controltac Plus Film (or equivalent);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Display a DCTC Certification Decal, of a size and shape determined by the Office, which shall be affixed in the lower left hand corner of the rear passenger window; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>If the owner has received express written approval from the Office, an insignia, logo, term, or symbol may be placed on the vehicle, consistent with the requirements of § 503.7, as follows —</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the owner is a taxicab company, or the vehicle is associated with a taxicab association or fleet, the insignia or logo of such company, association, or fleet may be centered on both rear passenger doors, which shall be no more than seventeen
        inches (17″) in width and shall be two inches (2″) from the closest gray edge/field; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Based on specifications set forth in one or more Office orders, where the vehicle is an alternative fuel vehicle, a term or symbol commonly used in the motor vehicle or taxicab industry to mark such vehicle may be placed on the vehicle.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>503.4.</num>
    <text>Additional information about the specifications for the uniform color scheme shall be maintained on the Commission’s website.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>503.5.</num>
    <text>It shall be the responsibility of each taxicab company, association, or fleet to ensure that any taxicab bearing its name, insignia, or logo is on the insurance list filed with the Office for that company, association, or fleet.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>503.6.</num>
    <text>The operation of a taxicab bearing a name, insignia, or logo in violation of this section shall be presumptive evidence that the operator and the owner are in violation of § 816 (fraud).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>503.7.</num>
    <text>Review process for proposed display of insignia, logo, term, or symbol.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An owner interested in displaying an insignia, logo, term, or symbol on its vehicle pursuant to § 503.3(f) shall submit an application under oath, in a form acceptable to the Office, accompanied by the appropriate fee, and —</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Either —</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>If the application seeks approval of a taxicab company, association, or fleet insignia or logo, pursuant to § 503.3(f)(1): an electronic rendering of the design accurately depicting the insignia or logo and its proposed location(s) on the vehicle;
        or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>If the application is for a term or symbol for an alternative fuel vehicle, pursuant to § 503.3(f)(2), then a website URL for a trade or industry association or vehicle manufacturer website where the term or symbol may be found and reflects that
        the term or symbol is commonly used in the motor vehicle or taxicab industry to mark such vehicle, and an electronic rendering accurately depicting the term or symbol and its proposed location(s) on the vehicle; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Such additional information and documentation that the Office may require to evaluate the request.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Office shall deny an application where the proposed insignia, logo, term or symbol would be offensive, in poor taste, confuse or mislead consumers, undermine the uniform color scheme, or violate any provision of this title or other applicable
        law.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Office shall render its decision to grant or deny an application in writing within thirty (30) days, which, if denied, may be appealed to the Chairman, whose decision shall be a final, appealable order of the Office.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>If the Office grants its approval, the owner shall complete placement of the insignia, logo, term, or symbol on all of its vehicles within sixty (60) days of the issuance of the approval.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>503.8.</num>
    <text>Prohibitions.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>No paint, graphic, vehicle wrap or decal, paint color, design, insignia, logo, term, symbol, advertisement, signage, display, label, sticker, or lettering shall be placed on any taxicab unless it complies with this section or the owner has obtained
        the express written approval of the Office.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>There shall not be placed on or in any taxicab, paint, graphic, vehicle wrap or decal, paint color, design, insignia, logo, term, symbol, advertisement, signage, display, label, sticker, lettering or other exterior object which has, tends to have,
        or may have the effect of confusing, misleading, or deceiving the public.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 3595, 3597 (June 1, 1990); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 4047 (June 25, 1993); by Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 2370 (April 29, 1994); by Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 6953
        (October 21, 1994); and by Final Rulemaking published 45 DCR 8866 (December 11, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8549, 8554 (July 20, 2012); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 12387 (August 30, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>