<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-822</num>
  <heading>OPERATION OF PUBLIC VEHICLES FOR HIRE (§ 31-822)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>822.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall be issued or allowed to renew a license for a public vehicle for hire vehicle identification (DCTC) card or operator identification (Face) card under D.C. Official Code §§ 47-2829(d) and (e) (2005 Repl.; 2011 Supp.)) unless that person
      has paid, together with the cost of the license; any outstanding assessment ordered by the Commission pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 50-320 (2009 Repl.; 2011 Supp.); all fines imposed for notices of infractions issued for violations of Commission
      rules or District traffic or parking regulations involving the operation of a public vehicle for hire; and all other outstanding taxes, fines, fees, penalties, or interest owed to the District in excess of one hundred dollars ($100) pursuant to
      D.C. Official Code § 47-2862 (2005 Repl.; 2011 Supp.). If the applicant has properly and timely filed an appeal of the assessment, taxes, fine, fees, penalties or interest and the appeal is still pending, the applicant shall be given temporary operating
      authority (a temporary license) pending disposition of the appeal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>822.2.</num>
    <text>No person shall counterfeit, make, duplicate, obtain, purchase, possess, display, or present a counterfeit, false, or altered official government issued operator identification (Face) card; a counterfeit, false, or altered official government issued
      public vehicle for hire identification (DCTC) card; or a temporary license issued pursuant to § 822.1. Penalties for a violation of this provision may include license suspension, revocation, or non-renewal, a fine as provided in § 825, or both.
      However, an operator may make, and keep secured, a personal copy of his or her official government issued operator identification (Face) card or official government issued public vehicle for hire identification (DCTC) card in his or her personal
      files. This personal copy may not be carried in the vehicle or presented or displayed as proof of licensure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>822.3.</num>
    <text>No person shall drive or be in physical control of a taxicab unless they have in their possession a valid identification card issued to them under D.C. Official Code §47-2829(e) (2001) and a valid District of Columbia motor vehicle operator&amp;#8217;s
      permit or, for non-District residents or persons exempt from obtaining a District motor vehicle operator&amp;#8217;s permit, a valid motor vehicle operator&amp;#8217;s permit issued by a state that is a party to the Driver License Compact Act, D.C.
      Official Code § 50-1001 et seq. (2001).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>822.4.</num>
    <text>It shall be the duty of the owner of a taxicab and their agent or lessee to prevent any person from driving a taxicab unless the person has in their possession a valid identification card issued to him or her and a valid District of Columbia motor
      vehicle operator&amp;#8217;s permit or, for non-District residents or persons exempt from obtaining a District motor vehicle operator&amp;#8217;s permit, a valid motor vehicle operator&amp;#8217;s permit issued by a state that is a party to the
      Driver License Compact Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>822.5.</num>
    <text>The fact that any unlicensed person is driving a taxicab shall be prima facie evidence that they are doing so with the permission of the owner, agent or lessee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>822.6.</num>
    <text>In the event an operator&amp;#8217;s identification card is suspended or revoked subsequent to receiving authority from the owner, agent or lessee to operate a taxicab, the owner, agent or lessee shall be held to have knowledge of the fact if notice
      of the revocation or suspension shall have been published or given to him or her, by the Commission or another agency of government.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>822.7.</num>
    <text>The Office of Taxicabs shall, by registered mail and within five (5) business days of a final decision of suspension, revocation, or non-renewal of a taxicab operator identification card, notify the association, corporation, organization, or person
      that maintains a taxicab lease or taxicab association or company membership agreement with the operator that the operator&amp;#8217;s privilege to operate a taxicab in the District of Columbia has been suspended, revoked, or not renewed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>822.8.</num>
    <text>The association, corporation, organization or person that maintains a lease with the operator shall, upon receipt of the notice required by § 822.6, terminate any lease agreement, written or otherwise, with the operator, and shall take reasonable
      steps to assure the return to the owner of any vehicle leased to the operator.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>822.9.</num>
    <text>Every person holding an identification card shall maintain at the Office of Taxicabs their correct name, residence address and telephone number, and if affiliated with a company or association, the association, company, organization or owner for which
      they drive. In the event of any change in this information, the licensee shall inform the Office of the change within five (5) business days. The licensee may elect to provide this information by certified mail with return receipt requested or by
      hand delivery to the Office. If the licensee delivers the information by hand delivery, the Office will provide proof of filing to the licensee. Failure to do so will result in a fine of one hundred dollars ($100.00) per offense. Any fine imposed
      pursuant to this section shall be collected at the time of the licensee&amp;#8217;s renewal period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>822.10.</num>
    <text>The operation of taxicabs shall be conducted in accordance with the laws of the District and with due regard for the safety, comfort and convenience of passengers, for the safe and careful transportation of property, and for the safety of the general
      public. All reasonable efforts shall be made to promote safety at all times and under all conditions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>822.11.</num>
    <text>No person shall drive a taxicab for hire when the operator does any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Is not clean in dress or in person;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Is not fully attired or is attired in such a manner as to give offense to the public; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Wears shorts, &amp;#8220;T&amp;#8221; shirts as an outer garment, sweat pants, sweat shirts, sweatsuits, or sandals.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>822.12.</num>
    <text>No person shall drive or be in physical control of any taxicab for the purpose of carrying passengers or parcels for a period in excess of twelve (12) hours in any twenty-four (24) hour period, unless the driving time is broken by a period of eight
      (8) continuous hours of rest. No taxicab shall be operated during a twenty-four (24) hour period for more than sixteen (16) hours.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>822.13.</num>
    <text>No person shall drive a taxicab for any period of time which, when added to the period of time they have driven any vehicle other than a taxicab, totals more than twelve (12) hours in any twenty-four (24) hour period, unless the driving time is broken
      by a period of eight (8) continuous hours of rest.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>822.14.</num>
    <text>No owner of a taxicab or their agent shall knowingly permit any taxicab owned by him or her to be driven in violation of §§ 822.11 or 822.12.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>822.15.</num>
    <text>No taxicab shall be driven when it is so loaded or when there is in the front seat such number of persons as to obstruct the view of the driver to the front or sides or to interfere with his or her control over the taxicab. No taxicab shall carry
      more adult passengers than the designed capacity of the vehicle, and no more children than can be seated comfortably on the seats.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>822.16.</num>
    <text>Taxicab operators shall travel the most direct and reasonable route between the origin and destination of each trip, as reasonably determined by the operator. To the extent feasible, taxicab operators shall utilize a global positioning system (“GPS”)
      device or a smart phone containing a GPS function to determine the most direct and reasonable route. The operator, if at all possible or in instances where the operator is unsure of the route, shall accept direction from the passenger to travel
      a certain route to the destination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>822.17.</num>
    <text>No taxicab operator shall stop to load or unload passengers on the traffic side of the street, while occupying any intersection or crosswalk, or in such a manner as to unduly interfere with the orderly flow of traffic. All taxicab drivers shall pull
      as close to the curb or edge of the roadway as possible to take on or discharge passengers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>822.18.</num>
    <text>No taxicab operator shall stop or park a taxicab adjacent to any curb except as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>While actually taking on or discharging passengers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>When occupying a designated public vehicle stand for taxicabs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>When answering a call or delivering a parcel; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>When not holding his or her vehicle for hire, in which event the identification card shall be removed from the taxicab and the driver shall be away from the taxicab on business of his or her own.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>822.19.</num>
    <text>Each taxicab in service shall be kept clean both inside and out, including the trunk. The inside shall be kept in a sanitary condition and shall be swept and dusted thoroughly. The exterior shall be thoroughly cleaned.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>822.20.</num>
    <text>Each operator of a taxicab shall, upon concluding taxicab operations for the day, make a diligent search of all parts of the taxicab for property left therein. The operator shall promptly turn in all property of any value to any police precinct station.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>822.21.</num>
    <text>At the request of the passenger, a taxicab operator shall turn off or turn down the sound on a radio, other than the radio used for communications with a dispatcher.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>822.22.</num>
    <text>Nothing shall be transported in any taxicab that will cause the interior of the vehicle to become soiled or offensive to passengers because of odor or appearance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 3595, 3623 (June 1, 1990); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 5958 (August 19, 1994); and Final Rulemaking published at 44 DCR 7686 (December 19, 1997); as amended by Final Rulemaking published
        at 52 DCR 11290 (December 30, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 9970, 9982 (August 17, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>