<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-824</num>
  <heading>SANCTIONS AND PENALTIES (§ 31-824)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>824.1.</num>
    <text>A person who violates a Commission rule may, upon determination of liability, be subject to civil fines or other sanctions pursuant to the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission Establishment Act of 1985, this title, and other District of Columbia
      laws and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>824.2.</num>
    <text>Penalties for violations of § 819 (Consumer Service and Passenger Relations) and § 821 (Taxicab Stands) shall be as provided in D.C. Official Code § 50-371 (2009 Repl.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>824.3.</num>
    <text>Penalties for violation(s) of D.C. Official Code § 47-2829(e)(1) (2001) may, in lieu of imposing a civil fine or other sanctions, be prosecuted pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 47-2846 (2001).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>824.4.</num>
    <text>Any Metropolitan Police Officer, Hack Inspector or law enforcement official may remove the license plates (tags) and DCTC vehicle registration from any District licensed taxicab that is operated by an unlicensed operator. The tags and DCTC vehicle
      registration shall be deposited at the Commission and released only to the registered owner of record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>824.5.</num>
    <text>For each violation of this section, a public vehicle for hire operator or a person acting on the operator’s behalf shall be subject to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The fines set forth in § 825 of this chapter, or if a specific fine or penalty is not listed in this chapter, a fine of one hundred dollars ($ 100);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Impoundment of the vehicle associated with the violation pursuant to the Taxicab and Passenger Vehicle for Hire Impoundment Act of 1992, effective March 16, 1993 (D.C. Law 9-199; D.C. Official Code § 50-331 (2009 Repl.; 2011 Supp.));</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>License suspension, revocation, or non-renewal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Remedial action, to assure the safety of the public, as a condition of re-instatement of a license after suspension or revocation, including but not limited to:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Attending an anger management course;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Cultural sensitivity training; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Re-taking the operator training course; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any combination of the sanctions listed in this subsection.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>824.6.</num>
    <text>Where a licensee is the subject of three (3) or more complaints resulting in findings of liability for civil infractions during any one year period, the Chairperson of the Commission, in the Chairperson’s sole discretion, may offer the licensee the
      option to successfully complete a course of remedial action in lieu of revocation or suspension of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>824.7.</num>
    <text>The cost of any course of remedial action pursuant to § 824.5 or 824.6 shall be borne by the licensee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>824.8.</num>
    <text>A decision of the Chairperson to refuse to make an offer of remedial action in lieu of license revocation or suspension of the license, or a determination that an offered course of remedial action was not successfully completed by the licensee, is
      not subject to appeal or review.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 3595, 3627 (June 1, 1990); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 43 DCR 6298 (November 22, 1996); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 9970, 9984 (August 17, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>