<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-803</num>
  <heading>RECEIPTS FOR TAXICAB SERVICE (§ 31-803)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>803.1</num>
    <text>803.1 At the end of each taxicab ride, the taxicab operator shall provide the passenger with a receipt containing the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The taxicab name and telephone number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The date of the trip;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The taxicab number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The operator’s DCTC operator Identification (Face Card) number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The trip number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The start and end time of the trip;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The mileage of the trip;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The total charges established by § 801.9, itemized to show the taximeter fare, any authorized additional charges, the passenger surcharge and gratuity, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The form of payment, including whether the payment was made by cash payment, credit card (and type), digital payment, mobile payment, voucher or account;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Last four digits of any applicable payment card number and the transaction authorization code;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>The following information:</text>
    </level>
    <text>DCTC COMPLAINTS LINE AND WEBSITE ADDRESS</text>
    <text>www.dctaxi.dc.gov</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.2.</num>
    <text>When payment is made by a cash or cashless payment, a printed receipt shall be provided using the vehicle’s MTS printer component. If the printer component malfunctions while printing a receipt, the operator shall provide the passenger with a handwritten
      receipt and the vehicle shall then be out of service until the printer component is operational.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.3.</num>
    <text>When payment is made by digital payment, the operator shall provide the passenger with the passenger’s choice of a printed receipt or an electronic receipt sent to the passenger via email address or SMS text message not later than when the passenger
      exits the vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>803.4</num>
    <text>803.4 In the case of messenger or parcel delivery service, the operator shall provide the customer with a written invoice describing the article(s) transported.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>PH</heading>
      <text>855-484-4967, TTY 711</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 3595, 3613 (June 1, 1990); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 3831 (April 11, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 9970, 9973 (August 17, 2012); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 60 DCR 7016 (May 17, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10997 (July 26, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>