<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-999</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 31-999)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>999.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following words and phrases shall have the meaning ascribed:</text>
    <text>Commissioner &amp;#8211; the Commissioner of Insurance, Securities, and Banking, or his or her designated agent.</text>
    <text>District &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>License Act – An Act making appropriations to provide for the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1903, and for other purposes, approved July 1, 1902 (32 Stat. 623); as amended by Public Law 237, approved July
      1, 1932 (47 Stat. 550; D.C. Official Code §§ 47-2801, et seq) (2005 Repl. &amp;#038; 2011 Supp.); see D.C. Official Code § 47-2829.</text>
    <text>Office &amp;#8211; the Office of Taxicabs established by § 13 of the District of Columbia Taxicab Establishment Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-97; D.C. Official Code §§ 50-301, et seq.) (2009 Repl. &amp;#038; 2011 Supp.).</text>
    <text>Owner &amp;#8211; a corporation, company, association, joint stock company, partnership, or person, including its lessees, trustees, or receivers appointed by any court, operating, controlling, managing, or renting a passenger vehicle for hire in
      the District of Columbia, except as to operations licensed under § 31(b) of the License Act, D.C. Official Code § 47 -2829(d) (2005 Repl. &amp;#038; 2011 Supp.), and except the common carriers as have been expressly exempted from the jurisdiction
      of the Commission.</text>
    <text>Public Vehicle for Hire – a passenger vehicle for hire licensed in the District of Columbia including, but not limited to, taxicabs and limousines.</text>
    <text>Taxicab &amp;#8211; a passenger vehicle for hire having a seating capacity of eight (8) or fewer passengers, exclusive of the driver, and operated or offered as a vehicle for passenger transportation for hire.</text>
    <text>Vehicle &amp;#8211; a passenger vehicle for hire in the District of Columbia except vehicles licensed under § 31(b) of the License Act, (D.C. Official Code § 47-2829(b) (2005 Repl. &amp;#038; 2011 Supp.)) and except vehicles operated by common carriers
      which have been expressly exempted from the jurisdiction of the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>14 DCRR §400.2, Special Edition (January 10, 1975); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 9847, 9851 (November 18, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>