<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-103</num>
  <heading>RESPONSIBILITIES OF THE DIRECTOR OF THE OFFICE OF HUMAN RIGHTS (§ 4-103)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>103.1.</num>
    <text>In addition to other duties, for purposes of this chapter, the Director shall advise the Mayor with respect to the preparation of plans, procedures, regulations, reports and other matters pertaining to the provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.2.</num>
    <text>The Director shall prepare all reports in connection with the EEO program as may be required by the Mayor or the EEOC.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.3.</num>
    <text>The Director shall recommend changes in policy, practices, and procedures designed to eliminate discriminatory practices and to improve the Mayor’s program for equal employment opportunity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.4.</num>
    <text>The Director shall establish a system for periodically evaluating the effectiveness of the District government’s overall EEO program, including the rules, and when appropriate report to the Mayor with recommendations for any improvement or correction
      needed, including remedial or disciplinary action with respect to managerial or supervisory employees who have failed to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.5.</num>
    <text>The Director shall prepare a model agency affirmative action program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.6.</num>
    <text>The Director shall consult with agency heads regarding the suitability of persons appointed or designated, or pending appointment or designation, as departmental EEO Officers and EEO Counselors. If the Director determines that an EEO Counselor or
      an EEO Officer has not responded to at least three (3) orders of OHR, the Director shall notify the responsible agency head and recommend that the EEO Counselor or EEO Officer be removed from the EEO role.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.7.</num>
    <text>The Director shall issue guidelines and procedures for counseling by an EEO Counselor of any aggrieved employee or applicant for employment who contends that he or she has been discriminated against because of race, color, religion, national origin,
      sex, age, marital status, personal appearance, sexual orientation, gender identity or expression, family responsibilities, matriculation, political affiliation, genetic information, and disability, with respect to any aspect of District government
      employment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.8.</num>
    <text>The Director shall receive and investigate complaints of alleged discrimination in personnel matters, from employees who contend that they have been discriminated against in connection with any aspect of District government employment because of race,
      color, religion, national origin, sex, age, marital status, personal appearance, sexual orientation, gender identity or expression, family responsibilities, matriculation, political affiliation, genetic information, and disability.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.9.</num>
    <text>The Director shall publicize to all District government employees the address of the Office of Human Rights (OHR), as well as the names, agency addresses, and phone numbers of all District EEO Counselors and EEO Officers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.10.</num>
    <text>The Director shall submit to the Director of the Department of Human Resources for prior review all recommendations of in-depth investigative or statistical reports when the recommendations or reports relate to or would affect in any manner programs
      involving the employment, employee relations, or other personnel actions of the District government.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.11.</num>
    <text>The Director shall designate, when necessary in the interest of fairness and justice, AtLarge EEO Counselors to handle EEO problems on an informal basis. An AtLarge EEO Counselor need not be an employee of the agency for which counseling service is
      provided. The OHR Compliance Officer may also take on this role.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 56, 59-60 (January 6, 1984); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 9162, 9164-9165 (October 1, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>