<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-1099</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 4-1099)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1099.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have the meaning ascribed:</text>
    <text>Commercial space &amp;#8211; any building, structure, or designated portion thereof which is occupied as, or designed or intended for, occupancy as an accommodation for business activity, and any vacant land which is offered for sale or lease for
      the construction or location thereon of any building, structure, or portion of the building or structure.</text>
    <text>Dwelling &amp;#8211; any building, structure, or portion of the building or structure, including a house or apartment, which is occupied as, or designed or intended for occupancy as, a residence by one or more families or business entities, and any
      vacant land which is offered for sale or lease for the construction or location thereon of any such building, structure, or portion thereof.</text>
    <text>Familial status &amp;#8211; has the same meaning found in § 102 of the Act (D.C. Code § 1-2502).</text>
    <text>Family &amp;#8211; a single individual or two or more related or unrelated persons who share a dwelling.</text>
    <text>Owner &amp;#8211; has the same meaning as found in § 102 of the Act (D.C. Official Code § 2-1401.02 (2001)).</text>
    <text>Owner’s family &amp;#8211; the owner’s spouse, the owner’s children, and the parents of the owner and the owner’s spouse.</text>
    <text>Person &amp;#8211; has the same meaning as found in § 102 of the Act (D.C. Official Code § 2-1401.02(21) (2001)).</text>
    <text>Prohibited basis &amp;#8211; any one or a combination of the following: race, color, religion, national origin, sex, age, marital status, personal appearance, sexual orientation, family responsibilities, matriculation, political affiliation, physical
      handicap, source of income, and place of residence or business of any individual.</text>
    <text>Real Property &amp;#8211; land and generally whatever is erected or affixed to the land, including condominiums and cooperatives.</text>
    <text>Restrictive covenant &amp;#8211; any written statement in a deed or other document related to the transfer of an interest in real property purporting to limit transfer, sale, or rental on the basis of race, color, religion, national origin, sex, age,
      marital status, personal appearance, sexual orientation, family responsibilities, matriculation, political affiliation, physical handicap, source of income, and place of residence or business of any individual.</text>
    <text>Sale &amp;#8211; a transaction in real property where there is a transfer of ownership of and title to real property from one person to another for consideration.</text>
    <text>Source of income &amp;#8211; has the same meaning as found in § 102 of the Act (D.C. Official Code § 2-1401.02(29) (2001)).</text>
    <text>To rent &amp;#8211; leasing, subleasing, to let, or otherwise to grant for a consideration the right to occupy premises not owned by the occupant.</text>
    <text>Transaction in real property &amp;#8211; has the same meaning as found in § 102 of the Act (D.C. Official Code § 2-1401.02(30) (2001)).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 5464, 5469 (July 15, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 4339 (May 14, 1999), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 2817, 2824 (March 19, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>