<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-1199</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 4-1199)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1199.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Contract &amp;#8211; any binding legal relationship between the District of Columbia and a contractor for supplies or services, including but not limited to, any District of Columbia government or District of Columbia government assisted construction
      or project, lease agreements, Industrial Revenue Bond financing, and Urban Development Action grants, or for the lease of District of Columbia property in which the parties, respectively, do not stand in the relationship of employer and employee.</text>
    <text>Contracting Agency &amp;#8211; any department, agency, or establishment of the District of Columbia which is authorized to enter into contracts.</text>
    <text>Contracting Officer &amp;#8211; any official of a contracting agency who is vested with the authority to execute contracts on behalf of an agency.</text>
    <text>Contractor &amp;#8211; any prime contractor holding a contract with the District of Columbia Government. The term shall also refer to subcontractors when the context so indicates.</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; the Director of the Office of Human Rights, or his or her designee.</text>
    <text>Dispute &amp;#8211; any protest received from a bidder or prospective contractor relating to the effectiveness of his or her proposed program of affirmative action for providing equal opportunity.</text>
    <text>Minority &amp;#8211; Black Americans, Native Americans, Asian Americans, Pacific Islander Americans, and Hispanic Americans, in accordance with D.C. Official Code § 2-215.02(l) (2001).</text>
    <text>Subcontract &amp;#8211; any agreement made or executed by a prime contractor or a subcontractor where a material part of the supplies or services, including construction, covered by an agreement is being obtained for use in the performance of a contract
      subject to Mayor’s Order No. 85-85, and any rules, regulations, and procedures issued pursuant thereto.</text>
    <text>Subcontractor &amp;#8211; any contractor holding a contract with a District prime contractor calling for supplies or services, including construction, required for the performance of a contract subject to Mayor’s Order No. 85-85, and any rules, regulations,
      and procedures promulgated pursuant thereto.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 4952, 4966 (August 15, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>