<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-1108</num>
  <heading>MINIMUM STANDARDS FOR MINORITY AND FEMALE EMPLOYMENT (§ 4-1108)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1108.1.</num>
    <text>The minimum standards for the utilization of minorities in the District of Columbia government construction contracts shall be forty-two percent (42%) in each trade for each project, and an aggregate workforce standard of six and nine-tenths percent
      (6.9%) for females in each project. Any changes in federal standards pertaining to minority group and female employment in federally involved construction contracts shall be taken into consideration in any review of these requirements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.2.</num>
    <text>The construction contractor’s standards established in accordance with §1108.1 shall express the contractor’s commitment of the forty-two percent (42%) of minority personnel who will be working in each specified trade on each of the contractor’s District
      of Columbia government projects, and the aggregate standard of six and nine-tenths percent (6.9%) for the employment of females in each District of Columbia government contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.3.</num>
    <text>The hours for minority and female workers shall be substantially uniform throughout the entire length of the construction contract for each trade used, to the effect that the same percentage of minority workers in the trades used shall be working
      throughout the length of work in each trade on each project, and the aggregate percentage in each project for females.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.4.</num>
    <text>The minimum standard for the utilization of minorities in non-construction contracts shall be twenty-five percent (25%) in each of the following nine (9) job categories:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Officials and managers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Professionals;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Technicians;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Sales workers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Office and clerical workers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Craftpersons (Skilled);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Operative (Semi-skilled);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Laborers (Unskilled); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Service workers.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.5.</num>
    <text>With respect to non-construction contracts the contractor’s standards established in accordance with § 1108.4 shall express the contractor’s commitment of the twenty-five percent (25%) of minority personnel who will be working in each specified craft
      or skill in each contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 4952, 4960-61 (August 15, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>