<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-1119</num>
  <heading>SANCTIONS (ยง 4-1119)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1119.1.</num>
    <text>The Director, upon finding that a contractor has failed to comply with the non-discrimination provisions of the contract required under ยง 1103, or has failed to make a good faith effort to achieve the utilization standards under an approved Affirmative
      Action Program, may impose sanctions contained in this section in addition to any sanctions or remedies as may be imposed or invoked under the Human Rights Act of 1977.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1119.2.</num>
    <text>Sanctions imposed by the Director may include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Order that the contractor be declared ineligible from consideration for award of District of Columbia government contracts or subcontracts until such time as the Director may be satisfied that the contractor has established and will maintain equal
        opportunity policies in compliance with this chapter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Direct each Contracting Officer administering any existing contract to cancel, terminate, or suspend the contract or any portion thereof, and to deny any extension, modification, or change, unless the contractor provides a program of future compliance
        satisfactory to the Director.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1119.3.</num>
    <text>Any sanction imposed under this chapter may be rescinded or modified upon reconsideration by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1119.4.</num>
    <text>An appeal of any sanction imposed by order of the Director under this chapter may be taken pursuant to applicable clauses of the affected contract or provisions of law and regulations governing District of Columbia government contracts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 4952, 4965-66 (August 15, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>