<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-110</num>
  <heading>INVESTIGATION (§ 4-110)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>110.1.</num>
    <text>Each complaint shall be promptly investigated by OHR.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>110.2.</num>
    <text>The investigator assigned to a case is authorized to administer oaths and require that the statement of a witness shall be under oath or affirmation, without a pledge of confidence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>110.3.</num>
    <text>A witness shall not be subjected to any form of restraint, interference, coercion, discrimination, or reprisal because of consultation with or information provided to the OHR staff.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>110.4.</num>
    <text>Pursuant to a Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) request, the Director or his designee shall arrange to furnish the complainant, the complainant’s representative, the appropriate agency EEO Officer, or the agency head a copy of the investigative file
      at the end of the reconsideration period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>110.5</num>
    <text>110.5 The investigator, upon completion of the investigation, shall submit to the Director, through its Office of General Counsel (OGC), a written statement of proposed findings of fact, conclusions, and recommendations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>110.6.</num>
    <text>OGC shall send a draft Letter of Determination (LOD) recommending probable cause or no probable cause to the Director. The Director shall review the LOD, make a substitute determination or approve the determination, and issue a final determination
      to the parties. The LOD shall state whether there is probable cause or no probable cause to credit the complaint, or whether the complaint should be dismissed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>110.7.</num>
    <text>The activities of the Director under this chapter shall be considered investigations or examinations of municipal matters within the meaning of D.C. Official Code § 1301.21 (2001) and D.C. Official Code § 5-1021 (2001), and the Director and hearing
      examiners shall possess the powers vested in the Mayor by those statutes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 73-22, approved November 16, 1973; Mayor’s Order 75-230, dated October 31, 1975, 34 DCRR; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 56, 68-69 (January 6, 1984); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 9162, 9174
        (October 1, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>