<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-1215</num>
  <heading>ANNUAL REPORT (§ 4-1215)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1215.1.</num>
    <text>Each covered entity with major public contact shall furnish a narrative report on progress made in the implementation of the Act at the end of each fiscal year to the LA Director. The report shall be included on a form designated by the LA Director
      and shall contain summary data on the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Total number of LEP/NEP individuals served or encountered from the total population served by the entity within the fiscal year (delineated by language);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A list of translated vital documents;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Oral language services offered through the entity’s services and programs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The names of all organizations to which the entity provides grants or contracts to provide services to its LEP/NEP customers.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>An itemized budget allocated for Language Access purposes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>A comprehensive list of the entity’s bilingual staff employed in public contact positions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>The list of contractors and grantees, as described in §§1205.3 and 1205.4, and the status of their compliance with the Act; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>The number of language access complaints received during the course of the fiscal year, and the steps taken to resolve those complaints.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1215.2.</num>
    <text>Annual reports shall be submitted to the LA Director by a deadline designated by the LA Director. Failure to fulfill the criteria set in section 1214.1 may also be reported to the Director OHR.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1215.3.</num>
    <text>The LA Director shall provide copies of the annual report to the OCA, the LA Coalition, OAA, OAPIA, and OLA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1215.4.</num>
    <text>Annual reports shall be made available to the public within thirty (30) days of a request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 6348 (June 6, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>