<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-127</num>
  <heading>THIRD PARTY ALLEGATIONS OF DISCRIMINATION (ยง 4-127)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>127.1.</num>
    <text>This section shall apply to general allegations by organizations or other third parties of discrimination in personnel matters within an agency of the District government which are unrelated to an individual complaint of discrimination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>127.2</num>
    <text>127.2 The organization or other third party shall state the allegation with sufficient specificity so that the agency may investigate the allegations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>127.3.</num>
    <text>The agency may require additional specificity as necessary to proceed with its investigation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>127.4.</num>
    <text>The agency shall establish a file on each general allegation, and this file shall contain copies of all material used in making the decision on the allegation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>127.5.</num>
    <text>The agency shall furnish a copy of this file to the party submitting the allegation and shall make it available to the Director for review on request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>127.6.</num>
    <text>The agency shall notify the party submitting the allegation of its decision, including any corrective action taken on the general allegations, and shall furnish to the Director or the City Administrator, on request, a copy of its decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>127.7.</num>
    <text>If the third party disagrees with the agency decision, it may within thirty (30) days after receipt of the decision, request that the Director review it.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>127.8.</num>
    <text>The request shall be in writing and shall set forth, with particularity, the basis for the request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>127.9.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of the request, the Director shall make, or require the agency to make, any additional investigation he or she deems necessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>127.10.</num>
    <text>The Director shall issue a decision on the allegation ordering corrective action, as he or she considers appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>127.11.</num>
    <text>Pursuant to ยง 114.4, either the third-party complainant or the agency may request that the Director reconsider the decision or to reopen the matter.</text>
    <text>Source: Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 9162, 9187-9188 (October 1, 2010).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>