<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-213</num>
  <heading>ATTORNEYS FEES (§ 4-213)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>213.1.</num>
    <text>If the prevailing complainant was represented by a privately retained attorney in any case in which the Commission has found that the respondent engaged in discriminatory acts or practices in violation of the Human Rights Act of 1977, the complainant
      shall be entitled to a reasonable attorney’s fee for the number of hours reasonably expended by the complainant’s attorney on claims upon which the complainant prevailed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>213.2.</num>
    <text>The reasonable hourly rate multiplied by the reasonable number of hours expended upon successful claims is presumed to be the reasonable attorney’s fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>213.3.</num>
    <text>In determining a reasonable hourly rate, the Commission shall consider the hourly rate charged by the prevailing complainant’s attorney for similar legal work in private representations. Where no hourly rate exists, or where otherwise necessary to
      arrive at a reasonable hourly-rate, the Commission may also consider rates charged in the community for similar legal work by attorneys of comparable skill, experience, and reputation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>213.4.</num>
    <text>The prevailing complainant shall bear the burden of demonstrating that an upward adjustment of the presumed reasonable attorney’s fee is necessary to provide fair compensation to the prevailing attorney.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>213.5.</num>
    <text>The unsuccessful respondent shall bear the burden of demonstrating that a downward adjustment of the presumed reasonable attorney’s fee is necessary to avoid a windfall to the prevailing attorney.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>213.6.</num>
    <text>In determining whether an adjustment of the presumed reasonable attorney’s fee is warranted, the Commission shall be guided by Supreme Court decisions interpreting the attorney’s fee provisions of Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, 42 U.S.C.
      § 2000 e-5(k) (1982); the Civil Rights Attorney’s Fees Awards Act of 1976, 42 U.S.C. §1988 (1982); and other similar federal fee-shifting laws.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>213.7.</num>
    <text>The complainant’s attorney’s fee petition shall be filed with the Commission no earlier than twenty (20) days after the issuance of the Commission’s Final Decision and Order and no later than thirty (30) days after the issuance of the Commission’s
      Final Decision and Order. Supplemental petitions may be filed if the Commission’s Final Decision and Order is appealed to the District of Columbia Court of Appeals.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>213.8.</num>
    <text>If a motion for reconsideration is filed, then the complainant shall file his or her attorney’s fee petition no earlier than twenty (20) days after the issuance of the Commission’s Final Decision and Order on Motion for Reconsideration and no later
      than thirty (30) days after the issuance of the Commission’s Final Decision and Order for Reconsideration. Supplemental petitions may be filed as in accordance with § 213.7.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 6259, 6266 (December 14, 1984); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 2804, 2810-11 (March 19, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>