<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-303</num>
  <heading>CONDUCT OF MEETINGS (§ 4-303)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>303.1.</num>
    <text>The Chairperson shall determine the order of business at meetings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>303.2.</num>
    <text>The Chairperson shall prepare an agenda for each regular Commission meeting. Any member of the Commission or member of the public may transmit material to the Chairperson for inclusion on the agenda. This material shall be included on the agenda if
      it is received in the Commission’s office not later than fourteen (14) calendar days prior to the meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>303.3.</num>
    <text>The Chairperson shall distribute the proposed agenda to the Commissioners no later than seven (7) calendar days prior to the date of the meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>303.4.</num>
    <text>Additional items may be placed on the agenda of a regular meeting by majority vote of the Commissioners present, and if applicable notice requirements have been met.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>303.5.</num>
    <text>If neither the Chairperson or the Vice-Chairperson is present at the time designated for any Commission meeting, the Secretary or any other Commissioner shall call the roll and, if six (6) or more of the Commissioners are present, shall call the meeting
      to order, and preside over the election of a Chairperson pro tempore who shall preside until the Chairperson or Vice-Chairperson arrives.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>303.6.</num>
    <text>The Chairperson or Chairperson pro tempore shall decide all questions of order at all meetings, subject to an appeal to the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>303.7.</num>
    <text>Matters not covered by this chapter or other District of Columbia laws or regulations shall be decided in accordance with Robert’s Rules of Order, Newly Revised.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 6720, 6722 (October 7, 1994).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>