<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-603</num>
  <heading>RESIDENCY HIRING (§ 4-603)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>603.1.</num>
    <text>Each franchisee shall make a good faith effort to have its workforce consist of fifty-one percent (51%) District residents.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.2.</num>
    <text>For the purpose of this chapter, a person is a “resident” when he or she establishes and maintains a physical presence in the jurisdiction and intends to remain in that jurisdiction for an indefinite period of time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.3.</num>
    <text>In order to determine the residency of its employees, the franchisee may consider, but not be limited to, documents reflecting the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Home address of an employee and his or her immediate family members;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Mailing address of the employee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Voter registration;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Motor vehicle registration;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Motor vehicle driver permit;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Withholding and payment of individual income taxes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Certified deed or lease or rental agreement for real property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Cancelled checks or receipts for mortgage or rental payments; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Utility bills and payment receipts.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.4.</num>
    <text>Each franchisee shall annually submit to the Office of Human Rights and the Commission on Human Rights a numerical and percentile breakdown of its full-time and part-time employees separately by residency. Each franchisee shall provide written verification
      of all employee tax withholdings which correspond with the employee’s residency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.5.</num>
    <text>The Office of Human Rights and the Commission on Human Rights shall report annually to the Council of the District of Columbia whether all the franchisee’s have reached the goal of hiring fifty-one percent (51%) District residents or are making good
      faith efforts to do so.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 7187, 7190-91 (September 30, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>