<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-711</num>
  <heading>INVESTIGATION (§ 4-711)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>711.1.</num>
    <text>The investigation file shall include the respondent’s Statement of Position, responses to the Office’s Request for Information and Documents, the complainant’s Rebuttal, affidavits of the parties and witnesses, and notes of interviews and fact-finding
      conferences, if appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>711.2.</num>
    <text>The investigation may be made by field visits, written or verbal inquiry, conference, or any other method or combination of methods suitable in the discretion of the Director or staff personnel assigned responsibility for the investigation, subject
      to appropriate guidelines.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>711.3.</num>
    <text>As part of the Office’s investigation, the Office may require the person claiming to be aggrieved to provide a statement which includes the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A statement of each specific harm that the aggrieved party has allegedly suffered and the date on which each harm occurred;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For each harm, a statement specifying the act, policy, or practice which is alleged to be unlawful; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>For each act, policy, or practice alleged to have harmed the aggrieved party, a statement of the facts which led the party to believe that the act, policy, or practice is discriminatory.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>711.4.</num>
    <text>If the investigator concludes that no additional information is necessary or that the investigation is complete, the investigator shall submit his or her findings of fact or investigative report to the Office of General Counsel (OGC) of the Office
      for legal sufficiency. OGC shall then submit a draft LOD to the Director for review, approval, and issuance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 007324 (September 4, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>