<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-722</num>
  <heading>CLASS ACTIONS (§ 4-722)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>722.1.</num>
    <text>A complaint containing a request for class certification may be filed either by an individual complainant or by an organization. Upon receipt of a notarized class action complaint, the Office shall within fifteen (15) days serve on the respondent
      a notice of the complaint and a copy of the complaint. The respondent shall, within ten (10) days of the receipt of the notice, file a written answer to the request for class certification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>722.2.</num>
    <text>Within thirty (30) calendar days of receipt of a notarized class action complaint, the Director shall certify the class only if all of the following are satisfied:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The class is so numerous that joinder of all injured persons is impracticable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Common questions of law and fact exist as to the injured persons;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Claims or defenses of the named complainant(s) are typical of the claims or defenses of the class members;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The named complainant(s) will fairly and adequately represent and protect the interests of the class; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The party opposing the class acted on grounds applicable to the class.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>722.3.</num>
    <text>The decision of the Director to certify a class shall be served on the complainant and the respondent in writing. When the Director denies certification of a class, the complaint shall be considered as an individual action. The time limitations in
      § 712 shall begin on the date that the parties receive notification of the Director’s decision to certify or to deny certification of a class.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>722.4.</num>
    <text>The time limits in § 712 may be adjusted at the discretion of the Director for a complaint certified as a class action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 007324 (September 4, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>