<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-800</num>
  <heading>PURPOSE (ยง 4-800)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>800.1.</num>
    <text>In order to meet the obligations to prohibit discrimination based on gender identity or expression as set forth in the Act, the Office and the Commission adopt this chapter for the following purposes:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>To implement the provisions of the Act regarding discrimination based on gender identity or expression in employment, housing, public accommodations, or educational institutions, including all agencies of the District of Columbia government and
        its contractors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>To provide guidance with regard to the requirements of the law to all employers, housing providers, businesses, organizations, educational institutions, and District government agencies and contractors in seeking compliance with the law;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>To educate the public on the behaviors, conduct, and actions that constitute unlawful discrimination based on gender identity or expression;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>To ensure that transgender people are treated in a manner that is consistent with their identity or expression, rather than according to their presumed or assigned sex or gender; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>To guide the internal processing of complaints filed with the Office or cases heard by the Commission.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is section 301(c) of the Human Rights Act of 1977 (Act), effective December 13, 1977 (D.C. Law 2-38; D.C. Official Code ยง 2-1403.01(c)).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 8751, 8751-52 (October 27, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>