<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-1004</num>
  <heading>NOTICES TO EMPLOYEES (ยง 7-1004)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1004.1.</num>
    <text>The Director shall provide a fact sheet and notice to each recipient of a District of Columbia government contract and government assistance subject to the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1004.2.</num>
    <text>The fact sheet and notice shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Notice of the living wage rate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A summary of requirements under the payment (section 103 of the Act, D.C. Official Code ยง 2-220.03) and record keeping (section 107 of the Act, D.C. Official Code ยง 2-220.07) provisions of the Act;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Information concerning enforcement (section 108, D.C. Official Code ยง 2-220.08) of the Act; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and telephone number of the individual or entity to which complaints of non-compliance with the Act may be made.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1004.3.</num>
    <text>All recipients of District of Columbia government contracts and government assistance subject to the Act, and all subcontractors subject to the Act, shall provide each affiliated employee with the fact sheet provided by the Director no later than
      the onset of performance of the contract or assistance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1004.4.</num>
    <text>All recipients of District of Columbia government contracts and government assistance subject to the Act, and all subcontractors subject to the Act, shall post in a conspicuous place in their places of business, the notice provided by the Director.
      If the contractor or recipient of government assistance subject to the Act, or subcontractor subject to the Act, establishes an onsite office or separate administrative location from which work subject to the Act is directed, a copy of the notice
      required by this subsection shall also be conspicuously posted in the onsite office or remote administrative location.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 2831, 2833 (April 1, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>