<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-105</num>
  <heading>PROGRAM NOTICES OF INITIAL DETERMINATIONS AND ELIGIBILITY DETERMINATIONS (§-105)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>105.1.</num>
    <text>The Program shall issue a notice of determination (NOD) regarding each ID and ED pursuant to this section. An NOD of an ID or ED shall be issued using a standard form developed by the Program that informs the claimant of the right to request reconsideration
      or a hearing before the OHA, whichever is applicable. Sample NODs shall be published on ORM’s website.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.2.</num>
    <text>An NOD shall be issued:</text>
    <text>When accepting a claim for benefits or when modifying, suspending, or terminating benefits;</text>
    <text>When changing the type of benefits a claimant receives;</text>
    <text>When amending an NOD pursuant to § 111 of this chapter;</text>
    <text>When accepting or denying a claim for recurrence of injury pursuant to § 120 of this chapter; or</text>
    <text>When issuing a schedule award pursuant to section 2307 of the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.3.</num>
    <text>An NOD shall contain a narrative description of the rationale for the decision, cite relevant portions of the supporting documentation or claim file, and attach supporting documentation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.4.</num>
    <text>An NOD shall be sent to the claimant&amp;#8217;s last known address by first-class mail, postage prepaid. A certificate of service shall be executed by the Program at the time of mailing. If the claimant is represented by an attorney, a copy of the
      NOD shall be sent to the claimant’s attorney.</text>
    <text>Failure to send a copy of the NOD to the claimant’s attorney shall not constitute a failure to provide notice to the claimant, nor shall it toll any deadlines under this chapter, unless failure to do so unduly prejudices the claimant.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 2307 (May 22, 1981); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 9540 (October 8, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by a Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR
      12224, 12227 (December 24, 2010); repealed and replaced by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8766, 8769 (July 27, 2012).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>