<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-130</num>
  <heading>HEARING PROCEDURES (ยง 7-130)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>130.1.</num>
    <text>Hearings pursuant to section 2324(b) of the Act shall be conducted by an OHA ALJ who has been duly designated by the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>130.2.</num>
    <text>The OHA shall set the time and place of the hearing, and shall mail or deliver in person written notices to the claimant and the Office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia (OAG) at least ten (10) days prior to the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>130.3.</num>
    <text>The hearing shall, when practicable, be set at a time and place convenient for the claimant and the OAG.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>130.4.</num>
    <text>The ALJ may, and when so requested by the claimant or the OAG, afford the parties a prehearing conference to clarify the issues involved in the claim and, when necessary, shall postpone the hearing for this purpose.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>130.5.</num>
    <text>A hearing may be rescheduled or dismissed upon the oral or written request of the claimant and the OAG if the request is received by the ALJ assigned to conduct the hearing at least forty-eight (48) hours prior to the time of the hearing or at the
      option of the ALJ.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>130.6.</num>
    <text>In conducting a hearing, evidence may be presented orally or in the form of written statements and exhibits.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>130.7.</num>
    <text>All evidence available to the claimant and the OAG on the date of the hearing shall be presented to the ALJ at the time of the hearing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>130.8.</num>
    <text>The ALJ, in his or her discretion, may leave the record open for a reasonable period subsequent to the hearing to receive any additional evidence prior to making a decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>130.9.</num>
    <text>The hearing shall be recorded and transcribed. Upon request, a copy of the complete transcript shall be provided to all interested parties at cost as established by the OHA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>130.10.</num>
    <text>If the claimant fails to appear at the time and place set for the hearing and does not, no later than ten (10) days after the time set for the hearing, show good cause for the failure to appear, the official record shall be closed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>130.11.</num>
    <text>The ALJ shall fix the time within which he or she will receive evidence to reflect findings of fact and conclusions of law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>130.12.</num>
    <text>The ALJ shall then issue an order to reverse, modify, affirm, or remand a determination rendered by the claims examiner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>130.13.</num>
    <text>The final decision shall be rendered within thirty (30) days after the hearing ends or the record closes, and then mailed or delivered to the claimant and the OAG at their last known address.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>130.14.</num>
    <text>The final decision shall put the claimant and the OAG on notice of their right to file an appeal from the ALJ&amp;#8217;s final decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8766, 8802 (July 27, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>