<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-1401</num>
  <heading>DEPOSIT AND INVESTMENT OF DEFERRED COMPENSATION (§ 7-1401)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1401.1.</num>
    <text>All amounts of compensation deferred under the Plan, all property and rights purchased with such amounts, and all income attributable to such amounts, property, or rights, shall remain (until made available to the participant or other beneficiary)
      solely the property and rights of the District of Columbia (without being restricted to the provision of benefits under the Plan) subject only to the claims of the District of Columbia&amp;#8217;s general creditors.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1401.2</num>
    <text>1401.2- The Deputy Mayor for Financial Management shall maintain a custodial account(s) for deposit of participant deferrals prior to the transmittal of such deferrals to the investment carriers and shall provide timely notice of such deposits to
      the Plan administrator(s).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1401.3.</num>
    <text>The plan administrator(s) shall instruct the bank maintaining the account(s) to transmit participants&amp;#8217; deferrals and all necessary information to the appropriate investment carrier within a reasonable time after receipt of appropriate deferral
      and investment data from the Deputy Mayor for Financial Management.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1401.4.</num>
    <text>The plan administrator(s) shall forward necessary investment instructions to the investment carriers in order that all deferrals shall be invested in a timely and proper manner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1401.5.</num>
    <text>Neither the Deputy Mayor for Financial Management nor any plan administrator shall deposit any funds pursuant to the Deferred Compensation Act of 1984 in any bank which has not made the certifications regarding loans to and investments in the Republic
      of South Africa and Namibia required by §2 of D.C. Law 5-50, §47-342, D.C. Code, 1981 ed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1401.6.</num>
    <text>No plan administrator shall invest any finds which are in its possession pursuant to the Deferred Compensation Act of 1984 in the stocks, securities and other obligations of any company which is listed as doing business in or with the Republic of
      South Africa or Namibia in the Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order issued pursuant to §5 of D.C. Law 5-50, §47-139, D.C. Code, 1981 ed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>