<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-1599</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 7-1599)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1599.1.</num>
    <text>The terms and phrases used in this title shall have the meaning set forth in this chapter unless the text or context of the particular chapter, section, subsection, or paragraph provides otherwise.</text>
    <text>Bill of Particulars &amp;#8211; A detailed order issued by the Board stating the claim as asserted.</text>
    <text>Board member &amp;#8211; any member serving as a trustee for the District of Columbia Retirement Board.</text>
    <text>Chairman &amp;#8211; the Chairman of the District of Columbia Retirement Board pursuant to §1502.1</text>
    <text>Executive Officer &amp;#8211; A member of the District of Columbia Retirement Board serving as Chairman, Secretary, Treasurer, Parliamentarian, or Sergeant-At-Arms pursuant to § 1502 et seq.</text>
    <text>Farm Team Investment Manager &amp;#8211; An eligible investment management firm qualifying to participate in the Board&amp;#8217;s program targeting 10% of the Boards total assets for allocation to minority-owned investment management firms and investment
      commitments to minority-sponsored private equity partnerships.</text>
    <text>Official acts &amp;#8211; same meaning as set forth in the District of Columbia Code at §2-531 (2001).</text>
    <text>Personally &amp;#038; Substantially &amp;#8211; Pursuant to § 1548 shall mean for trustees direct involvement in any matter in violation of any conflict of interest provisions or for staff involvement in matters that were germane to their position
      descriptions.</text>
    <text>Remuneration &amp;#8211; the rate or level of compensation to be paid an employee for the performance of his or her duties up to and including, but not more than, the maximum authorized and appropriated by law for that position.</text>
    <text>Retirement Funds Assets &amp;#8211; same meaning as set forth in the District of Columbia Code at §§1-712(a) and 1-713(a) (2001).</text>
    <text>Resolution &amp;#8211; an expression of a simple determination, decision or direction of the Board of a special or temporary character, including actions of the Board concerning its internal management and conduct.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 10813 (November 29, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>