<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-1503</num>
  <heading>EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR AND GENERAL COUNSEL (ยง 7-1503)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1503.1.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director shall be the chief administrative officer of the Board and shall be responsible for maintaining records of Board actions, hiring and retention of staff, and other duties assigned by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1503.2.</num>
    <text>The selection, duties and remuneration of the Executive Director shall be recommended to the Board by the Search and Selection Committee. The selection, duties, removal, and remuneration of the Executive Director shall be determined by majority vote
      of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1503.3.</num>
    <text>The outside General Counsel shall have the following responsibilities:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Advising the Board on legal matters as requested by the Chairman, a Committee Chair, the Executive Director, resident General Counsel, or the Board; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Providing adequate representation to the Board in any legal action or proceeding in which the Board becomes involved.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1503.4.</num>
    <text>Individual Board members sued in their capacity as Board members shall be represented by independent counsel, if appropriate, at the Board&amp;#8217;s expense.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1503.5.</num>
    <text>The selection, duties, and remuneration of the General Counsel shall be recommended to the Board by the Search and Selection Committee. The selection, duties, removal, and remuneration of the General Counsel shall be determined by majority vote of
      the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 10794 (November 29, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>