<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-1611</num>
  <heading>UNSOLICITED PROPOSALS (§ 7-1611)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1611.1.</num>
    <text>The Board will review unsolicited proposals and consider the feasibility of their implementation. An unsolicited proposal is one which:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Is innovative or unique;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Is independently originated and developed by the offeror;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Is prepared without the Board’s supervision;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Includes sufficient detail to permit a determination that the proposed product, services or work could benefit the Board’s mission or allow it to meet its responsibilities; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Is not an advance proposal for a known or anticipated Board requirement that can be procured by competitive methods.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1611.2</num>
    <text>1611.2 Unsolicited proposals may be the basis of a competitive procurement if deemed to be in the best interests of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1611.3</num>
    <text>1611.3 An offeror may designate portions of its proposal to be confidential if they include proprietary information or contain sensitive personnel information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1611.4</num>
    <text>1611.4 An unsolicited proposal shall be returned to an offeror, citing reasons, when the proposal:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Does not meet the criteria in § 1612.1; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Is not deemed to be advantageous to the Board.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1611.5</num>
    <text>1611.5 Acceptance of an unsolicited proposal may be recommended to the Executive Director, who may accept or reject it.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 12594, 12604 (December 31, 2010).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>