<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-1801</num>
  <heading>CLASSIFICATION POLICY (ยง 7-1801)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1801.1.</num>
    <text>Market pricing and job ranking are the methods implemented by the Retirement Board for establishing job classification, which involves gathering market data for comparable jobs in relevant markets and assigning jobs to a classification structure based
      on their market value.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1801.2.</num>
    <text>Jobs for which there is no market data available will be assigned to the classification structure based on an overall evaluation of the worth of the job, compared to other jobs assigned to the classification structure based on market data.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1801.3.</num>
    <text>Specially trained and experienced professionals who: (i) are skilled at analyzing market data, (ii) understand relevant job requirements, (iii) are capable of defending decisions made about job classification with appropriate documentary evidence,
      and (iv) have no direct or indirect financial interest that conflicts with the fair, impartial, and objective performance of duties involving job classification shall be retained to assist the Retirement Board in the job classification and reclassification
      process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1801.4.</num>
    <text>To be responsive to changing job requirements and the needs of a highly specialized staff, the Retirement Board shall eliminate obsolete job titles and update position descriptions as needed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1801.5.</num>
    <text>The position description format shall be designed to eliminate any former bias against qualified individuals with or without physical challenges by disclosing essential functions and working conditions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1801.6.</num>
    <text>The position description format shall include the following components:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>General summary of nature and purpose of job;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Primary duties and responsibilities (not intended to be exhaustive);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Competencies (i.e., knowledge, skills and abilities);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Reporting relationships and internal/external contacts; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Working (physical) environment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1801.7.</num>
    <text>The Retirement Board may use an automated system developed for the District government to assist individual staff in supervisory positions when generating and updating position descriptions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9895, 9896 (December 15, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>