<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-1803</num>
  <heading>SALARY ADMINISTRATION (ยง 7-1803)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1803.1.</num>
    <text>The Retirement Board shall determine, by majority vote, the job responsibilities (position description) and the level of compensation for the Executive Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1803.2.</num>
    <text>The Retirement Board shall delegate such authority deemed appropriate to the Executive Director to make compensation decisions for all other staff. Compensation decisions for staff shall be made consistent with applicable laws of the District of Columbia
      (including the Legal Service Act) and, classification and compensation program regulations and policy approved by the Retirement Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1803.3.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director shall develop and administer a job evaluation program which shall include regular review and reevaluation of position descriptions. Position descriptions shall be made available to Retirement Board members, staff, and to others
      upon request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1803.4.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director shall undertake at a minimum, a bi-annual review of compensation surveys of employees in relevant markets and/or organizations having similar jobs in order to recommend adjustments in the salary structure to ensure ongoing competitiveness
      of salary ranges.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1803.5.</num>
    <text>The bi-annual review of compensation surveys shall be conducted by specially trained and experienced professionals who have: (i) experience in market data analysis, (ii) a good working knowledge of the jobs involved, (iii) an obligation to justify
      all compensation decisions with documentary evidence and (iv) no direct or indirect financial interest that conflicts with the fair, impartial, and objective performance of duties required.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1803.6.</num>
    <text>If analysis from the bi-annual review of compensation surveys provides evidence of a change in the salaries paid in relevant markets for similar work, salary ranges for Retirement Board employees shall be adjusted accordingly. Such changes shall be
      implemented consistent with the compensation objectives set forth at section 1802.8.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1803.7.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director shall recommend for Retirement Board approval any adjustment to the salary structure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1803.8.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director shall manage a continuing review of staff compensation to ensure that each staff position is evaluated and assigned to a competitive and equitable salary range that equitably reflects each position&amp;#8217;s responsibilities
      and performance requirements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9898, 9899 (December 15, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>