<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-1800</num>
  <heading>ESTABLISHMENT OF CLASSIFICATION AND COMPENSATION POLICY (ยง 7-1800)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1800.1.</num>
    <text>Authority to establish a new classification and compensation system for staff appointed by the District of Columbia Retirement Board (&amp;#8220;Retirement Board&amp;#8221;) is set forth in Title IX, section 902(d) of the Service Improvement and Fiscal
      Year 2000 Budget Support Act of 1999, D.C. Law 13-38 (the &amp;#8220;Retirement Board Amendment Act of 1999&amp;#8243;), and the District of Columbia Retirement Reform Act, as amended (the &amp;#8220;Reform Act&amp;#8221;), effective November 17,
      1979 (Pub. L. 96-122, 93 Stat. 866). D.C. Code ยง 1-711(e)</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1800.2.</num>
    <text>Authority to convert Retirement Board staff attorneys who meet the qualifications for entry into the Legal Service and the Senior Executive Attorney Service, to implement a separate competitive salary structure, and to establish a performance management
      system for attorneys in the Legal Service and the Senior Executive Attorney Service employed by the Retirement Board is set forth in the Legal Service Establishment Act (&amp;#8220;Legal Service Act&amp;#8221;) of 1999, (D.C. Code ยง 1-609.51 et.
      seq.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1800.3.</num>
    <text>The Retirement Board&amp;#8217;s principal mission, as derived from the findings and purpose section of the Reform Act (D.C. Code&amp;#8217; 1-701), is to manage the assets of the D.C. Police Officers&amp;#8217; and Fire Fighters&amp;#8217; Retirement
      Fund, and the D.C. Teachers&amp;#8217; Retirement Fund, (collectively the &amp;#8220;Funds&amp;#8221;) on an actuarially sound basis in order to provide proper financing for the benefits to which the District&amp;#8217;s retired police officers,
      fire fighters and teachers are entitled.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1800.4.</num>
    <text>Pursuant to authority cited in sections 1800.1 and 1800.2 above, the Retirement Board hereby establishes policy and program regulations for a classification and compensation system for staff appointed by the Retirement Board, a separate competitive
      salary structure, and a performance management system for attorneys eligible for entry in the Legal Service and Senior Executive Attorney Service employed by the Retirement Board, as required by the Legal Service Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1800.5.</num>
    <text>The Retirement Board reserves the right to amend any part of this classification and compensation policy and program regulation based upon, without limitation, changes in fiscal condition, changes in operating requirements, and changes in applicable
      law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9894, 9895 (December 15, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>