<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-204</num>
  <heading>EMPLOYER RECORDS OF INJURIES (ยง 7-204)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>204.1.</num>
    <text>Under ยง32 of the Act [ยง36-331, D.C. Code, 1981 ed.], each employer shall maintain a record of all injuries to its employees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>204.2.</num>
    <text>Employer records of injuries shall be available for inspection by a representative of the Office during an employer&amp;#8217;s regular business hours at the employer&amp;#8217;s place of business.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>204.3.</num>
    <text>Employer records of injuries shall be adequate if they contain the information set forth in ยง203.4 of this Chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>204.4.</num>
    <text>No later than December 1st of each year, each insurer and self insured employer shall provide to the Office, a report from the previous fiscal year that shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>the total number of cases;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>the total number of lost time cases;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>the number of medical only cases;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>the number of cases where no compensation was paid;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>the number of temporary and permanent partial cases where more than 500 weeks of benefits are paid;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>the number of permanent partial disability scheduled awards cases;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>the number of permanent partial disability nonscheduled awards cases;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>the number of permanent total disability cases;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>the number of temporary total disability cases;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>the number of cases in which claimant was represented by an attorney, if known.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>total attorney fees paid;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>the number of cases controverted;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>any other information that the Office may require.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 6454 (August 11, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>