<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-2499</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 7-2499)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2499.1.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this chapter, the following definitions shall apply and have the meaning ascribed:</text>
    <text>“Chief” &amp;#8211; The Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
    <text>“Critical Incident” &amp;#8211; An incident where a member suffers a psychiatric injury and:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text></text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>the member took direct, authorized police action and the member was seriously wounded, or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>the member was the victim of an assault or other crime that could have resulted in the member being seriously wounded and the assault or other crime was related to that member&amp;#8217;s status as a police officer; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>the member took direct, authorized police action and that action directly caused the serious or fatal wounding of another individual.</text>
    </level>
    <text>“Department” &amp;#8211; The Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
    <text>“Director” &amp;#8211; The director of medical services for the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
    <text>“Limited duty” &amp;#8211; A temporary status for members who, because of injury or other temporary medical disability, are not able to perform the full range of duties, but are certified by a Police and Fire Clinic physician as being capable of effectively
      performing certain types of work within the department.</text>
    <text>“Maximum Medical Improvement” &amp;#8211; Reasonable medical probability that no further material recovery from or lasting improvement to an injury can reasonably be expected.</text>
    <text>“Member” &amp;#8211; A sworn employee of the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
    <text>“Performance of Duty” &amp;#8211; An injury or illness that arises out of and in the course of a member performing one or more of the essential tasks of his or her duties as a member of the Metropolitan Police Department. Psychiatric injuries shall
      only be deemed &amp;#8220;performance of duty&amp;#8221; if they are the result of a &amp;#8220;critical incident.&amp;#8221;</text>
    <text>Comments on these proposed amendments should be submitted, in writing, to Terrence D. Ryan, General Counsel, Metropolitan Police Department, Room 4125, 300 Indiana Avenue NW, Washington, D.C. 20001, within thirty (30) days of the date of the publication
      of this notice in the D.C. Register. Additional copies of these proposed amendments are available from the above address.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 6454 (July 8, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>