<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-2403</num>
  <heading>NON-PERFORMANCE-OF-DUTY ILLNESSES AND INJURIES (ยง 7-2403)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2403.1.</num>
    <text>If the Director, in consultation with Police and Fire Clinic physicians, determines that a member can neither perform the full range of duties nor work in a limited duty status due to a non-performance-of-duty injury or illness, the member shall be
      entitled to chargeable medical leave to the extent the member has leave in his or her sick leave and annual leave accounts, and in accordance with rules established by the Mayor under the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel
      Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-601 et seq.), and the District of Columbia Family and Medical Leave Act of 1990, effective October 3, 1990 (D.C. Law 8-181; D.C. Official Code ยง 32-501 et seq.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2403.2.</num>
    <text>If at any time the Director, in consultation with Police and Fire Clinic physicians, determines that a member who has sustained a non-performance-of-duty injury or illness will not be able to perform the full range of duties after achieving maximum
      medical improvement, the Director shall recommend the member for disability retirement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2403.3.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection 2403.4, and regardless of whether the prognosis is that the member who has sustained a non-performance-of-duty injury or illness will be able to perform a full range of duties after achieving maximum medical improvement,
      the Director shall process for disability retirement those Metropolitan Police Department members who spend all or part of 172 cumulative work days in a less-than-full-duty status over any 2-year period as a result of any one nonperformance-of-duty
      injury or illness, including any complications relating to the injury or illness as determined by the Director in consultation with Police and Fire Clinic physicians.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2403.4.</num>
    <text>The provisions of subsections 2403.2 and 2403.3 of this section shall not apply to members who are unable to perform a full range of duties as a result of pregnancy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 6451, 6452 (July 8, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>