<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-2519</num>
  <heading>ANNUAL MEDICAL EXAMINATION OF RETIRED ANNUITANT (ยง 7-2519)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2519.1.</num>
    <text>Each annuitant retired for disability shall appear before the Board of Surgeons, or before a medical specialist approved by the Board of Surgeons, at least once every year until he or she shall have reached the age of fifty (50) years, for a medical
      examination of the disability for which he or she was retired, to determine his or her current physical and/or mental condition, unless excused from the examination by order of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2519.2.</num>
    <text>The Board shall receive all medical and psychiatric reports through and from the Board of Surgeons and, upon review of the reports and recommendations made by the Board of Surgeons, determine the current status of the annuitant&amp;#8217;s disability
      and make a decision as to the disposition of the case.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2519.3.</num>
    <text>The Board may, in its discretion and in order to assist it in making a fair and just determination, require any disabled annuitant to report to the Board of Surgeons or to an outside medical consultant for an examination of the disability for which
      he or she was retired. Expenses incurred by an annuitant reporting to an outside consultant at the direction of the Board shall not-be borne by the annuitant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2519.4.</num>
    <text>In making the necessary determination with regard to the continuation of retirement eligibility of an annuitant the Board shall consider the written opinion and recommendation submitted to it by the Board of Surgeons concerning the annuitant&amp;#8217;s
      current physical and mental condition together with any other pertinent reports or records.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2519.5.</num>
    <text>An annuitant may not be required to appear before the Board in person but may be so required at the Board&amp;#8217;s discretion.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2519.6.</num>
    <text>If the Board finds there is sufficient evidence that the annuitant has recovered from the disability for which he or she retired, then the annuitant may be required to appear before the Board for a hearing. The expenses incurred by the appearance
      shall be borne by the annuitant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>