<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-256</num>
  <heading>OFFICE OF THE CLERK (ยง 7-256)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>256.1.</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided by these regulations, the filing and submission of Applications for Review, pleadings, motions and all other written communications with the Board shall be addressed to Clerk of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>256.2.</num>
    <text>Ex parte communications between any party and a Member of the Board regarding an Application for Review are strictly prohibited.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>256.3.</num>
    <text>The Office of the Clerk of the Board shall be open from 8:30 a.m. to 5:00 p.m. on all days except Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays, for the purpose of receiving Applications for Review and such other pleadings, motions and papers as are pertinent
      to any matter before the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>256.4.</num>
    <text>All requests to visit the Clerk&amp;#8217;s Office, for purposes other than the submission of documents as outlined in section 256.3, shall be submitted in writing. The Clerk of the Board shall schedule an appointment to be held at a mutually convenient
      time no later than five (5) working days from the date of receipt of the party&amp;#8217;s written request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>256.5.</num>
    <text>A docket of all proceedings shall be maintained by the Board. A party to an appeal (and his or her representative) shall have access to the Board&amp;#8217;s case file pertaining to such appeal after making an appointment with the Office of the Clerk.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>256.6.</num>
    <text>A party to an appeal, after contacting the Clerk of the Board in accordance with section 256.4, may make one copy of the documents contained in the Board&amp;#8217;s case file (excluding the hearing transcript) at the party&amp;#8217;s expense, at
      a reasonable rate set by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>256.7.</num>
    <text>The Clerk&amp;#8217;s Office shall serve the final decision of the Compensation Review Board in the following manner:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Hand deliver the document to the authorized representative of each party and secure a signature of the recipient; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Mail the document by certified or registered mail, return receipt requested, to the last known record address of the representative of each party; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Retain a copy for the official record.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Where a party is not represented, the Clerk&amp;#8217;s Office shall serve a copy of the final decision on the party.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 8405 (September 9, 2005) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 11093 (December 23, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>