<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-268</num>
  <heading>RECONSIDERATION (ยง 7-268)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>268.1.</num>
    <text>Any party may, within ten (10) calendar days from the date shown on the certificate of service of the Decision and Order of the Board or of any order issued by the Board, file a request for reconsideration thereof with the Clerk of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>268.2.</num>
    <text>A reconsideration request shall be in writing, in the form of a motion, and shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>state the supporting rationale for the request;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>include any material pertinent to the request;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>include an original and three copies of the request; and,</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>be served on all other parties.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>268.3.</num>
    <text>Any opposition to the motion for reconsideration shall be filed with the Board within five (5) calendar days of the date of service of said motion.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>268.4.</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise directed by the Chief Administrative Appeals Judge, the Review Panel assigned to the case shall review and rule on the motion for reconsideration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>268.5.</num>
    <text>Reconsideration of a Decision and Order shall require the affirmative vote of at least two members of the Review Panel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>268.6.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the filing of a request for reconsideration, the Chief Administrative Appeals Judge may, sua sponte, order reconsideration en banc of a Review Panel Decision and Order within ten (10) days of any Review Panel decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 8405 (September 9, 2005) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 11093 (December 23, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>