<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-314</num>
  <heading>REFUSAL OF TRAIUING REEMPLOYMENT SERVICES (ยง 7-314)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>314.1.</num>
    <text>In accordance with ยง10(e) of the Act, the Director shall hold ineligible for benefits any otherwise eligible individual who fails without good cause to attend a training or retraining course; provided, that the course is recommended by the Director
      and the course is available at public expense.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>314.2.</num>
    <text>The Director shall hold ineligible for benefits any otherwise eligible individual who fails without good cause to participate in job counselling or other reemployment services; provided, that such individual has been identified as in need of such
      counselling or reemployment services through a profiling system established by the Director to identify individuals who will be likely to exhaust their regular benefits.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>314.3.</num>
    <text>The following shall not constitute good cause for failure to attend training or for refusal to participate in job counselling or other reemployment services.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Refusal to attend at any time without strong compelling reason and excuse;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Personal inconvenience;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Personal dislike of curricula or teachers; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Personal dislike of job counselling, reemployment services, or counsellor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Disbarment from recommended training, job counselling, or reemployment services as a result of improper conduct or action on the part of a claimant.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>314.4.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, good cause for failure to attend training or participate in job counselling or other reemployment services includes, but is not limited to, the circumstances set forth in ยง316.4.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>314.5.</num>
    <text>The ineligibility from benefits for refusal of training or refusal to participate in job counselling or other reemployment services shall be imposed with respect to any week in which the failure occurred.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 43 DCR 1470 (March 22, 1996).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>