<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-3299</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 7-3299)
    <text>When used in this Chapter, the term:</text>
    <text>Act – means the Accrued Safe and Sick Leave Act of 2008, effective May 13,008 (D.C. Law 17-152; D.C. Official Code § 32-131.01 et seq.).</text>
    <text>Day – means the length of the employee’s customary work day or work shift.</text>
    <text>Director – means the Director of the District of Columbia Department ofmployment Services, or the Director’s designee.</text>
    <text>Discharge –means the involuntary severing of the employment relationship byhe employer.</text>
    <text>Domestic violence – means an intra-family offense as defined in D.C. Officialode § 16-1001(8).</text>
    <text>Emergency – means an unexpected or unforeseen event or events which render ann employee unable to contact the employer or communicate the need to accesseave accrued under the Act to the Employer as required by Sec. 3206.1, Sec.206.2 or Sec. 3206.3.
      An emergency shall include a personal illness, illness of family member, or an act of domestic violence or sexual abuse as defined inhe Act which requires the employee to seek medical treatment or law enforcementssistance for the employee or other
      persons covered by the Act.</text>
    <text>Employee – means an individual who has been employed by the same employer fort least one (1) year without a break in service except for regular holiday,ick, or personal leave granted by the employer and who has worked at least onehousand (1,000) hours
      of service with such employer during the previous2-month period. The term “employee” also includes an individual who meetshe foregoing criteria and who is employed by the employer in more than oneocation and spends more than fifty percent (50%)
      of his or her working time foris or her employer in the District of Columbia or whose employment is based inhe District of Columbia and who regularly spends a substantial part of his orer time working for the employer in the District of Columbia
      and does not spendore than fifty percent (50%) of his or her work-time working for the employern any particular state. The term “employee” shall not include: (1) anndependent contractor, (2) a student, (3) health care workers who choose toarticipate
      in a premium pay program, or (4) restaurant wait staff andartenders who work for a combination of wages and tips.</text>
    <text>Employer – means (including a for-profit or not-for-profit firm, partnership,roprietorship, sole proprietorship, limited liability company, association ororporation), or any receiver or trustee of such entity (including the legalepresentative of a
      deceased individual or receiver or trustee of anndividual), who employs an employee. The term “employer” includes theistrict of Columbia government.</text>
    <text>Non-covered employment position — means (1) an independent contractor, (2) atudent, (3) a health care worker who choose to participate in a premium payrogram, or (4) restaurant wait staff and bartenders who work for a combinationf wages and tips.</text>
    <text>Family member — means:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A spouse, including the person identified by an employee as his or heromestic partner, as defined in section 2(3) of the Health Care Benefitsxpansion Act of 1992, effective June 11, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-114; D.C. Officialode § 32-701(3));</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The parents of a spouse;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Children (including step-children, foster children, and grandchildren);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The spouses of children (including step-children, foster children, andrandchildren);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Parents (including step-parents);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Brothers and sisters (including step-brothers and sisters and half-brothersnd sisters);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The spouses of brothers and sisters (including step-brothers and sisters andalf-brothers and sisters);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>A child who lives with the employee and for whom the employee permanentlyssumes and discharges parental responsibility; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>A person with whom the employee shares or has shared, for not less than thereceding of twelve (12) months a mutual residence and with whom the employeeaintains a committed relationship, as defined in section 2(1) of the Healthare Benefits Expansion
        Act of 1992, effective June 11, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-114;.C. Official Code §32-701(1)).</text>
    </level>
    <text>Paid leave – means accrued hours of paid leave provided by an employer for usey an employee in hourly increments during an absence from work for any of theeasons specified in section 3(b) of the Act, for which the employee is paid athe same rate as
      if the employee were working.</text>
    <text>Premium pay program – means a plan offered by an employer by which an employeeay voluntarily elect to receive additional pay in lieu of benefits.</text>
    <text>Restaurant wait staff and bartenders-means waiters, waitresses, counterersonnel who serve customers, bus persons, server helpers, service bartendersnd barbacks.</text>
    <text>Sexual abuse – means an offense described in the Anti-Sexual Abuse Act of994, effective May 23, 1995 (D.C. Law 10-257; D.C. Official Code § 22-3001 eteq.).</text>
    <text>Student – means a person employed by an employer who:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>(A) Is a full-time student as defined by an accredited institution of higherducation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Is employed by the institution at which the student is enrolled;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Is employed for less than 25 hours per week (the number of hours beingetermined based on the standard or usual work week of the employee); and,</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Does not replace an employee covered by the Act; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Is employed as part of the Year Round Program for Youth as established byhe Department of Employment Services.</text>
    </level>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 5231, 5240 (June 18, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>