<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-399</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 7-399)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>399.1.</num>
    <text>The terms defined in the Act shall have the meanings set forth in the Act. In addition, when used in the Act or this chapter, the following words defined in this section shall have the meaning ascribed:</text>
    <text>Act &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act, as amended, 49 Stat. 946 (1935), ยง46-301, et seq., D.C. Code, 1981 ed.</text>
    <text>Active Progress &amp;#8211; the action being taken toward the settlement of a labor dispute, including but not limited to, negotiating, picketing, and court proceedings.</text>
    <text>Claim &amp;#8211; an application by a claimant for the determination of eligibility for benefits, benefit amount, and duration of benefits which certifies to the beginning date of a period of unemployment.</text>
    <text>Claimant &amp;#8211; an individual who files a claim for unemployment compensation.</text>
    <text>Continued Claim &amp;#8211; a week of unemployment for which waiting period credit or payment of compensation is requested.</text>
    <text>Deductible Retirement Pension or Annunity &amp;#8211; any amount received or applied for with respect to any week after March 31, 1980, as a retirement pension or annunity under a public or private retirement plan including any such sum under Title
      II of the Social Security Act.</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; the Director of the District of Columbia Department of Employment Services or his or her designee.</text>
    <text>Employer&amp;#8217;s Reserve &amp;#8211; an employer&amp;#8217;s cumulative contributions for taxable wages subsequent to May 31, 1939, less the cumulative benefits since July 1, 1939, as chargeable to his or her experience rating account through
      the computation date of each year.</text>
    <text>Experience Rating Account &amp;#8211; the account established and maintained by the Director pursuant to ยง3(c)(1) of the Act which shows each employer&amp;#8217;s cumulative contributions, cumulative benefit charges, average annual payroll, reserve,
      reserve ratio, and contribution rate for each calendar year or part thereof.</text>
    <text>Initial Claim &amp;#8211; the first claim filed in benefit year to request a determination of entitlement to and eligibility for compensation which results in an appealable determination.</text>
    <text>Interested Party &amp;#8211; a claimant or an employer whose statutory rights or obligations pursuant to administration of the Act may be affected by the outcome or disposition of a determination, redetermination, or decision.</text>
    <text>Labor Dispute &amp;#8211; Any controversy concerning terms, tenure or conditions of employment or concerning the association or representation of persons in negotiating, fixing, maintaining, changing, or seeking to arrange terms or conditions of employment,
      regardless of whether the disputants stand in the proximate relation of employer and employee.</text>
    <text>Lockout &amp;#8211; the withholding of otherwise available work by an employer.</text>
    <text>Month &amp;#8211; (a) with respect to employees paid on a weekly basis, that period covered by all the weeks which commence within the calendar month or (b) with respect to employees paid on any basis except a weekly basis, a calendar month.</text>
    <text>Reserve Ratio &amp;#8211; the employers reserve in relation to his or her average annual payroll.</text>
    <text>Severance Pay &amp;#8211; a payment in addition to any back wages due made by an employer to an employee whose employment is permanently terminated by the employer.</text>
    <text>Waiting Period &amp;#8211; the first week of eligibility within a benefit year for which compensation is not payable in accordance with ยง9(e) of the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 2375(April 1, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>