<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-406</num>
  <heading>YES GENERAL PLAN DESCRIPTION (ยง 7-406)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>406.1.</num>
    <text>The Director shall submit a YES General Plan to the Mayor. The Mayor may conditionally approved the Plan subject to final resolutions of any comments received during the comment and publication period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>406.2.</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall approve or disapprove the YES General Plan using the procedures set forth in ยง407.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>406.3.</num>
    <text>The YES General Plan shall consist of the following items, including but not limited to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Approval Request Letter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Narrative description which contains the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A statement of the problem and objectives;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Special conditions affecting the eligible population and labor market;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A statement of results and benefits accruing to participants; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A description of the preferred worksite including a copy of a representative worksite agreement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Descriptions of training, work experience and orientation component for participants, worksite supervisors and other worksite personnel, and administrative staff with respect to their responsibilities under the Plan;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Methods used to recruit, select, and verify eligibility of YES participants;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Description of special components, e.g., Vocational Exploration Program (VEP), special skills development activities, etc.; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Management and Administration as follows:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Organizational structure, personnel requirements, and staff responsibilities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Program monitoring and evaluation process;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Budget allocations, requisite payment schedule, contracted services and other funding requirements; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Submission of Interim and Final Reports to the Mayor.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>