<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-499</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 7-499)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>499.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Academic Credit &amp;#8211; for education, training or work experience applicable toward a secondary school diploma, post secondary degree or accredited certificate of completion consistent with applicable laws, policies, and requirements of an accredited
      educational agency or institution.</text>
    <text>Act &amp;#8211; Youth Employment Act of 1979 (D.C. Act 3-146) approved November 9, 1979.</text>
    <text>Artificial Barriers to Employment &amp;#8211; limitations (age, sex, race, national origin, parental status, credential requirements, criminal record, lack of child care, physical or mental status and absence of part-time or alternative working patterns/schedules)
      in hiring, firing, promotion, licensing, and conditions or employment which are not directly related to an individual&amp;#8217;s fitness or ability to perform the tasks by the job.</text>
    <text>Community Based Organization &amp;#8211; a private non-profit organization which is representative of the community or a significant segment of a community, and which the Department, a recipient or a sub-recipient pays for property, services, supplies,
      materials or equipment.</text>
    <text>Contract &amp;#8211; a procurement instrument by which the department, a recipient, or a sub-recipient pays for property, services supplies, materials or equipment.</text>
    <text>Contractor &amp;#8211; any person, corporation, partnership, public agency, or other entity which enters into a contract with the DES, a recipient or sub-recipient under the Act.</text>
    <text>Department &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia Department of Employment Services (DOES), including its agencies and organizational units.</text>
    <text>Employing Agency &amp;#8211; any public or private profit or non-profit employer which employs youth participants and which establishes and maintains the standards applicable to those participants covering such areas as wages rates, fringe benefits,
      job titles, and employment status.</text>
    <text>Entry Level &amp;#8211; the lowest position in any promotional line, as defined locally by D.C. Personnel regulations, past practices, and collective bargaining agreements.</text>
    <text>Family &amp;#8211; one (1) or more persons living in a single residence who are related to each other by blood, marriage or adoption. A step-child or a step-parent shall be considered to be related by marriage. The following description applies:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>For purposes of this chapter, one (1) or more persons not living in single residence but who were claimed as a dependent on another person&amp;#8217;s Federal Income Tax return for the previous year shall be presumed, unless otherwise demonstrated
        part of the other person&amp;#8217;s family; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Whether living in the residence or not, a handicapped individual who is sixteen (16) years of age or older may be considered a family of one (1) when applying for programs under the Act.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Handicapped Individual &amp;#8211; any person who has a physical or mental disability which constitutes a substantial barrier to employment and can benefit from YES Services.</text>
    <text>In-school youth &amp;#8211; a person fourteen (14) to twenty-one (21) who meets the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Is currently enrolled full-time in and attending a secondary, trade, technical, vocational school or junior or community college or is scheduled to attend full-time the next regularly scheduled quarter or semester of any of these schools;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Has not completed high school and is scheduled to attend or is attending, on a full-time basis, a program leading to a secondary school diploma or its equivalent. Full-time may be defined by the requirements of the agency administering the program.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Participant &amp;#8211; an individual who is as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Declared eligible upon intake; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Receiving employment, training or services (except post-termination services) funded under the Act following intake.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Placement &amp;#8211; the act of securing employment for or by a participant.</text>
    <text>Public Assistance &amp;#8211; Federal, State or Local Government cash payments for which eligibility is determined by a need or income test.</text>
    <text>Recipient &amp;#8211; person, firm, organization, private for profit or non-profit enterprise, which receives funds from the Department and YES to perform substantive work or provide services under the Act (employment, training, supportive services,
      etc.).</text>
    <text>YES &amp;#8211; Youth Employment for the Summer, Office of the District of Columbia Department of Employment Services (DC-DOES), authorized to implement the provisions of the Youth Employment Act of 1979, ยง2(a)(1) Summer Youth Jobs Programs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>