<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-604</num>
  <heading>REIMBURSEMENT (ยง 7-604)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>604.1.</num>
    <text>Participating employers shall be reimbursed as an incentive an average of fifty percent (50%) of the participant-employee&amp;#8217;s entrance level wage rate (exclusive of fringe benefits, overtime, premium pay and other labor costs) for a period
      of up to fifty-two (52) weeks of actual participant employment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>604.2.</num>
    <text>Employers shall provide for any periodic or other wage increase from their own funds.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>604.3.</num>
    <text>The Director and interested employers may, where appropriate, experiment with the following reimbursements schedule:</text>
    <text>Employment Period Percent of Wages</text>
    <text>1st 13 weeks 25%</text>
    <text>2nd 13 weeks 40%</text>
    <text>3rd 13 weeks 60%</text>
    <text>4th 13 weeks 75%</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>604.4.</num>
    <text>Participants-Employees in on-the-job training shall be compensated by the employer at reasonable rates, and shall consider such factors as industry and participant skills.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>604.5.</num>
    <text>Rates shall be in conformity with all federal and local laws and in no event shall the wage rate be less than the higher of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The minimum wage rate specified in ยง8(a)(1) of the Fair Labor Standards Act; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The minimum wage rates prescribed by applicable state or District laws and regulations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>604.6.</num>
    <text>Subject to legislative authorization, the Director may reimburse public agencies for one hundred percent (100%) of a participant&amp;#8217;s wage rate (exclusive of fringes, overtime premium pay, periodic or other wage increases, or other labor costs)
      for a period of up to fifty-two (52) weeks of actual participant employment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>