<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>9-135</num>
  <heading>ANNUAL REPORT OF WITHHOLDING (ยง 9-135)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>135.1.</num>
    <text>Duplicate copies of all withholding statements (Form D-2) or approved substitute withholding statements shall be sent to the District by each employer with the Form D-1 that is due on the last day of January; or with the employer&amp;#8217;s final
      return, if submitted before the end of the calendar year. For years beginning January 1, 1982 and thereafter, withholding statements shall be submitted with Form FR-9008.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>135.2.</num>
    <text>Form D-1 shall be accompanied by a list (in the form of an adding machine tape or a written itemization) setting forth the items of tax withheld at source as shown by the withholding statements (Form D-2).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>135.3.</num>
    <text>If an employer&amp;#8217;s total payroll consists of a number of separate units or establishments, the duplicate Forms D-2 may be assembled accordingly and a separate list or tape submitted for each unit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>135.4.</num>
    <text>If separate lists or tapes are submitted in accordance with ยง 135.3, a summary list or tape shall be submitted. The total of the summary list or tape shall agree with the corresponding entry made on Form D-1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>135.5.</num>
    <text>If the number of the duplicate statements is large, the statements may be forwarded in packages of convenient size.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>135.6.</num>
    <text>If statements are forwarded in packages under ยง 135.5, the packages shall be identified with the name of the employer and consecutively numbered. The number of packages shall be indicated immediately after the employer&amp;#8217;s name on Form D-1.
      Form D-1 and the remittance shall be filed in the usual manner, accompanied by a brief statement that Forms D-2 are in separate packages.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order 56-1431 effective July 24, 1956, 16 DCRR ยง 310.8; as amended by Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order 71-6 effective February 25, 1971, 17 DCR 567 (March 8, 1971); by Final Rulemaking published at 30 DCR 1453, 1454 (April
        1, 1983); and by Final Rulemaking published at 32 DCR 1453 (March 8, 1985).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>