<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>9-150</num>
  <heading>OVERPAYMENT OF TAX AND REFUND SET-OFFS (§ 9-150)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>150.1.</num>
    <text>If it is determined by the Deputy Chief Financial Officer that there has been an overpayment of any tax (whether as deficiency or otherwise), interest shall be allowed and paid upon that overpayment of tax at the rate of six per cent (6%) per annum
      from the date the overpayment was paid until the date of refund, except as otherwise provided in this section or the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.2.</num>
    <text>That part of any overpayment which was not assessed and paid as a deficiency or as additional tax shall bear interest only from the date on which a claim for refund was filed:</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.3.</num>
    <text>Interest on overpayments resulting from excessive withholding, excessive payments on declarations, or both, shall in no event begin to accrue prior to ninety (90) days after the overpayment is made or after the date of the filing of a final return,
      whichever is later.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.4.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, any tax deducted and withheld during any calendar year and any amounts paid except as provided for in § 149.2 prior to the fifteenth (15th) day of the fourth (4th) month after the close of the taxable year as estimated
      tax shall be deemed to have been paid on the fifteenth (15th) day of the fourth (4th) month following the close of the taxable year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.5.</num>
    <text>No interest may be paid unless a properly completed claim for refund is filed with the Deputy Chief Financial Officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.6.</num>
    <text>If the final return filed by an individual for the taxable year shows an overpayment resulting from excessive withholding or excessive payments on declarations, or both, an automatic refund of the overpayment shall be made; Provided, that all of the
      withholding statements supporting all of the withholding taxes claimed as a credit is submitted with the final income tax return. No interest on overpayments shall be allowed or paid on refunds made in this manner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.7.</num>
    <text>If a final return shows an overpayment of less than two dollars ($ 2), it shall be refunded only upon application to the Deputy Chief Financial Officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.8.</num>
    <text>No refund of estimated tax previously paid shall be made except upon the filing of a final income tax return on Form D-40 after the close of the taxable year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.9.</num>
    <text>Each claim for refund shall be in writing, under oath, and shall state the specific grounds upon which the claim is based.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.10.</num>
    <text>Forms to be used in filing a claim for refund may be obtained from the Deputy Chief Financial Officer, upon request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.11.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provisions of this section, a refund due on the return of an individual may be intercepted by the Deputy Chief Financial Officer, Office of Tax and Revenue in accordance with the provisions of § 11(a) of Title XII of the
      Act (D.C. Code § 47-1812(a)(4)(4a)) as amended.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.12.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term &amp;#8220;set-off&amp;#8221; shall mean the amount of a District of Columbia income tax refund intercepted from an individual who is in default on a National Direct Student Loan or a Nursing Student Loan
      or who is in arrears on court-ordered child support payments, or any combination thereof.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.13.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the phrase, &amp;#8220;affected agency&amp;#8221; means the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Department of Human Services for an arrearage of court-ordered child support payments; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The University of the District of Columbia for a default of a National Direct Student Loan or a Nursing Student Loan, or both.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.14.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the phrase &amp;#8220;authorized official&amp;#8221; shall mean, as it applies to the affected agency, the Deputy Director of the Department of Human Services or the Vice President of the Financial Management Division
      of the University of District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.15.</num>
    <text>The interception of a refund requested by married persons filing on a combined separate form (Columns A and B of Form D-40) shall be limited to the net refund attributable to the spouse who has a set-off. The following example illustrate the application
      of § 150.15:</text>
    <text>Example A:</text>
    <text>Husband</text>
    <text>(Col A)</text>
    <text>Refund</text>
    <text>$ 200.00</text>
    <text>Wife</text>
    <text>(Col. B)</text>
    <text>Refund</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>100.00</num>
    <text>100.00</text>
    <text>Total Refund</text>
    <text>$ 300.00</text>
    <text>The husband has a set-off. He is in arrears of child-support payments. Only two hundred dollars ($ 200.00) is subject to interception.</text>
    <text>Example B:</text>
    <text>Husband</text>
    <text>(Col. A)</text>
    <text>Refund</text>
    <text>$ 200.00</text>
    <text>Wife</text>
    <text>(Col. B)</text>
    <text>Balance</text>
    <text>$ 250.00</text>
    <text>Net Balance Due</text>
    <text>$ 50.00</text>
    <text>The husband is in arrears of child-support payments, a set-off, but no refund is due. Therefore, no interception can be made.</text>
    <text>Example C:</text>
    <text>Husband</text>
    <text>(Col. A)</text>
    <text>Balance Due</text>
    <text>$ 100.00</text>
    <text>Wife</text>
    <text>(Col. B)</text>
    <text>Refund</text>
    <text>$ 150.00</text>
    <text>Net Balance Due</text>
    <text>$ 50.00</text>
    <text>The wife is in default under the federal student loan program. A set-off is made. Although she computes a refund of one hundred and fifty dollars ($ 150.00), only the net refund of fifty dollars ($ 50) is subject to interception.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.16.</num>
    <text>The net refund on a joint return (where only Column B of Form D-40 is completed) shall be subject to interception.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.17.</num>
    <text>If the taxpayer contends that the intercepted refund is attributable in part to a spouse not subject to the set-off, the taxpayer shall submit a protest together with an amended Form D-40X utilizing the combined-separate filing status (Form D-40,
      Columns A and B) in accordance with the provisions of § 150.20 within the thirty (30) day period specified in paragraph (6) of § 11(a) of Title XII of the Act (D.C. Code § 47-1812.11(a)(5) and (6)).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.18.</num>
    <text>The Bureau of Paternity and Child Support Enforcement, Department of Human Services (hereinafter the &amp;#8220;Bureau&amp;#8221;) or the Office of Financial Management of the University of the District of Columbia (hereinafter the &amp;#8220;Division&amp;#8221;)
      shall afford any taxpayer aggrieved by the mandate of the Act the opportunity for a hearing to determine the existence and the amount of a child-support or loan default obligation within thirty (30) days of receipt of the notice of intent to intercept
      a part or all of the District tax refund.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.19.</num>
    <text>All taxpayer requests for a hearing under § 150.17 shall be made through the authorized official named in § 150.14, or his or her designee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.20.</num>
    <text>The aggrieved taxapayer&amp;#8217;s protest shall be limited to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The existence or amount of the offset;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The division of a joint return; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The existence of new facts, issues, or evidence not previously decided.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.21.</num>
    <text>Protests concerning the existence or amount of the set-off, or the existence of new facts, issues, or evidence not previously decided shall be reviewed by the affected agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.22.</num>
    <text>Protests concerning the apportionment of joint returns shall be reviewed by the Office of Tax and Revenue.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.23.</num>
    <text>The Office of Tax and Revenue or the affected agency shall maintain official records of each protest, including testimony and exhibits, regarding the interception of a refund when court-ordered child-support payments are in arrears, or when a Federal
      Student or Nurse Student Loan obligation is determined to be in default. Transcription of any proceedings shall not be required.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.24.</num>
    <text>The Office of Tax and Revenue or the affected agency shall notify the taxpayer in writing of any determination as a result of a protest. The notification shall set forth the reason(s) for the determination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.25.</num>
    <text>Any person aggrieved by a determination of the authorized official of the Department of Human Services concerning the existence and the amount of a support obligation may request an adminsitrative review by the Chief, Bureau of Paternity and Child
      Support Enforcement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.26.</num>
    <text>Any person aggrieved by a determination of the Office of the Comptroller of the University of the District of Columbia concerning the existence and the amount of a Federal Student or Nurse Student Loan obligation may request an administrative review
      by the Vice President of Financial Management of the University of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.27.</num>
    <text>The administrative review provided for in §§ 150.25 and 150.26 shall not include issues concerning the apportionment of joint returns. The determination of the Office of Tax and Revenue with respect to the apportionment of joint returns shall be final,
      and the determination shall not be subject to administrative review by the affected agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.28.</num>
    <text>If no protest or request for administrative review is filed within a thirty (30) day period, the decision of the affected agency shall be final.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>150.29.</num>
    <text>Any person aggrieved by a final determination of the Office of Tax and Revenue or an affected agency, made pursuant to the § 11(a) of Title 12 of the Act (D.C. Code § 47-1812.11(a)) may within six (6) months from the date of the determination appeal
      to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, in the same manner and to the same extent as set forth in D.C. Code §§ 47-3303, 47-3304 and 47-3306-3308; Provided, that the person aggrieved shall have first filed a protest and request for hearing,
      and a request for administrative review as provided for in the Act and this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order 56-1431 effective July 24, 1956, 16 DCRR §§ 310.37 and 310.38; as amended by 27 DCR 4929 (November 7, 1980), incorporating text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 3347 (August 1, 1980); by Final Rulemaking
        published at 30 DCR 1255, 1258 (March 18, 1983); by Final Rulemaking published at 30 DCR 3763 (July 29, 1983); and by Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 2028 (March 11, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>