<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>9-161</num>
  <heading>COMBINED REPORTING[COLON] WATER&amp;#8217;S-EDGE DETERMINATION (§ 9-161)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>161.1.</num>
    <text>Water’s-edge determination. Absent an election to report based upon a worldwide unitary combined reporting basis, taxpayer members of a unitary group shall determine each of their apportioned shares of the net business income or loss of the combined
      group on a water’s-edge unitary combined reporting basis. In determining tax on a water’s-edge unitary combined reporting basis, members shall take into account all or a portion of the income and apportionment factors as required under D.C. Official
      Code § 47-1810.07 (2005 Repl.) as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>One hundred percent (100%) included. All the income and apportionment factors must be included for the following members:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Domestic corporations and entities.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any member, regardless of where it is incorporated or formed, if the average of its property, payroll, and sales factors within the United States is twenty percent (20%) or more;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Domestic international sales corporations (DISC) described in I.R.C. §§ 991-994, foreign sales corporations (FSC) described in I.R.C. §§ 921-927, and export trade corporations (ETC) described in I.R.C. §§ 970-972; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any member doing business in a tax haven, as defined in D.C. Official Code § 47-1801.04(49) (2005 Repl.).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Partially included. The following members that are not described above are included only to the extent of any U.S. source income and factors:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any member shall include its business income that is effectively connected or treated as effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States and, for that reason, is subject to federal income taxation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Controlled foreign corporation (CFC) defined in I.R.C. § 957, if they have Subpart F income defined in I.R.C. § 952.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any member that is a resident of a country that does not have a comprehensive income tax treaty with the United States and earns more than twenty percent (20%) of its income, directly or indirectly, from intangible property or service-related activities
        that are deductible against the business income of the other members of the water’s-edge group, to the extent of that income and the apportionment factors related thereto.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 10875, 10886 (September 14, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>