<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>9-201</num>
  <heading>TAXABLE SITUS (ยง 9-201)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>201.1.</num>
    <text>The taxable situs of real estate is the place where the real estate is situated.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.2.</num>
    <text>The taxable situs of tangible personal property is the place where the property is physically located at the time of the decedent&amp;#8217;s death, except as otherwise provided in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.3.</num>
    <text>The taxable situs of tangible personal property which, by its nature, is readily movable shall be determined by the Deputy Chief Financial Officer from the facts of each case.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.4.</num>
    <text>If readily movable property belonging to a decedent domiciled within the District is accidentally or casually outside of the District at the time of the decedent&amp;#8217;s death, the taxable situs of that property shall be the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.5.</num>
    <text>The taxable situs of intangible personal property belonging to a non-alien decedent is the place where the decedent was domiciled at the time of death, except as otherwise provided by this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.6.</num>
    <text>If the non-alien decedent during his or her lifetime caused intangible personal property to become an integral part of a business, trade, profession, or vocation carried on by the owner and localized in the District, that property acquires a &amp;#8220;business
      situs&amp;#8221; in the District and has a taxable situs in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.7.</num>
    <text>Whether the intangible personal property of a non-alien decedent has acquired a &amp;#8220;business situs&amp;#8221; in the District shall be determined by the Deputy Chief Financial Officer. In making a determination, the Deputy Chief Financial Officer
      may consider evidence such as affidavits, bank records, court records, agreements, and any other evidence which appears material.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.8.</num>
    <text>Generally, all property of an alien decedent situated within the District at the time of the decedent&amp;#8217;s death has a taxable situs in the District, regardless of the domicile of the alien at the time of the alien&amp;#8217;s death.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.9.</num>
    <text>No tax is imposed upon any transfer of securities specifically exempted under the provisions of ยง 15 of Article 3 of the Act, even though the securities were issued by or are obligations of a corporation organized under the laws of the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order 299-637/12, effective June 14, 1944, 16 DCRR ยง 402.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>