<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>9-2006</num>
  <heading>SUPPLEMENTAL ASSESSMENTS (§ 9-2006)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2006.1.</num>
    <text>Any owner aggrieved by a final determination made on an administrative review may appeal the supplemental assessment to the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia within forty-five (45) days from the date of a notice of
      a final determination on an administrative review. The Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia shall hear an appeal of the supplemental assessment only if a request for an administrative review was timely filed with the
      Mayor. All notices of final determination shall be accompanied by assessor&amp;#8217;s worksheets indicating the rationale for the determination, if the assessment is raised or lowered.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2006.2.</num>
    <text>No administrative review shall be required before an owner may appeal to the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia a supplemental assessment conducted between January 1 and June 30 if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Mayor fails to notify the owner of the supplemental assessment on or before September 1; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Mayor fails to notify the owner of a final determination on an administrative review of the supplemental assessment on or before December 30 following the date of the notice of supplemental assessment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2006.3.</num>
    <text>Under the circumstance described in Subsection 2006.2, the owner may appeal the supplemental assessment to the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia on or before February 1 without first petitioning for an administrative
      review of the supplemental assessment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2006.4.</num>
    <text>No administrative review shall be required before an owner may appeal to the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia a supplemental assessment conducted between July 1 and December 31 if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Mayor fails to provide notice of the supplemental assessment on or before March 1; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Mayor fails to notify the owner of a final determination on an administrative review of the supplemental assessment on or before June 30.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2006.5.</num>
    <text>Under the circumstances described in Subsection 2006.4, the owner may appeal the supplemental assessment to the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia on or before August 1 without first petitioning for an administrative
      review of the supplemental assessment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2006.6.</num>
    <text>A written notice of each decision, along with the decision itself, shall be sent to each party by first class mail or electronic mail within five (5) business days after the decision is issued.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2006.7.</num>
    <text>The notice of the decision shall include the following text:</text>
    <text>“The petitioner has the right to appeal an adverse decision of the Commission to the Tax Division of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia. Payment of all real property taxes, together with interest and penalties (if applicable), before the
      filing of a petition in the Tax Division of the Superior Court, is a jurisdictional prerequisite to the appeal.”</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2006.8.</num>
    <text>Every decision of the Commission shall be maintained by the Commission for three (3) years and shall be made available for public examination and photocopying at the expense of the requester, subject to the confidentiality provisions of D.C. Official
      Code § 47-821(d)(2)(A) and (B) (2012 Supp.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2006.9.</num>
    <text>Each decision of the Commission shall also be placed on the website of the Commission, subject to redactions based on the confidentiality provisions of D.C. Official Code § 47-821(d)(2)(A) and (B) (2012 Supp.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 24, 29 (January 2, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 9888 (July 5, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>