<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>9-3703</num>
  <heading>DETERMINATION OF TAXABLE SITUS (ยง 9-3703)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3703.1.</num>
    <text>The taxable situs of real property shall be the place where the real property is situated.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3703.2.</num>
    <text>Real property having an actual situs outside the District shall not be taxable with respect to a resident decedent where the property is held in a personal trust.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3703.3.</num>
    <text>Real property having an actual situs in the District shall be taxable with respect to a nonresident decedent, including property held in a personal trust.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3703.4.</num>
    <text>All other indirect interests in real estate (e.g., partnership, corporate) shall for District estate tax purposes be regarded as intangible personal property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3703.5.</num>
    <text>A contract to convey land shall constitute an equitable conversion so that the seller&amp;#8217;s interest is personal property and the buyer&amp;#8217;s interest is real property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3703.6.</num>
    <text>The taxable situs of tangible personal property shall be the place where the property is customarily located at the time of the decedent&amp;#8217;s death.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3703.7.</num>
    <text>The taxable situs of tangible personal property which, by its nature, is readily movable shall be determined by the Deputy Chief Financial Officer from the facts of each case.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3703.8.</num>
    <text>If readily movable tangible personal property belonging to a decedent domiciled within the District is accidentally or casually outside of the District at the time of the decedent&amp;#8217;s death, the taxable situs of that property shall be the
      District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3703.9.</num>
    <text>The taxable situs of intangible personal property other than business use intangible personal property shall be the domicile of the decedent at the time of the decedent&amp;#8217;s death.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3703.10.</num>
    <text>The taxable situs of business use intangible personal property as defined in ยง 3799.2 shall be in the District, regardless of the resident of the decedent.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 2353, 2358 (April 1, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>