<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>9-9901</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS[COLON] INCOME AND FRANCHISE TAXES (§ 9-9901)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>9901.1.</num>
    <text>The definitions in this section apply to the provisions of Chapter 1 of this title, “Income and Franchise Taxes.”</text>
    <text>Allocated &amp;#8211; (as used in reference to income and deductions from income) a determination based upon actual figures specifically applicable to income and deductions.</text>
    <text>Apportioned &amp;#8211; (as used in reference to net income) a ratable portion determined on a percentage basis.</text>
    <text>Business income &amp;#8211; income arising from transactions and activity in the regular course of the taxpayer’s trade, business, or profession; including income from tangible and intangible property if the acquisition, management, and disposition
      of the property constitute integral parts of the taxpayer’s regular trade, business, or professional operations. (Commissioners’ Order 65-742 and 30 DCR 1922)</text>
    <text>Commercial domicile &amp;#8211; the principal place from which the trade, business, or profession of the taxpayer is directed or managed. (Commissioners’ Order 65-742 and 30 DCR 1922)</text>
    <text>Compensation &amp;#8211; wages, salaries, commissions, and any other form of remuneration paid or accrued to employees for personal services. (Commissioners’ Order 65-742 and 30 DCR 1922)</text>
    <text>Non-business income &amp;#8211; all income other than business income. (Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order 65-742 and 30 DCR 1922)</text>
    <text>Sales &amp;#8211; all gross receipts of a taxpayer not allocated in accordance with the allocation provisions of Chapter 1 of this title. (Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order 65-742)</text>
    <text>State &amp;#8211; any state of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, any territory or possession of the United States, and any foreign country or political subdivision of a foreign country. (Commissioners&amp;#8217;
      Order 65-742 and 30 DCR 1922)</text>
    <text>Transportation Company &amp;#8211; any person engaged in the transportation of persons or goods or property of others for hire. (30 DCR 1922)</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>