<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-5800</num>
  <heading>UST SYSTEM UPGRADES (ยง 20-5800)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5800.1.</num>
    <text>Not later than December 22, 1998, the owner or operator of each existing petroleum UST system, except heating oil USTs, shall have ensured that the UST system complies with one (1) of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>For UST systems installed before December 22, 1988, the upgrade requirements set forth in this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For UST systems installed after December 22, 1988 and prior to November 12, 1993, the federal mandatory new tank performance standards set forth in 40 CFR 280.20;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>For UST systems installed after November 12, 1993, the new UST system performance standards set forth in Chapter 57; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The permanent closure requirements set forth in Chapter 61, and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Applicable requirements for corrective action set forth in Chapter 62.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5800.2.</num>
    <text>No person shall deposit a regulated substance into an UST, except heating oil USTs, that has not been upgraded in accordance with ยง 5800.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5800.3.</num>
    <text>Not later than December 22, 1994, the owner or operator of each existing hazardous substance UST system shall ensure that the UST system complies with one (1) of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The new UST system performance standards set forth in Chapter 57 for hazardous substance UST systems; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The permanent closure requirements set forth in Chapter 61, and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Applicable requirements for corrective action set forth in Chapter 62.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is ยง13 of the District of Columbia Underground Storage Tank Management Act of 1990, as amended, D.C. Law 8-242, D.C. Code ยง6-995.1 et seq. (1995 Repl. Vol.), Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 91-160 dated
        October 9, 1991; and the District of Columbia Water Pollution Control Act of 1984, D.C. Law 5-188, D.C. Code 6-921 (1995 Repl. Vol.), Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 85-152 dated September 12, 1985.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 7835, 7860 (November 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7699 (October 1, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>