<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-5801</num>
  <heading>TANK UPGRADES (§ 20-5801)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5801.1.</num>
    <text>Steel tanks shall be upgraded in accordance with the requirements of this chapter. Owners or operators shall follow the manufacturer&amp;#8217;s specifications or established procedures and practices adopted by a nationally recognized association
      or an independent testing laboratory, specified by the Director pursuant to §§ 5506.1 and 5506.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5801.2.</num>
    <text>An underground storage tank may be upgraded by internal lining if the following requirements are met:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The interior of the tank is inspected and assessed to ensure that the tank is structurally sound prior to installing the internal lining in accordance with current practice recommended by the American Petroleum Institute (&amp;#8220;API&amp;#8221;);
        and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The lining is installed in accordance with the requirements of § 5902 of this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5801.3.</num>
    <text>Within ten (10) years after lining, and every five (5) years thereafter, the interior of the lined tank shall be inspected to ensure it is structurally sound, free of corrosion holes and that the lining is still performing in accordance with original
      design specifications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5801.4.</num>
    <text>Tank linings that have lost adhesion, cracked, or otherwise fail to meet original design specifications shall be replaced unless the damaged lining may be repaired and restored to a level of performance in accordance with original design specifications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5801.5.</num>
    <text>A tank may be upgraded by cathodic protection if the cathodic protection system meets the requirements of either § 5701.2 (a) or (b) and § 5701.3, and the integrity of the tank is ensured using one (1) of the following methods:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The interior of the tank is inspected and assessed to ensure that the tank is structurally sound and free of corrosion holes prior to installing the cathodic protection system; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The tank has been installed for less than ten (10) years and is monitored monthly for releases in accordance with §§ 6008 through 6012; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The tank has been installed for less than ten (10) years and is assessed for corrosion holes by conducting two (2) tank tightness tests that meet the requirements of § 6007. The first tank tightness test shall be conducted prior to installing the
        cathodic protection system. The second tank tightness test shall be conducted between three (3) and six (6) months following the first operation of the cathodic protection system; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The tank is assessed for corrosion holes by a method that is determined by the Director to prevent releases in a manner that is no less protective of human health and the environment than a system which complies with §§ 5801.5(a) through (c) of
        this section.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5801.6.</num>
    <text>An underground storage tank may be upgraded by both internal lining and cathodic protection if the following requirements are met:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The lining is installed in accordance with the requirements of § 5902; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The cathodic protection system meets the requirements of either § 5701.2 (a) or (b) and § 5701.4.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 7835, 7860 (November 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7699 (October 1, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>