<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-8902</num>
  <heading>PROVIDER INCENTIVE PAYMENTS (§ 29-8902)
    <text>For all payment years, MEIP incentive payments for each eligible provider shalle subject to all of the following conditions:</text>
    <text>Incentive payments shall be calculated pursuant to 42 C.F.R. § 495.310;</text>
    <text>An eligible provider may receive a MEIP incentive payment so long as theligible provider meets all MEIP requirements as set forth in this chapter; and</text>
    <text>No eligible provider shall receive an incentive payment after payment year 2021.</text>
    <text>In the first payment year, to receive an incentive payment, an eligiblerofessional shall meet all eligibility and volume requirements in accordanceith Sections 8900, “Provider Eligibility” and 8901, “Methodology forolume Requirements;” and satisfy
      one (1) of the following conditions:</text>
    <text>Demonstrate and attest to adopting, implementing or upgrading EHR technology asefined in 42 C.F.R. § 495.302 that has been certified by the Office of theational Coordinator for Health Information Technology; or</text>
    <text>Demonstrate that it is a meaningful EHR user as defined in 42 C.F.R. § 495.4.</text>
    <text>Incentive payments to an eligible professional in the first payment year shalleet the following requirements:</text>
    <text>An initial incentive payment shall not be dispersed after CY 2016;</text>
    <text>An incentive payment shall not exceed twenty-one thousand two hundred fiftyollars ($21,250);</text>
    <text>Incentive payments cannot be received from more than one State or Medicaidncentive payment program in a payment year;</text>
    <text>Incentive payments to pediatricians shall be subject to the limitations of 42.F.R. § 495.310(a)(4); and</text>
    <text>Incentive payments to professionals that are Medicaid and Medicare eligiblehall be subject to the limitations set forth in 42 C.F.R. § 495.10(e).</text>
    <text>In the second, third, fourth, fifth, and sixth payment year, to receive anncentive payment, an eligible professional shall meet all eligibilityequirements in accordance with Sections 8900, “Provider Eligibility” and901, “Methodology for Volume Requirements;”
      and demonstrate that it is aeaningful EHR user as defined in 42 C.F.R. § 495.4.</text>
    <text>Incentive payments to an eligible professional in subsequent payment years shalleet the following requirements:</text>
    <text>Incentive payments shall be disbursed consistent with the CY on aon-consecutive, annual basis, following verification of eligibility for theayment year;</text>
    <text>A single incentive payment may not exceed eight thousand five hundred dollars$8,500);</text>
    <text>An eligible professional shall not participate in MEIP for more than a total ofix (6) years. Incentive payments shall not exceed sixty-three thousand sevenundred and fifty dollars ($63,750) over a six (6) year period;</text>
    <text>Incentive payments to pediatricians shall be subject to the limitations of 42.F.R § 495.310(a)(4); and</text>
    <text>Incentive payments to professionals that are Medicaid and Medicare eligiblehall be subject to the limitations set forth in 42 C.F.R. § 495.10(e).</text>
    <text>In the first payment year, to receive an incentive payment, an eligible hospitalhall meet all eligibility requirements in accordance with Sections 8900,Provider Eligibility” and 8901, “Methodology for Volume Requirements;”nd satisfy one (1) of the
      following conditions:</text>
    <text>Demonstrate and attest to adopting, implementing or upgrading EHR technology asefined in 42 C.F.R. § 495.302 that has been certified by the Office of theational Coordinator for Health Information Technology; or</text>
    <text>Demonstrate that it is a meaningful EHR user as defined in 42 C.F.R. § 495.4.</text>
    <text>Incentive payments to an eligible hospital in the first payment year shall meethe following requirements:</text>
    <text>Incentive payments shall be disbursed consistent with the Federal FY on aolling basis following verification of eligibility for the payment year;</text>
    <text>An initial incentive payment shall not be dispersed after FY 2016; and</text>
    <text>An eligible hospital shall receive an incentive payment from only one State oredicaid incentive payment program in a payment year.</text>
    <text>In the second, third, fourth, fifth, and sixth payment year, to receive anncentive payment, an eligible hospital shall meet all eligibility requirementsn accordance with Sections 8900, “Provider Eligibility” and 8901,Methodology for Volume Requirements;”
      and demonstrate that it is aeaningful EHR user as defined in 42 C.F.R. § 495.4.</text>
    <text>Incentive payments to an eligible hospital in subsequent payment years shalleet the following requirements:</text>
    <text>Incentive payments shall be disbursed consistent with the Federal FY on aolling basis following verification of eligibility for the payment year;</text>
    <text>Prior to FY 2016, incentive payments may be disbursed on a non-consecutive,nnual basis for the fiscal year;</text>
    <text>After 2016, incentive payments shall be dispersed only to an eligible hospitalhat received an incentive payment in the prior FY;</text>
    <text>Incentive payments shall be dispersed over a minimum of a three (3) year periodnd a maximum of a six (6) year period;</text>
    <text>An eligible hospital shall receive an incentive payment from only one State oredicaid incentive payment program in a payment year;</text>
    <text>No single incentive payment may exceed fifty percent (50%) of the aggregate EHRncentive amount as calculated under 42 C.F.R. § 495.310(g);</text>
    <text>The total incentive payment received over all payment years of the program shalle no greater than the aggregate EHR incentive amount as calculated under 42.F.R.§ 495.310(g); and</text>
    <text>No incentive payments over a two (2) year period may exceed ninety percent (90%)f the aggregate EHR hospital incentive amount as calculated in 42 C.F.R.§95.310(g).</text>
    <text>Incentive payments, identified in Subsections 8902.1 through 8902.9, may bessigned to a third party employer or to an entity under the followingonditions:</text>
    <text>The third party must have a contractual arrangement with the eligible hospitalhat allows the third party to bill and receive payment for the eligibleospital&amp;#8217;s covered professional services;</text>
    <text>Assignments in Medicare must be consistent with § 1842(b)(6)(A) of the Socialecurity Act and 42 C.F.R. §§ 424.70 – 424.90;</text>
    <text>Medicaid eligible providers may also assign their incentive payments to aaxpayer Identification Number (TIN) for an entity promoting the adoption of EHRechnology, consistent with 42 C.F.R. §§ 495.300 – 495.370; and</text>
    <text>Each eligible provider may reassign the entire amount of the incentive paymento only one employer or entity.</text>
    <text>Incentive payments, identified in Subsections 8902.1 through 8902.9, that areisbursed through Medicaid managed care plans shall not exceed one hundred andive percent (105%) of the capitation rate pursuant to 42 C.F.R. §38.6(c)(5)(iii).</text>
    <text>Incentive payments assigned to third party employers and other entities asescribed in Subsection 8902.10 shall not be implemented until on or afterovember 1, 2013.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 61 DCR 237 (January 10, 2014).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>