<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-3309</num>
  <heading>DCRA FIRE PROTECTION DIVISION INFRACTIONS (§ 16-3309)
    <text>The following abbreviations apply to this section:</text>
    <text>IFC- International Fire Code</text>
    <text>IBC- International Building Code</text>
    <text>NFPA- National Fire Protection Association</text>
    <text>IPMC- International Property Maintenance Code</text>
    <text>Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 1 infraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>12G DCMR PM § 705.1 (failure to remedy dangerous conditions to remove hazardous materials);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>12A DCMR § 114.10 (failure to comply with terms of a stop work order);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>12A DCMR § 114.3 (unauthorized removal of a posted stop work order);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Reserved;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Reserved;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>IBC § 709.3 (failure to maintain all required fire resistance rated doors or smoke barriers);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>IFC § 901.4.1 (failure to maintain in an operative condition at all times fire protection and life safety systems, devices, units, or service equipment);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>12H DCMR § F-906.1 (failure to provide fire extinguishers);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>IFC § 1003.1 (failure to maintain in a safe condition and free of all obstructions the means of egress from each part of the building);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>IBC § 1004.1 (overcrowding or admitting persons beyond the established posted occupants load);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>IFC § 508.5.4 (fire hydrants, fire department inlet connections, or fire protection system control valves are obstructed in such manner as to interfere with fire fighting access);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>IFC § 1006.1 (failure to provide adequate lighting for stairways, hallways, and other means of egress); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>IBC § 1024.6 (exits fail to discharge directly at a public way or at a yard, court, or open space of the required width and size to provide all occupants with a safe access to a public way).</text>
    </level>
    <text>Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 2 infraction:</text>
    <text>IPMC § 307.1 (permitting the accumulation of waste paper, wood, hay straws, weeds, litter, or combustible or flammable waste or rubbish of any kind);</text>
    <text>IFC § 904.11 (failure to provide or maintain an automatic activation kitchen hood fire extinguishing system);</text>
    <text>IFC § 904.11.1 (failure to provide or maintain a manual activation device for the hood fire extinguishing system);</text>
    <text>NFPA 70 § 110.32 (failure to provide the required clearance between all electrical service equipment and storage);</text>
    <text>IFC § 904.11.5 (failure to provide a sufficient number of portable fire extinguishers);</text>
    <text>IFC § 906.2 or 12G DCMR PM § 705.2 (failure to maintain, test, or recharge hand-operated portable fire extinguishing equipment);</text>
    <text>IFC § 315.2.2 (storing combustible or flammable materials on any portion of an exit, elevator car, stairway, fire escape, or other means of egress);</text>
    <text>IBC § 1005.1 (door openings fail to meet the requirements of minimum width based upon occupant load);</text>
    <text>IBC § 1008.1.9 (doors are not equipped with approved panic hardware);</text>
    <text>IBC § 1008.1.2 (exit doors swing in the wrong direction);</text>
    <text>12E DCMR M § 1004.1 (failure to provide an oil burner emergency switch);</text>
    <text>IBC § 1011.5.3 (failure to provide emergency lights, alarms, or power back-ups);</text>
    <text>IBC § 1011.1 (permitting decorations, furnishings, or equipment that impairs the visibility of exit signs);</text>
    <text>IBC § 715.4.7.3 (failure to maintain self-closing and automatic doors or to provide a fire or smoke barrier);</text>
    <text>IBC § 1004.3 (failure to conspicuously post sign stating the number of occupants permitted within such space for each place of assembly);</text>
    <text>IBC § 1011.1 (failure to maintain exit signs in theaters or other places of public assembly); or</text>
    <text>IBC § 806 (decorative materials are not non-combustible or flame resistant).</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <num>3309.3.</num>
    <text>Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 3 infraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>IFC § 904.1 (extinguishing systems are not inspected and tagged);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>IBC § 1003.2.10.2 or 12G DCMR § PM-702.6 (exit signs are not maintained or clearly illuminated at all times when the building is occupied); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any provision of the District of Columbia Construction Codes adopted pursuant to the Construction Codes Approval and Amendment Act of 1986, effective March 21, 1987 (D.C. Law 6-216; D.C. Official Code §§ 6-1401 et seq.) which is not cited elsewhere
        in this section shall be a Class 3 infraction.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 4908 (May 27, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 3096 (April 9, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>