<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-3307</num>
  <heading>BUILDING CONDEMNATION DIVISION INFRACTIONS (§ 16-3307)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3307.1.</num>
    <text>Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 1 infraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 4 of An Act To create a board for the condemnation of insanitary buildings in the District of Columbia, approved May 1, 1906 (34 Stat. 158, ch. 2073; D.C. Official Code § 6-904) (permitting the occupancy of a condemned building without authorization
        by the Board for the Condemnation of Insanitary Buildings);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 5 of an Act To create a board for the condemnation of insanitary buildings in the District of Columbia (D.C. Official Code § 6-905) (failure to obtain any required permit when work is undertaken to repair, make habitable or demolish a condemned
        building.); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Section 12 of An Act To create a board for the condemnation of insanitary buildings in the District of Columbia (D.C. Official Code § 6-912) (defacing, removing or concealing any copy of any order of condemnation which has been affixed to any condemned
        building).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3307.2.</num>
    <text>Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 2 infraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 11 of An Act To create a board for the condemnation of insanitary buildings in the District of Columbia (D.C. Official Code § 6-911) (hindering, preventing or refusing to permit a lawful inspection of the premises.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 3 of An Act To create a board for the condemnation of insanitary buildings in the District of Columbia (D.C. Official Code § 6-903) (failure to show cause within the time specified why such building or part of building should not be condemned);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Section 7 of An Act To create a board for the condemnation of insanitary buildings in the District of Columbia (D.C. Official Code § 6-907) (failure of the owner to cause such building to be put into a habitable and sanitary condition or to be demolished
        and removed within the time specified by the Board in the order of condemnation); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Section 15 of an Act To create a board for the condemnation of insanitary buildings in the District of Columbia (D.C. Official Code § 6-915) (tenants or occupants neglecting or causing to exist unsanitary conditions which have led to the condemnation
        of a building.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 4908 (May 27, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>