<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2800</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS AND PURPOSES (HE) (§ 11-2800)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2800.1.</num>
    <text>The Hill East (HE) District is applied to Federal Reservation 13, which is designated for mixed use development on the Future Land use Map of the Comprehensive Plan and the Reservation 13 Hill East Waterfront Master Plan, as approved by the Council
      of the District of Columbia on October 15, 2002, and is the subject of the Hill East Waterfront Design Guidelines, June 2008.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2800.2.</num>
    <text>Any reference to a street or a square refers to proposed streets and squares as depicted in Map A attached to the Office of Planning report dated June 1, 2007, filed in Zoning Commission Case Number 04-05, which may be viewed at the D.C. Office of
      Zoning.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2800.3.</num>
    <text>Any reference to a street shall be deemed to include a reference to the Southeast (S.E.) quadrant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2800.4.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this chapter the terms:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>“Primary street” shall mean Independence Avenue, Massachusetts Avenue, and Water Street; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>“Secondary street” shall refer to 19th Street, 20th Street, 21st Street, Burke Street, C Street, and C Place.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2800.5.</num>
    <text>The boundaries of the HE District correspond to Federal Reservation 13, which is bounded by Independence Avenue on the north, 19th Street on the west, Water Street on the east, and the Congressional Cemetery on the south.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2800.6.</num>
    <text>The HE District is divided into the following four subdistricts for the purpose of lot occupancy, floor area ratio ( “FAR”) and building height:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>HE-1 (19th Street) Subdistrict, which includes squares with frontage onto 19th Street, between Independence Avenue and Massachusetts Avenue);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>HE-2 (20th Street) Subdistrict, which includes squares with frontage on 20th Street;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>HE-3 (Water Street) Subdistrict, which includes squares with frontage on Water Street; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>HE-4 (Corrections) Subdistrict, which includes squares N and O.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2800.7.</num>
    <text>The purposes of the Hill East District are to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Connect and integrate Reservation 13 with adjacent neighborhoods, and the new waterfront park along the Anacostia River;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Utilize the site to meet a diversity of public needs, including health care, education, employment, government services and administration, retail, recreation and housing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Extend the existing pattern of local streets to and through the site to create simple, well-organized city blocks and appropriately-scaled development;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Maintain a human-scale of building heights that match existing neighborhood buildings and increase in height as the site slopes downward to the Anacostia waterfront;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Connect the Hill East neighborhood and the city at large to the waterfront via tree-lined public streets, recreational trails, and increased access to waterfront parklands;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Demonstrate environmental stewardship through environmentally-sensitive design, ample open spaces, and a waterfront park that serve as public amenities and benefit the neighborhood and the city;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Promote the use of mass transit by introducing new uses near Metro stations, and create an environment where the pedestrian, bicycle, and auto are all welcome, complementary, and unobtrusive, reducing the impact of traffic on adjacent neighborhood
        streets;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Limit the Central Detention Facility and the Correction Treatment Facility to areas south of Massachusetts Avenue; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Create attractive “places” of unique and complementary character including:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A new, vital neighborhood center around the Metro station at C and 19th Streets that serves the unmet neighborhood commercial needs of the community and extends to the waterfront with a new residential district;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Massachusetts Avenue as a grand Washington ‘boulevard’ in the tradition of the L’Enfant plan;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A district for city-wide uses and services, such as health care, education, and recreation along Independence Avenue; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A grand public waterfront park incorporating monumental places and quiet natural retreats accessed by a meandering park drive set back from the Anacostia River.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2800.8.</num>
    <text>The Hill East District shall constitute the Zoning Regulations for the geographic area referred to in § 2800.1. Where there are conflicts between this chapter and other parts of the Zoning Regulations, the provisions of the Hill East District shall
      govern.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2800.9.</num>
    <text>Unless specifically exempted, the requirements of the HE District shall apply to all new buildings and to all other buildings where any additions, alterations, or repairs within any 12-month period exceed one hundred percent (100%) of the assessed
      value of the building as set forth in the records of the Office of Tax and Revenue as of the date of a building permit application, provided:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The cost basis for alterations or additions to an existing building shall be the amount indicated by the applicant on the application for a building permit; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>In the case of an addition, the requirements and incentives of this Chapter apply only to the addition.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking and Order No. 04-05 published at 56 DCR 6181 (August 7, 2009); as corrected by Errata Notice published at 58 DCR 4314, 4316 (May 20, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>