<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2814</num>
  <heading>DESIGN REQUIREMENTS FOR BUILDINGS LOCATED ON PRIMARY STREETS (HE) (§ 11-2814)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2814.1.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section set forth standards for buildings and structures with frontage(s) on a primary street.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2814.2.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding §§ 2813.2 and 2813.3, the fronts of buildings located at street intersections shall be constructed to the property lines abutting each intersecting street, without any setback, for a minimum of fifty feet (50 ft.) from the intersection,
      along each street frontage.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2814.3.</num>
    <text>The corner of the building at the intersection of two primary streets or a primary and secondary street shall incorporate articulation such, as but not limited to, being angled, curved, or chamfered to emphasize the corner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2814.4.</num>
    <text>The distance from the corner shall not exceed twenty feet (20 ft.), measured from the corner of the lot to the end of the angled or curved wall segment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2814.5.</num>
    <text>Entrances into a building shall be no more than fifty feet (50 ft.) apart and recessed no more than six feet (6 ft.) deep or ten feet (10 ft.) wide.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2814.6.</num>
    <text>Buildings shall incorporate vertical elements in the street-facing façade to create a series of storefront-type bays where preferred uses are present.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2814.7.</num>
    <text>Residential buildings shall have at least one primary entrance directly accessible from the public sidewalk.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2814.8.</num>
    <text>Instead of the windows required by § 2812.1(d), on primary streets, artwork and displays relating to activities occurring within the building shall be permitted as a special exception if approved by the Zoning Commission pursuant to § 3104, provided
      the applicant demonstrates that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The building has more than fifty percent (50%) of its ground level space in storage, parking, or loading areas, or in uses which by their nature are not conducive to windows (such as theaters); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The artwork or displays are consistent with the objective of providing a pleasant, rich, and diverse pedestrian experience.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking and Order No. 04-05 published at 56 DCR 6181 (August 7, 2009); as corrected by Errata Notice published at 58 DCR 4314, 4317 (May 20, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>