<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6699</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 17-6699)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6699.1.</num>
    <text>When used in these regulations, the following terms, shall have the following meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Act &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, D.C. Law 6-99, as amended.</text>
    <text>General supervision &amp;#8211; supervision in which the supervisor is available to the person supervised, either in person or by a communications device.</text>
    <text>Immediate supervision &amp;#8211; supervision in which the supervisor is physically present with the person supervised and either discussing or observing the person&amp;#8217;s practice.</text>
    <text>Practice of professional counseling &amp;#8211; engaging in counseling activities, for compensation, by a person who represents, by title or description of services, that he or she is a &amp;#8220;professional counselor&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;licensed
      professional counselor,&amp;#8221; and includes the processes of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>conducting assessments for the purpose of determining treatment goals and objectives;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>assisting clients through a professional relationship to achieve effective mental, emotional, physical, social, educational, or career development and adjustment throughout the life span; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>using counseling treatment interventions to facilitate human development and to identify and remediate mental, emotional, or behavioral conditions and associated difficulties which interfere with functional wellness.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Professional counselor &amp;#8211; a person licensed under the Act to practice professional counseling.</text>
    <text>Student &amp;#8211; an individual who is enrolled in an academic program which meets the requirements of ยง 6602.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 5238 (August 5, 1994).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>