<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6602</num>
  <heading>EDUCATIONAL REQUIREMENTS (ยง 17-6602)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6602.1.</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, an applicant for licensure shall furnish proof satisfactory to the Board, in accordance with ยง 710 of the Act, D.C. Official Code ยง 3-1207.10, of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That the applicant has received a master&amp;#8217;s degree or higher from an institution of higher education which was accredited, at the time the degree was conferred, by an accrediting body recognized by the Secretary of the United States Department
        of Education, the Council on Postsecondary Accreditation or its successor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That the applicant has completed a minimum of sixty (60) semester hours or the equivalent number of quarter or trimester hours converted into semester hours in counseling or related subjects after earning a bachelor&amp;#8217;s degree; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>That the applicant shall have obtained satisfactory documentation of the required number of semester hours as converted from quarter hours or trimester hours into semester hours from the educational institution based on the institutions formula
        for conversion of quarter hours and trimester hours into semester hours.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6602.2.</num>
    <text>For purposes of meeting the requirements of subsection 6602.1, the following shall apply:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>All courses earned in a graduate degree program in counseling shall be counted toward the required sixty (60) semester hours. Courses earned outside of a counseling degree program shall be evaluated individually.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Subjects related to counseling acceptable to the Board include:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Social science;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Psychology;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Social work;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Human services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Behavioral science;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Psychiatric nursing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Rehabilitation counseling;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Family counseling;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Individual and family development;</text>
    </level>
    <text>(10) Student counseling and personnel services;</text>
    <text>(11) Mental health and human services;</text>
    <text>(12) Family and community services; and</text>
    <text>(13) Creative arts therapy.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The content of an applicant&amp;#8217;s degree program and courses shall include, at a minimum, the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Counseling theory and practice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Human growth and development;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Lifestyle and career development;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Group counseling;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Appraisal, assessment, and testing of individuals;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Principles of etiology, diagnosis, treatment planning, and prevention of mental and emotional disorders and dysfunctional behavior;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Social and cultural foundations including multicultural counseling;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Marriage and family counseling;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Research and program evaluation;</text>
    </level>
    <text>(10) Professional orientation and ethics; and</text>
    <text>(11) Counseling practicum or internship.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>It is not necessary for a separate course to have been completed in the content areas listed in paragraph (c); however evidence is required that the content of each area has been covered in courses completed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6602.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall submit to the Board certified transcripts of the applicant&amp;#8217;s educational records from each educational institution from which credits were earned that are relevant to this licensure application with the completed application.
      Transcripts shall be accepted if they are mailed directly by the educational institution from which credits were earned or if submitted directly by an applicant in a sealed university envelope with a registrar&amp;#8217;s signature across the seal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6602.4.</num>
    <text>The applicant shall provide the Board with course descriptions detailing the subject matter of courses named on the applicant&amp;#8217;s certified transcript that differ from those courses outlined in ยง 6602.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 5238 (August 5, 1994); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 6178 (July 1, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>