<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-802</num>
  <heading>PLASTIC BAGS FOR UNCOMPACTED SOLID WASTE (§ 21-802)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>802.1.</num>
    <text>Average thickness of all bags within an individual package (carton, cases, etc.) shall be within seven percent (± 7%) of labelled thickness.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>802.2.</num>
    <text>The film used to construct plastic bags shall be capable of incineration under normal municipal incinerating practices.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>802.3.</num>
    <text>The bags shall comply with the following inside dimension, within one and one-half percent (± 1.5%):</text>
    <text>28 in. x 35 in. bag: 56 in. circumference and inside length of 35 in.;</text>
    <text>30 in. x 37 in. bag: 60 in. circumference and inside length of 37 in.;</text>
    <text>33 in. x 40 in. bag: 66 in. circumference and inside length of 40 in.; and</text>
    <text>33 in. x 44 in. bag: 66 in. circumference and inside length of 44 in.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>802.4.</num>
    <text>Bags shall withstand hanging by the neck for two (2) minutes, followed by a drop of five feet (5 ft.) on its end onto smooth concrete. The bags shall be filled with redwood bark, at approximate density of eighteen pounds per cubic foot (18 lbs./ft.3),
      to the total weight indicated as follows:</text>
    <text>Bag Size</text>
    <text>Load (lbs.)</text>
    <text>28 in. x 35 in.</text>
    <text>35 pounds;</text>
    <text>30 in. x 37 in.</text>
    <text>40 pounds;</text>
    <text>33 in. x 40 in.</text>
    <text>45 pounds; and</text>
    <text>33 in. x 44 in.</text>
    <text>50 pounds.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>802.5.</num>
    <text>Count shall meet National Bureau of Standards Handbook 67 (Rev.) procedures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>802.6.</num>
    <text>Each package (carton, case, etc.) shall contain an equal amount to the labelled statement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>802.7.</num>
    <text>Any heat seal shall withstand a ten (10) minute tensile loading of one pound per inch (1 lb./in.) of seal without failure in accordance with ASTM F-88-68, method A.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>802.8.</num>
    <text>All bag packaging shall be labelled with the Universal Product Code (UPC) or the stock number or the number imprinted on the bag. The display of the numbers on the bag packaging shall be considered the manufacturer&amp;#8217;s certification that the
      bag and all bags contained in the packages conform to specification and testing procedures prescribed herein.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>802.9.</num>
    <text>All bag packaging shall have marked on the bag the name and address of the principal place of business of the manufacturer or distributor of the same and a code identifying the date and location of the manufacture of the bag.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 26 DCR 6221 (January 5, 1979), incorporating text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 359 (November 3, 1978); 5T DCRR §§7(a)-(h) (September 21, 1970).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>