<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-800</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 21-800)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>800.1.</num>
    <text>The purpose of the specifications set forth in this chapter is to establish minimum standards for the containerization of solid waste (refuse), and thereby promote the health, safety and welfare of the people of the District of Columbia, as well as
      enhance and improve the quality of the environment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>800.2.</num>
    <text>The specifications set forth in this chapter shall apply to all of the containerization of solid waste (refuse) within the District of Columbia except containers used by residential property owners whose solid waste is collected by the District of
      Columbia government.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>800.3.</num>
    <text>All paper bags (wet strength Kraft paper), plastic bags (polyethylene or ethylene copolymer resin), thermoplastic containers, galvanized metal cans, and other specially designed containers distributed, sold, and used for the containment of solid waste
      (refuse) within the District shall conform to specifications prescribed in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>800.4.</num>
    <text>Prior to granting the approval for the distribution, sale, or use of any bags, containers, or other specially designed containers for the containment of solid waste (refuse) in the District, the Director of the Department of Public Works (hereafter
      referred to as the &amp;#8220;Director&amp;#8221;) may conduct, or order the manufacturer or distributor of the product(s) to conduct, the necessary laboratory tests to determine whether the product(s) is(are) in conformity with the specifications
      prescribed in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>800.5.</num>
    <text>A permit shall be issued to applicants (manufacturers or distributors only) who have complied with the applicable requirements of the specifications set forth in this chapter. The permit shall be non-transferrable and shall be exclusive property of
      the applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>800.6.</num>
    <text>The Director may conduct or order the manufacturer or distributor of any container displaying the official logo or printed statement of approval (as prescribed in the specifications set forth in this chapter) to conduct, in an independent testing
      laboratory selected by the Director, any tests which are necessary to determine whether the container is in conformity with the provisions of the specifications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>800.7.</num>
    <text>The expenses for all tests shall be borne by the manufacturer or distributor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>800.8.</num>
    <text>The Director may require the appearance for testing purposes of any manufacturer, distributor, retailer, or user of any container displaying the official logo or printed statement of approval.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>800.9</num>
    <text>800.9 &amp;#8211; 800.25 [Reserved]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>800.26.</num>
    <text>Any person who fails to comply with any provision of Chapter 8 shall, upon conviction, be punished by the fines set forth in Title 24 DCMR, Chapter 13 (Civil Fines Under D.C. Law 6-100).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is §§401 and 402 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967, effective August 11, 1967, filed August 11, 1967, D.C. Code Vol. 1 at 126 (1981 Ed.); Commissioner&amp;#8217;s Order 71-255 dated July
        27, 1971, and Commissioner&amp;#8217;s Order 71-329 dated August 27, 1971; §412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 790. Pub.L. 93-198, D.C. Code §1-227(a) (1992 Repl. Vol.).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 26 DCR 6221 (January 5, 1979), incorporating text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 4228 (November 3, 1978); 5T DCRR §§1. 2. 4, 13, and 16 (September 21, 1970); as amended by §2(e) of the Litter Control Fine
        Increase Amendment Act of 1995), D C Law 11-13 24 DCR 1268, 1280 (March 17, 1995).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>