<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-806</num>
  <heading>CONTAINERIZATION SYSTEMS (§ 21-806)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>806.1.</num>
    <text>The owner or other person in charge of the premises served by a solid waste (refuse) containerization system (referred to in this section as simply the &amp;#8220;premises&amp;#8221;) shall maintain in a safe, clean, odor-free, and properly operating
      condition all multiple-use containers (also referred to in this section simply as &amp;#8220;containers&amp;#8221;) and other equipment kept on the premises in connection with the operation of the system.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.2.</num>
    <text>The owner of the premises shall keep the place of storage for the containers safe, clean, and odor-free at all times.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.3.</num>
    <text>The owner of the premises or other person shall keep on the premises a hose and brush or a steam cleaner and all other necessary equipment to properly clean the containers, unless the containers are regularly cleaned at a location of the premises
      and the equipment is not required by other District laws or regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.4.</num>
    <text>Each container shall be cleaned on a concrete or other paved surface properly drained in a sanitary or combined sewer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.5.</num>
    <text>The debris shall not drain into a storm sewer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.6.</num>
    <text>The cleaning surface and drainage system shall be maintained in a safe, clean, odor-free, and properly operating condition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.7.</num>
    <text>A solid waste (refuse) system shall be of sufficient capacity to permit the safe and sanitary storage of all solid waste normally accumulated on or generated within the premises during a period of seventy-two (72) hours, or one hundred fifty percent
      (150%) of all solid wastes normally accumulated or generated within the premises between any regularly scheduled collections, whichever is greater.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.8.</num>
    <text>In cases of hardship, the Director may permit a solid waste (refuse) containerization system of lesser capacity, but in no event less than would permit the safe and sanitary storage of all solid wastes normally accumulated or generated within the
      premises during a period of seventy-two (72) hours or between regularly scheduled collections, whichever is greater.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.9.</num>
    <text>Except when in process of being collected or emptied, all containers shall be kept and stored on the premises at all times in rooms or compartments which comply with the provisions of D.C. Building Code or in any other location not prohibited by District
      laws or regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.10.</num>
    <text>If the place of storage is outside the premises, the containers shall be kept in a location where the containers shall not be unsightly and shall not cause a nuisance to residents of the premises or residents of neighboring premises.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.11.</num>
    <text>If possible, the containers shall be screened from the view of the public by an attractive enclosure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.12.</num>
    <text>The place of storage of the containers shall be one from which the containers may be safely moved to the location where the containers are emptied or collected.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.13.</num>
    <text>The location where containers are emptied or collected shall be one to which collection vehicles have safe and convenient access and which shall be suitably equipped, adequately illuminated, and of sufficient size for the safe loading or emptying
      of the containers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.14.</num>
    <text>The place of storage of the containers and the location where the containers are emptied or loaded shall be subject to approval by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.15.</num>
    <text>Containers shall be compatible in all respects (including, without limitation, dimensions and loading mechanisms) with the collection vehicles which service those containers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.16.</num>
    <text>Containers in which tenants are required or permitted to deposit solid waste shall be of types which can safely, easily, and conveniently be opened and closed by all tenants using the containers, and while available for tenant use shall be kept in
      a place which provides safe and convenient access.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.17.</num>
    <text>Containers shall meet the following specifications:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be constructed of continuously welded steel with all welds and edges ground smooth;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be capable of holding seven hundred pounds of solid waste (refuse) per cubic yard of capacity (700 lbs./yd.3), when at rest and during loading and unloading without permanent distortion;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Have adequate provision of reinforcement, stiffening, and protection at point of high stress of wear;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Hold liquids without leaking and be equipped with a drain plug at the bottom on one end; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Have heavy duty skids or rollers or other devices to keep the bottom of the container off the ground and reduce wear when the container is moved.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.18.</num>
    <text>Containers shall have tight-fitting doors or lids which shall meet the following specifications:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be attached by means of heavy duty hinges;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be equipped with counterbalance springs wherever necessary to prevent destructive or dangerous overwinging;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Be reinforced to prevent bending and warping; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Completely seal the container to prevent rodents, insects, and other pest from entering.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.19.</num>
    <text>The Director shall keep and make available to the public a list of containers which meet the physical specifications prescribed in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.20.</num>
    <text>Unless made of stainless steel or another material not subject to corrosion or wear, containers shall be completely primed and painted inside and out with corrosion-resisting primer and paint.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.21.</num>
    <text>Containers shall be repainted whenever the metal shows through the paint and whenever necessary to prevent them from becoming unsightly.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.22.</num>
    <text>Each solid waste (refuse) containerization system shall be inspected once each year by the Director to ascertain that the system complies with the specifications prescribed in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.23.</num>
    <text>All approved multiple-use containers used for the containment of solid waste (refuse) in the District shall contain a printed statement of approval on a pressure sensitive backed label (serially numbered) in a conspicuous place). The label shall be
      affixed by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.24.</num>
    <text>Containers shall have painted in block letters at least four inches (4 in.) high on one vertical side the name and business telephone number of the licensed private collector, the capacity of the container in cubic yards and the official tare weights
      of the containers in pounds. The posted tare weights shall be certified by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>806.25.</num>
    <text>The permit approval and compliance provisions of this chapter (§§810 and 811) shall not apply to the approval procedures for solid waste (refuse) containerization systems.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 26 DCR 6221 (January 5, 1979), incorporating text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 359 (November 3, 1978), 5T DCRR §§11(a)-(i) (September 21, 1970).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR&amp;#8217;S NOTE</heading>
      <text>The Building Code referred to in this section has been superseded by 0 C Law 6-216, Construction Codes Approval and Amendments Act of 1986, effective March 21, 1987. Section 12 of D C Law 6.216 provides that the construction regulations existing
        prior to March 21, 1987, remain in effect for projects having reached specified stages of completion. D C Law 6-216 adopted the 1984 National BOCA Codes, and the 1985 D.C. Supplement to the National BOCA Codes. Effective November 27 1992 (39 DCR
        8665), the 1984 BOCA Codes, and the 1985 D.C. Supplement to the National BOCA Codes were superseded by the adoption of the 1990 BOCA Codes, and the 1992 D.C. Supplement to the BOCA Codes.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>