<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-1009</num>
  <heading>VALIDITY OF SIGNATURES ON PETITIONS (§ 3-1009)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1009.1.</num>
    <text>The signature on a petition shall be made by the person whose signature it purports to be and not by any other person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1009.2.</num>
    <text>Registered voters who are unable to sign their names may make their marks in the space provided for signatures. These marks shall not be counted as valid signatures unless the person(s) witnessing the marks has attached an affidavit to the petition,
      wherein it is stated that the contents of the petition were explained to the signatory and that the affiant witnessed their marks.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1009.3.</num>
    <text>The petition shall also contain the signer’s printed or typed name, residence address at which the signer is registered to vote as shown on the Board’s records, ward number, and the date signed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1009.4.</num>
    <text>A signature may not be counted as valid unless all required information is provided.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1009.5.</num>
    <text>If a person has signed an initiative or referendum petition more than once, only one (1) signature shall be counted for that person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1009.6.</num>
    <text>The circulator of a petition page may not act as witness to his or her own petition signature on that page.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1009.7.</num>
    <text>If a person who has signed a petition is a qualified registered elector in a ward other than that which was indicated on the petition sheet, that person’s signature shall be counted from the proper ward in which he or she resides.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1009.8.</num>
    <text>When some but not all signatures on a petition have been signed outside the presence of the circulator, only those signatures signed outside the circulator’s presence shall be invalid, and the remaining signatures on the sheet shall be deemed valid
      if there are no other defects in the signatures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1009.9.</num>
    <text>In addition to the signature of the registered voter, the petition shall contain the voter’s current residence address and the date the voter signed the petition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1009.10.</num>
    <text>A signature shall not be counted as valid in any of the following circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The signer’s voter registration was designated &amp;#8220;inactive&amp;#8221; on the voter roll pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 1-1001.07(j)(2) (2011 Repl.) at the time the petition was signed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The signer, according to the Board’s records, was not registered to vote at the address listed on the petition at the time the petition was signed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The signer is not a &amp;#8220;duly registered voter;&amp;#8221;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The signature is not dated;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The petition does not include the printed or typed address of the signer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The petition does not include the printed or typed name of the signer where the signature is not sufficiently legible for identification;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The signer was also the circulator of the same petition sheet where the signature appears; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The circulator of the petition sheet did not meet the petition circulator requirements set forth in § 1005.1 at the time the petition was signed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1009.11.</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, a &amp;#8220;duly registered voter&amp;#8221; shall be a registered qualified elector who is registered to vote at the address listed on the petition as shown on the Board’s voter registration records and whose registration
      is not designated &amp;#8220;inactive&amp;#8221; on the voter roll at the time the petition is signed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1009.12.</num>
    <text>A registered voter may submit a written notarized request to the Board to disallow the voter’s signature from being counted on the petition; provided, that the request shall be received by the Board prior to the time the petition is filed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 43 D.C. Reg. 103, 115-16 (January 12, 1996); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 6977 (August 27, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 4773, 4774 (May 11, 2012); as corrected by an
        Errata Notice published at 59 DCR 5193 (May 18, 2012); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 5582 (April 12, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>