<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-6201</num>
  <heading>UTILITY ALLOWANCE (§ 14-6201)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6201.1.</num>
    <text>The DCHA shall establish on a project basis, in accordance with Federal regulations, appropriate utility allowances for tenants with individual utility meters who pay for their own electricity or gas.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6201.2.</num>
    <text>Allowances shall be based on average consumption levels and information provided by the D.C. Public Service Commission regarding rates approved for utility companies supplying electricity or gas to those dwelling units.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6201.3.</num>
    <text>Average consumption level calculations shall take into account major equipment provided by DCHA at the project or property, and shall make allowance for minor equipment normally provided by the tenant, except that items provided by the tenant listed
      in § 6202.1 of this chapter shall not be considered in development of average consumption calculations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6201.4.</num>
    <text>As utility rates in the District of Columbia are revised, DCHA shall revise its utility allowances, when the computation of the rate change(s) in relation to DCHA’s utility allowance results in a change in excess of ten percent (10%) in the monetary
      allowance for a specific utility. When DCHA revises a utility allowance, it shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Provide notice to tenants regarding increases or decreases in tenant rent due to revised utility allowances;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Make tenant rent increases effective at the start of the first month following thirty (30) day notice to the tenant, and make tenant rent decreases effective at the start of the first month following the change in utility allowance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Prepare and execute a special supplement to the dwelling lease, with an explanation of the reason(s) for the change, consistent with § 6200.9 of this chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6201.5.</num>
    <text>Actual charges billed directly to the tenant shall be his or her responsibility, regardless of whether the charges are above or below the utility allowance approved by DCHA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6201.6.</num>
    <text>The DCHA shall also establish appropriate utility allowances, on a project basis, for tenants with checkmeters where DCHA pays the utility supplier but individual units have checkmeters that measure consumption rates for the unit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6201.7.</num>
    <text>The DCHA shall be authorized to obtain records of tenants’ utility consumption and related charges billed data from utility companies for tenants with individual utility meters who pay for their own electricity or gas.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 7973, 8004-8005 (December 26, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>