<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-1718</num>
  <heading>DECISIONS OF THE BOARD (§ 23-1718)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1718.1.</num>
    <text>Within ninety (90) calendar days after the close of the record, the Board shall render its written decision accompanied by Findings of Fact and Conclusions of Law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1718.2.</num>
    <text>Findings of Fact and Conclusions of Law shall consist of a concise statement of the Board&amp;#8217;s conclusions on each contested issue of fact, and shall be based solely upon evidence contained in the record and facts of which the Board properly
      took judicial notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1718.3.</num>
    <text>Findings of Fact and Conclusions of Law shall be supported by and in accordance with reliable, probative, and substantial evidence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1718.4.</num>
    <text>In cases where a hearing for an original application or the transfer of an existing license to a new location is sought, the Findings of Fact and Conclusions of Law shall include, but not be limited, to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The boundaries of the neighborhood;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The appropriateness of the location for which the license in sought, in accordance with D.C. Official Code §§ 25-313 and 25-314, and § 400 of this title; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A finding as to the wishes of the persons voting, owning property or residing in the vicinity.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1718.5.</num>
    <text>All written decisions of the Board shall be available for public inspection and copying at a reasonable cost.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 4309 (April 30, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12991 (December 26, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>