<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-2368</num>
  <heading>REFEREE TESTS (§ 15-2368)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2368.1.</num>
    <text>Upon a customer’s written application to the Commission, a test shall be made of the customer&amp;#8217;s meter as soon as practicable that shall be witnessed by a representative of the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2368.2.</num>
    <text>A one dollar ($1) fee shall be paid at the same time of the application by check or money order made payable to the gas corporation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2368.3.</num>
    <text>On receipt of the request from a customer, the Commission shall notify the gas corporation, and the gas corporation shall not knowingly remove or adjust the meter until instructed by the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2368.4.</num>
    <text>The customer, or his or her representative, may be present when the meter is tested but shall not interfere with the testing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2368.5.</num>
    <text>Included in the referee test of the meter shall be a test for the accuracy of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The pressure device;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The temperature correcting device, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The index; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any other device or instrument used in measuring gas consumption.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2368.6.</num>
    <text>A written report of the results of the test shall be sent to the customer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2368.7.</num>
    <text>If a consumer complaint hearing is held at the Commission pertaining to the meter accuracy, all relevant documentation shall be made a part of the official record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2368.8.</num>
    <text>If the meter is found to over-register or under-register consumption by more than two percent (2%), the gas corporation shall credit the customer for the one dollar ($1) testing fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 7938, 7947 (November 4, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 7 (January 4, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>