<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-2377</num>
  <heading>PRESSURE OF GAS SUPPLIED TO CONSUMERS (ยง 15-2377)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2377.1.</num>
    <text>The gas supplied by corporation low pressure (LP) district regulator station shall be maintained at a pressure of not less than six inches (6 in.) or more than ten inches (10 in.) of water pressure. Certain customers, however, require higher pressures
      which may be mutually agreed upon by the customer and the gas corporation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2377.2.</num>
    <text>The daily variation in the low pressure network system, during any day at any gauge station, shall not exceed two and a half inches (2.5 in.) of water pressure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2377.3.</num>
    <text>There shall be supplied, installed, and maintained by each gas corporation pressure gauges which shall furnish an accurate record of the pressure maintained throughout the District of Columbia. The records shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The type, number, and locations of pressure gauges shall be approved by the Commission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The gauges shall be subject to inspection and test by the Commission at any time;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The original record of each and every gauge shall be available for inspection by the Commission and shall be preserved for at least one (1) year;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The maximum and minimum pressures measured at each gauge during all gauge periods, and the number and magnitude of daily variations in excess of the daily variation provided for in ยง 2377.2, shall be reported to the Commission monthly, on or before
        the tenth (10th) day of each month; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Additional gauges shall be installed whenever and wherever ordered by the Commission.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2377.4.</num>
    <text>In cases where it is necessary to install a pressure regulator or governor on the consumer&amp;#8217;s premises ahead of the consumer&amp;#8217;s meter, the regulator shall be installed in accordance with the Gas Fitting Regulations for the District
      of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2377.5.</num>
    <text>The gas corporation shall inspect the regulator and vent pipes when installed, and thereafter at intervals not greater than the time of the periodic test for the meter it supplies, to determine that they are in safe operating condition. If found faulty
      in any respect, the fault shall be corrected immediately.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 7938, 7952 (November 4, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 7 (January 4, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>