<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>4-1210</num>
  <heading>ROLES OF MAYORS OFFICE ON AFRICAN AFFAIRS, THE MAYORS OFFICE ON ASIAN ANDACIFIC ISLANDER AFFAIRS, AND THE MAYORS OFFICE ON LATINO AFFAIRS (CONSULTATIVEGENCIES) (§ 4-1210)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1210.1.</num>
    <text>OAA, OAPIA, and OLA (collectively referred to as “consultative agencies”) shall serve as consultative bodies to the LA Director and the OHR Director to develop and update covered entities’ BLAPs, and assist in the implementation of the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1210.2.</num>
    <text>The consultative agencies shall furnish demographic data on their respective communities to covered entities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1210.3.</num>
    <text>The consultative agencies shall also provide outreach to LEP/NEP communities in the District on the Act and assist the LACs to develop and implement outreach efforts</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1210.4.</num>
    <text>The consultative agencies shall assist OHR in the development of quality control instruments for their respective languages.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1210.5.</num>
    <text>The consultative agencies shall provide technical assistance to the District of Columbia Department of Human Resources (“DCHR”) and the personnel authorities of covered entities who have independent hiring authority (collectively personnel authority”)
      regarding issues related to the recruitment and hiring of bilingual public contact personnel.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1210.6.</num>
    <text>The consultative agencies shall assist their constituents with language access concerns by first referring the concern to the LAC of the entity in question. If the concern is not addressed by the entity, the consultative agency shall refer the allegation
      to the attention of the LA Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 6348 (June 6, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>