<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-1328</num>
  <heading>USA PATRIOT ACT COMPLIANCE (§ 18-1328)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1328.1.</num>
    <text>All drivers renewing or applying for a hazardous material endorsement shall pass a security threat assessment conducted by the Transportation Security Administration of the Federal Department of Homeland Security, and meet all other requirements in
      49 CFR Part 1572.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1328.2.</num>
    <text>[REPEALED]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1328.3.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of a finding by the Transportation Security Administration that an applicant or permittee represents a security threat, the Director shall refuse to issue, or shall immediately revoke any hazardous materials endorsement effective 5 days
      after mailing a notice of revocation to the permittee’s address in the Department’s records.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1328.4.</num>
    <text>At least sixty (60) days before the expiration date of the CDL or a hazardous materials endorsement, the Department of Motor Vehicles shall notify the holder of a hazardous materials endorsement that the holder must pass a Transportation Security
      Administration security threat assessment process as part of his or her application for renewal of the hazardous materials endorsement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1328.5.</num>
    <text>The notice shall advise the driver that, in order to expedite the security screening process, he or she should file a renewal application as soon as possible, but no later than thirty (30) days before the expiration date of the hazardous materials
      endorsement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1328.6.</num>
    <text>An individual who does not successfully complete the Transportation Security Administration security threat assessment process referenced in this subsection shall not be issued a hazardous materials endorsement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 10913 (November 26, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 5758 (June 17, 2005); as amended by as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 2206 (March 24, 2006); as amended by Notice
        of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 10912, 10915 (November 19, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>