<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-1315</num>
  <heading>COMMERCIAL DRIVERS LICENSE KNOWLEDGE TEST (§ 18-1315)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1315.1.</num>
    <text>Applicants for a commercial driver’s license shall be required to successfully pass, with a minimum score of eighty percent (80%), one or more knowledge tests meeting the standards set forth in 49 CFR 383. The knowledge tests include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A general knowledge test, which shall be administered to all applicants;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A passenger transport test, which shall be administered to persons who apply to operate vehicles that carry more than fifteen (15) passengers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An air brake test, which shall be administered to persons who apply to operate trucks and buses with air brakes. Applicants who fail or do not take the air brake test shall have a restriction placed on their driver’s license as provided in § 1313.3(b);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A combination vehicle test, which shall be administered to persons who apply to operate combination vehicles;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A hazardous materials test, which shall be administered to persons who apply to operate vehicles that haul hazardous materials. Drivers who possess a commercial driver’s license with a Hazardous Material Endorsement shall meet the following requirements:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Pass a hazardous material test either upon renewal of a commercial driver’s license; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Pass a hazardous material test upon conversion of a commercial driver’s license from another state;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A tanker test, which shall be administered to persons who apply to operate vehicles that haul liquids;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A double/triple trailer test, which shall be administered to persons who apply to operate vehicles that pull double or triple trailers; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>A School Bus test, which shall be administered to persons who apply to operate school buses.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>An air brake test, which shall be administered to persons who apply to operate a vehicle with air brakes.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1315.2.</num>
    <text>The information needed to successfully pass the commercial driver’s license knowledge tests shall be provided in the District of Columbia Commercial Driver’s License Manual and shall meet the requirements in 49 CFR 391.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1315.3.</num>
    <text>The Director, or his or her designee, may offer the knowledge tests provided for in this section orally.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1315.4.</num>
    <text>[REPEALED]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1315.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant may take the applicable commercial driver’s license knowledge test no more than six (6) times within a twelve (12) month period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 10913 (November 26, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 5758 (June 17, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 2206 (March 24, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published
        at 56 DCR 5764 (July 17, 2009); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 10921, 10915 (November 19, 2010); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 9016 (October 21, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>