<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-1305</num>
  <heading>COMMERCIAL DRIVER&amp;#8217;S LICENSE REQUIRED (§ 18-1305)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1305.1.</num>
    <text>No resident of the District of Columbia shall drive a commercial vehicle unless he or she has been issued a valid commercial driver’s license or a valid commercial driver’s instruction license, which authorizes him or her to operate the following
      types of vehicles:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A single vehicle, or a combination of vehicles, with a gross vehicle weight rating of over twenty-six thousand (26,000) pounds, or a lesser rating as determined by Federal regulations, but not less than a gross vehicle weight rating of ten thousand
        (10,000) pounds;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A vehicle designed to transport more than fifteen (15) passengers, including the driver;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A vehicle used to transport a material found to be hazardous in accordance with the District of Columbia Hazardous Materials Transportation and Motor Carrier Safety Act of 1988, effective March 16, 1989 (D.C. Law 7-190; D.C. Official Code § 8-1401
        et seq.) and that are required to be placarded under Federal regulations, 49 CFR part 172, subpart F; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A school bus or a multi-purpose school vehicle.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1305.2.</num>
    <text>No resident under the age of twenty-one (21) may be issued a commercial driver’s instruction license or commercial driver’s license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1305.3.</num>
    <text>No person shall drive a commercial motor vehicle in this jurisdiction unless the person holds a commercial driver’s license with the applicable class and endorsements for the vehicle(s) he or she is driving, except when driving under a commercial
      driver’s instruction license and accompanied by the holder of a commercial driver’s license for the vehicle being driven.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1305.4.</num>
    <text>Commercial drivers shall be held to the same standards that apply to anyone who drives in the District of Columbia without a valid operator’s permit, as provided in § 7(d) of the District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925, effective September 27, 1985
      (D.C. Official Code § 50-1401.01(d)).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 10913 (November 26, 2004); as amended by as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 2206 (March 24, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 10071 (July 12, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>