<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-1307</num>
  <heading>COMMERCIAL MOTOR VEHICLE DRIVER RESPONSIBILITY (§ 18-1307)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1307.1.</num>
    <text>A person who operates a commercial motor vehicle and is domiciled in the District of Columbia shall have a commercial driver’s license issued by the Department of Motor Vehicles.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1307.2.</num>
    <text>When the holder of a commercial driver’s license changes his or her name, mailing address or residence, he or she shall file an application for a duplicate commercial driver’s license with the Department of Motor Vehicles within thirty (30) calendar
      days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1307.3.</num>
    <text>A commercial motor vehicle driver shall notify his or her employer by the end of the next business day when any of the following occurs:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The driver’s license is suspended, revoked or cancelled by the District of Columbia or by any state;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The driver has been disqualified from the operation of a commercial motor vehicle for any period; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The driver has received an out-of-service order.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1307.4.</num>
    <text>A commercial motor vehicle driver convicted of committing a traffic infraction (except parking) in any jurisdiction shall notify his or his employer within thirty (30) calendar days of the finding of liability, regardless of the type of vehicle he
      or she was operating.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1307.5.</num>
    <text>A commercial motor vehicle driver convicted of committing a traffic infraction (except parking) in any other jurisdiction shall notify the Department of Motor Vehicles within thirty (30) calendar days of the finding of liability, regardless of the
      type of vehicle he or she was operating.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 10913 (November 26, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>