<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-1327</num>
  <heading>PHYSICAL QUALIFICATIONS AND EXAMINATIONS (§ 18-1327)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1327.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall be issued a new or renewed commercial driver’s license unless he or she is physically qualified and, except as provided in the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Regulations (FMCSR), 49 CFR 391.49, possesses an original of a medical examiner’s
      certificate, not more than two (2) years old, reflecting that he or she is physically qualified to drive a commercial vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1327.2.</num>
    <text>A person shall be considered physically qualified to drive a motor vehicle if that person meets the requirement in 49 CFR 391.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1327.3.</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, a medical examination to determine an applicant’s physical qualification to operate a commercial motor vehicle shall be performed by a licensed doctor of medicine.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1327.4.</num>
    <text>A licensed ophthalmologist or optometrist may perform so much of the medical examination as pertains to visual acuity, field of vision, and the ability to recognize colors as specified in § 1327.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1327.5.</num>
    <text>The medical examination shall be performed, and its results shall be recorded, in substantial accordance with the instructions and examination forms that are prescribed in the FMCSR, 49 CFR 391.43.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1327.6.</num>
    <text>A physician who performs a medical examination pursuant to § 1327.3, after completion of such examination, shall provide the commercial driver a signed copy of the forms provided for in § 1327.5.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1327.7.</num>
    <text>Persons issued a District of Columbia commercial driver’s license with a Hazardous Material Endorsement shall present medical documentation, as provided for in § 1327.5, to the Department of Motor Vehicles every two (2) years, beginning from the date
      of issuance of their commercial driver’s license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1327.8.</num>
    <text>Any commercial motor vehicle driver whose ability to perform his or her normal duties has been impaired by a physical or mental injury or disease must be reexamined and submit the certification required by § 1327.3.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 10913 (November 26, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 5758 (June 17, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>