<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-1000</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 11-1000)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1000.1.</num>
    <text>The Mixed Use Diplomatic (D) Overlay District is established to implement the Foreign Missions Act, approved August 24, 1982 (96 Stat. 282, as amended; D.C. Official Code §§ 6-1301 to 6-1315 (formerly codified at D.C. Code §§ 5-1201 to 5-1215 (1994
      Repl.))).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.2.</num>
    <text>The D Overlay District shall be mapped at suitable locations in implementation of the Foreign Missions Act and the Foreign Missions and International Organizations element of the Comprehensive Plan.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.3.</num>
    <text>The D Overlay District shall be mapped in combination with another district and not instead of the underlying district.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.4.</num>
    <text>All uses, buildings, and structures permitted in accordance with this chapter, and the appropriate regulations of the underlying district with which the mapped D Overlay District is combined, shall be permitted in the combined districts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.5.</num>
    <text>All restrictions and prohibitions provided with respect to either of the districts combined in accordance with this chapter shall also apply, except as specifically modified by this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1000.6.</num>
    <text>The criteria and procedures in this chapter also apply to chancery uses in R-5-D, R-5-E, and SP Districts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is the Zoning Act of 1938 (52 Stat. 797, as amended; D.C. Official Code §§ 6-641.01 to 6-641.15 (formerly codified at D.C. Code §§ 5-413 to 5-432 (1994 Repl. &amp;#038; 1999 Supp.))), and §
        206 of the Foreign Missions Act, approved August 24, 1982 (96 Stat. 283, 286; D.C. Official Code § 6-1306 (formerly codified at D.C. Code § 5-1206 (1994 Repl.))).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 30 DCR 3270, 3272 (July 1, 1983); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 6623 (September 30, 1994); and Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text
        of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8436 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>