<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-539</num>
  <heading>ASSIGNMENT OF STATIONARY ROADWAY VENDING LOCATIONS (ยง 24-539)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>539.1.</num>
    <text>For a period of one (1) year from the publication in the District of Columbia Register of a notice of final rulemaking adopting this chapter, MPD shall oversee the lottery for stationary roadway Vending Locations. Upon the expiration of the yearlong
      period, the DCRA Director shall oversee the lottery.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>539.2.</num>
    <text>Stationary Roadway Vending Locations shall be assigned as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>All Stationary Roadway Vending Locations shall be allocated by lottery;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The lottery shall be conducted monthly, with Vending Locations allocated to a vendor by the following days of the week:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Monday;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Tuesday;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Wednesday;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Thursday;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Friday;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Saturday; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Sunday.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>There shall be equal allocation in the lottery of Class A and Class B licenses; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>No vendor shall be issued Stationary Roadway Vending Site Permits for more than two (2) Stationary Roadway Vending Sites at any one time.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>539.3.</num>
    <text>No Stationary Roadway Vending Site Permit shall be distributed until full payment is received from the roadway vendor or person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>539.4.</num>
    <text>A vendor shall have thirty-five (35) calendar days from the billing date to remit payment for the Stationary Roadway Vending Locations the vendor has won. Failure to remit payment shall allow the DCRA Director to rescind the offer to the winning vendor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>539.5.</num>
    <text>The DCRA Director may lottery off unclaimed Stationary Roadway Vending Locations until all Stationary Roadway Vending Locations are awarded.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>539.6.</num>
    <text>The DCRA Director shall register licensed roadway vendors, which may include both stationary roadway vendors and mobile roadway vendors, for participation in the lottery by assigning each vendor a registration number.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>539.7.</num>
    <text>No vendor may participate in the lottery for Stationary Roadway Vending Locations unless the vendor holds a valid Vending Business License for roadway vending and is registered for the lottery.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>539.8.</num>
    <text>No vendor may operate on more than one (1) Stationary Roadway Vending Location per day, and only one (1) vendor may occupy an assigned Stationary Roadway Vending Location as described on the Stationary Roadway Vending Site Permit, unless otherwise
      specified by the DCRA Director on the Stationary Roadway Vending Site Permit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>539.9.</num>
    <text>No lottery registration or Stationary Roadway Vending Location assignment or permits may be transferred from a vendor to any other person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>539.10.</num>
    <text>The DCRA Director may contract out the function of performing the lottery for Stationary Roadway Vending Locations; provided that the lottery may be subject to any government-required audit or review.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 13055 (September 20, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>