<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-574</num>
  <heading>VENDING DEPOT REQUIREMENTS (§ 24-574)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>574.1.</num>
    <text>Vending depots servicing vending vehicles or carts with Class A Vending Business Licenses shall provide all of the following services to a vendor in accordance with Chapter 37, Subtitle A (Food and Food Operations) of Title 25 of the DCMR:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Storage of the vending vehicle or cart;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Food preparation, including approved food handling areas, as needed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Proper storage of inventory, such as food, utensils and supplies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Basic maintenance and cleaning, including:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Hot and cold water;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Sloped and properly drained cleaning area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Potable water; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Electrical outlets; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Proper disposal of trash and food waste, such as garbage and liquid.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>574.2.</num>
    <text>The operator of a vending depot shall maintain a ledger that includes current information on the name, license number, and address of each vendor and supplier doing business with the operator. This ledger shall be made available during regular business
      hours for inspection by any duly authorized District government agent in accordance with § 3701, Subtitle A of Title 25 of the DCMR.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>574.3.</num>
    <text>The operator of a vending depot may offer additional services to a vendor, such as the wholesale sale of food or beverages or towing services; provided, that the vending depot shall not require that a vendor accept any additional services as part
      of the contract to provide the minimum services set forth in § 574.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>574.4.</num>
    <text>The operator of a vending depot shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Comply with all applicable laws and regulations regarding registration of the person’s business with the Office of Tax and Revenue and DCRA;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Obtain all necessary business licenses from DCRA; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Comply with the Subtitle A of Title 25 of the DCMR and all applicable standards imposed by DOH or other relevant agencies.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 13055 (September 20, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>