<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-529</num>
  <heading>VENDING LOCATIONS[COLON] NATIONALS PARK VENDING ZONE (§ 24-529)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>529.1.</num>
    <text>The streets listed in this section shall constitute the Nationals Park Vending Zone, in which sidewalk Vending Locations shall be allowed on the following streets and in the following numbers:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>East side of First Street, SE, between N Street, SE, and N Place, SE – two (2) Vending Locations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>East side of First Street, SE, between N Place, SE, and O Street, SE – two (2) Vending Locations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>West side of Half Street, SE, between M Street, SE, and N Street, SE –</text>
    </level>
    <text>seven (7) Vending Locations; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>North side of N Street, SE, between Half Street, SE, and Van Street, SE – three (3) Vending Locations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>529.2.</num>
    <text>The DDOT Director may, at his or her discretion, approve additional sidewalk Vending Locations in the Nationals Park Vending Zone in addition to those listed in § 529.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>529.3.</num>
    <text>The DCRA Director shall assign the Vending Locations in the Nationals Park Vending Zone by lottery.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>529.4.</num>
    <text>Applicants may apply electronically, via designated computer kiosks, for each monthly lottery by visiting the DCRA Business Licensing Center, which shall maintain information regarding the application process and qualifications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>529.5.</num>
    <text>Winners of each monthly lottery shall be notified by phone, first-class mail, or electronic mail, and by being listed on the DCRA website (http://dcra.dc.gov).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6846, 6850 (September 29, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 558 (January 12, 1990); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 13055 (September 20, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>