<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-573</num>
  <heading>SOLICITING[COLON] GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 24-573)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>573.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall solicit any person from a street, sidewalk, or other public space, or in any way interfere with the free passage of any person along any street, sidewalk, or other public space, for the purpose of inducing that person to do any of
      the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Buy any merchandise, food, or service;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Patronize any hotel, motel, inn, or boarding house; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Patronize any place of entertainment or amusement.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>573.2.</num>
    <text>No person shall solicit any other person within or on the grounds of any railroad or bus station or depot, or on public space in the District, for the purpose of securing a passenger or passengers for transportation for hire, unless properly licensed
      and permitted to do so by the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>573.3.</num>
    <text>No person shall, on any public highway in the District, solicit employment to guard, watch, wash, clean, repair, or paint, any automobile or other vehicle, except as provided for in Title 18 of the DCMR.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>573.4.</num>
    <text>No person shall remain in front of or enter any store or vending business where goods are sold at retail for the purpose of enticing away or in any manner interfering with any person who may be in front of or who may have entered the store or vending
      business for the purpose of buying.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>573.5.</num>
    <text>Unless issued a valid Class D Vending Business License or engaged in a transaction with a Class D Vending Business Licensed vendor, no person shall sell or offer to sell tickets from the sidewalks, streets, or public spaces anywhere in the District
      for any sightseeing bus tours of any kind.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>573.6.</num>
    <text>Class D Vendors may only sell tickets in areas designated for that specific purpose, pursuant to § 573.7.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>573.7.</num>
    <text>Class D license holders who provide sightseeing bus services are authorized to vend from public space within ten feet (10 ft.) of a sign designating a stop of the sightseeing bus for which the person is selling tickets; provided, that the sign has
      been permitted and approved by the DDOT Director pursuant to § 3306 of Chapter 33 of Title 24 of the DCMR. No structure or fixture, including “A” frame signs, podiums, kiosks, or any other material, whether temporary or permanent, shall be placed
      in public space.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 13055 (September 20, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>