<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-555</num>
  <heading>OPERATIONAL STANDARDS[COLON] FOOD PREPARATION AND HANDLING (§ 24-555)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>555.1.</num>
    <text>All preparation, handling, transportation, and storage of food vended under this chapter shall be in compliance with:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An Act Relating to the adulteration of foods and drugs in the District of Columbia, approved February 17, 1898 (30 Stat. 246; D.C. Official Code §§ 48-101 et seq. (2009 Repl. &amp;#038; 2011 Supp.));</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Subtitle A (Food and Food Operations) of Title 25 (Food Operations and Community Hygiene) of the DCMR;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any other applicable law or regulation related to the preparation, handling, transportation, or storage of food;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Requirements of, and conditions imposed by, the health inspection certificate, including any plans or standards approved or imposed as part of the issuance of the health inspection certificate; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any applicable standards established by DOH.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>555.2.</num>
    <text>No food vending equipment shall be used for purposes other than those authorized by the DOH Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>555.3.</num>
    <text>No food may be vended from a vending vehicle, cart, or stand unless there is a person in charge on site at the time of the preparation, handling, and sale of the food who holds a valid:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Food Protection Manager Certificate issued by the Conference of Food Protection Standards for Accreditation of Food Protection Manager Certification Programs in accordance with § 203 of Subtitle A (Food and Food Operations) of Title 25 of the DCMR;
        and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>DOH-issued a Certified Food Protection Manager Identification Card in accordance with § 203 of Subtitle A (Food and Food Operations) of Title 25 of the DCMR;</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 13055 (September 20, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>