<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-510</num>
  <heading>VENDING SITE PERMIT[COLON] ISSUANCE (§ 24-510)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>510.1.</num>
    <text>Upon the submission of a completed application, the DCRA Director shall issue a Vending Site Permit if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The applicant holds:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A valid Vending Business License; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A current receipt for payment of all relevant Vending Business License fees;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The applicant has identified and applied for a Vending Site Permit for a Vending Location that meets DDOT standards, pursuant to §§ 524-528, or through the creation of a Vending Development Zone, pursuant to § 570;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A vendor shall have a right of preference for the issuance of a Vending Site Permit for a Vending Location if:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The individual received a site permit for the same location pursuant to the District of Columbia Department of Transportation and Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Vending Consolidation of Public Space and Licensing Authorities Temporary
        Act of 2006, effective March 8, 2007 (D.C. Law 16- 252; 54 DCR 3037);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The individual has vended in the location continuously and exclusively without sale, assignment, transfer, or other conveyance of the location to another vendor or individual, whether sold, assigned, transferred, or conveyed for money or anything
        else of value; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The vendor is vending in a location that is in compliance with this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The merchandise, food, or services is authorized to be vended at the available Vending Location;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The applicant provides a Clean Hands Certification; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The applicant has paid all the required fees.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The DCRA Director may use a lottery to assign Vending Site Permits for designated unoccupied Vending locations, if necessary.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>510.2.</num>
    <text>No more than one (1) vendor may occupy an assigned Vending Location, unless the DCRA Director specifies on the Vending Site Permit that the Vending Location is subject to a shared site agreement between several licensed vendors.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>510.3.</num>
    <text>The Vending Site Permit shall delineate the specific site, zone, dates and times of validity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>510.4.</num>
    <text>A Vending Site Permit is issued only to the permittee and may not be sold, transferred, conveyed, or otherwise assigned to any other person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 74-39 (21 DCR 1285 (December 23, 1974)); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 4935 (October 5, 1984); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 32 DCR 134 (March 8, 1985); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at
        32 DCR 5746 (October 11, 1985); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 32 DCR 7586 (December 27, 1985); as amended by § 3 of the District of Columbia Noise Control Act of 1977 Amendment Act of 1986, effective February 24, 1987 (D.C. Law 6-180;
        33 DCR 7660 (December 12, 1986)); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 2021 (March 27, 1987); as amended by D.C. Act published at 45 DCR 1172 (March 6, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 5953 (June 24, 2005);
        as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 8520 (September 16, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 13055 (September 20, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>