<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-538</num>
  <heading>ASSIGNMENT OF SIDEWALK VENDING LOCATIONS (§ 24-538)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>538.1.</num>
    <text>Designated unoccupied sidewalk Vending Locations identified by the DCRA Director and approved by the DDOT Director may be assigned to licensed sidewalk vendors through a lottery conducted by the DCRA Director. No vendor or applicant may participate
      in a lottery for unoccupied sidewalk Vending Locations unless the vendor holds a Vending Business License or the person holds a current receipt for payment of Vending Business License fees for sidewalk vending and is registered for the lottery.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>538.2.</num>
    <text>In addition to the lottery conducted pursuant to § 538.1, a vendor may, when submitting an application for a Vending Site Permit pursuant to § 510.1(b), identify a potential sidewalk Vending Location that the vendor believes meets the DDOT standards
      in §§ 524-528. If the DDOT Director approves the location as an authorized sidewalk Vending Location, that Vending Location shall be assigned to the vendor who first identified it on his or her completed and accepted Vending Site Permit application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>538.3.</num>
    <text>No holder of a Vending Business License shall be assigned more than five (5) sidewalk Vending Locations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>538.4.</num>
    <text>No more than one (1) vendor may occupy an assigned Vending Location, unless the DCRA Director specifies on the Vending Site Permit that the Vending Location is subject to a shared site agreement between several licensed vendors.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>538.5.</num>
    <text>No lottery registration or Vending Location assignment may be transferred, sold, conveyed, or assigned from the assigned vendor to any other person. Any attempt to transfer a lottery registration or Vending Location assignment will disqualify from
      the lottery both the vendor seeking to transfer the registration and the person seeking to obtain it.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>538.6.</num>
    <text>The DCRA Director may contract out the function of performing the lotteries for sidewalk Vending Locations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>538.7.</num>
    <text>No Vending Site Permit shall be distributed until full payment is received from the vendor or person.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>538.8.</num>
    <text>A vendor shall have thirty-five (35) calendar days from the billing date to remit payment for the sidewalk Vending Locations the vendor has won. Failure to remit payment shall allow the DCRA Director to rescind the Vending Site Permit offer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 13055 (September 20, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>