<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-511</num>
  <heading>FRAUD, MISREPRESENTATION, LARCENY, AND OTHER UNLAWFUL ACTIVITIES PROHIBITED (ยง1-511)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>511.1.</num>
    <text>No owner, agent, or employee of a taxicab company, association, or fleet, or his or her representative or affiliate, while performing duties and responsibilities for the taxicab company, association, or fleet, shall commit or attempt to commit, alone
      or in concert with another, any act of fraud, misrepresentation, or larceny. Examples of fraud, larceny, or misrepresentation include, but are not limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Falsification or counterfeiting of an official document;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Knowingly accepting falsified, counterfeit, or duplicated official documents;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Making a false, misleading, deceptive, or materially incomplete statement, written or oral, to the Commission or a Commission representative or on an application or in a communication to the Commission or Commission representative; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Knowingly concealing or misrepresenting the true ownership of a taxicab or a taxicab company, association, or fleet.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>511.2.</num>
    <text>An owner, agent, or employee of a taxicab company, association, or fleet or his or her representative or affiliate shall not willfully perform an act of omission or commission that is against the best interest of the public, even if the act is not
      specifically prohibited by these rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>511.3.</num>
    <text>An owner, agent, or employee of a taxicab company, association, or fleet or his or her representative or affiliate shall not use or permit another person to use an office of the company, association, or fleet for an unlawful purpose.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>511.4.</num>
    <text>An owner, agent, or employee of a taxicab company, association, or fleet or his or her representative or affiliate shall not conceal evidence of a crime connected with the company, association, or fleet.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>511.5.</num>
    <text>An owner, agent, or employee of a taxicab company, association, or fleet or his or her representative or affiliate shall report immediately to the Commission and the appropriate law enforcement authority any attempt to use any office of the company,
      association, or fleet for any unlawful purpose.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>511.6.</num>
    <text>An owner, agent, or employee of a taxicab company, association, or fleet or his or her representative or affiliate shall not file with the Commission a statement that he or she knows or reasonably should know to be false, misleading, deceptive, or
      materially incomplete.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8549, 8559 (July 20, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>