<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-3301</num>
  <heading>PROHIBITION ON USE OF GOVERNMENT RESOURCES FOR CAMPAIGN-RELATED PURPOSES (ยง-3301)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3301.1.</num>
    <text>No District of Columbia government resources shall be used to support or oppose any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A candidate for elected office, whether partisan or nonpartisan; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An initiative, referendum, or recall measure, or a charter amendment referendum.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3301.2.</num>
    <text>Resources of the District of Columbia government shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The personal services of employees during their hours of work; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Nonpersonal services.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3301.3.</num>
    <text>Nonpersonal services shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Supplies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Materials;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Equipment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Office space;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Facilities; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Utilities, for example, telephone, gas, and electric services.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3301.4.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the prohibition set forth in ยง 3301.3, the following public officials may, as part of their official duties, express their views on a District of Columbia election:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Mayor;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Chairman of the Council;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Each Member of the Council;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The President of the State Board of Education; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Each Member of the State Board of Education.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 3161, 3191-93 (May 22, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 3233-3237 (April 21, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 2263, 2264 (March 19, 2010); as amended by Final
        Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 1402 (February 8, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11864 (August 16, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>