<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2532</num>
  <heading>STI PROGRAM –UNIT IDENTIFICATION (§ 29-2532)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2532.1.</num>
    <text>Participation in the STI Program is conditional on accepting a unit that passes a housing inspection and meets Fair Market Rent standards established for the District of Columbia by the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2532.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall be assigned one (1) unit in the Program’s unit inventory list. An applicant may also find a unit of their choice, except that the unit shall pass a housing inspection and shall not exceed HUD Fair Market Rent standards for their
      family size.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2532.3.</num>
    <text>To facilitate timely unit identification and entry into the STI Program, an applicant shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Make a reasonable effort to meet with the Provider’s representative in a timely manner to view a unit. Refusal to meet with the Provider’s representative three (3) times without good cause shall be considered not making a reasonable effort;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>After viewing a unit, submit a timely and complete application to the landlord; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Accept a unit that meets the HUD Fair Market Rent standards for their family size.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2532.4.</num>
    <text>Refusal to complete any of the requirements set forth in subsection 2532.3 shall result in the applicant’s loss of the apartment unit and placement at the bottom of the waiting list.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2532.5.</num>
    <text>A participant in the STI Program may move to an alternate unit at any time, as long as the participant:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Exits the existing lease with the landlord according to the terms of the lease or receives the landlord’s written approval to exit the lease without financial cost to the STI Program;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Identifies an alternate unit that passes a housing inspection and does not exceed the HUD Fair Market Rent standards for their family size;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Submits an application to the landlord within the necessary timeframe; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Accepts the alternate unit and provides the STI Program with all necessary information regarding the new unit.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2532.6.</num>
    <text>If requested by the participant, the STI Program will assist the participant identify an alternate unit that better meets their needs, to the extent possible considering the availability of units within the STI Program inventory and the needs of new
      applicants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 6438 (July 23, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice Emergency Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11353 (November 26, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergency Rulemaking published
        at 58 DCR 3007 (April 8, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 7442, 7479 (August 19, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>