<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2508</num>
  <heading>INTAKE FOR FAMILIES –PRIORITY DETERMINATION FOR SHELTER OR SUPPORTIVE HOUSING§ 29-2508)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2508.1</num>
    <text>2508.1 Based on the information received from the completed and signed application and an intake interview with the applicant, the intake center shall make a determination of priority for shelter and supportive housing in accordance with the following:</text>
    <text>Degree of homelessness:</text>
    <text>A family that is homeless and:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Living in a place not intended as a residence, such as outdoors, in a vehicle, or in a condemned or abandoned building; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Living in any situation that is dangerous to the health or safety of any household member, shall be given the first priority;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A family that is homeless and living with another household or in another living situation that is tenuous and in which the family’s right to remain has been revoked shall be given the second priority; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A family that is at imminent risk of becoming homeless, such as when the family is at risk of foreclosure or eviction, or is living with another household but the family’s right to remain has not yet been revoked shall be given the third priority;
        and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A determination of priority for shelter or supportive housing may be delayed if an applicant does not provide information sufficient to making such determination.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.2.</num>
    <text>The intake center may re-determine a family’s priority determination at any time based on assessment, re-assessment, or new or changed information or circumstances.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.3.</num>
    <text>The intake center shall make the priority determination for a family applicant and provide written notice to the applicant of the priority determination, which shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A clear statement of the family’s priority determination;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A clear and detailed statement of the factual basis for the priority determination;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A reference to the statute or regulation that is the basis for the priority determination; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A clear and complete statement of the client’s right to request a reconsideration of the priority determination and information regarding how to request reconsideration, including the appropriate deadlines for making the request.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2508.4.</num>
    <text>Upon giving the applicant the written notice of the applicant’s priority determination for family shelter or supportive housing, the intake center shall also orally inform the applicant of the priority determination assigned to the family, and provide
      an explanation to the applicant of the basis of such determination consistent with the information provided in the written notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 470, 483 (January 24, 1992); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 6438 (July 23, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice Emergency Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11353 (November
        26, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergency Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 3007 (April 8, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 7442, 7448 (August 19, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>