<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2557</num>
  <heading>SPECIAL ELIGIBILITY CRITERIA FOR REFERRAL TO THE LOCAL RENT SUPPLEMENT PROGRAM ELIGIBILITY REQUIREMENTS (ยง 29-2557)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2557.1.</num>
    <text>An applicant unit shall be eligible for referral to the DCHA for the LRSP vouchers if the applicant unit is a family, as defined in ยง 2599, that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Is currently homeless, because the applicant unit:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Lacks a fixed, regular residence that provides safe housing, and lacks the financial means to acquire such a residence immediately, including victims of domestic violence who cannot remain in their present housing for safety reasons;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Has a primary nighttime residence that is a supervised publicly or privately operated shelter or transitional housing facility designed to provide temporary living accommodations governed by this chapter or is currently receiving a rental subsidy
        through the Family Re-Housing and Stabilization Program governed by Chapter 28 of Title 29 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Has no other housing options identified;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Is a resident of the District of Columbia as defined by D.C. Official Code ยง 4-751.01(32) (2008 Repl. &amp;#038; 2012 Supp.); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Has significant barriers to increasing income or achieving housing stability as demonstrated by having at least one (1) of the following household characteristics:</text>
    </level>
    <text>Head of household, or both heads of household if a two (2)-parent household, is disabled and unable to work, as demonstrated by receiving Supplemental Security Income (SSI) or Social Security Disability Insurance (SSDI) benefits, or other medical
      documentation;</text>
    <text>Household include a child or children with a moderate to severe physical, behavioral, developmental, or mental health disability that is a barrier to housing stability;</text>
    <text>Head of household, particularly youth head of household defined as twenty-four (24) years of age or younger, in which at least one (1) parent has aged out of foster care, experienced significant involvement with child welfare as a minor child, or
      experienced significant involvement with the youth rehabilitation or correctional systems as a minor child;</text>
    <text>when the requirements would make it more difficult for the applicant or recipient to escape family violence, place the applicant or recipient at further risk of violence, or where failure to comply with work requirements is a result of family violence.
      when the requirements would make it more difficult for the applicant or recipient to escape family violence, place the applicant or recipient at further risk of violence, or where failure to comply with work requirements is a result of family violence.Head
      of household is a victim of an intrafamily offense, domestic violence, dating violence, or stalking that is a barrier to work either because working places the person at further risk of violence or the family violence has resulted in creating barriers
      to work for the victim; or</text>
    <text>Large family size, defined as a household with five (5) or more minor children.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2557.2</num>
    <text>2557.2 Families determined to be eligible pursuant to ยง 2557.1(c), may be prioritized for referral based on the:</text>
    <text>Severity of barrier(s) to achieving housing stability absent a LRSP voucher;</text>
    <text>Length of time on the Public Housing or Housing Choice Voucher Waiting list at the DCHA; or</text>
    <text>Number of episodes or length of time of homelessness.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11631 (August 9, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>