<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2529</num>
  <heading>STI PROGRAM – TENANT HOUSING COST CONTRIBUTION AND PROGRAM HOUSING COSTSSISTANCE (§ 29-2529)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2529.1.</num>
    <text>Each household shall contribute toward the cost for housing thirty percent (30%) of their adjusted annual income, determined in accordance with the Housing Choice Voucher Program (HCVP) regulations found at 14 DCMR § 6200. The STI Program shall pay
      the difference in the cost of housing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2529.2.</num>
    <text>The STI Program shall pay the difference between the household’s housing cost contribution and the cost of housing. For purposes of this section, the cost of housing shall include the cost of utilities, the relative share of which shall be determined
      as set forth in the DCHA Housing Choice Voucher Program regulations found at 14 DCMR § 6200. Subject to the availability of funds, the Department may pay an increased share of rent or utilities, when the housing cost exceeds the HUD Fair Market
      rent standards.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2529.3.</num>
    <text>To ensure that a security deposit is not a barrier to participation in the STI Program, applicants shall be referred to and assisted in accessing available community and public resources to obtain the necessary security deposit. Only as a last resort,
      the STI Program may provide funds to meet a gap in resources necessary to meet a reasonable security deposit, based on demonstrated need by the client and exhaustion of other community-based and public resources, and availability of STI Program
      funding.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2529.4.</num>
    <text>To ensure that moving expenses and move-in expenses, such as basic furniture and household items, are not a barrier to participation in the STI Program, applicants shall be referred to and assisted in accessing available community and public resources
      to obtain these services. Only as a last resort, the STI Program may provide funds to meet a gap in resources necessary to meet reasonable moving and move-in expenses, based on demonstrated need by the client and exhaustion of other community-based
      and public resources, and availability of STI Program funding.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2529.5.</num>
    <text>Income and asset information provided by participants may be subject to verification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 6438 (July 23, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice Emergency Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11353 (November 26, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergency Rulemaking published
        at 58 DCR 3007 (April 8, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 7442, 7476 (August 19, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>