<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2514</num>
  <heading>CLIENT RESPONSIBILITIES (§ 29-2514)
    <text>Clients shall seek appropriate permanent housing or Housing First, except whenhe client is residing in severe weather and low barrier shelter.</text>
    <text>Clients shall seek employment, education, or training when appropriate, excepthen the client is residing in severe weather and low barrier shelter.</text>
    <text>Clients shall refrain from the following behaviors while on a Provider’sremises:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The use or possession of alcohol or illegal drugs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The use or possession of weapons;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Assaulting or battering any individual, or threatening to do so; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any other acts that endanger the health or safety of the client or any otherndividual on the premises.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Clients shall ensure that children within the client’s family and physicalustody are enrolled in school, where required by law.</text>
    <text>Clients shall ensure that the client’s minor children receive appropriateupervision while on the Provider’s premises.</text>
    <text>Clients shall utilize child care services that they qualify for and can afford,hen available and necessary to enable the adult client to seek employment orousing or to attend school or training, unless the client meets any of thexemptions of section
      519g of the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of982, effective April 20, 1999 (D.C. Law 12-241; D.C. Official Code § 4-205.19g2008 Repl.)), or section 5809.4(b)-(e) of Title 29 of the District of Columbiaunicipal Regulations, including
      any subsequent revisions.</text>
    <text>Clients shall respect the safety, personal rights, and private property ofrovider staff members and other clients.</text>
    <text>Clients shall maintain clean sleeping and living areas, including bathroom andooking areas.</text>
    <text>Clients shall use communal areas appropriately, with attention to cleanlinessnd respect for the interests of other clients.</text>
    <text>Clients shall be responsible for one’s own personal property.</text>
    <text>Clients shall follow all Program Rules established by a Provider pursuant toubsection 2515.17.</text>
    <text>Clients residing in temporary shelter and transitional housing shall participaten the assessment and case management services.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 6438 (July 23, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice Emergency Rulemakingublished at 57 DCR 11353 (November 26, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Noticef Emergency Rulemaking published at
        58 DCR 3007 (April 8, 2011)[EXPIRED]; asmended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 7442, 7454 (August9, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>