<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2543</num>
  <heading>OFFICE OF SHELTER MONITORING (§ 29-2543)
    <text>The Office of Shelter Monitoring (Office) shall monitor and evaluate theervices delivered by all programs covered by the Act.</text>
    <text>For shelters and supportive housing programs, the Office shall monitor theonditions, services, and practices, evaluating, to the extent applicable, the:</text>
    <text>Health, safety, and cleanliness of shelters and site-based supportive housingrogram. For programs with individual, scattered site housing, the quality ofhe housing offered;</text>
    <text>Policies, practices, and Program Rules;</text>
    <text>Accessibility of program to clients with disabilities;</text>
    <text>Appropriateness of facility for families;</text>
    <text>Respect for applicable client rights set forth in sections 2512 and 2513;</text>
    <text>Compliance with applicable Provider standards set forth in sections 2515 through519;</text>
    <text>Comments of clients and program staff;</text>
    <text>Ability of the program to facilitate transition from homelessness to permanentousing; and</text>
    <text>Any other information deemed appropriate.</text>
    <text>For each program required to be monitored the Office shall conduct an inspectionn the premises at least once during each calendar year. The Office may conductore than one (1) inspection per year per program and may conduct inspections onn announced
      or unannounced basis.</text>
    <text>For each monitoring inspection, the Office shall issue to the Provider aonitoring report summarizing the findings of the inspection.</text>
    <text>For purposes of this section, if the Provider is a subcontractor of a Districtontractor, all written communications and reports from the Office to therovider shall also be provided to the prime contractor. Likewise, any writtenommunication from the
      Provider to the Office shall also be provided to therime contractor.</text>
    <text>The monitoring report shall provide a comprehensive assessment of the program,ncluding identifying areas of excellence, competence, and deficiencies. Fordentified deficiencies the report shall also include required correctivections and required timeframe
      for completion of corrective action.</text>
    <text>Generally, Providers shall have up to seven (7) days from the date of theonitoring report to correct health and safety deficiencies, except that theffice may require more immediate action for deficiencies that present anmmediate danger to residents,
      staff, or the public. For purposes of thisubsection, health and safety shall include deficiencies under federalisability law, including the Americans with Disabilities Act, effective July6, 1990 (104 Stat. 327; 42 U.S.C. §§ 12131 – 12134 (as amended),
      and the.S. Attorney General’s implementing regulation, 28 C.F.R. Part 35, and anyucceeding legislation, unless otherwise noted by the Office. For non-health orafety deficiencies, Providers shall have thirty days from the date of theonitoring to
      report correct the deficiency, unless otherwise noted in theeport.</text>
    <text>The Provider shall correct the deficiencies noted, and submit documentation tohe Office that such corrective actions were taken within the requiredimeframes.</text>
    <text>If the Provider is unable to complete a corrective action within the requiredimeframes, the Provider shall submit to the Office the reason for not meetinghe required timeframe along with a proposed corrective action plan witheasonable deadlines that
      will correct the deficiencies in as timely a manner asossible. The proposed corrective action plan shall be submitted to the Officey the deadline given for the corrective action. The corrective action planill be considered accepted by the Office,
      unless the Office notifies therovider otherwise within five business days of receiving the proposedorrective action plan.</text>
    <text>Based on the corrective action plan, the Provider shall submit follow-upocumentation to the Office that the required corrective actions were takenithin the projected timeframes, or why such work has not been completed in aimely manner and the Provider’s
      proposed solution.</text>
    <text>If the Office determines that the Provider has not satisfactorily corrected theeficiencies set forth in the monitoring report, either as required by theonitoring report or the corrective action plan submitted by the Provider, theffice shall notify
      the Provider of the remaining deficiencies and theorrective action that is required, as well as any new deadlines for correctingeficiencies.</text>
    <text>At any time in the monitoring process, and particularly where the Provider failso timely correct deficiencies outlined in a monitoring report, the Office mayursue additional remedies, including requiring acceptance of technicalssistance, training,
      increasing the number of announced or unannounced visitsy Office monitors, or other applicable remedies necessary to ensure Providerompliance. When determining whether to renew a contract with a provider, theepartment or its contractor shall consider
      annual monitoring reports as well asnvestigatory findings made in response to complaints about the program filedith either the ADA Coordinator or OSM.</text>
    <text>If the Provider is a direct contractor with the District, and the Officeetermines that the Provider has not satisfied the deficiencies in theonitoring report, the Office shall notify the Contracting Officer’s Technicalepresentative (COTR) of the Provider’s
      non-compliance.</text>
    <text>If the Provider is a subcontractor of a District contractor and the Officeetermines that the Provider has not satisfied the deficiencies in theonitoring report, the Office, after providing adequate and timely notice to therime contractor in accordance
      with the timeframes established in the contracto correct the deficiencies, shall notify the COTR that the prime contractor hasailed to ensure that its subcontractor is in compliance.</text>
    <text>Once the COTR receives notice that a Provider, or the prime contractor, ison-compliant with the contract, the COTR shall notify the Department’sontracting Officer in writing of the prime contractor’s violation of theerms and conditions of the contract
      and shall develop a proposed notice to cureor review and approval by the Contracting Officer. The Contracting Officerhall proceed to send the notice to cure to the contractor in accordance with 27CMR §§ 3711 – 3712, and any other applicable laws,
      policies, andegulations.</text>
    <text>If the contractor, whether the Provider or the prime contractor, fails toatisfy the terms of the notice to cure, the Contracting Officer may proceedith any remedy available under 27 DCMR §§ 3711 – 3712, and any otherpplicable laws, policies, and regulations.</text>
    <text>The Office shall create and utilize a systematic tracking system to track theonitoring reports, deficiencies found, corrective action taken, and theimeframes within which deficiencies were corrected.</text>
    <text>The Office shall make available, upon request, each annual monitoring inspectioneport to clients of the program and members of the Interagency Council onomelessness.</text>
    <text>In all activities conducted by the Office pursuant to this section, and in anyeports released pursuant to subsection 2543.18, the Office shall ensureonfidential treatment of the personal, social, legal, financial, educational,nd medical records and
      information related to a client or any member of alient&amp;#8217;s family, whether obtained from the client or from any otherource, consistent with confidentiality requirements of District and federalaw.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 6438July 23, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice Emergency Rulemaking published at7 DCR 11353 (November 26, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergencyulemaking published at
        58 DCR 3007 (April 8, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended byotice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 7442, 7489 (August 19, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>