<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2530</num>
  <heading>STI PROGRAM – ANNUAL RECALCULATION OF TENANT RENT CONTRIBUTION (§ 29-2530)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2530.1.</num>
    <text>The STI Program shall examine and recalculate annually each household’s housing cost contribution to ensure that participating households are paying the appropriate tenant housing cost contribution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2530.2.</num>
    <text>For each household, the annual recalculation date shall be twelve (12) months after the date of the initial housing placement. The STI Program may adjust the annual recalculation date in order to schedule some or all household annual recalculations
      at the same time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2530.3.</num>
    <text>Each household is responsible for providing to the STI Program the appropriate documents confirming income, family composition or other information requested by the Program during an annual recalculation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2530.4.</num>
    <text>If the STI Program determines that a change in the housing cost assistance is required as a result of an annual recalculation, the Provider shall give the household a written notice of the change in the household’s rent contribution, which shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A clear statement of the factual basis of the change in the household’s housing cost contribution;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A clear and detailed statement of the computation of the household’s new housing cost contribution;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A clear and detailed statement of the computation of the STI Program’s housing cost assistance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A clear statement of the effective date of the new household housing cost contribution;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A reference to the regulation or policy pursuant to which the change was made; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A clear and complete statement of the client&amp;#8217;s right to a reconsideration of the change of household housing cost contribution by the Department or the Department’s designee if such reconsideration is requested within ten (10) days of
        receipt of the Notice, including the appropriate deadlines for instituting the request for reconsideration.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2530.5.</num>
    <text>If a recalculation of tenant housing cost contribution results in a decrease in the amount of the tenant contribution and an increase in the STI Program assistance, the change shall be effective the first day of the month (or the next day that rent
      is due) following the completion of the recalculation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2530.6.</num>
    <text>If a recalculation of tenant rent contribution results in an increase in the amount of the tenant contribution and a decrease in the STI Program rental assistance, the change shall be effective thirty (30) calendars days after written notice of the
      change in assistance is provided to the household.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 6438 (July 23, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice Emergency Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 11353 (November 26, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergency Rulemaking published
        at 58 DCR 3007 (April 8, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 7442, 7477 (August 19, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>