<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2513</num>
  <heading>ADDITIONAL RIGHTS FOR CLIENTS IN TEMPORARY SHELTER OR SUPPORTIVE HOUSING (§9-2513)
    <text>Clients shall be permitted to receive visitors in designated areas of thehelter or housing premises during reasonable hours and under such reasonableonditions as specified in the Provider&amp;#8217;s approved Program Rules.</text>
    <text>Clients shall be permitted to leave and return to the shelter or housingremises within reasonable hours as specified by the Provider’s approvedrogram Rules.</text>
    <text>Clients shall receive reasonable prior notice specifying the date and time ofny inspections of a client&amp;#8217;s living quarters and of the Provider staffember authorized to perform the inspection, except when, in the opinion of therovider&amp;#8217;s
      executive or program director, there is reasonable cause toelieve that the client is in possession of a substance or object that poses anmminent threat to the health and safety of the client or any other person onhe Provider&amp;#8217;s premises.
      Reasonable cause shall be documented in thelient’s record.</text>
    <text>Clients shall be permitted to be present or have an adult member of the familyresent at the time of any inspection unless, in the opinion of the Provider’sxecutive or program director, there is reasonable cause to believe that thelient is in possession
      of a substance or object that poses an imminent threato the health and safety of the client or any other person on the Provider’sremises. Reasonable cause shall be documented in the client’s record.</text>
    <text>Clients shall be provided reasonable privacy in caring for personal needs and inaintaining personal living quarters.</text>
    <text>Clients shall be permitted to conduct their own financial affairs, subject tohe reasonable requirements of the Provider’s Program Rules developed andpproved in accordance with subsection 2515.17, or subject to a Service Planeveloped pursuant to subsection
      2512.12.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 470, 488 (January 24, 1992); asmended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 6438July 23, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice Emergency Rulemaking published at7 DCR 11353 (November
        26, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergencyulemaking published at 58 DCR 3007 (April 8, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended byotice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 7442, 7453(August 19, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>