<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2502</num>
  <heading>INTAKE FOR SEVERE WEATHER SHELTER FOR INDIVIDUAL ADULTS (§ 29-2502)
    <text>Intake for severe weather shelter for individual adults shall consist of anligibility determination and placement in a shelter.</text>
    <text>An individual adult applicant shall apply directly to and be determined eligibleor severe weather shelter by the Provider from whom the individual is seekingervices.</text>
    <text>Placement of eligible applicants in a specific severe weather shelter shall ben a first come, first served basis. If there is no available space in thehelter for an eligible applicant, the shelter shall arrange transportation forhat person to another
      appropriate shelter that has available space.</text>
    <text>A Provider of severe weather shelter may fill a bed or unit allocated to anndividual who leaves the facility for more than thirty (30) minutes afterights out. If the individual later returns to the severe weather shelter andhe original bed was given
      to another individual, the Provider shall give thendividual another bed. If no bed is available, the Provider shall arrangeransportation for the individual to a severe weather shelter with an availableed.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR’S NOTE</heading>
      <text>The provision cited in this subsection, D.C. Code, 2001 Ed. §-1208, was repealed by D.C. Law 12-241 § 7.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 470, 472 (January 24, 1992); asmended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 6438July 23, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice Emergency Rulemaking published at7 DCR 11353 (November
        26, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergencyulemaking published at 58 DCR 3007 (April 8, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended byotice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 7442, 7444 (August 19, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>