<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-603</num>
  <heading>GENERIC LOTTERY TICKET VALIDATION REQUIREMENTS (ยง 30-603)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>603.1.</num>
    <text>In order for any lottery game ticket to be valid, all of the following conditions shall be met:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The ticket shall be validated in accordance with all procedures for claiming and paying prizes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The ticket shall not be stolen or appear on any list of omitted tickets on file with the Agency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The ticket shall be intact and shall not have been mutilated, altered, reconstituted or tampered with in any manner;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The ticket shall not be defective, fraudulent, counterfeit in whole or in part, or a duplicate of another winning ticket;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The ticket shall have been issued by the Agency through a licensed agent in an authorized manner;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The ticket shall not be blank or partially blank, or printed or produced in error;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The ticket shall not have been previously presented for payment and a prize paid thereon;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The period designated for claiming a prize pursuant to this title shall not have expired; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The ticket shall pass all other confidential security checks of the Agency.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.2.</num>
    <text>Any lottery game ticket not passing all of the validation checks required by this title for that particular lottery ticket shall be void and shall not be paid except as provided in ยง503.7.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.3.</num>
    <text>The final determination on validation rests with the Executive Director, except that the determinations shall be subject to the provisions of Chapter 4 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.4.</num>
    <text>Any person who submits a lottery ticket for validation or who claims a prize, in whatever capacity, agrees to be bound and shall be bound by the provisions of ยง500.6.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>603.5.</num>
    <text>Any person presenting a fraudulent, counterfeit or duplicate ticket may be subject to criminal prosecution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 7439, 7444 (October 2, 1992).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL NOTE</heading>
      <text>Prior to October 2, 1992, the D.C. Lottery and Charitable Games Control Board published Final Rulemaking al 29 DCR 2202, 2211 (May 28, 1982).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>