<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-7607</num>
  <heading>SECURITY DEPOSIT AND FIRST MONTH&amp;#8217;S RENT (§ 29-7607)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7607.1.</num>
    <text>HPRP assistance may be provided to pay for security deposits for eligible program participants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7607.2.</num>
    <text>The maximum HPRP payment for a security deposit shall be the actual amount of the deposit, which may not exceed more than the cost of one (1) month’s unsubsidized rent, which must meet HUD’s Rent Reasonableness standard, up to one thousand five hundred
      dollars ($1,500) for an individual and up to two thousand two hundred dollars ($2,200) for a family.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7607.3.</num>
    <text>The security or damage deposit payment shall be made directly to the landlord.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7607.4.</num>
    <text>HPRP assistance may be provided to pay the first month’s rent for an eligible applicant where:</text>
    <text>The first month’s rent must be paid in conjunction with the security deposit;</text>
    <text>The applicant unit has no other means available for paying the first month’s rent at the time it is required; or</text>
    <text>Neither short nor medium term HPRP rental assistance is necessary to stabilize the housing of the applicant unit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7607.5.</num>
    <text>The maximum HPRP payment for first month’s rent shall not exceed the actual amount of one (1) month’s unsubsidized rent, which must meet HUD’s Rent Reasonableness standard, up to one thousand five hundred dollars ($1,500) for an individual and up
      to two thousand two hundred dollars ($2,200) for a family.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7607.6.</num>
    <text>Any applicant unit coming directly from a transitional housing program that requires an escrow account for purposes of obtaining permanent housing shall demonstrate why they do not have sufficient resources available for security deposit or first
      month’s rent.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 2116 (March 12, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 5973 (July 9, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking
      published at 58 DCR 1566, 1570 (February 25, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>