<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-7602</num>
  <heading>APPLICANT UNIT (§ 29-7602)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>7602.1.</num>
    <text>The applicant unit shall be composed of each individual who lives in the same household and whose needs, assets, and income are combined to determine eligibility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7602.2.</num>
    <text>The applicant unit shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Persons related by full or half blood;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Persons related by legal adoption;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Persons related by marriage, including stepchildren and unmarried parents of a common child who live together; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Persons with legal responsibility for an unrelated minor child, or an unrelated adult with a disability.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7602.3.</num>
    <text>The applicant unit may include any person not included by subsection 7602.2, regardless of blood relationship, age, or marriage, whose history and statements reasonably tend to demonstrate that they intend to remain together as a family unit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7602.4.</num>
    <text>A person temporarily away from home due to employment, hospitalization, vacation, or a visit shall be considered to be living in the household. A minor child who is away at school is considered to be living in the household if he or she returns to
      the home on occasional weekends, holidays and during the summer vacations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7602.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant unit may be comprised of a single individual.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>7602.6.</num>
    <text>The name of a non-household member on a rental lease shall have no effect on eligibility, except that receipt of benefits under sections 7607 through 7610 shall be conditioned on:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The applicant documenting that he or she is responsible for the payment; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Both the applicant and the landlord agreeing to change the lease to reflect only the applicant’s name, unless the name of the non-household member is a co-signor required by the landlord.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Source: Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 2116 (March 12, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 5973 (July 9, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking
      published at 58 DCR 1566, 1570 (February 25, 2011).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>