<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-1402</num>
  <heading>ISSUANCE OF LICENSE (ยง 19-1402)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1402.1.</num>
    <text>Prior to the issuance of a license for owning or operating a video arcade or for offering mechanical amusement machines for public use, the Mayor shall find that the applicant, if an individual, or if a partnership, each of the members of the partnership,
      or if a corporation, each of its principal officers, is not less than 21 years of age and has not, within five years prior to the filing of the application, been convicted of any felony.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1402.2.</num>
    <text>Subsection 1402.1 shall not operate to deny a license to own or operate a video arcade or establishment in which mechanical amusement machines are offered for public use to any person who, on the effective date of this act, is licensed to own or operate
      a video arcade or establishment in which mechanical amusement machines are offered for public use and who has not been convicted of any felony after the date of the issuance of such license in effect on the date that this act becomes law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1402.3.</num>
    <text>In the case of an application for a license to own or operate a video arcade, the place for which the license is to be issued must be consistent with these regulations, considering such factors as the character of the premises, its surroundings, and
      the views of the persons residing or owning property in the vicinity of the premises for which the license is to be issued.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1402.4.</num>
    <text>Prior to the issuance of a license for the operation of a video arcade, the Mayor shall give notice by advertisement published twice a week for at least two weeks in a newspaper of general circulation published in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1402.5.</num>
    <text>The fee for the advertisement required by subsection 1402.4 shall be paid by the applicant at the time of filing of the application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1402.6.</num>
    <text>The published advertisement required by subsection 1402.4 shall contain any information that the Mayor shall prescribe, and the information shall include, but not be limited to, a statement that interested persons are entitled to be heard prior to
      the granting of a license and designating the date prior to which any statements shall be considered in determining whether to grant the applicant a license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1402.7.</num>
    <text>The applicant shall be required to post one notice, for ten days, in a conspicuous place on the outside of the premises for which the license is to be issued.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1402.8.</num>
    <text>The notice required by subsection 1402.7 shall contain any information that the</text>
    <text>Mayor shall prescribe, and the information shall include, but not be limited to, a statement that interested persons are entitled to be heard prior to the issuance of a license and informing them of the date prior to which their statements shall be
      considered in determining whether to grant the applicant a license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1402.9.</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall not issue a license for the operation of a video arcade or for offering mechanical amusement machines for public use to any establishment located within a radius of 600 feet of the property lines of the lot or parcel of ground upon
      which is located a public, private or parochial school in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1402.10.</num>
    <text>Subsection 1402.9 shall not be construed to apply to owners or operators of video arcades or establishments offering mechanical amusement machines for public use in operation on or prior to the effective date of the Police Regulations of the District
      of Columbia/Video Arcades and Mechanical Amusement Machines Regulations Amendment Act of 1984.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1402.11.</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall be authorized to establish and change from time to time the period for which any license to own or operate a video arcade or offer mechanical amusement machines for public use may be issued.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1402.12.</num>
    <text>Licenses for owning or operating a video arcade or for offering mechanical amusement machines for public use, issued at any time after the beginning of the license year, shall date from the first day of the month in which license was issued and end
      of the last day of the license year prescribed by the Mayor, and payment shall be made of the proportionate amount of the annual license fee; provided that no fee shall be prorated to an amount less than ten dollars.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>D.C. Act 5-129, ยง 2(c)-(g), published at 31 DCR 2331, 2333-36 (May 18, 1984).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>