<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-1299</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 16-1299)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1299.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms and phrases shall have the meanings ascribed:</text>
    <text>Agent &amp;#8211; a person employed by a proprietary school, whether such school is located within or outside the District, who solicits in the District students or enrollees for the school by any means and in any place.</text>
    <text>Department &amp;#8211; the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
    <text>Person &amp;#8211; includes individuals, firms, partnerships, corporations, associations, and organizations.</text>
    <text>Proprietary school &amp;#8211; a privately-owned school in the District, or any branch, extension, or facility in the District of a proprietary school located elsewhere, which offers for a consideration resident or correspondence courses or training
      or instruction for the purpose of enabling an individual to improve his or her intellectual aptitude, or which purports to prepare or qualify individuals for employment in any occupation or trade or in work requiring mechanical, technical, artistic,
      or clerical skills.</text>
    <text>The term &amp;#8220;proprietary school&amp;#8221; shall not include any of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Residential Institutions providing exclusively elementary (including kindergarten) and secondary education;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Degree-granting institutions of higher learning licensed by the Educational Institution Licensure Commission or chartered by an Act of Congress;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Schools conducted by any person solely for the training of the employees of that person, and for which no fee is charged;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any course of instruction offered by the District or federal government or any instrumentality of the District or federal government; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Education which is solely avocational or recreational in nature, and institutions offering avocational or recreational education exclusively.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Student &amp;#8211; a full-time or part-time enrollee in a proprietary school.</text>
    <text>Non-immigrant alien student &amp;#8211; any student having a residence in a foreign country who has acquired this status to pursue a full course of study in the United States.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>