<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-1411</num>
  <heading>DISBURSEMENT OF BINGO RECEIPTS (§ 30-1411)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1411.1.</num>
    <text>All gross receipts from each bingo operation, less the amount awarded as cash prizes, shall be deposited in a separate bingo bank account by the end of the next business day following the date of each bingo operation; Provided, that for recreational
      bingo played under a Class D license all gross receipts from each bingo operation must be paid out for prizes and for expenses pursuant to §§1408.3, 1412.1, and 1412.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1411.2.</num>
    <text>Money shall be withdrawn from the bingo account for only the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Payment of expenses in accordance with § 1411; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Disbursement from net proceeds for the lawful purpose stated in the application.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1411.3.</num>
    <text>Use of gross receipts less prizes shall be completed pursuant to §1411.2 within thirty (30) days of each bingo operation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1411.4.</num>
    <text>The licensed organization shall not commingle any funds derived from the operation of bingo with any other funds, except in compliance with §1411.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1411.5.</num>
    <text>If a licensed organization fails to renew its license to conduct bingo or its license is suspended or revoked, the licensed organization shall immediately distribute all net proceeds pursuant to § 1411.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3788, 3809 (May 20, 1988).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL NOTE</heading>
      <text>Prior to May 20, 1988, the D.C. Lottery and Charitable Games Control Board published Final Rulemaking at 29 DCR 5016, 5028 (November 12, 1982).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>