<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-3200</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 24-3200)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3200.1.</num>
    <text>The requirements of this chapter shall apply to all window-cleaning operations that are performed by an employee from a position that is wholly or partially on the outside of a building more than one (1) story high, or in which the sills of windows
      are located ten feet (10 ft.) or more above the grade or the adjoining flat roof.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3200.2.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this chapter shall apply to the cleaning of the inside face of any window where the window cleaner cleans the window while resting on a level that is ten feet (10 ft.) or more above the floor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3200.3.</num>
    <text>The requirements of this chapter shall not apply to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A dwelling house less than three (3) stories high;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A dwelling house occupied by less than three (3) families; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A window opening to a fire escape balcony or other balcony that is two feet (2 ft.) or more wide and twelve inches (12 in.) or less below the window sill.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3200.4.</num>
    <text>Upon the written application of an employer, the Minimum Wage and Industrial Safety Board may approve the use of existing anchor installations, safety devices, and methods of cleaning windows other than those specified in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is the District of Columbia Minimum Wage Act approved September 19, 1918, 40 Stat. 960, D.C. Code §§36-401 through 36-422); as amended by An Act approved October 14, 1941, Title II entitled
        &amp;#8216;Industrial Safety,&amp;#8217; 55 Stat. 738, D.C. Code §§36-431 through 36-442; paragraphs 283 and 284 of §402 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967; and Reorganization Order No. 36, C.O. 302,853/14, June 16, 1953, as amended.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Sections 11-2503 and 11-2504, effective September 1, 1958, ch. 25, 5 DCR 28 (August 11, 1958); 11B DCRR, Special Edition.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR&amp;#8217;S NOTE</heading>
      <text>The rules published in this chapter have been superseded in whole or in part by rules promulgated by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration, U.S. Department of Labor and published at 29 CFR Part 1926 (July 1, 1995 ed.). The Minimum Wage
        and Industrial Board (Board) referenced in this chapter was abolished by Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1978, effective June 27, 1978. Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1978 transferred the powers, duties and functions of the Board to the Director of
        the Department of Labor, and also established a new Occupational Safety and Health Board. Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1980, effective April 17, 1980; and Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1980, effective January 10, 1981, transferred those functions
        to the Department of Employment Services.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>