<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-805</num>
  <heading>INVESTIGATION OF APPLICANTS AND LICENSEES (ยง 16-805)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>805.1.</num>
    <text>The Director is authorized, in connection with the consideration of license applications and from time to time during the license year, during regular business hours, to require any applicant or licensee to make available to the Director such information
      as the Director considers necessary in determining or verifying whether the applicant or licensee has or retains the qualifications necessary for obtaining or retaining a license, or has violated or failed to comply with any provision of statute
      or regulation relating to the conduct of the home improvement business or to obtaining or retaining a license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.2.</num>
    <text>The investigation by the Director may include determination or verification of the identity of any person associated with the applicant or licensee in the home improvement business, and the extent, if any, of that person&amp;#8217;s control, either
      directly or indirectly, over the business activities of the applicant or licensee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.3.</num>
    <text>Failure to make information available to the Director; failure to furnish to the Director the information the Director is authorized to request by this section; or failure to furnish to the Director or to permit the Director to make one (1) or more
      copies of such records maintained by the applicant or licensee as the Director may specify, shall be grounds for denial, suspension, or revocation of a license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>805.4.</num>
    <text>The information required by this section to be furnished to the Director may, at the option of the applicant or licensee, be furnished to the Director at the Director&amp;#8217;s office or, upon notice to the Director, at the place of business of
      the applicant or licensee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>