<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-807</num>
  <heading>ADVERTISING (§ 16-807)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>807.1.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the applicable provisions of regulations governing refrigeration and air conditioning licensing and electrical licensing and bonding, and plumbing, but subject to the provisions of this section, a home improvement contractor licensed
      under the authority of this chapter may advertise in any manner and may state orally to a prospective customer that any contract between the customer and the contractor may provide for the performance of electrical, plumbing, gasfitting, or refrigeration
      and air conditioning work, or any combination of those services. In any advertisement, the licensee shall include his or her license number.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>807.2.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § 807.1, all plumbing, gasfitting, electrical, or refrigeration and air conditioning work, or any combination of those services, to be performed under any contract between a homeowner and a home improvement contractor, shall
      be performed in accordance with all of the requirements of the regulations applicable to that work, with particular reference to the use of qualified personnel (whenever required by the applicable regulations) in the securing the permits and in
      the performance of the work.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>807.3.</num>
    <text>A licensee shall maintain a list that includes information about all permits obtained and all contractors or subcontractors performing work on any project permitted or requiring a permit under this chapter. Such list shall include the contractor or
      subcontractor’s name and address and, if applicable, their license number. If requested by the Director, the licensee shall produce this list within forty-eight (48) hours of the Director’s request.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 3098 (April 24, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>