<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-761</num>
  <heading>C-5 (PAD) DISTRICT USES (§ 11-761)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>761.1.</num>
    <text>Any use permitted in a C-4 District under § 751 shall be permitted in the C-5 (PAD) District as a matter of right, except that an animal boarding use shall be prohibited and a gasoline service station shall be permitted only as an accessory use to
      a parking garage subject to the conditions of § 701.1(i).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>761.2.</num>
    <text>Uses as specified and controlled under §§ 753 and 754 shall be permitted in the C-5 (PAD) District if approved by the Board of Zoning Adjustment in accordance with the conditions specified in § 3104 for special exceptions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>761.3.</num>
    <text>Mechanical amusement machines shall be permitted in a C-5 (PAD) District as an accessory use incidental to the uses permitted in this section, subject to the provisions of § 2501.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>761.4.</num>
    <text>A child development home shall be permitted in the C-5 (PAD) District as an accessory use incidental to the uses permitted in this section; provided:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The dwelling unit in which the use is located shall be the principal residence of the caregiver; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The use otherwise shall meet the definition of a home occupation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>761.5.</num>
    <text>Other accessory uses customarily incidental and subordinate to the uses permitted in the C-5 (PAD) District shall be permitted in the C-5 (PAD) District if approved by the Board of Zoning Adjustment in accordance with the conditions specified under
      § 3104 for special exceptions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>761.6.</num>
    <text>A drive-through accessory to a fast food establishment shall be permitted in the C-5 (PAD) District, subject to the special provisions for drive-throughs in § 2304.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 2726, 2734 (September 22, 1978); as amended by:</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 29 DCR 4913, 4916 (November 5, 1982); Final Rulemaking published at 32 DCR 4374, 4378 (July 26, 1985); and Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 974143 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed
        Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8406 (October 20, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 6363 (August 4, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 9393 (September 28, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>