<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-774</num>
  <heading>REAR YARDS (C) (§ 11-774)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>774.1.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in this section, a rear yard shall be provided for each structure located in a Commercial District, the minimum depth of which shall be as prescribed in the following table:</text>
    <text>ZONE DISTRICT ANDSTRUCTURE</text>
    <text>MINIMUM DEPTH OFREAR YARD</text>
    <text>C-1</text>
    <text>20 feet</text>
    <text>All structures</text>
    <text>C-2-A, C-2-B, C-2-C</text>
    <text>15 feet</text>
    <text>All structures</text>
    <text>C-3-A, C-3-B, C-3-C, C-4, C-5 (PAD)</text>
    <text>All structures</text>
    <text>2-1/2 inches per foot of vertical distance from the mean finished grade at the</text>
    <text>middle of the rear of the structure to the highest point of the main roof or parapet wall, but not less than 12 feet</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>774.2.</num>
    <text>The Board of Zoning Adjustment may waive the rear yard requirements of this section pertaining to C-3-A, C-3-B, C-3-C, and C-4 Districts in accordance with the requirements of § 3104 for special exceptions; provided, that the standards in §§ 774.3
      through 774.6 shall be met.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>774.3.</num>
    <text>Apartment and office windows shall be separated from other buildings that contain facing windows a distance sufficient to provide light and air and to protect the privacy of building occupants.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>774.4.</num>
    <text>In determining distances between windows in buildings facing each other, the angle of sight lines and the distance of penetration of sight lines into habitable rooms shall be sufficient to provide adequate light and privacy to the rooms.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>774.5.</num>
    <text>The building plan shall include provisions for adequate off-street service functions, including parking and loading areas and access points.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>774.6.</num>
    <text>Upon receiving an application for an approval under § 774.2, the Board shall submit the application to the D.C. Office of Planning for coordination review, report, and impact assessment, along with reviews in writing of all relevant District of Columbia
      departments and agencies including the Departments of Transportation and Housing and Community Development and, if a historic district or historic landmark is involved, the State Historic Preservation Officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>774.7.</num>
    <text>In a C-1, C-2, or C-3-A District, where a lot upon which a building or other structure is located abuts an alley, the rear yard, as required by §§ 774.1 through 774.6, may be measured as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>For that portion of the structure below a horizontal plane twenty feet (20 ft.) above the mean finished grade at the middle of the rear of the structure from the center line of the alley to the rear wall of the portion; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For that portion of the structure above the horizontal plane described in § 774.7(a), the depth of rear yard shall be measured from the rear lot line to the rear wall of that portion immediately above the plane.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>774.8.</num>
    <text>Subsection 774.7 shall not apply to any one-family dwelling.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>774.9.</num>
    <text>In the C-3-B, C-3-C, C-4, and C-5 (PAD) Districts, the depth of rear yard required in §§ 774.1 through 774.6 may be measured as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Where a lot abuts an alley, the depth of rear yard may be measured from the center line of the alley, to the rear wall of the building or other structure. A rear yard on the lot need not be provided below a horizontal plane twenty feet (20 ft.)
        above the mean finished grade measured at the middle of the rear wall of that portion of the building or other structure below the twenty foot (20 ft.) plane;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Where a lot does not abut an alley, the depth of rear yard shall be measured as specified in the definition of rear yard in § 199.1, except a rear yard need not be provided below a horizontal plane twenty feet (20 ft.) above the mean finished grade
        measured at the middle of the rear wall of that portion of the building or other structure below the twenty foot (20 ft.) plane; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>In the case of a corner lot, a court complying with the width requirements for a closed court as specified in § 776 may be provided in lieu of a rear yard. For the purpose of this section, the required court shall be provided above a horizontal
        plane beginning not more than twenty feet (20 ft.) above the curb grade opposite the center of the front of the building, and the width of the court shall be computed for the entire height of court.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>774.10.</num>
    <text>Subsection 774.9 shall not apply to any one-family dwelling.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>774.11.</num>
    <text>In the case of a through lot or a corner lot abutting three (3) or more streets, the depth of rear yard may be measured from the center line of the street abutting the lot at the rear of the building or other structure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§§ 5303.1 through 5303.1 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 2226, 2227 (May 23, 1980); and Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference
        the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8411-12 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>