<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-733</num>
  <heading>FAST FOOD ESTABLISHMENTS (C-2-A) (§ 11-733)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>733.1.</num>
    <text>Fast food establishments shall be permitted in a C-2-A District as a special exception if approved by the Board of Zoning Adjustment under § 3104, subject to the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>733.2.</num>
    <text>No part of the lot on which the use is located shall be within twenty-five feet (25 ft.) of a Residence District unless separated therefrom by a street or alley.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>733.3.</num>
    <text>If any lot line of the lot abuts an alley containing a zone district boundary line for a Residence District, a continuous brick wall at least six feet (6 ft.) high and twelve inches (12 in.) thick shall be constructed and maintained on the lot along
      the length of that lot line. The brick wall shall not be required in the case of a building that extends for the full width of its lot.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>733.4.</num>
    <text>Any refuse dumpsters shall be housed in a three (3) sided brick enclosure equal in height to the dumpster or six feet (6 ft.) high, whichever is greater. The entrance to the enclosure shall include an opaque gate. The entrance shall not face a Residence
      District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>733.5.</num>
    <text>The use shall not include a drive-through.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>733.6.</num>
    <text>There shall be no customer entrance in the side or rear of a building that faces a street or alley containing a zone district boundary line for a Residence District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>733.7.</num>
    <text>The use shall be designed and operated so as not to become objectionable to neighboring properties because of noise, sounds, odors, lights, hours of operation, or other conditions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>733.8.</num>
    <text>The use shall provide sufficient off-street parking, but not less than that required by § 2101.1, to accommodate the needs of patrons and employees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>733.9.</num>
    <text>The use shall be located and designed so as to create no dangerous or other objectionable traffic conditions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>733.10.</num>
    <text>There shall be adequate facilities to allow deliveries to be made and trash to be collected without obstructing public rights-of-way or unreasonably obstructing parking spaces, aisles, or driveways on the site.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>733.11.</num>
    <text>The Board may impose conditions pertaining to design, screening, lighting, soundproofing, off-street parking spaces, signs, method and hours of trash collection, or any other matter necessary to protect adjacent or nearby property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>733.12.</num>
    <text>An applicant for special exception under this section may request the Board to modify the conditions enumerated in §§ 733.2 through 733.4; provided that the general purposes and intent of this section are complied with.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 4374, 4375 (July 26, 1985); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8398-99 (October
        20, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 9393 (September 28, 2007); corrected by Errata Notice published at 58 DCR 4314 (May 20, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>