<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-1108</num>
  <heading>COMPLAINTS UNDER INDIVIDUAL APPRENTICESHIP AGREEMENTS (ยง 7-1108)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1108.1.</num>
    <text>Any controversy or difference arising under an Apprenticeship Agreement which cannot be resolved by the sponsor, or which is not covered by a collective bargaining agreement, may be submitted by an apprentice or the apprentice&amp;#8217;s authorized
      representative to the Director for review.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.2.</num>
    <text>All matters covered by a collective bargaining agreement shall be submitted and processed in accordance with the procedures therein provided.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.3.</num>
    <text>A complaint shall be in writing, shall be signed by the complainant, shall be submitted by the apprentice or the apprentice&amp;#8217;s authorized representative within sixty (60) days of receipt of sponsor&amp;#8217;s decision, shall set forth the
      specific problem, including all relevant facts, and shall include copies of all pertinent documents and correspondence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.4.</num>
    <text>The Director shall make every effort to informally resolve the complaint.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.5.</num>
    <text>The Director shall report all unresolved complaints with recommendation for resolution to the Council within sixty (60) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.6.</num>
    <text>If necessary to resolve disputed questions of material fact, the Apprenticeship Council shall hold a hearing in accordance with the provisions of section 1104 of this Chapter. Otherwise, the Council shall make a decision based on the Director&amp;#8217;s
      recommendation within ten (10) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1108.7.</num>
    <text>The Council shall notify all parties of the decision which shall be a final administrative action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 6007(September 14, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>