<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-1109</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 7-1109)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1109.1.</num>
    <text>The definitions contained within the act (D.C. Code ยง 36-401 et seq. (1988)) shall apply to this Chapter. In addition, the following terms shall have the meaning ascribed:</text>
    <text>Apprenticeable Occupation &amp;#8211; a skilled occupation which possesses all of the following characteristics:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The occupation is customarily learned in a practical way through both training and work experience obtained on-the-job</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The occupation is clearly identified and commonly recognized throughout an industry.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The occupation involves manual, mechanical, or technical skills and knowledge which require a minimum of two thousand (2,000) hours per year of on-the-job work experience not including the time spent in related instruction.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The occupation requires instruction to supplement on-the-job training.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Apprentice &amp;#8211; a person at least 16 years of age who has entered into an apprenticeship agreement with an employer, an association of employers, or an organization of employees, which provides for reasonably continuous employment for the person
      and for participation in an approved apprenticeship program.</text>
    <text>Apprenticeship Agreement &amp;#8211; a written agreement between an apprentice and either the apprentice&amp;#8217;s employer, or an apprenticeship committee acting as agent for employers, which agreement contains the terms and conditions of the employment
      and training of the apprentice and must be registered with the Director.</text>
    <text>Apprenticeship Council &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia State Apprenticeship Council.</text>
    <text>Apprenticeship Program &amp;#8211; a program registered with the Apprenticeship Council, evidenced by a Certificate of Registration or other appropriate documents as meeting the apprenticeship standards of the Apprenticeship Council.</text>
    <text>Cancellation &amp;#8211; the termination of an apprenticeship agreement at the request of either the sponsor or the apprentice.</text>
    <text>Certification &amp;#8211; the written approval by the District of Columbia Apprenticeship Council of a set of apprenticeship standards or of an individual for employment as an apprentice in an apprenticeship program.</text>
    <text>D.C. Apprenticeship Act &amp;#8211; D.C. Apprenticeship Act of May 21, 1946 (D.C. Code ยง 36-401 et seq. (1988)).</text>
    <text>Deregistration of Programs &amp;#8211; the termination of the registration or approval status of an apprenticeship program upon written request of the sponsor or upon cause by the Apprenticeship Council instituting formal deregistration proceedings
      in accordance with the provisions of this Chapter.</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; the Director of the District of Columbia Department of Employment Services or any person designated by the Director to supervise the administration of the provisions of the act.</text>
    <text>District of Columbia State Plan for Equal Opportunity in Apprenticeship Training &amp;#8211; a plan outlining policies and procedures for promoting equality of opportunity in the recruiting and selection of apprentices and in all conditions of employment
      and training during the term of apprenticeship, adopted in accordance with 29 CFR Part 30 (1988).</text>
    <text>Registration Agency &amp;#8211; the District of Columbia Apprenticeship Council.</text>
    <text>Related Instruction &amp;#8211; an organized and systematic form of instruction designed to provide the apprentice with knowledge of the theoretical and technical subjects related to the apprentice&amp;#8217;s trade. The sponsor shall be responsible
      for the administration and supervision of related and supplemental instruction for apprentices and coordination of the instruction with job experience; the selection and training of teachers and coordinators for such instruction shall be approved
      by the Apprenticeship Council.</text>
    <text>Sponsor &amp;#8211; any person or organization operating an apprenticeship program, irrespective of whether such person or organization is an employer.</text>
    <text>Workforce &amp;#8211; all employees paid by the employer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 6007-09(September 14, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>