<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-100</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 7-100)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>100.1</num>
    <text>100.1 The provisions of this chapter are promulgated to implement title 23 of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 (Act) (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Official Code §§ 1-623.01, et seq. (2006 Repl. &amp;#038; 2012
      Supp.)), which governs the Public Sector Workers’ Compensation Program (Program).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>100.2</num>
    <text>100.2 The Office of Risk Management (ORM) has oversight and administrative responsibility for the Program, including all Initial Determinations (IDs) and Eligibility Determinations (EDs) rendered by the Program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>100.3.</num>
    <text>All employees, contractors, sub-contractors, and agents, acting for or on behalf of the District to implement the Program pursuant to the Act, including third-party administrators, shall comply with these rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>100.4.</num>
    <text>Nothing in these rules, or any instructions or attachments related thereto, shall be interpreted as:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Creating an entitlement or property interest in any employee, contractor, sub-contractor, or agent to whom these rules are applicable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Making any person or entity a third-party beneficiary to any contract with the District or with any of its contractors or sub-contractors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Establishing a standard of care; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Limiting the District&amp;#8217;s ability to amend, modify, or rescind these rules, consistent with any applicable law, including the Act and the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968, 82 Stat. 1203 (D.C. Official
        Code §§ 2-501, et seq. (2011 Repl. &amp;#038; 2012 Supp.)), binding case law, government contract provisions and modifications, and applicable judgments or settlements.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 2307 (May 22, 1981); repealed and replaced by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8766 (July 27, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>