<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-103</num>
  <heading>SUBPOENAS (ยง 7-103)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>103.1.</num>
    <text>The Program may issue subpoenas as part of its authority to conduct investigations pursuant to ยง 102 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.2.</num>
    <text>The Program may issue a subpoena for the following purposes:</text>
    <text>To compel the attendance of employees, claimants, or witnesses within a radius of one hundred miles (100 mi.) of the District of Columbia at interviews, alive and well checks, depositions, settlement conferences, or any other inquiry being held for
      the purposes of obtaining information about a claim;</text>
    <text>To administer an oath or affirmation and to examine employees, claimants, or witnesses; and</text>
    <text>To require the production of books, papers, documents, and other evidence.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.3.</num>
    <text>A subpoena issued under this section shall provide notice to the recipient of the legal authorization for the subpoena, the testimony or evidence being sought by the Program, the deadline for providing the testimony or evidence, and the telephone
      number and mailing address of the authorizing official issuing the subpoena.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.4.</num>
    <text>Subpoenas may be issued pursuant to this section only upon written authorization of the Chief Risk Officer, as attested to by the signature of the Chief Risk Officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.5.</num>
    <text>Subpoenas issued pursuant to this section shall be enforced by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>Source: Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 2307 (May 22, 1981); as amended by a Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 9540 (October 8, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended by a Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57
      DCR 12224, 12225 (December 24, 2010); repealed and replaced by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8766, 8767 (July 27, 2012).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>