<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-108</num>
  <heading>INDICATIONS OF ANATOMICAL GIFTS ON LICENSES AND SPECIAL IDENTIFICATION CARDS (§8-108)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>108.1.</num>
    <text>Each operator&amp;#8217;s license or special identification card issued or renewed on or after April 15, 2008, shall contain, as part of the license or card, a statement or symbol indicating whether or not the holder of the license or card has made
      an anatomical gift.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>108.2.</num>
    <text>The Director shall provide a method for permitting an individual making application for a new license, renewal of a license, or for an identification card to designate that he or she has elected, pursuant to the Uniform Anatomical Gift Revision Act
      of 2008, effective April 15, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-145; D.C. Official Code § 7-1531.01 et seq.) (“Uniform Anatomical Gift Revision Act”), to be a donor of his or her body, or tissue or organ, or part of the body, for the purpose of transplantation,
      therapy, medical research, or education.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>108.3.</num>
    <text>Upon designation, the Director shall make the notation &amp;#8220;DONOR&amp;#8221; on the license or identification card of the individual identifying that individual as one who has signed an anatomical gift card or otherwise authorized a statement
      or symbol indicating that the donor has made an anatomical gift.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>108.4.</num>
    <text>The notation referred to in § 108.3 shall constitute legal authority under the Uniform Anatomical Gift Revision Act, for the donation of any body, or the removal of tissue or any organ, part of an organ, or part of a body, upon the donor&amp;#8217;s
      death.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>108.5.</num>
    <text>The notation referred to in § 108.3 shall be removed from a licensee&amp;#8217;s identification card or license only after thirty (30) days written notice has been given to the Director by the licensee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>108.6.</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>108.7.</num>
    <text>Each applicant for an identification card or a license shall be asked if they wish to be a &amp;#8220;DONOR.&amp;#8221;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>108.8.</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>108.9.</num>
    <text>Each individual who applies for a learner&amp;#8217;s permit, temporary motor vehicle operator&amp;#8217;s permit, operator&amp;#8217;s license, or identification card shall be provided a written explanation about the donation of anatomical gifts
      in the District of Columbia, including the right to amend, revoke, or refuse to make an anatomical gift.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>D.C. Act 17-311 published at 55 DCR 2532 (March 14, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 5243, 5244 (June 18, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>