<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-103</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION FOR A DRIVER&amp;#8217;S LICENSE OR LEARNER&amp;#8217;S PERMIT (§ 18-103)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>103.1.</num>
    <text>Each application for a learner’s permit, a provisional permit, or for a driver’s license shall be made upon a form furnished by the Director and shall be accompanied by the proper fee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.2.</num>
    <text>Each application shall state the applicant’s true and lawful name (which shall include the applicant’s full and complete name, including any given middle name or names); the applicant’s date of birth; sex; social security number, if such a number
      was issued to the applicant, or, if required by the Director, proof that the applicant is not eligible for a social security number, the residence address of the applicant; and a brief description of the applicant, including, but not necessarily
      limited to, the applicant’s height, weight, color of eyes, and color of hair.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.3.</num>
    <text>Each application shall state whether the applicant has been previously licensed as an operator and, if so, when and by what state or country; and whether any such license has ever been suspended or revoked; whether an application has ever been refused;
      and, if so, the date of and reason for the suspension, revocation, or refusal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.4.</num>
    <text>Each application shall also include any other information that the Director may require in order to determine the competency, eligibility, or identity of the applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.5.</num>
    <text>Each applicant for a learner’s permit or driver’s license shall be required to display a birth certificate and social security card, if such a card was issued to the applicant, or other documentary evidence of the date of birth and social security
      number, if the applicant was issued such a number, of the applicant satisfactory to the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.6.</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.7.</num>
    <text>The application of any person under eighteen (18) years of age for a learner&amp;#8217;s permit, a provisional permit, or driver&amp;#8217;s license, except those endorsed by the State Department as enjoying the privilege of diplomatic immunity, shall
      be accompanied by a written, notarized statement signed by one of the applicant&amp;#8217;s parents or a guardian consenting to the issuance of the permit or license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.8.</num>
    <text>The following fees shall apply to permit applicants:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Knowledge test $ 10;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Driver’s permit road test $ 10;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Driver’s permit application fee $ 44;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Learner’s permit application fee $ 20;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Provisional operator’s permit application fee $ 20; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Ignition Interlock Application fee $ 50.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.9.</num>
    <text>An applicant who fails to appear for a scheduled road test shall be required to pay a penalty of thirty dollars ($30), unless the applicant cancels the road test at least 2 business days prior to the scheduled road test.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>103.10.</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 10819 (December 19, 2003); as amended by D.C. Act 15-704 published at 52 DCR 1700 (February 25, 2005); as amended by D.C. Act 16-636 published at 54 DCR 903 (February 2, 2007); as amended by D.C. Act published
        at 55 DCR 7598 (July 18, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 5243 (June 18, 2010); as amended by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 5697 (July 8, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final
        Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 6938 (August 12, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>