<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-102</num>
  <heading>DRIVING UNDER INSTRUCTION[COLON] LEARNER&amp;#8217;S PERMITS (§ 18-102)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>102.1.</num>
    <text>Any person who is at least sixteen (16) years of age may apply to the Director for a learner&amp;#8217;s permit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.2.</num>
    <text>The Director may, in his discretion, after the applicant has successfully passed all parts of the examination other than the driving test, issue to the applicant a learner&amp;#8217;s permit which shall entitle the applicant, while having such permit
      in his immediate possession, to drive a specified type or class of motor vehicle upon the public highways for a period not in excess of 1 year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.3.</num>
    <text>A learner&amp;#8217;s permit may be renewed or a new permit may be issued for an additional period not in excess 1 year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.4.</num>
    <text>The issuance of a learner&amp;#8217;s permit, a provisional permit, or a driver&amp;#8217;s license to a person under eighteen (18) years of age shall be subject to the following restrictions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The licensee shall not drive any motor vehicle other than a passenger vehicle, or motorized bicycle;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The licensee shall not drive any vehicle for compensation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.5.</num>
    <text>A person holding a learner&amp;#8217;s permit shall not operate a motor vehicle except between the hours of 6 a.m. and 9 p.m., and while under the instruction of, and when accompanied by the holder of a valid driver&amp;#8217;s license who is at least
      21 years of age and who shall occupy the seat beside the permittee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.6.</num>
    <text>A junior high or high school student enrolled in an approved driver education and training course may operate a dual-control motor vehicle when the student is under instruction and accompanied by a licensed motor vehicle driving instructor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.7.</num>
    <text>The instructor shall, at all times while engaged in instruction, have in his possession a certificate from the principal or other person in charge of the school stating that the instructor is officially designated to instruct students enrolled in
      the course.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.8.</num>
    <text>Whenever demand is made by a police officer, the instructor shall display the certificate to the officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.9.</num>
    <text>No other person shall ride in or on a vehicle when the driver is under instruction, except as provided in § 102.11.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.10.</num>
    <text>Subsections 102.5 and 102.9 do not apply to the operation of motorcycles or motorized bicycles by a person holding a learner&amp;#8217;s permit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.11.</num>
    <text>When any person in possession of a learner&amp;#8217;s permit is accompanied by a person holding a motor vehicle instructor&amp;#8217;s license, or when an unlicensed student is accompanied by an instructor holding a certificate described in § 102.7,
      not more than three (3) other persons may ride on the back seat of the vehicle, and then only for the sole purpose of receiving instruction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.12.</num>
    <text>All seating positions in each dual control vehicle used for driver&amp;#8217;s instruction shall be equipped with seat belts or safety harnesses which shall be used by all persons riding in the vehicle whenever the vehicle is being operated for instructional
      purposes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.13.</num>
    <text>The person acting as instructor shall be held responsible for the strict observance of all regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>102.14.</num>
    <text>A person holding a provisional permit shall not operate a motor vehicle between 11:00 p.m. on any Sunday, Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, or Thursday until 6:00 a.m. on the following day during any month except July or August, and from 12:01 a.m. until
      6:00 a.m. during July and August and on any Saturday or Sunday the rest of the year, except if travelling to or from employment, a school-sponsored activity, religious or an athletic event or related training session in which the permittee is a
      participant, sponsored by the District of Columbia, a civic organization, or another similar entity that takes responsibility for the minor, or unless accompanied by the holder of a valid driver’s license who is at least 21 years of age and who
      shall occupy the seat beside the permittee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 2065 (March 4, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 5754 (June 17, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>