<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-2211</num>
  <heading>NOTICE OF THE NOTICE OF INFRACTION (ยง 1-2211)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2211.1.</num>
    <text>A Notice of Infraction (&amp;#8220;NOI&amp;#8221;) shall be in the form prescribed by the Mayor&amp;#8217;s appointee or the Gas Station Advisory Board (&amp;#8220;GSAB&amp;#8221;) Chairman and will be issued for infractions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2211.2.</num>
    <text>A NOI must include the following information</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of the respondent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A citation to the law or rule that the respondent allegedly violated;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The amount of the fine;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The nature, time and place of the infraction;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Notification that:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The respondent must request a hearing or pay the fine within fifteen days of the date the NOI was served on the respondent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A penalty equal to the amount of the fine may be imposed on the respondent if the respondent does not pay the fine within fifteen days;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The respondent may request a hearing according to procedures described in the NOI;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The respondent may pay by: (A) cash, which must be paid in person as directed in the NOI; or (B) certified check, postal or bank money order payable to the District of Columbia Treasurer, any of which may be submitted in person or by mail as directed
        in the NOI.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>If the respondent answers &amp;#8220;Admit&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;Admit with Explanation,&amp;#8221; he or she must certify that each infraction on the NOI has been abated; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Any other information the Director may require.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2211.3.</num>
    <text>If the fine listed on the NOI is inconsistent with the fine listed in the statute, the respondent can be subject only to the lesser fine.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2211.4.</num>
    <text>Upon observing an infraction, the investigator may issue an NOI.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2211.5.</num>
    <text>A properly completed NOI signed by the issuing agent constitutes prima facie evidence of the statements contained in the Notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2211.6.</num>
    <text>Each incident of prohibited conduct constitutes a separate infraction subject to penalty.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 555 (January 27, 2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>