<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-3706</num>
  <heading>PAYMENT AFTER SETTLEMENT (ยง 27-3706)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3706.1.</num>
    <text>After execution of a settlement agreement in accordance with ยง3703, the contractor shall submit a voucher or invoice showing the amount agreed upon less any portion previously paid. The contracting officer shall attach a copy of the settlement agreement
      to the voucher or invoice and forward the document to the appropriate office for payment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3706.2.</num>
    <text>If the settlement is by determination under ยง3705, payment shall be effected in the following manner:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If there is no appeal within the allowed time, the contractor shall submit a voucher or invoice showing the amount determined due, less any portion previously paid; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If there is an appeal, the contractor shall submit a voucher or invoice showing the amount finally determined due on the appeal, less any portion previously paid.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3706.3.</num>
    <text>In the case of construction contracts, before forwarding the final payment voucher, the contracting officer shall ascertain whether there are any outstanding labor violations. If any violations are outstanding, the contracting officer shall determine
      the amount to be withheld from the final payment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3706.4.</num>
    <text>The District shall not pay interest on the amount due under a settlement agreement or a settlement by determination. However, the District shall pay interest on amounts found due to a contractor on claims in accordance with ยง806 of the Act from the
      date the Director receives the claim.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3706.5.</num>
    <text>The total amount payable to the contractor under a settlement, before deducting disposal or other credits, exclusive of settlement costs, shall not exceed the contract price less payments otherwise made or to be made under the contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking publishing at 35 DCR 1696 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>