<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-3713</num>
  <heading>NOTICE OF TERMINATION FOR DEFAULT (ยง 27-3713)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3713.1.</num>
    <text>If, after consideration of all facts and circumstances, and after compliance with the provisions of this chapter, the contracting officer determines that a termination for default is proper, the contracting officer shall issue a notice of termination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3713.2.</num>
    <text>In addition to the requirements of ยง3701, a notice of termination for default shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The acts or omissions constituting the default;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A statement that the contractor&amp;#8217;s right to proceed further under the contract, or a specified portion of the contract, is terminated;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A statement that the goods or services terminated may be purchased against the contractor&amp;#8217;s account, and that the contractor will be held liable for any excess costs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>If the contracting officer has determined that the failure to perform is not excusable, a statement that the notice of termination constitutes a decision to that effect, and that the contractor has the right to appeal the decision under the disputes
        clause in the contract;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>That the District reserves all rights and remedies provided by law or under the contract, in addition to charging excess costs; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>That the notice constitutes a decision that the contractor is in default as specified, and that the contractor has the right to appeal the termination under the disputes clause in the contract.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3713.3.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall make the same distribution of the termination notice as was made of the contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3713.4.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall furnish a copy to the contractor&amp;#8217;s surety, if any, when the notice is furnished to the contractor. The contracting officer shall request the surety to advise the contracting officer if it desires to arrange
      for completion of the work.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3713.5.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall immediately notify the payment office to withhold further payments under the terminated contract pending further notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking publishing at 35 DCR 1702 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>