<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-912</num>
  <heading>CREDIT PROGRAM IMPLEMENTATION (§ 20-912)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>912.1.</num>
    <text>Credits will only be generated when a covered fleet operator acquires above and beyond the required amount and type of vehicles for compliance with the purchase requirements contained in § 906.1 of this chapter</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>912.2.</num>
    <text>Credits can be generated by a covered fleet operator in the covered area if the vehicles acquired meet all of the requirements of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>912.3.</num>
    <text>Credits may be used by covered fleets as substitutes for vehicle acquisitions to meet the acquisition requirements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>912.4.</num>
    <text>Conversions to clean-fuel vehicles shall earn credits in the same manner as other acquired vehicles.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>912.5.</num>
    <text>Covered fleet operators shall meet the fleet vehicle purchase requirements of this Act by purchasing clean-fuel vehicles, whether a new, used, or converted vehicle, or by trading and banking clean-fuel fleet vehicle credits for vehicle purchases.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>912.6.</num>
    <text>All credit-generating vehicles must meet the applicable emission standards and other requirements contained in § 906 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>912.7.</num>
    <text>While in a covered area, a duel-fuel, bi-fuel, or flexible-fuel vehicle purchased by a fleet operator to comply with fleet purchase reuirements shall be operated at all times on the fuel or fuels on which it was certified as a clean-fuel fleet vehicle.
      If the fleet operator receives credit for a dual-fuel, bi-fuel, or flexible-fuel vehicle purchase, the vehicle must operate at the same emission level for which the vehicle generated clean-fuel fleet credit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>912.8.</num>
    <text>All covered fleets shall be eligible to generate credits.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>912.9.</num>
    <text>Credits may be traded or sold for use in the covered area.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>912.10.</num>
    <text>Trading of credits among all subclasses of LDVs and LDTs is permitted. Credit trading is not allowed between the LDT/LDV classes and HDV classes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>912.11.</num>
    <text>Clean-fuel fleet vehicle credits may be earned by a covered fleet operator for any of the following qualifying purchases:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Purchase of a clean-fuel vehicle during any period subsequent to July 15, 1994, but prior to September 1, 1997, if the purchase meets all other clean-fuel fleet vehicle requirements applicable to the purchase, including the statutory requirement
        to use only the fuel on which the vehicle was certified;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Purchase of a greater number clean-fuel fleet vehicles than is required under this chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Purchase of a clean-fuel fleet vehicle that meets more stringent emission standards than required under this chapter (ULEVs, ZEVs, and ILEVs);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Purchase of a clean-fuel fleet vehicle in an exempt vehicle category by the operator of a covered or partialy covered fleet; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Purchase of a clean-fuel vehicle by a noncovered fleet operator.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>912.12.</num>
    <text>For LDVs and LDTs, credit values shall be determined in accordance with tables 9-6, 9-7, and 9-8.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>912.13.</num>
    <text>For HDVs, credit values shall be determined in accordance with tables 9-9, 9-10, and 9-11.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>912.14.</num>
    <text>Credit values shall be calculated to two (2) decimal places.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>912.15.</num>
    <text>Credits shall be designated as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Credits generated by the purchase of a qualifying clean-fuel fleet LDV or LDT shall be designated at the time of issuance as light-duty clean-fuel fleet vehicle credits;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Credits generated by the purchase of a qualifying clean-fuel fleet HDV shall be designated at the time of issuance as heavy-duty clean-fuel fleet vehicle credits; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Credits generated by the purchase of a light heavy-duty or a medium heavy-duty qualifying clean-fuel fleet vehicle shall be designated at the time of issuance as light heavy-duty or medium heavy-duty credits, respectively.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>912.16.</num>
    <text>The following are credit tables:</text>
    <text>Table 9-6</text>
    <text>LDV, LDT</text>
    <text>LDT ≤6000</text>
    <text>LDT &gt; 6000</text>
    <text>LDT &gt; 6000</text>
    <text>LDT &gt; 6000</text>
    <text>≤6000</text>
    <text>GVWR</text>
    <text>GVWR</text>
    <text>GVWR</text>
    <text>GVWR</text>
    <text>GVWR</text>
    <text>&gt;3750</text>
    <text>≥3750 TW</text>
    <text>&gt;3750 TW</text>
    <text>&gt;5750 TW</text>
    <text>NMOG+NO2</text>
    <text>≤3750</text>
    <text>LVW</text>
    <text>≤5750</text>
    <text>≤5750 TW</text>
    <text>LEV</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1.00</num>
    <text>1.00</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1.26</num>
    <text>1.26</text>
    <text>.71</text>
    <text>.91</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1.11</num>
    <text>1.11</text>
    <text>ULEV</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1.20</num>
    <text>1.20</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1.54</num>
    <text>1.54</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1.00</num>
    <text>1.00</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1.29</num>
    <text>1.29</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1.47</num>
    <text>1.47</text>
    <text>ZEV</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1.43</num>
    <text>1.43</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1.83</num>
    <text>1.83</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1.43</num>
    <text>1.43</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1.83</num>
    <text>1.83</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>LIGHT DUTY VEHICLE CREDIT GENERATION</heading>
      <text>PURCHASING MORE CLEAN-FUEL VEHICLES THAN REQUIRED BY THE MANDATE</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>