<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-906</num>
  <heading>CLEAN FUEL FLEET VEHICLE ACQUISITION REQUIREMENTS (ยง 20-906)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>906.1.</num>
    <text>Of the new covered fleet vehicles purchased each year by a covered fleet operator beginning in Model Year 1998 and thereafter, at least a specified percentage of the vehicles shall be clean-fuel vehicles, as provided in this section. The vehicles
      shall operate on clean fuels when operating in the covered area. The required new vehicle purchase percentages for each vehicle type shall be those set forth in table 9-1 of this subsection:</text>
    <text>Table 9-1</text>
    <text>CFFV PURCHASE REQUIREMENTS</text>
    <text>VEHICLE CLASS</text>
    <text>MODEL YEAR 1998</text>
    <text>MODEL YEAR 1999</text>
    <text>MODEL YEAR 2000 plus</text>
    <text>LDVs and LDTs under 6.000 lbs. GVWR</text>
    <text>30%</text>
    <text>50%</text>
    <text>70%</text>
    <text>LDT 6.000 lbs GVWR or higher but not over 8.500 lbs. GVWR</text>
    <text>30%</text>
    <text>50%</text>
    <text>70%</text>
    <text>HDVs over 8,500 lbs. and below 26,000 lbs. GVWR</text>
    <text>50%</text>
    <text>50%</text>
    <text>50%</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>906.2.</num>
    <text>Any clean-fuel vehicle purchased pursuant to the requirements of ยง 906.1 of this chapter shall meet the emission standard for its respective vehicle class and category as contained in ยง 906.3 and as may be amended by the Mayor to the extent necessary
      to conform with revised emission standards promulgated after the date of enactment of the Clean Air Act by the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>906.3.</num>
    <text>The emission tables are as follows:</text>
    <text>Table 9-2</text>
    <text>CFFV EMISSION STANDARDS FOR LOW EMISSION VEHICLES (LEVs) &amp;#8211; LDVs AND LDTs</text>
    <text>LDV, LDT</text>
    <text>LDT โค6000</text>
    <text>LDT &gt; 6000</text>
    <text>LDT &gt; 6000</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>