<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-913</num>
  <heading>TRANSPORTATION CONTROL MEASURE EXEMPTIONS (ยง 20-913)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>913.1.</num>
    <text>Clean-fuel vehicles operated by covered fleets shall be exempt from measures which restrict vehicle usage based primarily on temporal considerations, such as time-of-day and day-of-week restrictions and commercial vehicle bans. This exemption does
      not include access to High-Occupancy Vehicle lanes, except as provided in ยง 913.2 of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>913.2.</num>
    <text>A fleet vehicle which has been certified by the Environmental Protection Agency as an ILEV, is operated by a covered fleet, and continues to be in compliance with applicable ILEV emission standards shall be exempt from High-Occupancy Vehicle lanes.
      This exemption shall not apply if, by regulation, it is determined that it would create a clear and direct safety hazard.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>913.3.</num>
    <text>The exemptions provided under this section shall be available to covered fleet vehicles upon the adoption of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>913.4.</num>
    <text>Transportation control measure exemptions shall be subject to the following conditions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The exemptions shall not be effective outside of the covered area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The exemptions shall not be transferable among vehicles in the same fleet; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Covered fleet operators may not buy, sell, or trade such exemptions.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>913.5.</num>
    <text>The transportation control measure exemptions provided to covered fleet vehicles under this section shall remain in effect only if the subject vehicle is in compliance with the clean-fuel vehicle emission standards contained in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 3(a) of the Clean Fuel Fleet Vehicle Program and Alternative Fuels Incentives Amendment Act of 1994, D.C. Law 10-201, 41 DCR 7178, 7194 (November 4, 1994).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>