<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6004</num>
  <heading>RIGHTS AND RESPONSIBILITIES OF FOSTER CHILDREN LIVING IN FOSTER HOMES (ยง9-6004)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6004.1.</num>
    <text>A foster child living in a foster home has the right to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Have her or his health, safety, and welfare be the primary consideration in implementing these rules;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be consulted about or informed of all decisions made on his or her behalf as appropriate to the foster child&amp;#8217;s age;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Safety and protection;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Opportunities to develop emotionally, socially, physically, educationally, culturally, and spiritually in a nurturing environment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Information about the reason for the foster child&amp;#8217;s placement, and help in developing an explanation of the foster child&amp;#8217;s situation to others;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Help in dealing with the effects of separation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Opportunities for continued connection with the foster child&amp;#8217;s family and others with whom the foster child has had meaningful relationships, unless such a connection would be harmful to the child&amp;#8217;s health or safety; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Return to the foster child&amp;#8217;s family or be placed in another permanent placement as expeditiously as possible consistent with the foster child&amp;#8217;s case plan.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6004.2.</num>
    <text>A foster child living in a foster home is responsible for:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Keeping his or her room and possessions in good order and completing assigned daily or weekly chores, consistent with the foster child&amp;#8217;s age and level of development;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Attending school or other alternate education or training programs, if the foster child is of school age; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Following appropriate minimum personal care and hygiene standards consistent with the foster child&amp;#8217;s physical and developmental capabilities.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6004.3.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section of the DCMR shall be read to limit any other right, privilege, or opportunity provided to a foster child under this chapter of the DCMR or any other provision of law or policy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 6617 (July 27, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>