<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6031</num>
  <heading>SUSPENSION OR REVOCATION OF LICENSE (§ 29-6031)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6031.1.</num>
    <text>If, as a result of an investigation undertaken pursuant to § 6024, or through any other means, CFSA finds evidence of gross incompetence, misconduct in operating the foster home, supported neglect or abuse of children, or any other condition that
      poses an immediate threat to the health or safety of foster children, CFSA shall immediately:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Suspend the license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Remove any foster child who remains in the foster home; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Begin steps to revoke the license.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6031.2.</num>
    <text>If, as a result of an investigation undertaken pursuant to § 6024, or through any other means, CFSA finds evidence of any condition that may pose a threat to the health or safety of foster children if not remedied, CFSA may immediately suspend a license
      for a period not exceeding thirty (30) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6031.3.</num>
    <text>CFSA may extend the suspension period under § 6030.2 for no more than an additional thirty (30) days if the extension is necessary to remedy the condition for which the license was suspended.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6031.4.</num>
    <text>In lieu of an immediate suspension pursuant to § 6030.2, CFSA may notify a foster parent of its intent to suspend the license if the condition is not remedied by a specific date not to exceed thirty (30) days. If the condition is not remedied by the
      date, CFSA may suspend the license pursuant to § 6030.2, but may not extend the suspension period in accordance with § 6030.3.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6031.5.</num>
    <text>Except for a suspension under § 6030.1, by the end of the suspension period, CFSA shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Revoke a suspended license if the condition is not remedied; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Restore a suspended licensure if the condition is remedied.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6031.6.</num>
    <text>If a license is revoked:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>No agency may place any foster child in the foster home; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>If any foster child remains in the home, the foster child shall be removed immediately.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6031.7.</num>
    <text>If a license is suspended:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>No agency may place any child in the foster home; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Each foster child shall be removed from the home by the end of the suspension period if the condition is not remedied.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6031.8.</num>
    <text>In the event of a planned revocation or suspension, at least ten (10) business days before the planned date, CFSA shall send the foster parent a notice of intended action that includes:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The intended action;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A statement of the specific rule violated; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A statement describing the foster parent&amp;#8217;s right to appeal.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6031.9.</num>
    <text>Within five (5) business days after the suspension or revocation of a license, CFSA shall send the foster parent a notice that includes:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The action;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A statement of the specific rule violated; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A statement describing the foster parent&amp;#8217;s right to appeal.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6031.10.</num>
    <text>Unless CFSA has removed a foster child from the foster home pursuant to §§ 6024 or 6030.1 and if the revocation is a planned revocation, CFSA shall immediately remove each foster child from a foster home when a license is revoked unless CFSA sent
      the foster parent a notice of intended action pursuant to § 6030.8 and the foster parent filed an appeal within ten (10) days of the notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6031.11.</num>
    <text>Once suspended or revoked, a license may not be restored, a foster home license may not be renewed, and foster children may not be placed in the home unless:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>There has been a hearing decision favorable to the foster parent; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Director or designate has given written approval.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking publish at 48 DCR 6617 (July 27, 2001); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 8609 (September 3, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>