<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6018</num>
  <heading>DISCIPLINE AND CONTROL (ยง 29-6018)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6018.1.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall teach and guide each foster child with techniques that stress praise and encouragement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6018.2.</num>
    <text>Discipline shall be appropriate to the age and handicapping condition, if any, of the foster child.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6018.3.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall establish well-defined rules that set the expectations for and the limits of behavior.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6018.4.</num>
    <text>No foster parent shall subject a child to physical, emotional, or verbal abuse, derogatory remarks about the child or family members, or threats of removal from the foster home.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6018.5.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall not use forms of discipline that involve cruel, severe, or humiliating actions, including, but not limited to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Physical punishment inflicted in any manner upon the body;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Denial of balanced nutrition, clothing, or shelter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Denial of visits, telephone calls, or mail contact with family members, social workers, or attorneys; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Assignment of strenuous exercise or work to the point of endangering the health of the child.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6018.6.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall not punish a child for bed-wetting or any action regarding toilet training.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6018.7.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall take steps to ensure that any other person providing care to a foster child adheres to the requirements of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 6617 (July 27, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>