<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6013</num>
  <heading>MAINTAINING FOSTER CHILDREN&amp;#8217;S RECORDS (ยง 29-6013)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6013.1.</num>
    <text>A foster parent shall maintain records on each foster child placed in the home. All information regarding a foster child shall be kept confidential and released only in accordance with ยง 6023.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6013.2.</num>
    <text>A foster child&amp;#8217;s records shall include the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The foster child&amp;#8217;s name, birth date, and Medical Assistance number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name, address, and telephone number(s) of each person to contact in case of emergency and each person authorized to give medical consent;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A record of the foster child&amp;#8217;s medical and dental appointments, illness and health problems, prescribed medications, and hospitalizations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Reports of the foster child&amp;#8217;s medical tests and any information or counseling received regarding chronic and handicapping conditions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A copy of any service agreement for the foster child;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Dates of future Court or administrative reviews, any medical or other appointments, and planned activities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The dates that the foster child arrived at and departed from the foster home;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>A listing of the activities in the foster child&amp;#8217;s case plan for which the foster parent is responsible;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>School reports; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>A record of the foster child&amp;#8217;s memberships, activities, and participation in extracurricular activities.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 6617 (July 27, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>