<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-202</num>
  <heading>SUMMARY OF SHORT TERM DEBT (ยง 15-202)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>202.1.</num>
    <text>The following data shall be provided for short term debt (consolidated, partially consolidated or other) for the historical test year and the proposed test year, as applicable:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Type of instrument, term, maturity date, and holder;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Amount outstanding or to be outstanding;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Applicable interest rate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Annualized interest requirement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Composite cost rate for total short term debt;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Standby fee or compensating balances, if any, currently required or expected to be required. Also indicate whether required by formal contractual agreement or by informal understanding;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Lines of credit and principal lending institutions for the current calendar year and subsequent year; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Average historical daily cash balances as recorded on the books of the utility, by bank, for the most recent twelve (12) month period where such balances are used to meet line of credit requirements.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.2.</num>
    <text>Bell Atlantic &amp;#8211; Washington, D.C., Inc., shall provide the data cited under ยง202.1 for its corporate entity and need not provide the data regarding its corporate parent or other Bell Atlantic affiliated companies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>202.3.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, the term &amp;#8220;average&amp;#8221; is used to indicate the arithmetic mean.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 1155, 1160 (February 13, 1987); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 42 DCR 2340, 2342 (May 12, 1995).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>