<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3116</num>
  <heading>MINIMUM STANDARDS FOR FUNERAL SERVICES ESTABLISHMENTS (§ 17-3116)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3116.1</num>
    <text>3116.1 The business or practice of funeral directing shall be conducted onlyrom a funeral services establishment that is located at a licensed fixedddress registered with the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3116.2</num>
    <text>3116.2 A funeral services establishment shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A chapel or reposing room, containing at least three hundred (300) squareeet of floor space, used exclusively for funeral services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An arrangement office, to be used exclusively for making funeralrrangements and for related business matters; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A preparation room, to be used exclusively for the preparation,reservation (including embalming), or other care of human remains.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3116.3</num>
    <text>3116.3 Separate buildings, or portions thereof, that are connected by a privateassageway, walk, or driveway, may constitute a single funeral servicesstablishment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3116.4</num>
    <text>3116.4 A preparation room shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be clean and sanitary at all times;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Contain at least one-hundred and twenty (120) square feet of floor space;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Be lighted at a minimum of thirty-five (35) foot candles of light on eachreparation table, and twenty-five (25) foot candles of light on all otherorking surfaces;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Be ventilated at a rate of twelve (12) air changes per hour, and betherwise in compliance with the BOCA Mechanical Code, section M-1600 et seq.1990) and 20 DCMR Chapter 9; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Be equipped with:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Floor, wall, ceiling, and working surfaces made of tile or other hard,mooth, durable, nonporous, washable, and light-colored material;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Hot and cold running water, a utility sink, and cabinets, closets, orhelves for instruments and supplies;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Adequate sewage disposal, waste disposal, and drainage equipment andacilities which meet the requirements of the District of Columbia Hazardousaste Management Act of 1977, D.C. Law 2-64, D.C. Code, section 6-701, et seq.,nd implementing rules;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Doors and windows, if any, that are rigid and right-closing and that do notermit any view into the room;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A non-porous table for preparing or preserving human remains; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Disinfectants for the proper sterilization of the preparation room,quipment, and instruments.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3116.5</num>
    <text>3116.5 Temporary storage of uncasketed human remains awaiting burial or otherinal disposition shall take place only in a preparation room or in a storageoom. Unembalmed human remains that are stored for over twenty-four (24) hourshall be stored in
      a refrigerated storage room.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3116.6</num>
    <text>3116.6 A funeral services establishment shall have a business telephone inorking order at its registered address, the number of which shall be listed inhe name of the business. Any other telephone number also listed for theuneral services establishment
      shall be specifically designated as aresidence telephone number”, a “number to call if no answer”, ortherwise identified.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3116.7</num>
    <text>3116.7 A funeral services establishment shall display a sign that states theame of the establishment as registered with the Director. The sign shall beonspicuously located at or near the main entrance and shall be visible from thexterior of the establishment.
      The lettering on the sign shall be legible andave a minimum height of one and one-half (1-1/2) inches.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3116.8</num>
    <text>3116.8 A funeral services establishment shall conspicuously display its currenticense in the establishment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3116.9</num>
    <text>3116.9 A funeral services establishment shall use only its name as registeredith the Director in telephone listings, publications, advertisements, ortherwise conducting business.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3116.10</num>
    <text>3116.10 Use of space, facilities, equipment, or supplies for, or thereparation, sale, service, or distribution of food or beverages in any part of funeral services establishment to or by clientele is prohibited, excepteverage vending machines are
      permitted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3661.11</num>
    <text>3661.11 A funeral services establishment shall provide telephone information, aasket price list, an outside receptacle price list, and a general price list asequired by the Funeral Industry Practices Rules of the Federal Trade Commission16 Code of
      Federal Regulations, section 453.2). Copies of these rules may bebtained from the Director upon payment of the prescribed fee.</text>
    <text>Source: Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 7853, 7861 (October 23, 1992).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>