<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3120</num>
  <heading>GROUNDS FOR DENIAL, REVOCATION, OROTHER DISCIPLINARY ACTION (ยง 17-3120)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3120.1</num>
    <text>3120.1 Upon finding that an applicant for or a holder of a license engaged inonduct described in section 3120.2, the Director may, after providing noticend an opportunity for a hearing pursuant to this chapter, take one or more ofhe following actions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Deny a license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Suspend or revoke a license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Refuse to renew or reinstate a license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Impose a civil fine pursuant to procedures established by the Department ofonsumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985, D.C. Code,ection 6-2701 et seq.; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Impose restrictions on the license to operate a funeral servicesstablishment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3120.2</num>
    <text>3120.2 The Director may take one (1) or more of the actions listed in section120.1 if the Director finds that an applicant for a license or a licenseeommits one of the following acts:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Engages in any conduct prohibited by D.C. Code, section 2-208;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Violates any provision of the act, this chapter, Chapter 30 of this title,r other District or federal law pertaining to the practice of funeral directingr funeral service establishment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Denies access by the Director to a funeral services establishment or itsecords;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Fails to comply with an order of or agreement with the Director; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Fails to pay a civil fine imposed pursuant to the Department of Consumernd Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985, D.C. Law 6-42, D.C. Code,ection 6-2701 et seq.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Source: Final Rulemaking published at 39 DCR 7853, 7863 (October 23, 1992).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>