<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-3644</num>
  <heading>WATER QUALITY INFRACTIONS (§ 16-3644)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3644.1.</num>
    <text>Violation of Section 3 of the Water Pollution Control Act of 1984, effective March 16, 1985 (D.C. Law 5-188; D.C. Official Code § 8.103.02) (discharge of pollutants to the waters of the District without a permit) shall be a Class 1 infraction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3644.2.</num>
    <text>Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 2 infraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 7(a) of the Water Pollution Control Act of 1984 (D.C. Official Code 8.103.06(a)) (discharging corrosive, flammable or explosive material into a sewer);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 8(e) of the Water Pollution Control Act of 1984 (D.C. Official Code § 8.103.07(e)) (discharging used motor oil into a sewer); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>21 DCMR § 1407.1 (the use of any herbicide or chemical to control submerged aquatic vegetation without approval).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3644.3.</num>
    <text>Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 3 infraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 7(m) of the Water Pollution Control Act of 1984 (D.C. Official Code § 8.103.06(m)) (discharging sanitary sewage, wash or process water, oil laden bilge water, refuse or litter from a watercraft);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 8(d) of the Water Pollution Control Act of 1984 (D.C. Official Code § 8.103.07(d)) (discharging oil, gasoline, antifreeze, acid or other hazardous substance, pollutant or nuisance material into a public space);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Section 17(b)(1) of the Water Pollution Control Act of 1984 (D.C. Official Code § 8.103.16(b)(1)) (making a false statement in an application, record, report, plan, or other document filed under the Water Pollution Control Act); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>21 DCMR § 1401.3 (harvesting, cutting, removing, or eradication of submerged aquatic vegetation without plan approval).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 5056 (May 27, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>