<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-3624</num>
  <heading>(§ 16-3624)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3624.1.</num>
    <text>Reserved</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3624.2.</num>
    <text>Reserved</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3624.3.</num>
    <text>Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 3 infraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2809 (operating a barbershop or beauty parlor without a license);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>17 DCMR § 3701.9 (engaging in the practice of barbering or cosmetology when suffering from a known infectious or contagious disease unless the licensee takes appropriate precautions and uses safeguards that prevent the spread of the disease to the
        public);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>17 DCMR § 3702.1 (a) through (g) (operating a barbershop or beauty parlor without a license or certificate of registration);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>17 DCMR § 3702.2 (engaging in the practice of barbering or cosmetology before the issuance of all required licenses);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>17 DCMR § 3702.2 (owning a salon or shop before the issuance of all required licenses);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>17 DCMR § 3702.2 (operating a salon or shop before the issuance of all required licenses);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>17 DCMR § 3716.1 (operating a salon or shop without first having obtained the appropriate business licenses, registrations, and/or certificates, except as specified in § 3721); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>17 DCMR § 3727.1 (failure to permit an inspection of the premises).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3624.4.</num>
    <text>Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 4 infraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>17 DCMR § 3716.7 (operating a salon or shop without a licensed manager on duty at all times during operating hours, except as specified in section 3721); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>17 DCMR § 3718.1 through 3718.18 (failure to comply with minimum equipment requirements in violation of public health regulations).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3624.5.</num>
    <text>Violation of any provision of District of Columbia Barber and Cosmetology Regulations, 17 DCMR, Chapter 37, which is not cited elsewhere in this section, shall be a Class 5 infraction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 5044 (May 27, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>