<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-3618</num>
  <heading>PHARMACY DRUG HANDLING AND RECORDKEEPING INFRACTIONS (§ 16-3618)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3618.1</num>
    <text>3618.1 Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 1nfraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.10(a)(3) (2005 Repl.), 22 DCMR B § 1901.5,nd 22 DCMR B § 1901.6 (selling or offering for sale an adulterated orisbranded drug or device);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.12 (2005 Repl.)(failure to comply with therovision governing the bulk sale or transfer of drugs or medical devices);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.13(a) (2005 Repl.)and 22 DCMR B § 1901.6selling or dispensing drugs after the expiration date designated on the labelf the original container, or not in accordance with applicable District ofolumbia or federal laws or
        regulations);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.13(a) (2005 Repl.) and 22 DCMR B §911.11(failure to store drugs under conditions specified on the label of theriginal container and in accordance with applicable District of Columbia orederal laws or regulations);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.13(c) (2005 Repl.)and 22 DCMR B § 1329.1placing in stock for reuse or resale, or accepting back to the pharmacy, a drughich has been returned after leaving the pharmacy, except manufacturer packagednit dose or unit of
        use drugs which have been unopened and unaltered);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.15(a), (c) (2005 Repl.), 22 DCMR B § 1913.2,nd 22 DCMR B § 1913.4 (failure to maintain in every pharmacy, or in thestablishment or institution where a pharmacy is located, a suitable book, file,r other easily retrievable
        records, for a period of not less than five (5)ears, for every prescription dispensed or refilled at the pharmacy fornspection, during regular business hours);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1300.7 (dispensing a medication or device pursuant to arescription that the pharmacist knows is not based on a validatient–practitioner relationship);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1302.2 (failure to immediately reduce an oral prescriptionrder to writing);</text>
    </level>
    <text>22 DCMR B § 1302.3 through § 1302.9 (failure to include all requirednformation on an oral prescription drug order);</text>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1303.6 through 1303.12 (failure of telephone facsimile orderso contain all required information);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1301 and 22 DCMR B § 1304 (dispensing a medication or deviceased upon a prescription order that fails to contain the required information);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1305.6 (dispensing a medication or device pursuant to arescription that the pharmacist knows was not issued in the usual course ofrofessional treatment or in legitimate and authorized research);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1503.1 and 22 DCMR B § 1913, with the exception</text>
    </level>
    <text>of § 1913.6 (failure to maintain prescription files in conformity with theequirements of 22 DCMR B 1913);</text>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1901.4 (stocking, maintaining, selling, compounding,ispensing, or distributing drugs, medical devices, or chemicals for compoundinghat are not registered with the FDA);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1901.7 (obtaining drugs or medical devices from an entity thats not registered or exempted from registration in the District of Columbiaursuant to the Uniform Controlled Substances Act or the federal government orhe state in which it
        is located);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(p)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1903.16(b) (failure of a non-resident pharmacy to maintainecords of prescription drugs and devices dispensed to patients in the Districtf Columbia in a readily retrievable manner for a period of five (5) years fromhe date of first dispensing);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(q)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1903.16(c) (failure a non-resident pharmacy to comply with theaws and regulations regarding confidentially of prescription records);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(r)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1911 (failure to comply with the packaging and handlingequirements under District of Columbia or federal laws and regulations);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(s)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1911.9 (failure to maintain a log of drugs that have beenompounded, repackaged, or prepackaged under a pharmacist’s supervisionontaining the required information);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(t)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1913.11 (failure to maintain a patient record system withmmediate retrieval of required patient information during pharmacy operatingours);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(u)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 48-803.03a (2001 Supp.), 22 DCMR B § 1327.1, and 22CMR B § 1328.5, (failure to properly notify an individual of a drugubstitution and provide the right to refuse the substitution prior to theurchase of the substitute drug product);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(v)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 48-803.03 (2009 Repl.; 2011 Supp.) and 22 DCMR B §328.3 (dispensing a therapeutically equivalent drug product without the priorpproval of the prescriber);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(w)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 48-803.03 (2009 Repl.; 2011 Supp.)(dispensing aubstitute product when the person purchasing the drug product or the patientor whom it is intended indicates a preference for the drug product actuallyrescribed);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(x)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 48-803.03 (2009 Repl.; 2011 Supp.)(dispensing aherapeutically equivalent drug product for a prescription refill of anntipsychotic, antidepressant, chemotherapy, antiretroviral, ormmunosuppressive drug);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(y)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1325.1 (failure to dispense a prescription non- controlledubstance or a medical device pursuant to a valid written, oral, facsimile, orlectronic prescription issued in compliance with this chapter by a licensedractitioner authorized
        to prescribe the substance or medical device;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(z)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1325.6 (failure to affix a label to the non-controlled</text>
    </level>
    <text>substance prescriptions package meeting the requirements as set</text>
    <text>forth in chapter 19 of subtitle B of title 22 of the DCMR);</text>
    <text>(aa) 22 DCMR B § 1325.8 (filling a prescription for a non-controlledsubstance more than one (1) year after the date on which the prescription wasssued);</text>
    <text>(bb) 22 DCMR B § 1325.9 (filling a prescription order for a non- controlledubstance in excess of a one (1) year supply); or</text>
    <text>(cc) 22 DCMR B § 1328.4 (failure to properly document in a readily retrievableorm the documented policy, which clearly indicates</text>
    <text>that the provider has intended to approve the therapeutic interchange).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3618.2</num>
    <text>3618.2 Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 2nfraction:</text>
    <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.13(b) (2005 Repl.)(selling drugs designated as</text>
    <text>“sample”);</text>
    <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.14 (2005 Repl.) and 22 DCMR B §§ 1912.1, et seq.(failure of pharmacy to dispense a drug, except to inpatients of a</text>
    <text>licensed hospital, in a suitable container appropriately labeled for</text>
    <text>subsequent administration to, or use by, an individual entitled to the</text>
    <text>drug);</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1316 (failure to comply with the provisions for transferring prescription between pharmacies for refill purposes);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1903.14 (failure of a non-resident pharmacy to provideoll-free telephone communication consultation and affix the number to each drugr device dispensed to patients in the District as required);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1903.15 (failure of a non-resident pharmacy to immediatelyotify a patient or prescriber of any expected delay in delivering therescribed drug or device that may jeopardize or alter the drug therapy of theatient);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1912.4 (failure to label prepackaged or repackaged containersith a label containing required information required under District of Columbiar federal laws and regulations);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1912.6 (failure to place the appropriate expiration date onulti-dose containers after they are opened);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1914 (failure to comply with the requirements for computerizedecordkeeping under District of Columbia or federal laws and regulations);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1915 (failure to comply with the requirements for automatededication dispensing systems under District of Columbia or federal laws andegulations);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1916.1 (failure to comply with the requirements for remoteutomated pharmacy services under District of Columbia or federal laws andegulations);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1917.1 (failure to comply with the requirements forelepharmacy services under District of Columbia or federal laws andegulations);</text>
    </level>
    <text>D.C. Official Code § 48-803.02 (2009 Repl.; 2011 Supp.) and 22 DCMR B § 1326.1when dispensing a generically equivalent drug, failure to dispense the drugroduct in stock having the lowest cost to the person purchasing the drugroduct; or when the prescriber
      has specified that the prescribed brand is to beispensed);</text>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1325.10 (failure to properly document and uniformly maintainn a readily retrievable record each refilling of a non-controlled substance);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1325.12 (failure to document required refill authorizationnformation on each prescription refill); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1326.3 (use of a formulary of drug products other than thehemical and generic drugs contained in the publication, “Approved Drugroducts with Therapeutic Equivalence Evaluations (also known as the Orangeook),” and its monthly updates).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3618.3</num>
    <text>3618.3 Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 3nfraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 3-1210.06a(a)(1) through (a)(6)(2007 Repl.); and D.C. Official Code § 3-1210.06a(a)(8) (2007 Repl.)(failing to consult with medical assistance recipients or caregivers who present anriginal prescription order for outpatient
        drugs);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 3-1210.06a(c)(1) (2007 Repl.)(failure to documenthe refusal for a consultation by a Medical Assistance Recipient or Caregiver);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.15(b)(2)(A) (2005 Repl.) and D.C. Officialode § 47-2885.15(c) (2005 Repl.)(failure to maintain a bound volume containingimilar information concerning each sale of hypodermic syringes, needles, orther medical devices
        which may be used in the administration of controlledubstances, and to make such available for inspection during regular businessours);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.15(b)(1) (2005 Repl.), and D.C. Official Code 47-2885.15(c) (2005 Repl.)(failure to maintain and make available fornspection during regular business hours, in every pharmacy, or establishment ornstitution where a pharmacy
        is located, bound volumes recording the informationequired by law or regulation concerning the over-the-counter sales of thoserugs which are listed in Schedule V established or amended pursuant to theederal Comprehensive Drug Abuse Prevention
        and Control Act of 1970 (21 U.S.C.§ 801, et seq.);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.15(b)(2)(C) (2005 Rep.) and D.C. Official Code 47-2885.15(c) (2005 Repl.)(failure to maintain a bound volume containingimilar information concerning each sale of diluents or adulterants, such asactose or quinine, in
        quantities sufficient to indicate an intention to useuch substances for the illegal distribution or dispensing of any controlledubstance, and to make such available for inspection during regular businessours);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1315 (failure to comply with the provisions for delivering arescription medication by mail, common carrier, employee or courier service);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1333.7 (filling a written prescription, for a Medicaideneficiary, that is not submitted on a tamper resistant prescription</text>
    </level>
    <text>form meeting the requirements set forth in 22 DCMR B § 1333.2, in the absencef an emergency situation, or failure to obtain a verbal, telephone facsimile,lectronic, or compliant written prescription within seventy-two (72) hoursfter filling);</text>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1913.6 (failure to put in place systems to assign a securedentification for each pharmacist for use on verification of records, or toequire manual signatures of pharmacists performing final verifications);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1918 (failure of the pharmacist on duty to conduct arospective drug regimen review prior to or at the time of dispensing arescription drug order as required under District of Columbia or federal lawsr regulations);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1919 (failure of the pharmacist on duty or registered pharmacyntern acting under the direct supervision of a</text>
    </level>
    <text>license pharmacist, to offer to counsel, counsel, or notify of the opportunityo receive a consultation, to a non-inpatient or the patient’s agent, whetherr not the patient is a medical assistance recipient, or to comply with theatient counseling requirements
      under District of Columbia or federal laws oregulations);</text>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1325.15 (failure to properly document the partial filling of prescription for a non-controlled substance);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1325.15 (a partial filling of a non-controlled substance thatxceeds the total quantity prescribed);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1325.15 (dispensing a partial filling of a non-controlledubstance more than one year after the date on which the prescription wasssued);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1325.16 (failure to notify the prescribing physician when theharmacist is unable to dispense the remaining portion of a partially filledrescription for a prescription non-controlled substance within a reasonableeriod of time, the inability
        to do so lies with the pharmacy, and theharmacist believes the delay may jeopardize or alter the drug therapy of theatient);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1327.1(b) (failure to document the dosage form substitution onhe prescription record);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(p)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1327.1(c) (failure to notify the practitioner of the dosageorm substitution prior to dispensing or as soon as is reasonably possiblehereafter);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(q)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1327.1(d) (the dosage form dispensed fails to contain thedentical amount of the active ingredients as the dosage prescribed; or is annteric-coated or time release product; or otherwise alters desired clinicalutcomes); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(r)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1327.3 (making a dosage form substitution with the use of aroduct that has been compounded by the pharmacist without obtaining theractitioner’s approval prior to dispensing).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 5026 (May 27, 2005); as amended byotice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 7425, 7435 (August 19, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>