<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-3617</num>
  <heading>PHARMACY OPERATIONS INFRACTIONS (§ 16-3617)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3617.1</num>
    <text>3617.1 Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 1nfraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.09(d) (2005 Repl.)(failure to report a burglary or damage to a pharmacy or its contents by fire, flood, or otherause or dispensing, selling, or giving away a drug or other merchandiseamaged by fire, flood, or other cause
        prior to approval by the Mayor);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.10(a)(2) (2005 Repl.), D.C. Official Code §7-2885.16 (2005 Repl.), and D.C. Official Code § 48-903.02(f) (2009epl.)(refusing to allow an inspection in accordance with D.C. Official Code§ 47-2885.10(a)(2) and 47-2885.16
        (2009 Repl.); refusing to allow entry intony pharmacy or drug outlet, at reasonable times, for the purpose of makingnspections to determine compliance with this chapter or with other laws oregulations applicable to the practice of pharmacy; or
        failure to allow theayor or an agent of the Mayor entry into an establishment during reasonableours for the purpose of conducting an inspection of the establishment of aegistrant);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.11(a)(1) (2005 Repl.; 2011 Supp.)(pharmacyersonnel actively engaged in any work, which includes contact with anyerchandise or drugs in a pharmacy or the care of dispensing, manufacturing, ortorage facilities, in a pharmacy
        who is affected by a communicable disease, oro be a carrier of a communicable disease in any capacity dispensing,anufacturing, or storing merchandise or drugs when infected with a communicableisease);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.11(a)(2) (2005 Repl.; 2011upp.)(intentionally permitting a person to engage in work activities whilenfected with a communicable disease);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.11(b)(1) (2005 Repl.; 2011 Supp.)(working inny capacity in a pharmacy when infected with a boil, infectious wound, sore orn acute respiratory infection);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.11(b)(3) (2005 Repl.; 2011 Supp.)(working inny capacity in a pharmacy when suffering from chronic alcoholism);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.11(b)(2) and (b)(4) (2005 Repl.; 2011upp.)(working in any capacity in a pharmacy without following hygienic workractices or while wearing unclean garments);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1900.4 (failure to maintain written policies and proceduresegarding cleanliness and hygiene standards; or ensure employees comply withuch);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1901.8 (failure to report thefts, suspected diversions,ignificant losses of drug inventory or the inability to account for suchnventory, to the Director within forty-eight (48) hours after discovery);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1903.16(d) (failure of a non-resident pharmacy to comply withll requests for information made by the Department pursuant to 22 DCMR B §903);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1908 (failure to comply with sanitation standards; orerforming professional services under unsanitary conditions under District ofolumbia or federal laws and regulations);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1920 (failure to comply with the requirements and duties for aharmacist-in-charge under District of Columbia or federal laws andegulations);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1921 (failure to comply with the requirements fornstitutional pharmacies under District of Columbia or federal laws andegulations); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1922 (failure to comply with the requirements for nuclearharmacies under District of Columbia or federal laws and regulations).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3617.2</num>
    <text>3617.2 Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 2nfraction:</text>
    <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.09(b) (2005 Repl.)(failure of pharmacist on dutyo control all professional aspects of the practice of pharmacy, or allowingny usurpation, in reference or impairment of the exercise of professionaludgment of the pharmacist
      on duty by a non-pharmacist proprietor or personnel);</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 47-2885.09(c) (2005 Repl.)(failure to securely encloseharmacy area so as to prevent unauthorized access to pharmacy areas and torevent the diversion of drugs stored in pharmacy areas; to substantiallyonstruct pharmacy and any
        storage areas for prescription drugs outside of theharmacy; to have doors capable of being securely locked, to restrict access toharmacists, the proprietor of the pharmacy, or persons authorized by aharmacist with the consent of the proprietor;
        or to maintain the key or keys tohe pharmacy areas under the control or in the possession of the pharmacist onuty or the proprietor of the pharmacy);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1500.1(d) (failure to furnish a sufficient sample of any drugr article of food for analysis);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1900.3 (having drugs in a pharmacy before a pharmacy licenseas been obtained from the Director);</text>
    </level>
    <text>22 DCMR B § 1900.5 (failure to review, revise, or document the review ofritten policies and procedures as required);</text>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1907, with the exception of § 1907.3 (failure to comply withhe physical standards requirements for operation of a pharmacy under Districtf Columbia or federal laws or regulations); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1910, with the exception of § 1910.9 (failure to comply withecurity and safeguards against diversion requirements under District ofolumbia or federal laws and regulations).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3617.3</num>
    <text>3617.3 Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 3nfraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 48-801.04 (2009 Repl.)(failure to make availablepon request the current selling price of all prescription drugs, includinghose not required to be posted, dispensed by each pharmacy and the pharmacy’siscounts and professional
        and convenience services and charges therefor);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>D.C. Official Code § 48-801.05 (2009 Repl.)(failure to provide to anyonsumer the discounts and services stated on the poster, under the eligibility,rice, and other terms there stated);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1909 (failure to comply with the equipment and referenceaterial requirements under District of Columbia or federal laws andegulations); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR B § 1910.9 (displaying or storing drugs, medical devices, oredical supplies in an area accessible to the public which are (1) prescription drugs or devices; (2) devices that may be used in the</text>
    </level>
    <text>administration of controlled substances; (3) over-the counter medicines thatontain controlled substances; or (4) over-the-counter medicines that haveeen identified by the Food and Drug Administration or the Director asaving a potential for misuse
      or abuse).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 5026 (May 27, 2005); as amended byotice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 7425, 7432 (August 19, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>