<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-3631</num>
  <heading>RODENT CONTROL INFRACTIONS (§ 16-3631)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3631.1.</num>
    <text>RESERVED</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3631.2.</num>
    <text>RESERVED</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3631.3.</num>
    <text>Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 3 infraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>21 DCMR § 700.3 (failure to properly containerize solid wastes);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>21 DCMR § 705.3 (permitting spillage of waste from a container or collection vehicle at a point of collection);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>21 DCMR § 707.3 (failure to provide a sufficient number of food waste containers);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>21 DCMR § 707.9 (failure to properly store grease held for recycling or disposal);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>21 DCMR § 707.11 (failure to use a properly constructed and properly maintained commercial waste container);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>25 DCMR I § 200.1(a) (failure to comply with an order to provide vent stoppage of any rat-infested building or other structure or part thereof);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>25 DCMR I § 200.1(b) (failure to comply with an order to remove trash or refuse from the premises which may provide rat harborage);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>25 DCMR I §200.1(c) (failure to comply with an order to protect food and garbage from rats);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>25 DCMR I § 200.1(d) (failure to comply with an order to exterminate rats on the premises of buildings or other structures);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>25 DCMR I § 200.4 (refusal to permit or interfering with inspections to determine the prevalence of rats);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>25 DCMR A §2705.1 (failure to have tight-fitting lid, door, or cover on a food waste receptacle);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>25 DCMR A § 2705.2 (failure to install waste handling unit for refuse and recyclables in a manner that minimizes insect and rodent harborage and allows effective cleaning around and under the unit);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>25 DCMR A § 2706.1 (failure to maintain sufficient storage capacity for refuse, recyclables, and returnables);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>25 DCMR A § 2706.2 (failure to provide a waste receptacle in each area where refuse is generated or recyclables or returnables are placed);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>25 DCMR A § 2706.3 (failure to place a waste receptacle in a lavatory where disposable towels are used);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(p)</num>
      <text>25 DCMR A § 2710.1 (failure to store refuse, recyclables, and returnables in receptacles so they are inaccessible to insects and rodents);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(q)</num>
      <text>25 DCMR A § 2712.1 (storage of unprotected plastic bags, paper bags, or baled units containing food residue outside);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(r)</num>
      <text>25 DCMR A § 2712.2 (storage of packaging material in a way that creates a rodent harborage problem);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(s)</num>
      <text>25 DCMR A § 2713.1 (failure to keep waste handling units covered when used inside and not in continuous use);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(t)</num>
      <text>25 DCMR A § 2713.2 (failure to keep waste handling units for refuse, recyclables, and returnables covered with tight-fitting lids or doors when kept outside);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(u)</num>
      <text>25 DCMR A § 2714.1 (failure to have a drain plug in place in a receptacle for refuse, recyclable, and returnables);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(v)</num>
      <text>25 DCMR A § 2715.1 (failure to keep storage area for refuse, recyclables, and returnables clean and free of unnecessary equipment);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(w)</num>
      <text>25 DCMR A §2716.1 (failure to thoroughly clean receptacles and waste handling units for refuse, recyclables, and returnables);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(x)</num>
      <text>25 DCMR A § 2716.2 (failure to clean receptacles and waste handling units for refuse, recyclables, and returnables frequently enough to prevent attracting insects and rodents);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(y)</num>
      <text>25 DCMR A § 2717.1 (failure to remove refuse, recyclables, and returnables from the premises frequently enough to minimize objectionable odors and other conditions that attract or harbor insects and rodents);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(z)</num>
      <text>25 DCMR A § 2717.2 (failure to maintain copies of waste removal contractor records);</text>
    </level>
    <text>(aa) 25 DCMR A § 2717.3 (failure to comply with a solid waste collection requirement of 21 DCMR Chapter 7);</text>
    <text>(bb) Section 908(c) of the Rodent Control Act of 2000, effective October 19, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-172; D.C. Official Code § 8-2103.05 (c)(2008 Repl.)) (failure to use a licensed and certified pest controller to abate existing rodent populations due to
      the accumulation of debris on public or private property);</text>
    <text>(cc) Section 908(b) of the Rodent Control Act of 2000, effective October 19, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-172; D.C. Official Code § 8-2103.05(b)(2008 Repl.)) (failure of an owner to comply with an order to take appropriate abatement measures if signs of past
      rodent harborage are found upon transfer or change of occupancy of real property); and</text>
    <text>(dd) Section 908(c) of the Rodent Control Act of 2000, effective October 19, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-172; D.C. Official Code § 8-2103.05(c)(2008 Repl).)) (failure to comply with an order to remove debris from public or private property).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3631.4.</num>
    <text>Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 4 infraction:</text>
    <text>21 DCMR § 708.10 (using plastic bags to store and dispose of solid waste other than yard waste; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 908(c) of the Rodent Control Act of 2000, effective October 19, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-172; D.C. Official Code § 8-2103.05(c)(2008 Repl.)) (failure to comply with an order to keep grass or weeds cut to a height of less than eight inches (8 in.)).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3631.5.</num>
    <text>Violation of 21 DCMR § 707.12 (failure to store pet food or bird seed in a rodent-proof container or remove uneaten food or feed remaining on the ground after birds and pets have been fed) shall be a Class 5 infraction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 5045 (May 27, 2005); as amended at 53 DCR 9008 (November 3, 2006); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 5687 (July 8, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>