<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-3609</num>
  <heading>BACKGROUND CHECKS FOR HEALTH-CARE WORKERS INFRACTIONS (§ 16-3609)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3609.1.</num>
    <text>Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 1 infraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 4701.1(a) (employing or using the contract services of a person convicted of a listed offense);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 4705.1 (employing or using the contract services of a person convicted of a listed offense;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 4701.1(b) (employing or using the contract services of a person listed on the Nurse Aide Abuse Registry);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 4703.2 (continuing to employ or use the contract services of a current staff member if a background check reveals a conviction for a listed offense); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 4705.2 (employing or using the contract services of a person convicted of a listed misdemeanor offense unless the specified requirements for employment are met).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3609.2.</num>
    <text>Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 2 infraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 4701.2 (failure to obtain a criminal background check and/or a Nurse Aide Abuse Registry check before employing or using the contract services of a covered person);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 4704.1(d) (failure to maintain documentation of an employee&amp;#8217;s criminal background check results);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 4704.1(e) (failure to maintain documentation of an employee&amp;#8217;s Nurse Aide Abuse Registry check results); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 4705.3 (failure to verify whether a person convicted of a misdemeanor meets the specified requirements for employment).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3609.3.</num>
    <text>Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 3 infraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 4701.5 (failure to obtain a complete criminal background check as specified before employing an individual);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 4704.2 (improper disclosure of criminal background check records);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 4704.3 (failure to manage recordkeeping and disclosure of Nurse Aide Abuse Registry information in compliance with the Abuse Registry rules);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 4704.4 (failure to maintain an employee&amp;#8217;s criminal background records for 1 year following the end of that person&amp;#8217;s employment).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3609.4.</num>
    <text>Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 4 infraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 4701.3 (failure to inform an applicant of the background check requirement, or to obtain the information necessary for the performance of the check, before offering employment);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 4704.1(a) (failure to maintain documentation of an employee&amp;#8217;s date of hire);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 4704.1(b) (failure to maintain documentation of the date a background check was requested for an employee);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 4704.1(c) (failure to maintain documentation of the date the background check results for an employee were received);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 4704.1(f) (failure to maintain documentation of any sworn statements submitted by an employee related to his or her background check); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>22 DCMR § 4704.1(g) (failure to maintain documentation of any action taken by the employer facility as a result of information obtained from a background check).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 5017 (May 27, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>