<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-3601</num>
  <heading>HEALTH PRACTICE INFRACTIONS (§ 16-3601)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3601.1.</num>
    <text>Violation of the following provision shall be a Class 1 infraction: Section 501 of the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, effective Mar. 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code § 3-1205.01) (practicing medicine, acupuncture,
      chiropractic, registered nursing, practical nursing, dentistry, dental hygiene, dietetics, nutrition, nursing home administration, occupational therapy, optometry, pharmacy, physical therapy, podiatry, psychology, social work, as a physician&amp;#8217;s
      assistant or as an occupational therapy assistant without a license).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3601.2.</num>
    <text>Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 2 infraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 901 of the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 (D.C. Official Code § 3-1209.01) (practicing naturopathy or naturopathic healing without a certificate of registration);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 902 of the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 (D.C. Official Code § 3-1209.02) (engaging in the practice of dance therapy or recreation therapy without a certificate of registration); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Section 101 of the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 (D.C. Official Code § 3-1210.01) (practicing a health occupation, other than one enumerated in D.C. Official Code § 3-1205.01, without a license).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3601.3.</num>
    <text>Violation of any of the following provisions shall be a Class 4 infraction:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 513(a) of the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 (D.C. Official Code § 3-1205.13(a)) (failure to display license conspicuously in any and all places of business or employment of the licensee); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 513(b) of the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 (D.C. Official Code § 3-1205.13(b)) (failure to notify the board of any changes of address of the place of residence or place of business or employment within 30
        days after the change of address).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 4980 (May 27, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>