<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-615</num>
  <heading>COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES (CR) (§ 11-615)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>615.1.</num>
    <text>College or university use shall be permitted as a special exception in a CR District when authorized by the Zoning Commission under § 3104, if the Commission considers that this use is appropriate in furthering the objectives of the CR Districts,
      subject to the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>615.2.</num>
    <text>The college or university use shall be located so that it is not likely to become objectionable to neighboring property because of noise, traffic, number of students, or other objectionable conditions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>615.3.</num>
    <text>The applicant shall submit to the Commission a plan for developing the campus as a whole, showing the location, height, and bulk, where appropriate, of all present and proposed improvements including but not limited to buildings, parking and loading
      facilities, screening, signs, streets, and public facilities, athletic and other recreational facilities, and a description of all activities conducted or to be conducted in the facilities, and of the capacity of all present and proposed campus
      development.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>615.4.</num>
    <text>Within a reasonable distance of the college or university campus, and subject to compliance with §§ 615.2 and 3104, the Commission may also permit the interim use of land or improved property with any use that the Commission may determine is a proper
      college or university function.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>615.5.</num>
    <text>Before taking final action on an application for college or university use, the Commission shall refer the application to the D.C. Office of Planning for coordination, review, and report.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>615.6.</num>
    <text>The Office of Planning report shall include the reports and recommendations of the D.C. Department of Transportation and of other departments and agencies of the District of Columbia as appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§ 4502.310 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9725, 9733-34 (December 8, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>