<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-605</num>
  <heading>PLANNING OFFICE REVIEW (CR) (§ 11-605)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>605.1.</num>
    <text>Wherever §§ 606 and 608 through 618 require referral of an application to the D.C. Office of Planning for coordination, review, and report, including the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Whether the proposed use furthers the objectives of the CR District;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The relationship of the proposed use to other planning considerations for the area and the District of Columbia as a whole, including the plans, programs, and policies of other departments and agencies of the District government;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The proposed site plan, including the relationship of different uses on the site;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The impact of the proposed site plan on neighboring properties; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any other matters that are within the Office&amp;#8217;s jurisdiction.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>605.2.</num>
    <text>Wherever §§ 606 and 608 through 618 require referral of an application by the D.C. Office of Planning to the D.C. Department of Transportation, the report by the Department of Transportation to the Office of Planning shall include the following matters
      related to transportation and the environment:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Considerations of the traffic to be generated and its impact;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Location and design of vehicular access and parking facilities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Number of parking and loading facilities;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Treatment of public space;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Availability of sewer and water capacity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Impact on air quality;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Potential noise from commercial, industrial, and traffic sources; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Any other matters that are within the Department&amp;#8217;s jurisdiction.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§ 4502.313 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8380-81 (October 20,
        2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>