<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-630</num>
  <heading>HEIGHT OF BUILDINGS OR STRUCTURES (CR) (§ 11-630)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>630.1.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in this section, the height of buildings and structures shall not exceed ninety feet (90 ft.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>630.2.</num>
    <text>Free-standing, primarily ground-supported signs shall not exceed twenty feet (20 ft.) in height.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>630.3.</num>
    <text>Spires, towers, domes, pinnacles or minarets serving as architectural embellishments, penthouses over elevator shafts, ventilator shafts, antennas, chimneys, smokestacks, or fire sprinkler tanks may be erected to a height in excess of that which this
      sections otherwise authorizes. This section shall not be interpreted to bypass otherwise required special exception reviews.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>630.4.</num>
    <text>If housing for mechanical equipment or a stairway or elevator penthouse is provided on the roof of a building or structure, it shall be erected or enlarged as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>It shall meet the requirements of § 411;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>It shall be set back from all exterior walls a distance at least equal to its height above the roof upon which it is located; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>It shall not exceed eighteen feet, six inches (18 ft., 6 in.), in height above the roof upon which it is located. Mechanical equipment shall not extend above the permitted eighteen foot, six inch (18 ft., 6 in.), height of the housing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>630.5.</num>
    <text>Housing for mechanical equipment or a stairway or elevator penthouse may be erected to a height in excess of that authorized in the district in which located.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>630.6.</num>
    <text>A public recreation and community center shall not exceed a height of forty-five (45) feet.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE §§ 4503.1 through 4503.5 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by:</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 3975, 3977 (July 4, 1986); Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 179, 192 (January 8, 1988); and Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 974143 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed
        Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8385 (October 20, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 10137 (November 28, 2003); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 34 (January 4, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>