<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-618</num>
  <heading>MISCELLANEOUS USES (CR) (§ 11-618)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>618.1.</num>
    <text>Other uses not specified in § 601 and not prohibited by § 602 shall be permitted in a CR District as a special exception when authorized by the Board of Zoning Adjustment in accordance with § 3104, if the Board considers that this use is appropriate
      in furthering the objectives of the CR Districts, subject to the provisions of this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>618.2.</num>
    <text>Uses authorized under this section shall not adversely affect the present character and future development of the neighborhood.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>618.3.</num>
    <text>No dangerous or otherwise objectionable traffic conditions shall result from the establishment of any miscellaneous use.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>618.4.</num>
    <text>The Board may impose requirements pertaining to the design, appearance, screening, or any other requirements that it deems necessary for the protection of neighboring or adjacent property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>618.5.</num>
    <text>Before taking final action on an application for any miscellaneous use, the Board shall refer the application to the D.C. Office of Planning for coordination, review, and report.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>618.6.</num>
    <text>The report of the Office of Planning shall include the reports and recommendations of the D.C. Department of Transportation, and of other departments and agencies of the District of Columbia as appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§ 4502.311 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8385 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>