<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-600</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (CR) (§ 11-600)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>600.1.</num>
    <text>The purpose of the Mixed Use Commercial Residential (CR) District shall be to encourage a diversity of compatible land uses that may include a mixture of residential, office, retail, recreational, light industrial, and other miscellaneous uses.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.2.</num>
    <text>Development shall be guided by an approved public policy or plan and through the use of the planned unit development, special exception, or other site plan review process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.3.</num>
    <text>By the use of the public review and planning powers, the provisions of this chapter also shall be intended to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Help create major new residential and mixed use areas in planned locations at appropriate densities, heights, and mixtures of uses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Encourage the preservation and rehabilitation of structures of historic or architectural merit in the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Encourage areas devoted primarily to pedestrians by separating pedestrian and vehicular circulation patterns and by requiring off-street parking spaces in accordance with this objective and with the objectives of specific area plans;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Encourage flexibility in architectural design and building bulk; provided, that the designs and building bulk shall be compatible and harmonious with adjoining development over the CR District as a whole;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Make recreation areas more accessible to the CR District&amp;#8217;s residents and visitors; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>In a variety of ways, create environments conducive to a higher quality of life and environment for residents, businesses, employees, and institutions in the District of Columbia as specified in District plans and policies.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.4.</num>
    <text>The CR District shall be applied to selected geographic areas where a mixture of uses and building densities is intended to carry out elements of District of Columbia development plans, including goals in employment, population, transportation, housing,
      public facilities, and environmental quality.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.5.</num>
    <text>A CR District may be located on the periphery of the Central Employment Area.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.6.</num>
    <text>In certain of these areas, as designated now or in the future by public plans and policies, a mixture of uses and building densities shall be intended to promote and protect the public health, safety, convenience, order, prosperity, and general welfare
      of the community as best accomplished by the CR District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.7.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in chapters 23 through 25 of this title, in the CR District, no building or premises shall be used and no building shall be erected or altered that is arranged, intended, or designed to be used, except for one (1) or more of the
      uses listed in §§ 601, 606, and 608 through 618.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is the Zoning Act of 1938, approved June 20, 1938 (52 Stat. 797, as amended; D.C. Official Code §§ 6-641.01 to 6-641.15 (formerly codified at D.C. Code §§ 5-413 to 5-432 (1994 Repl. &amp;#038;
        1999 Supp.))).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§§ 4501.1 and 4502.1 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 29 DCR 584 (February 5, 1982); and Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the
        text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8379 (October 20, 2000).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>