<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-201</num>
  <heading>SEARCH AND REPRODUCTION SERVICES[COLON] OFFICE OF THE MAYOR (§ 1-201)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>201.1.</num>
    <text>There shall be no charge to the public for searches for documents which can be readily obtained from current office files. Charges shall be made for all searches for documents requiring lengthy searching (quarter hour or longer) and requesting from
      remote storage locations. All searches will be dependent on available manpower and restricted in accordance with demands of official workload.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.2.</num>
    <text>Photographic reproductions shall be provided to the public in reasonable quantities (limited only by availability of equipment and manpower). Workloads for official purposes shall take priority over demands of the public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.3.</num>
    <text>The following fees shall be charged for services provided to the public:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Photographic reproductions (xerox or equivalent), page size up to eight and one-half inches by fourteen inches (8½ in. x 14 in.), per page &amp;#8211; twenty five cents (25¢);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Certification (true copies of original), per document &amp;#8211; one dollar ($1.00);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Attestation under seal of the District government, per document &amp;#8211; two dollars ($2.00); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Document searches &amp;#8211; one dollar ($1.00) for each fifteen (15) minutes or fraction thereof, with a minimum charge of four dollars ($4.00).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.4.</num>
    <text>Fees shall be waived for services to District government offices and agencies or may be waived as a courtesy to other municipal, state, or federal government offices.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.5.</num>
    <text>When individual fees to be collected are less than one dollar ($1.00), such fees may be administratively waived.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>201.6.</num>
    <text>Payments for services shall be made in cash or by money order or check made payable to the D.C. Treasurer. Postage stamps shall not be accepted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>1 DCRR §§ 215.1 through 215.5 (May 30, 1972).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>