<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-777</num>
  <heading>ARCHITECTURAL AND INDUSTRIAL MAINTENANCE COATING – REPORTING REQUIREMENTS (§0-777)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>777.1.</num>
    <text>Upon request by the Department, any manufacturer of clear brushing lacquers shall submit a report to the Department that specifies the number of gallons of clear brushing lacquers sold in the District of Columbia during the preceding calendar year,
      and describes the method used by the manufacturer to calculate District of Columbia sales.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>777.2.</num>
    <text>Upon request by the Department, any manufacturer of rust preventive coatings shall submit an annual report to the Department that specifies the number of gallons of rust preventive coatings sold in the District of Columbia during the preceding calendar
      year, and describes the method used by the manufacturer to calculate District of Columbia sales.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>777.3.</num>
    <text>Upon request by the Department, any manufacturer of specialty primers, sealers, and undercoaters shall submit an annual report to the Department that specifies the number of gallons of specialty primers, sealers, and undercoaters sold in the District
      of Columbia during the preceding calendar year, and describes the method used by the manufacturer to calculate District of Columbia sales.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>777.4.</num>
    <text>Upon request by the Department, any manufacturer of architectural coating that contains perchloroethylene or methylene chloride shall submit an annual report to the Department that specifies the following information for products sold in the District
      of Columbia during the preceding year:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The product brand name and a copy of the product label with the legible usage instructions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The product category listed in the Table of Standards in § 774.10, to which the coating belongs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The total sales in the District during the calendar year to the nearest gallon; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The volume percentage, to the nearest one tenth of a percent (0.1%), of perchloroethylene and methylene chloride in the coating.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>777.5</num>
    <text>777.5 Upon request by the Department, any manufacturer of recycled coatings shall submit a letter to the Department certifying its status as a recycled paint manufacturer and shall submit an annual report to the Department. The report shall include,
      for all recycled coatings, the total number of gallons distributed in the District of Columbia during the preceding year and shall describe the method used by the manufacturer to calculate District of Columbia distribution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>777.6.</num>
    <text>Upon request by the Department, any manufacturer of bituminous roof coatings or bituminous roof primers shall submit an annual report to the Department that specifies the number of gallons of bituminous roof coatings or bituminous roof primers sold
      in the District of Columbia during the preceding calendar year and describes the method used by the manufacturer to calculate District of Columbia sales.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 11286, 11404 (December 30, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>