<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2502</num>
  <heading>PUBLIC NOTIFICATION (ยง 24-2502)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2502.1.</num>
    <text>The Chief of Police shall provide public notification prior to the deployment of any permanent cameras, except:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Under exigent circumstances; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>When cameras are deployed pursuant to a court order.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.2.</num>
    <text>Public notice shall include the general capabilities of CCTV systems, their use in departmental operations, and the duration of the deployment. Public notice will also identify the viewing area, but not necessarily the precise location of the camera.
      The precise location of a camera may be disclosed if the Chief of Police determines that disclosure will not undermine the security of the camera and the efficacy of the deployment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.3.</num>
    <text>The public shall have thirty (30) days to submit comments regarding a proposed deployment to the Chief of Police. The public may submit comments to the Chief of Police at any time regarding a particular camera deployment or the CCTV system in general.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.4.</num>
    <text>The Chief of Police shall consider the comments submitted by the public in determining whether to go forward with deployment of the camera. The Chief of Police will provide public notice of his decision and provide an explanation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.5.</num>
    <text>In exigent circumstances, the Chief of Police is authorized to deploy cameras without first consulting or soliciting comments from the public. After the conclusion of the exigent circumstance, the camera shall be turned off immediately. As soon as
      feasible after the conclusion of the exigent circumstance, the Chief of Police shall have the camera removed. The Chief of Police will provide post-deployment public notification of any camera deployed under this provision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.6.</num>
    <text>When cameras are deployed pursuant to a court order, neither pre nor post-deployment notification is required.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.7.</num>
    <text>MPD will post and maintain signage indicating the presence of CCTV systems in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.8.</num>
    <text>On a semi-annual basis, MPD will provide updates on the CCTV system at community meetings to be announced to the public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2502.9.</num>
    <text>MPD will provide information about the CCTV system and its usage in its Annual Report. The information shall include the viewing area of cameras, periods of activation and/or recording and the purposes of activation and recording, disposition of any
      recordings, and an evaluation of whether the camera achieved the purposes stated in section 2500. The MPD shall not include any information pertaining to cameras deployed pursuant to a court order or deployed as part of an on-going criminal investigation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking Published at 49 DCR 11443 (December 20, 2002); as amended by D.C. ACT 16-642 published at 54 DCR 938 (February 2, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>