<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2505</num>
  <heading>AUTHORIZATION TO RECORD AND RETAIN RECORDINGS (ยง 24-2505)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2505.1.</num>
    <text>Except in exigent circumstances or when recording is being done pursuant to a court order, the Chief of Police shall issue written authorization prior to recording any CCTV feed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.2.</num>
    <text>Every recording shall be documented. The record shall include a copy of any written authorizations pertaining to each period of recording, the name(s) of any person(s) recording, a general description of the activity being recorded, and documentation
      as to when the recording began and ended.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.3.</num>
    <text>When recordings are made in exigent circumstances, the recording documentation shall also include a description of the exigency that gave rise to the need to record without prior written authorization.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.4.</num>
    <text>All recorded CCTV footage shall be maintained and secured by the official in command.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.5.</num>
    <text>Video recordings shall be indexed, stored, and maintained for 10 business days after which time they will be recorded over or destroyed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.6.</num>
    <text>Recordings may be retained beyond 10 business days because the recordings contain evidence of criminal activity, because the recordings capture an occurrence that may subject MPD to civil liability, or because the recording will be used for training
      purposes. Recordings that contain evidence of criminal activity or recordings that capture an occurrence that may subject MPD to civil liability shall be maintained to final case disposition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.7.</num>
    <text>The Chief of Police must provide, in writing, any decision to retain any recording beyond 10 business days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.8.</num>
    <text>Decisions to retain recordings beyond 10 business days must include the purpose of the retention, the nature of the recording, and length of time for the retention. Retention of recordings for training purposes must additionally include a written
      description of the training purpose to be served by the recording as well as a description of the recording&amp;#8217;s unique suitability for the training purpose.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.9.</num>
    <text>Recordings retained for training purposes may only be retained as long as they are actively used for training purposes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.10.</num>
    <text>Recordings retained for criminal or civil purposes shall be secured as evidence, and access to the recordings shall be appropriately limited and documented.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2505.11.</num>
    <text>MPD personnel shall maintain a video catalog of all tapes held beyond 10 days, including a copy of any written authorizations pertaining to each activation/recording, the name(s) of any person(s) doing any recording, a general description of each
      activation/recording, and documentation as to when activation/recording began and ended.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking Published at 49 DCR 11443 (December 20, 2002); as amended by D.C. ACT 16-642 published at 54 DCR 938 (February 2, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>