<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-2501</num>
  <heading>POLICY (ยง 24-2501)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2501.1.</num>
    <text>MPD shall comply with all federal and District law applicable to the use of CCTV cameras in public space.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2501.2.</num>
    <text>The technology will not be used to replace current policing techniques.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2501.3.</num>
    <text>Under no circumstances shall the CCTV systems be used for the purpose of infringing upon First Amendment rights.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2501.4.</num>
    <text>Operators of the CCTV systems shall not target/observe individuals solely because of their race, gender, ethnicity, sexual orientation, disability or other classifications protected by law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2501.5.</num>
    <text>CCTV systems shall be used to observe locations that are in public view and where there is no reasonable expectation of privacy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2501.6.</num>
    <text>MPD shall not use audio in conjunction with the CCTV unless appropriate court orders are obtained.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2501.7.</num>
    <text>MPD is authorized to enter into agreements with public entities to access their external video feeds for the purposes established in 2500.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2501.8.</num>
    <text>MPD is authorized to enter into agreements with private entities to access their external video feeds for discrete periods and only in exigent circumstances.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2501.9.</num>
    <text>MPD shall abide by these regulations if it receives CCTV feeds from another agency, jurisdiction, or entity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2501.10.</num>
    <text>Until legislation is enacted authorizing the use of CCTV for other purposes such as general crime deterrence in non-exigent circumstances, additional permanent cameras will only be installed after public notification has been provided and only in
      locations that will advance the purposes defined in section 2500 of these regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking Published at 49 DCR 11443 (December 20, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>