<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2802</num>
  <heading>INFANTS OF UNKNOWN PARENTAGE[COLON] FOUNDLING REGISTRATION (§ 29-2802)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2802.1.</num>
    <text>The report for an infant of unknown parentage shall be registered on a foundling certificate by the person who initially assumes responsibility for the infant. A brief statement shall be provided on the certificate stating the circumstances surrounding
      the finding of the child, and shall contain at a minimum, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Name given to the foundling;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Place found;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Date found;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Date of birth, assigned by approximation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Sex of the child;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Name and address of the person or institution with whom the child has been placed for care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Name of the person assigning the child’s name;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Other significant identifying data; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Name and address of the person who found the child; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Name and signature of the person initially assuming responsibility for the child.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2802.2.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, a person initially assuming legal responsibility includes:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An employee of the District of Columbia government, acting in an official capacity and within the scope of the employee(s authority;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A law enforcement official, acting in an official capacity and within the scope of the official’s authority; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any other person whose authority and conduct, under the circumstances of the discovery of the foundling, clearly indicate assumption of responsibility.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2802.3.</num>
    <text>A report registered under this section shall constitute the certificate of birth for the child.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 38 DCR 781, 783 (January 25, 1991).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>