<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2824</num>
  <heading>RETENTION AND ACCESS TO RECORDS RELATED TO VITAL RECORDS (§ 29-2824)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2824.1.</num>
    <text>Each funeral director shall maintain a record of each dead body or fetus which he or she handles.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2824.2.</num>
    <text>Each record listed under § 2824.1 shall be indexed alphabetically and by date of death and shall contain the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The date, place, time of receipt and manner of disposition;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The date of delivery if the dead body or fetus is delivered to another funeral director and the name and address of the funeral director to whom delivered; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>All information required by the certificate of death for those death certificates that the funeral director filed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2824.3.</num>
    <text>Medical records pertaining to births or deaths shall be retained by each health care facility for a minimum of five (5) years.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2824.4.</num>
    <text>Each health care facility with a delivery room shall maintain a permanent delivery room log containing information about each infant delivered in the hospital and the infant’s mother.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2824.5.</num>
    <text>Entries of each birth in the delivery room log shall be made immediately upon an infant’s delivery.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2824.6.</num>
    <text>Each health care institution shall maintain a permanent log of deaths which shall include the name of the deceased, the date of death, and the name and address of the person removing the body from the institution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2824.7.</num>
    <text>The records and logs required by this section shall be available for review by the Registrar.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 38 DCR 781, 798 (January 25, 1991).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>