<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-2819</num>
  <heading>AMENDMENT OF VITAL RECORDS OTHER THAN BIRTH CERTIFICATES (ยง 29-2819)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2819.1.</num>
    <text>To amend a death certificate, application may be made by the next of kin, by the informant, the funeral director or by the person acting as such who signed the death certificate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2819.2.</num>
    <text>An application to amend the medical certification shall be made only by the physician who signed the medical certification or by the medical examiner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2819.3.</num>
    <text>A death certificate shall neither be amended nor added to except by the Registrar.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2819.4.</num>
    <text>The Registrar may, in the exercise of his or her discretion, decline to amend or add information to a death certificate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2819.5.</num>
    <text>If the Registrar declines, the record shall be amended or added to only upon an order of a District of Columbia Court.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2819.6.</num>
    <text>To amend a marriage record or a report of divorce, dissolution of marriage, or annulment, a signed statement shall be required from the custodian of the official record from which the record or report was prepared, stating in what manner the record
      has been amended.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2819.7.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of a certified copy of an order of a court of competent jurisdiction indicating that the sex of an individual born in the District of Columbia has been changed, the Registrar shall attach the court order to the back of the original birth
      certificate and annotate the change to the lower front margin of the original certificate, taking care not to alter or obscure the original entries in any way.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 38 DCR 781, 797 (January 25, 1991).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>