<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6105</num>
  <heading>REVIEW (§ 29-6105)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6105.1.</num>
    <text>CFSA shall conduct a review of a permanent guardianship subsidy:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Annually;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Whenever CFSA has information that indicates that the factors set forth in § 6104.4 apply;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Whenever changes in the foster care board and care payments or the child&amp;#8217;s age would change the permanent guardianship subsidy amount; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Upon request of the permanent guardian.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6105.2.</num>
    <text>The review shall determine at least:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Whether the legal guardian continues to meet the requirements of these rules;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Whether any of the factors set forth in § 6104.4 apply;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Whether any adjustment in the amount of the permanent guardianship subsidy should be made in light of the child&amp;#8217;s age and any changes in the foster care board and care payment; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Whether there are any other factors that may necessitate a change in the permanent guardianship subsidy.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6105.3.</num>
    <text>A review conducted pursuant to § 6105.1(d) shall commence not later than thirty (30) days after a completed written request is received by CFSA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6105.4.</num>
    <text>An adjustment in the amount of the permanent guardianship subsidy made as a result of a review conducted pursuant to § 6105.1(d) may be made retroactive to the date that the completed written request is received by CFSA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6105.5.</num>
    <text>If a recipient fails to cooperate with CFSA in its conduct of the review, CFSA shall terminate the permanent guardianship subsidy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 3671 (April 27, 2001) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 10740 (November 23, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>