<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-6104</num>
  <heading>PERMANENT GUARDIANSHIP SUBSIDY AGREEMENT (ยง 29-6104)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6104.1.</num>
    <text>A person shall enter into a permanent guardianship subsidy agreement with CFSA prior to receiving a permanent guardianship subsidy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6104.2.</num>
    <text>The permanent guardianship subsidy agreement is the sole and complete statement of the funds and services a person shall receive from a permanent guardianship subsidy related to the child(ren) named therein.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6104.3.</num>
    <text>A permanent guardianship subsidy agreement shall include at least:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The amount of the permanent guardianship subsidy;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The duration of the permanent guardianship subsidy; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A statement as to whether District of Columbia Medicaid shall be provided.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6104.4.</num>
    <text>A permanent guardianship subsidy agreement shall terminate:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>By the terms of the agreement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Based on information learned through a review in accordance with ยง 6105;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>If the permanent guardian dies or is removed from the position; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Upon the earlier of the child&amp;#8217;s:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Eighteenth (18th) birthday;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Residence outside the home of the permanent guardian, unless the permanent guardian can demonstrate that he or she retains financial responsibility for the child and the child is attending a residential school;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Marriage;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Death; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Enlistment in the military.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6104.5.</num>
    <text>The recipient shall notify CFSA within two (2) weeks of:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The occurrence of any of the factors listed in ยง 6104.4(d); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Any change of address.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6104.6.</num>
    <text>Nothing in these rules shall be read as prohibiting a person from receiving any service from CFSA to which the person is otherwise entitled or which is otherwise available.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 3671 (April 27, 2001) [EXPIRED]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 10740 (November 23, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>