<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-107</num>
  <heading>FORM AND FILING OF PLEADINGS, MOTIONS, AND OTHER SUBMISSIONS (ยง 27-107)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>107.1</num>
    <text>107.1</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>There shall be no filing fees.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An original and two (2) copies of all paper protests, agency reports, notices of appeal, complaints, answers, motions, and responses thereto, shall be filed with the Board. All paper filings shall contain proof of service, in accord with Rule 109.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Electronic filings shall be made pursuant to Chapter 4. No proof of service shall be required for conforming electronic filings.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.2.</num>
    <text>A filing may be made by mail, hand-delivery or electronically, unless otherwise ordered by the Board. Irrespective of the method used for filing, a submission shall only be considered timely filed if it is actually received in the Board&amp;#8217;s
      office during business hours or received by the electronic filing vendor within the time established by law, regulation, or Board order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.3.</num>
    <text>Notices of appeal, protests, and other pleadings shall, on the first page, contain a caption setting forth the name of the Board, title of the case, and contain a heading under the caption describing the nature of the pleading, motion, or matter being
      brought to the attention of the Board. The caption and heading shall be in the following format:</text>
    <text>GOVERNMENT OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA CONTRACT APPEALS BOARD</text>
    <text>[PROTEST] OR [APPEAL] OF:</text>
    <text>[NAME OF PROTESTER or APPELLANT]</text>
    <text>)</text>
    <text>)</text>
    <text>CAB No.</text>
    <text>[ADDRESS OF PROTESTER or APPELLANT]</text>
    <text>)</text>
    <text>)</text>
    <text>Under [IFB or RFP] or [Contract] No.</text>
    <text>)</text>
    <text>[HEADING]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.4.</num>
    <text>In addition to the requirements of Rule 107.3, the initial filing by or on behalf of a party shall have in the caption the name and full business or residence address of the party. If the party is appearing pro se (without an attorney), the caption
      shall also include the party&amp;#8217;s business or residence telephone number. In the initial filing by a non-governmental corporate body party, the party shall file a corporate disclosure statement identifying all parent companies, subsidiaries
      (except wholly-owned subsidiaries), and affiliates that have issued shares to the public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.5.</num>
    <text>A submission signed by an attorney shall contain the name, office address, telephone number, and bar identification number of the attorney. Notice of a change in address or telephone number of the attorney, or a party not represented by an attorney,
      shall be filed within five (5) business days of the change.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.6.</num>
    <text>Unless they are changed by a notice filed with the Board, the address and telephone number of a party or any attorney noted on the first filing shall be conclusively taken as the last known address and telephone number of the party or attorney.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.7</num>
    <text>107.7</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The original of a paper submission that is filed with the Board shall be signed in ink by the party, its attorney, or its authorized representative.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The original of a document filed electronically shall be signed in ink by the party, its attorney, or authorized representative and maintained by the party filing the document.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.8.</num>
    <text>All submissions filed shall be typed (double spaced), reproduced by any duplicating or copying process that produces a clear black image on white 8 1/2 x 11 inch size paper, and fastened at the top.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.9.</num>
    <text>A submission shall not include documents that are not relevant to the case. Irrelevant documents shall be rejected by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.10.</num>
    <text>Submissions that do not conform to the requirements of this Rule may be rejected either before or after filing. If the submission is rejected after filing, the effect shall be the same as if it had not been filed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 49 DCR 2078 (March 8, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>