<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1152</num>
  <heading>BENEFICIAL USE CLASSES FOR GROUND WATER (ยง 21-1152)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1152.1.</num>
    <text>The following ground waters shall be classified as Class G1 if they are of drinking water quality:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Ground waters that are highly vulnerable to contamination;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Ground waters in recharge areas of drinking water aquifers of adjacent jurisdictions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Ground waters that are hydrologically connected to surface waters of the District including designated antidegradation segments; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Ground waters that discharge to a sensitive ecological system that supports a unique habitat.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1152.2.</num>
    <text>The following ground waters shall be classified as Class G2:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Ground waters that are of drinking water quality but are not classified as G1;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Ground waters in recharge areas of drinking water aquifers of adjacent jurisdictions but are not drinking water quality;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Ground waters that are hydrologically connected to surface waters of the District including designated antidegradation segments but are not of drinking water quality; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Ground waters that are not of drinking water quality but can be made suitable for drinking water by conventional treatment processes.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1152.3.</num>
    <text>Class G3 ground waters shall be those that can neither be grouped under Class G1 nor under Class G2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1152.4.</num>
    <text>In order to adequately maintain and preserve ground water quality within the District, where land use is affecting or has the potential to affect ground water quality, the Director, Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs, shall identify areas
      that are highly vulnerable to ground water contamination. Class G1, G2, G3 ground water shall then be designated as ground water vulnerable to ground water contamination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 4203, 4204 (July 2, 1993); renumbered by Final Rulemaking published at 41 DCR 1075 (March 4, 1994).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>