<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-2013</num>
  <heading>REQUIRED SOURCES OF SUPPLIES AND SERVICES (§ 30-2013)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2013.1.</num>
    <text>Except for the procurement of utility services, or as authorized under this chapter or by law, the Agency shall satisfy requirements for supplies and services from or through the sources and publications listed in this subsection in descending order
      of priority:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Existing inventories maintained by the Agency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Excess from other District agencies or federal agencies, as long as the excess items are readily available without cost or at a lower cost than any other source;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Existing requirements contracts executed by the Agency or other District requirements contracts which, pursuant to agreement between the Executive Director and the Director, DAS, or other District procurement official, include the Agency as a using
        agency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>To the extent of the minimums required under the applicable term contract, existing indefinite quantity contracts executed by the Agency or other • District indefinite quantity contracts which, pursuant to agreement between the Executive Director
        and the Director, DAS or other District procurement official, include the Agency as a using agency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Procurement lists of products and services available from the Committee for Purchase of Products and Services of the Blind and Other Severely Handicapped;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Federal supply schedules, to the extent that the items available meet the minimum requirements of the Agency and can be obtained at prices lower than can be obtained with a new contract;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>District of Columbia Department of Corrections, Industries Division;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Federal Prison Industries, Inc.; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Other sources, including open and sheltered market commercial sources, and educational and nonprofit institutions.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2013.2.</num>
    <text>The provisions of Chapter 21 of Title 27 DCMR shall apply to procurement by the Agency, except as provided otherwise in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2013.3.</num>
    <text>The requirements of §2103.1 of Title 27 DCMR shall apply to the Director, DAS and shall not apply to the Director of Procurement; Provided, that the Director of Procurement shall attempt to obtain information from the Director, with respect to the
      availability of supplies and services to the Agency under District term contracts.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2013.4.</num>
    <text>The provisions of §2105.2 of Title 27 DCMR shall not apply to procurement by the Agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2013.5.</num>
    <text>Exceptions to requirements for purchasing from handicapped and prison sources under §2112 of Title 27 DCMR may be granted by the Director of Procurement, in accordance with the provisions of §2112 of Title 27 DCMR.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2013.6.</num>
    <text>The provisions of §2115 of Title 27 DCMR relating to procurement of printing services shall not apply to procurement by the Agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6681, 6690 (September 22, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>