<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-704</num>
  <heading>AGREEMENTS WITH PARTICIPATING EMPLOYERS (ยง 7-704)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>704.1.</num>
    <text>Participating employers shall enter into a formal agreement with the Director in order to participate in the program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>704.2.</num>
    <text>The agreement shall contain the employer&amp;#8217;s guidelines concerning employee participants in jobs approved by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>704.3.</num>
    <text>The agreement shall certify the employer&amp;#8217;s intention to employ participants for the entire period of program operations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>704.4.</num>
    <text>In addition, the participation agreement shall contain as a minimum the following elements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A brief outline of the work experience;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Academic credit, to be received, if applicable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The number of applicants to be employed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The method of computing, and the maximum amount of reimbursement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A requirement that employers are to maintain payroll records, as well as time and attendance records; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>An assurance that the employer will comply with the Act and rules and regulations issued under the Act and other terms and conditions normally associated with employment and training agreements.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>704.5.</num>
    <text>The Director shall agree to reimburse a participating employer as frequently as every thirty (30) days based upon the submission by the employer of a certified invoice/report in the form specified by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>704.6.</num>
    <text>The Director shall exercise authority with respect to contracts and subgrant agreements in accordance with the delegation contained in Commissioner&amp;#8217;s Order No. 74-144.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>