<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4702</num>
  <heading>EDUCATIONAL AND TRAINING REQUIREMENTS (§ 17-4702)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4702.1.</num>
    <text>An applicant under this section, shall meet the education and training requirements for licensure by furnishing proof satisfactory to the Board that the applicant has met the requirements of of §§ 4702.2, 4702.3, 4702.4, or 4702.5.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4702.2.</num>
    <text>The Board may approve the education and training qualifications of an applicant who has successfully completed a program in the practice of acupuncture that is as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Is provided by a school that is legally chartered or organized in the state, territory or country where the school is located, or is accredited or recognized by the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The National Accreditation Commission for Schools and Colleges of Acupuncture and Oriental Medicine;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An accrediting body recognized by the Secretary of the United States Department of Education; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A Department of Education of a state or territory of the United States that uses published standards to evaluate the program&amp;#8217;s content, facilities and administration; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Consists of one of the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Three (3) academic years of instruction including five hundred (500) hours of clinical training in a school for acupuncture; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Two (2) academic years of instruction in a school of acupuncture; and fifteen hundred (1500) contact hours of apprenticeship under a preceptor who is a licensed acupuncturist in good standing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4702.3.</num>
    <text>The Board may approve the education and training qualifications of an applicant who has completed apprenticeship in acupuncture that is as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Extends for a period of three (3) years;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Includes a minimum of forty-five hundred (4500) contact hours of clinical training with increasing responsibilities in patient care culminating in complete treatment; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Is under a preceptor who is a licensed acupuncturist in good standing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4702.4.</num>
    <text>The Board may approve the education and training qualifications of an applicant who, prior to October 13, 1989, meets the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Has completed three (3) years of practice that consists of:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Treating a minimum of one hundred (100) patients per year with a minimum of five hundred (500) patient visits;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Treating patients with general health problems; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Documents the practice to the satisfaction of the Board by the following evidence, keeping confidential a patient&amp;#8217;s identity:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Patient records;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Billing records; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Other credible evidence.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4702.5.</num>
    <text>The Board may approve the education and training qualifications of an applicant who meets the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Is a physician duly licensed in good standing in the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Completes two hundred and fifty (250) hours of instruction in the practice of acupuncture in one of the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A program of training and instruction accredited by an entity listed in § 4702.2(a); or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A continuing education program that is designated as an American Medical Association Physicians Award category I program by the sponsoring organization.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4702.6.</num>
    <text>An applicant who seeks licensure based upon a formal academic program shall submit with a completed application a certified transcript and an official certificate of graduation to the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4702.7.</num>
    <text>An applicant who seeks licensure based upon an apprenticeship training program under § 4702.3 shall submit with a completed application the following documentation from the applicant&amp;#8217;s preceptor:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A certified copy of the preceptor&amp;#8217;s license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A certification from the preceptor&amp;#8217;s licensing board that the preceptor is in good standing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An affidavit that describes the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The preceptor&amp;#8217;s practice, including patient hours and type of practice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The apprenticeship, including the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The starting and finishing dates;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The total number of contact hours;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The topics and skills covered during the training; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s responsibilities.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 7159, 7160 (October 13, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 2747, 2749 (May 4, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>