<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-4712</num>
  <heading>ACUPUNCTURE PRACTICE (§ 17-4712)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4712.1.</num>
    <text>An acupuncturist who is not a physician licensed by the District shall practice only in general collaboration with a physician, pursuant to an agreement registered in accordance with § 4715.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4712.2.</num>
    <text>An acupuncturist who is a physician licensed by the District shall be exempt from the requirements of §§ 4712.3, 4712.4 and §§ 4712.7 through 4712.10.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4712.3.</num>
    <text>Prior to initiating treating of a patient, an acupuncturist shall have written authorization from the collaborating physician to commence treatment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4712.4.</num>
    <text>An acupuncturist shall comply with any restrictions or conditions placed on the acupuncture treatment by the collaborating physician.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4712.5.</num>
    <text>An acupuncturist shall be solely responsible for acupuncture evaluation and treatment of the patient.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4712.6.</num>
    <text>An acupuncturist shall use aseptic practices that comply with accepted standards of sterilization in the field of acupuncture.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4712.7.</num>
    <text>An acupuncturist shall advise a patient to consult with the collaborating physician if the patient&amp;#8217;s condition worsens, changes unexpectedly, or fails to improve after the prescribed course of treatment or if the patient develops a new ailment
      or condition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4712.8.</num>
    <text>An acupuncturist shall immediately notify the collaborating physician, by communication devise followed by written memorandum, of any worsening in a patient&amp;#8217;s condition or ailment, new ailment, or unexpected change in a patient&amp;#8217;s
      condition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4712.9.</num>
    <text>An acupuncturist shall provide written notice to a collaborating physician of the acupuncturist&amp;#8217;s intent to terminate the collaboration prior to terminating a collaboration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4712.10.</num>
    <text>If a collaboration is terminated, an acupuncturist shall immediately cease performing acupuncture on all patients for whom the collaborating physician had agreed to provide care and consultation and assist a patient whose treatment is disrupted to
      find appropriate substitute care.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 7159, 7164 (October 13, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>