<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2200</num>
  <heading>RESPONSIBLE PROSPECTIVE CONTRACTORS (§ 27-2200)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2200.1.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall make purchases from and award contracts only to responsible contractors.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2200.2.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall not make a purchase or award unless the contracting officer has determined in writing that the prospective contractor is responsible in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2200.3.</num>
    <text>In the absence of information clearly indicating that the prospective contractor is responsible, the contracting officer shall make a determination of nonresponsibility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2200.4.</num>
    <text>To be determined responsible, a prospective contractor shall meet all of the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Financial resources adequate to perform the contract or the ability to obtain them;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Ability to comply with the required or proposed delivery or performance schedule, taking into consideration all existing commercial and governmental business commitments;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A satisfactory performance record;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A satisfactory record of integrity and business ethics;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The necessary organization, experience, accounting and operational controls, and technical skills or the ability to obtain them;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Compliance with the applicable District licensing and tax laws and regulations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The necessary production, construction, and technical equipment and facilities or the ability to obtain them; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Other qualifications and eligibility criteria necessary to receive an award under applicable laws and regulations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2200.5.</num>
    <text>If the contracting officer determines that the price bid or offered by a prospective contractor is so low as to appear unreasonable or unrealistic, the contracting officer may determine the prospective contractor to be nonresponsible.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>D.C. Code §§ 1-1181; Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 2002-207.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1525 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>