<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2206</num>
  <heading>PREAWARD SURVEYS (ยง 27-2206)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2206.1.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer may require a preaward survey to assist in determining a prospective contractor&amp;#8217;s capability to perform a proposed contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2206.2.</num>
    <text>If the contemplated contract will be ten thousand dollars ($10,000) or less, or will have a fixed price of less than one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000) and will involve only commercial products, the contracting officer shall not request a preaward
      survey unless circumstances justify the cost of the survey.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2206.3.</num>
    <text>Before beginning a preaward survey, the contracting officer shall ascertain whether the prospective contractor is debarred, suspended, or ineligible. If the prospective contractor is debarred, suspended, or ineligible, the contracting officer shall
      not proceed with the preaward survey.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2206.4.</num>
    <text>When the prospective contractor surveyed is a certified minority business, the contracting officer shall request information and advice concerning the contractor&amp;#8217;s capability and past performance from the District of Columbia Local Business
      Opportunity Commission before making a determination regarding the contractor&amp;#8217;s responsibility or nonresponsibility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2206.5.</num>
    <text>When a preaward survey discloses unsatisfactory performance, the contracting officer shall determine the extent to which the prospective contractor plans, or has taken, corrective action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2206.6.</num>
    <text>The preaward survey report shall indicate any persistent pattern of need under prior contracts for costly and burdensome District assistance to the contractor (such as engineering, inspection, or testing) that were provided to protect the District&amp;#8217;s
      interests but not contractually required.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2206.7.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall prepare a narrative preaward survey report that documents the results of the preaward survey and provides support for both the evaluation ratings and the determination of responsibility or nonresponsibility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2206.8.</num>
    <text>The preaward survey report shall, as necessary, include information concerning the contractor&amp;#8217;s technical capabilities, financial capability, quality assurance procedures, and the quality of the contractor&amp;#8217;s accounting system.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2206.9.</num>
    <text>The preaward survey report shall be prepared in the form prescribed by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1530 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>