<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2220</num>
  <heading>ORGANIZATIONAL CONFLICTS OF INTEREST (ยง 27-2220)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2220.1.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section shall apply to all procurements. Contracting officers shall seek to avoid organizational conflicts of interest, especially when procuring the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Management support services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Consultant or other professional services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Contractor performance of or assistance in technical evaluations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Systems engineering and technical direction work performed by a contractor that does not have overall contractual responsibility for development or production.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2220.2.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall analyze each planned procurement in order to identify and evaluate potential organizational conflicts of interest as early in the procurement process as possible and avoid, neutralize, or mitigate significant potential
      conflicts before contract award.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2220.3.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall seek to prevent the existence of conflicting roles that might bias a contractor&amp;#8217;s judgment and shall seek to prevent unfair competitive advantage.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2220.4.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall obtain the advice of the Attorney General and the assistance of appropriate technical specialists in evaluating potential conflicts and in developing any necessary solicitation and contract clauses approved by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 1540 (February 26, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>