<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-3006</num>
  <heading>ANSWERS TO NOTICES OF INFRACTION (§ 18-3006)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3006.1.</num>
    <text>A respondent shall answer a notice of infraction in accordance with the provisions of the Traffic Adjudication Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3006.2.</num>
    <text>Answers of “Admit” shall be accompanied by a check or money order for the payment in full of the scheduled fines and penalties as listed in chapter 26 of this title, and mailed to the Bureau of Traffic Adjudication, P.O. Box 2014, Washington, D.C.,
      20013.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3006.3.</num>
    <text>Answers of “Deny” or “Admit with Explanation” may be made by mailing the Notice of Infraction with the answer form completed to the Bureau of Traffic Adjudication, 601 Indiana Ave., NW, Wash., D.C. 20001.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3006.4.</num>
    <text>Answer by mail entered by the respondent shall be made in the following manner:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Entering the desired answer form on the back of the ticket;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Entering the respondent’s name and address in the space provided on the answer form; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Signing and dating the answer form.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3006.5.</num>
    <text>For any notice of infraction issued between July 9, 2005 and August 23, 2005 pursuant to the Traffic Adjudication Act of 1978, effective September 12, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-104; D.C. Official Code §§ 50-2301.01 et seq.) (“the act”), a respondent must answer
      within sixty (60) days after the date the notice was issued or a penalty equal to the amount of the civil fine shall be added.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3006.6.</num>
    <text>For any notice of infraction issued between June 9, 2005 and August 23, 2005 pursuant to the act a respondent must answer within ninety (90) days after the date the notice was issued or they shall be deemed to have admitted the infraction and all
      applicable penalties, fines and points shall be assessed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Emergency And Proposed Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 5281 (September 2, 2005) [EMERGENCY]; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 9383 (October 21, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>