<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-3002</num>
  <heading>ISSUANCE OF PARKING VIOLATIONS ONLY (§ 18-3002)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3002.1.</num>
    <text>The following are empowered to issue Notices of Infraction for parking violations within their respective jurisdictions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>District of Columbia Protective Services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>District of Columbia Department of Human Services at D.C. General Hospital;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>District of Columbia Department of Public Works;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Saint Elizabeth&amp;#8217;s Hospital Security Force;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>United States Bureau of Engraving and Printing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>United States Government Printing Office;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>United States Park Police Visitor Aides;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>University of the District of Columbia Security Police;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Fort Lesley J. McNair;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>District of Columbia Public Library;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>United States Department of Commerce Special Agents;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>United States Defense Intelligence Agency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(m)</num>
      <text>United States Central Intelligence Agency Security Protective Service;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(n)</num>
      <text>Superior Court of the District of Columbia Security Police;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(o)</num>
      <text>United States Supreme Court Police;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(p)</num>
      <text>District of Columbia Housing Authority Special Police Officers: and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(q)</num>
      <text>United States Department of State Uniformed Protection Officers.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3002.2.</num>
    <text>REPEALED</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3002.3.</num>
    <text>When information is entered on the ticket manually, the original ticket, signed by the issuing officer, constitutes a complaint.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3002.4.</num>
    <text>A copy of the signed ticket shall be issued to the respondent in the manner provided for in § 3004.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3002.5.</num>
    <text>The respondent may use the copy as a form for answering the Notice in accordance with § 3007 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3002.6.</num>
    <text>When a hand-held electronic device is used, the one-page printout Notice shall constitute the complaint.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3002.7.</num>
    <text>The one-page printout Notice will be issued to the respondent, as provided in § 3004.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3002.8.</num>
    <text>The respondent may use the reverse side of the one-page printout Notice as a form for answering the Notice in accordance with § 3007 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3002.9.</num>
    <text>Except for tickets issued through the use of a hand-held electronic device, the original ticket shall be submitted to the Department of Motor Vehicles within fifteen (15) calendar days of issuance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3002.10.</num>
    <text>Except for tickets issued by certified mail pursuant to § 3004.9(b), the ticket information for tickets issued through the use of a hand-held electronic device shall be submitted within one (1) business day.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 4907 (June 4, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 6681 (August 13, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 5558 (July 7, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published
        at 49 DCR 5817 (June 21, 2002); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 850 (February 10, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5017 (June 26, 2009); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 4563
        (May 27, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>