<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-306</num>
  <heading>DEFERRED PAYMENT AGREEMENTS (§ 15-306)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>306.1.</num>
    <text>The Utility, Energy Supplier or Telecommunications Service Provider and the Customer may enter into a Deferred Payment Agreement (DPA). The Utility shall include the Utility, Energy Supplier or Telecommunications Service Provider past due balances
      as part of its DPA. No Charges, other than those accrued as of the date of settlement, and no interest shall be charged as part of the Deferred Payment Agreement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>306.2.</num>
    <text>Every DPA negotiated and agreed to between the Customer and the Utility, Energy Supplier, or Telecommunications Service Provider shall be provided to the Customer in writing within ten (10) Business Days and shall include the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The date of the DPA;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The amount overdue and the payment terms of the DPA, including down payment amount and installment terms;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The process that the Utility, Energy or Telecommunications Service Provider will follow, including a notice of Disconnection, to enforce the terms of the DPA;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A Customer’s failure to make a scheduled payment under the DPA when due is a default and places the Account in delinquent status as of the date of default. Late payment Charges shall apply to any default of a DPA and may cause the DPA to become
        void; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The DPA shall state that all subsequent Bills must be paid on or before the due date. Failure to pay all such subsequent Bills as stated will cause the DPA to become void. In such cases, normal collection activities, up to and including Disconnection
        may resume.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 10381, 10397 (June 1, 1979); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 10014 (September 26, 2008); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12494 (December 12, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>