<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-323</num>
  <heading>OFFICE OF CONSUMER SERVICES (§ 15-323)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>323.1.</num>
    <text>There is established within the Public Service Commission an Office of Consumer Services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>323.2.</num>
    <text>The Office of Consumer Services shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Answer inquiries regarding residential utility service, the services provided by each Energy Supplier and Telecommunications Service Provider and the procedures for resolving disputes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Assist in the informal resolution of Customer complaints and disputes that have not been resolved under the Utility’s or Energy Supplier’s or Telecommunications Service Provider’s own procedures; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Refer to the Commission for formal adjudication any Customer’s complaint that cannot be resolved informally.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>323.3.</num>
    <text>Any applicant for utility, energy or Telecommunications services, or the Applicant’s or Customer’s designated representative, as the case may be, may complain to the Commission concerning a Deposit requirement, the service provided, or a Utility or
      an Energy Supplier or Telecommunications Service Provider’s Bill. Should a party other than the Applicant, Customer of record, or the Office of the People’s Counsel file such a Complaint, the Applicant or Customer of record shall file a notarized
      letter authorizing the designee to act on his or her behalf, and the individual or entity shall file a notice that authorizes it to act on the Applicant’s or Customer’s behalf.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>323.4.</num>
    <text>If a Complaint addresses a matter that has failed to be resolved under the Utility’s, Energy Supplier’s or Telecommunications Service Provider’s procedures, the Office of Consumer Services shall handle the matter as an Informal Complaint for resolution.
      If the Complaint has not been referred to the Utility, Energy Supplier or Telecommunications Service Provider of the service in question, the matter shall be referred to the Utility, Energy Supplier or Telecommunications Service Provider for an
      attempt at direct resolution. In every case of a dispute between a Customer and a Utility, Energy Supplier or Telecommunications Service Provider, the first attempt at resolution shall be made directly between the parties.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>323.5.</num>
    <text>The Utility, Energy Supplier or Telecommunications Service Provider shall respond to the Informal Complaint or similar Customer related referral to the Office of Consumer Services within fourteen (14) Business Days or within such time as shall be
      specified by any extension of time that may be granted by that office. If the Complaint or matter is not resolved within that time, the Utility, Energy Supplier or Telecommunications Service Provider shall refer the matter back to the Office of
      Consumer Services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>323.6.</num>
    <text>If the Office of Consumer Services handles a matter informally, the office shall notify the Utility, Energy Supplier or Telecommunications Service Provider by telephone, in writing or other technological means to investigate the matter and attempt
      through mediation to resolve the matter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>323.7.</num>
    <text>If the Office of Consumer Services determines that a matter cannot be resolved informally, then within five (5) Business Days, the Office of Consumer Services shall notify the Complainant in writing and invite the Complainant to file a Formal Complaint
      with the Commission. The Utility, Energy Supplier or Telecommunications Service Provider shall be copied on this notification. The notification shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>State that the Complainant has the right to file, at no cost, a Formal Complaint, if he or she so desires;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>State that a Formal Complaint must be filed within fourteen (14) Days of the date of mailing of the notification or the matter shall be dismissed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Indicate the availability of assistance and legal representation by the Office of the People’s Counsel and the address and telephone number of the Office of the People’s Counsel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Indicate that the Complainant may be represented by him or herself, by counsel, by the Office of the People’s Counsel, or by a third party of the Complainant’s choosing; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Set forth the Commission’s Formal Complaint and hearing procedures.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 10381, 10415 (June 1, 1979); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 10014 (September 26, 2008); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12494 (December 12, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>