<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-300</num>
  <heading>PURPOSE AND APPLICABILITY (§ 15-300)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>300.1.</num>
    <text>Technological changes, new federal and District of Columbia laws, and the actions of the Public Service Commission have created competitive natural gas, electricity and telecommunications service markets in the District of Columbia providing residential
      consumers with new choices. Consumers have access to an array of competitive Service Provider services as well as continued access to the regulated services of Utilities. The purpose of this chapter is to set forth residential consumer rights, responsibilities
      and rules for the initiation and acquisition of services, such as, but not limited to Meter reading, Billing, Deposits, Disconnections and Reconnections of service and the resolution of Complaints between residential consumers and a Utility, Energy
      Supplier or Telecommunications Service Provider.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>300.2.</num>
    <text>This chapter applies to those Residential Services regulated by the Public Service Commission (“Commission”) provided by Electric, Natural Gas and Telephone Utilities, and Residential Services provided by Energy Suppliers and Telecommunications Service
      Providers licensed or certified by the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>300.3.</num>
    <text>No residential Customer shall be discriminated against or penalized by a Utility, Energy Supplier or Telecommunications Service Provider for exercising any right granted by this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>300.4.</num>
    <text>Utilities, Energy Suppliers or Telecommunications Service Providers shall not discriminate against any Customer based wholly or partly on the race, color, creed, national origin, geographic location, sex, or sexual orientation of the Customer or for
      any arbitrary, capricious, or unfairly discriminatory reason.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 10381, 10389 (June 1, 1979); Final Rulemaking published at 27 DCR 1834 (April 24, 1981); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 10014 (September 26, 2008); as amended by Notice of Final
        Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12494 (December 12, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>