<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-313</num>
  <heading>FIELD SERVICE IDENTIFICATION AND PAYMENT PROCEDURES (§ 15-313)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>313.1.</num>
    <text>The field representative shall produce an identification badge containing the Utility’s name and logo, the field representative picture and full name, and, if applicable, the representative shall wear a company uniform bearing the company’s name and
      logo.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>313.2.</num>
    <text>The natural gas or electric field service representative shall have a statement of the amount due and inquire whether the Bill has been paid. If evidence is presented which reasonably indicates that the Bill has been paid, that a DPA has been entered
      into, that the Bill is currently the subject of a pending proceeding before the Commission, or that the Customer has demonstrated a medical emergency consistent with the provisions of this chapter, service shall not be disconnected.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>313.3.</num>
    <text>The natural gas or electric field service representative shall be authorized to accept payment. If payment in full of all Charges due and owing is tendered, service shall not be disconnected. Tender of payment by personal check shall be accepted unless
      the Customer has within the past twelve (12) months paid the Utility with a check not honored by a bank.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>313.4.</num>
    <text>The natural gas or electric field service representative shall seek authorization from his or her supervisor to accept partial payments or to override his or her orders to disconnect service upon a reasonable explanation by the Customer of the delinquency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 10381, 10408 (June 1, 1979); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 10014 (September 26, 2008); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12494 (December 12, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>