<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-311</num>
  <heading>PROCEDURES FOR UTILITY DISCONNECTION (§ 15-311)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>311.1.</num>
    <text>A Utility shall postpone the Disconnection of service for a reasonable time not to exceed twenty-one (21) Days if the Utility is provided with a physician’s certificate or notice from a public health official which states that Disconnection would
      be detrimental to the health and safety of a bona fide occupant of the premises; provided that the Customer enters into a DPA. The postponement may be extended for one (1) additional period of not more than twenty-one (21) Days by renewal of the
      certificate or notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>311.2.</num>
    <text>A Utility shall not disconnect service when a dispute involving the Account in question has been filed with the Office of Consumer Services and the dispute is still pending at the Public Service Commission, provided, that payments are made for amounts
      not in dispute.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>311.3.</num>
    <text>A Utility shall not disconnect Residential Service unless a Disconnection notice has been sent to the Customer at the billing address by either first class mail or other technological means at least fifteen (15) Days prior to the date of proposed
      Disconnection. The Utility providing telecommunications services shall not suspend Residential Service unless a suspension notice has been sent to the Customer at the billing address by either first class mail or other technological means at least
      ten (10) Days prior to the date of proposed suspension. Any notice required to be sent to a Customer prior to Disconnection or suspension of service may be sent along with the Bill for service; however, the notice of Disconnection or suspension
      of service must be on the first page of the Bill and shall be in bold print. Upon request of the Customer, a duplicate copy of the notice shall be sent by either first class mail or Internet or other technological means to a designated third party.
      The third party assumes no obligation for the Customer’s Account.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>311.4.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall preclude a Utility from taking immediate action necessary to correct any condition which threatens the health or safety of the Customer, the public or the integrity of the Utility’s distribution system or action taken
      in cooperation with civil or law enforcement authorities. However, where that corrective action is taken, the Utility shall not thereupon discontinue service to any Customer whom it believes to be responsible for creation of that condition until
      it has complied with the notice provisions of this section. The notice and reconnection required by this rule shall not be required in the event that service has been disconnected for theft of services, unauthorized use, diversion or interference
      with utility service on or about the Customer’s premises.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>311.5.</num>
    <text>The disconnection notice shall state the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Customer&amp;#8217;s name, address and Account number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The address where service is to be discontinued, if different;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Charges for reconnection of service, if any;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A statement of the total amount due, if applicable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The reason for the proposed Disconnection of service;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The earliest date on which service will be disconnected in the absence of payment or adjustment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The telephone number and address of the Utility, and an invitation to contact the Utility to resolve the matter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The Customer’s right to delay Disconnection of service</text>
    </level>
    <text>for medical reasons;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The possibility of deferred payments; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>The right to file a complaint with the Public Service Commission, and the availability of legal representation and assistance by the Office of the People’s Counsel and the address and telephone number of the Office of the People’s Counsel.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>311.6.</num>
    <text>Utility service shall not be disconnected and shall be restored if Disconnected where a Customer has established or is reinstated to a DPA for utility charges that are the basis of the notice of Disconnection and the Customer has not defaulted on
      such DPA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>311.7.</num>
    <text>A Utility shall not disconnect service for the period after 5:00 p.m. Thursday and before 8:00 a.m. Monday, and it may not disconnect on a legal holiday, or on a Day that the Utility is closed to the public, except as provided in subsections 311.8
      and 311.9.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>311.8.</num>
    <text>A Utility may disconnect service on Friday or Saturday if the following applies:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Meter is located on the inside of the premises or is otherwise not readily accessible; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Utility has previously and unsuccessfully attempted to gain access to the premise as stated in subsection 310.1(e), on at least two (2) week days.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>311.9.</num>
    <text>Subsections 311.7 and 311.8 shall not apply to service disconnections to abandoned buildings, where the customer has requested disconnection in circumstances of unsafe conditions or of theft of natural gas or electricity, or to disconnect telephone
      service where there is evidence of toll abuse or fraud.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 25 DCR 10381, 10405 (June 1, 1979); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 443 (January 24, 1986); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 10014 (September 26, 2008); as amended by Notice
        of Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12494 (December 12, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>