<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-840</num>
  <heading>HEIGHT OF BUILDINGS OR STRUCTURES (C-M, M) (§ 11-840)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>840.1.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § 840.2 and in chapters 20 through 25 of this title, the height of buildings or structures in an Industrial District shall not exceed that given in the following table:</text>
    <text>ZONE DISTRICT</text>
    <text>MAXIMUMHEIGHT(Feet)</text>
    <text>MAXIMUMHEIGHT(Stories)</text>
    <text>C-M-1</text>
    <text>40</text>
    <text>3</text>
    <text>C-M-2</text>
    <text>60</text>
    <text>No Limit</text>
    <text>C-M-3</text>
    <text>90</text>
    <text>No Limit</text>
    <text>M</text>
    <text>90</text>
    <text>No Limit</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>840.2.</num>
    <text>Spires, towers, domes, pinnacles or minarets serving as architectural embellishments, penthouses over elevator shafts, ventilator shafts, antennas, chimneys, smokestacks, or fire sprinkler tanks may be erected to a height in excess of that which this
      section otherwise authorizes. This section shall not be interpreted to bypass otherwise required special exception reviews.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>840.3.</num>
    <text>If housing for mechanical equipment or a stairway or elevator penthouse is provided on the roof of a building or structure, it shall be erected or enlarged as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>It shall meet the requirements of § 411;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>It shall be set back from all exterior walls a distance at least equal to its height above the roof upon which it is located; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>It shall not exceed eighteen feet, six inches (18 ft., 6 in.), in height above the roof upon which it is located. Mechanical equipment shall not extend above the permitted eighteen foot, six inch (18 ft., 6 in.), height of the housing.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>840.4.</num>
    <text>Housing for mechanical equipment or a stairway or elevator penthouse may be erected to a height in excess of that authorized in the District in which it is located.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>840.5.</num>
    <text>Where required by the Act to Regulate the Height of Buildings in the District of Columbia, approved June 1, 1910 (36 Stat. 452, as amended; D.C. Official Code §§ 6-601.01 to 6-601.09 (formerly codified at D.C. Code §§ 5-401 to 5-409 (1994 Repl. &amp;#038;
      1999 Supp.))), a height in excess of that permitted in that Act shall be authorized by the Council of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§§ 6201.1, 6201.2 and 6201.3 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 3975, 3979 (July 4, 1986); by Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 1509, 1523 (February 24, 1989); Final Rulemaking
        published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8422-23 (October 20, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 34 (January 4, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>