<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-2230</num>
  <heading>CANCELLATION OF AN INVITATION FOR BIDS AFTER OPENING (ยง 30-2230)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2230.1.</num>
    <text>An IFB may be cancelled, or all bids rejected, only if the Director determines in writing that the action taken is in the best interests of the Agency. If all bids have been rejected, the contracting officer shall cancel the solicitation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2230.2.</num>
    <text>Every effort shall be made to anticipate changes in a requirement before the date of bid opening and to notify all prospective bidders of any resulting modification or cancellation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2230.3.</num>
    <text>After the opening of a bid, an IFB shall not be cancelled and resolicited due solely to increased requirements for the items being procured. Award shall be made on the initial IFB and the additional quantity shall be treated as a new procurement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2230.4.</num>
    <text>An IFB may be cancelled and all bids rejected before award but after opening when the Director determines in writing that cancellation is in the best interests of the Agency for any reason, including the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Inadequate or ambiguous specifications were cited in the IFB;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Specifications have been revised;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The supplies or services being contracted for are no longer required;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The IFB did not provide for consideration of all factors of cost to the Agency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Bids received indicate that the needs of the Agency can be satisfied by a less expensive article differing from that for which the bids were invited;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>All otherwise acceptable bids received are at unreasonable prices, or only one (1) bid is received and the contracting officer cannot determine the reasonableness of the bid price, or no responsive bid has been received from a responsible bidder;
        or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The bids were not independently arrived at in open competition, were collusive, or were submitted in bad faith.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2230.5.</num>
    <text>If administrative difficulties are encountered after bid opening which may delay award beyond the bidders&amp;#8217; acceptance period, the several lowest bidders shall be requested before expiration of their bids, to extend the bid acceptance period
      (with consent of sureties, if any) in order to avoid the need for readvertisement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6681, 6727 (September 22, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>