<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-2253</num>
  <heading>RECEIPT AND EVALUATION OF STEP ONE PROPOSALS (ยง 30-2253)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2253.1.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt, the contracting officer shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Safeguard proposals against disclosure to unauthorized persons;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Accept and handle data with restrictive disclosure procedures in accordance with Chapter 31 of Title 27 DCMR; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Remove any reference to price or cost.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2253.2.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer shall establish a time period for evaluating technical proposals. The period may vary with the complexity and the number of proposals received.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2253.3.</num>
    <text>Evaluations shall be based on the criteria in the request for technical proposals without consideration of responsibility.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2253.4.</num>
    <text>Proposals shall be categorized as one (1) of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Acceptable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Reasonably susceptible of being made acceptable; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Unacceptable.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2253.5.</num>
    <text>Any proposal which modifies or fails to conform to the essential requirements or specifications of the request for technical proposals shall be considered nonresponsive and categorized as unacceptable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2253.6.</num>
    <text>The contracting officer may proceed directly with step two if there are a sufficient number of acceptable proposals to ensure adequate price competition under step two, and if further time, effort, and delay to make additional proposals acceptable
      and thereby increase competition would not be in the best interests of the Agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2253.7.</num>
    <text>If it is not in the best interests of the Agency to proceed directly with step two, the contracting officer shall request prospective bidders whose technical proposals may be made acceptable to submit additional clarifying or supplemental information.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2253.8.</num>
    <text>If discussions are held, the contracting officer shall identify the nature of the deficiencies in the technical proposal or the nature of the additional information required.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2253.9.</num>
    <text>No technical proposal shall be discussed with any prospective bidder other than the prospective bidder submitting the technical proposal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2253.10.</num>
    <text>When requesting additional information, the contracting officer shall fix an appropriate time for prospective bidders to conclude, discussions, if any; to submit all additional information; and to incorporate that additional information as part of
      their proposals.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2253.11.</num>
    <text>The time for completing the actions under ยง2253.10 may be extended at the discretion of the contracting officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2253.12.</num>
    <text>If the additional information incorporated as part of a technical proposal within the , final time fixed by the contracting officer establishes that the technical proposal is acceptable, it shall be so categorized. Otherwise, it shall be categorized
      as unacceptable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2253.13.</num>
    <text>If a technical proposal is found unacceptable, either initially or after clarification, the contracting officer shall promptly notify the prospective bidder of the basis of the determination and notify the prospective bidder that a revision of the
      proposal will not be considered.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2253.14.</num>
    <text>Upon written request, and as soon as possible after award, the contracting officer may debrief unsuccessful bidders.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2253.15.</num>
    <text>If it is necessary to discontinue two-step sealed bidding, the contracting officer shall include a statement of the facts and circumstances in the contract file.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2253.16.</num>
    <text>Each prospective bidder shall be notified in writing of the discontinuance of two- step sealed bidding.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6681, 67357 (September 22, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>