<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-5806</num>
  <heading>JOB READINESS AND JOB SEARCH (ยง 29-5806)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5806.1.</num>
    <text>All TANF applicants shall be preliminarily assessed by an IMA eligibility worker for skills, prior work experience, employability, barriers to employment, including, but not limited to, disability, domestic violence, or English proficiency, eligibility
      for exemption, and eligibility for the POWER program pursuant to Section 5829, and Diversion payment pursuant to Section 5832.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5806.2.</num>
    <text>In accordance with the preliminary assessment and unless not otherwise exempt pursuant to Section 5810, a TANF applicant or recipient who is seeking recertification of TANF eligibility and who does not have paid employment of the minimum hours required
      per week by the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982, as amended, and as set forth in subsection 5804.2, and who is not required to meet the school attendance requirements of Section 565 of the District of Columbia Public Assistance
      Act of 1982, as amended, shall be referred by DHS to sign and comply with an agreement to participate in job search or job readiness activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5806.3.</num>
    <text>The Director may require each TANF applicant or recipient that is referred for job search or job readiness activities to attend initial orientation, counseling, assessment, or other job readiness or job search activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5806.4.</num>
    <text>The Director shall not sanction a TANF applicant or recipient for failure to comply with job readiness or job search requirements if the applicant or recipient has been referred for job search or job readiness activities, and is subsequently found
      to be exempt from initial job readiness and job search requirements for any of the reasons listed in subsection 5810.3.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5806.5.</num>
    <text>The agreement referenced in subsection 5806.2 shall set forth the applicant&amp;#8217;s or recipient&amp;#8217;s responsibilities and those of the Director or his or her designee concerning job search or job readiness activities. The agreement shall
      include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s or recipient&amp;#8217;s obligations, including any reporting or verification of job search activity that the Director or his or her designee may direct;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The length of participation in job search or job readiness activities; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The resources that the Director or his or her designee may provide to assist in job search or job readiness activities, which may include information on transportation, education, training, or child care.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 10251 (November 9, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>