<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-5819</num>
  <heading>NOTICES REGARDING DOMESTIC VIOLENCE GOOD CAUSE WAIVERS (ยง 29-5819)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5819.1.</num>
    <text>The Director or his or her designee shall provide a notice to an applicant or recipient of his or her right to request a domestic violence good cause waiver from the work requirements and/or child support cooperation requirements. The notices shall
      be provided orally and in writing, at the time of application and before any sanction is imposed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5819.2.</num>
    <text>The notice shall inform each applicant or recipient that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>He or she has a right to request a domestic violence good cause waiver of the work requirements and the child support cooperation requirements at any point in time;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Director shall refer victims of domestic violence to appropriate services;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Disclosure of domestic violence is voluntary and will not adversely affect or delay the ability to receive aid; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Disclosed information will be confidential; however, disclosed information about child abuse, child neglect or elder abuse must be reported to Child Protective Services or Adult Protective Services.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5819.3.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this chapter, the definition of domestic violence is the same as that of &amp;#8220;battered or subject to extreme cruelty&amp;#8221; as set forth in Section 511a (e) of the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982, as amended.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 10251 (November 9, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>