<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-5813</num>
  <heading>WORK PARTICIPATION ALLOWANCE AND INCENTIVE PAYMENTS TO ELIGIBLE TANF RECIPIENTS§ 29-5813)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5813.1.</num>
    <text>The Director or his or her designee may provide recipients participating in mandatory programs an allowance for the cost of transportation or other costs that are reasonably necessary and directly related to participation in the mandatory program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5813.2.</num>
    <text>The work participation allowance shall reflect the approximate costs for participation in the mandatory program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5813.3.</num>
    <text>The work participation allowances are designed to reimburse a participant for expenses related to a mandatory program, such as travel, meals away from home and transportation to and from the mandatory program, but shall not be considered income to
      the household.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5813.4.</num>
    <text>A recipient who is participating in a mandatory program may be provided the following allowances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An allowance of ten dollars ($10.00) per day of participation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An allowance for significant, discrete customer work-related expenses such as obtaining medical examinations, which are not covered by Medicaid or the purchase of uniforms for customers who have a firm job offer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The amount authorized under subsection (b) shall not exceed two hundred fifty dollars ($250.00) per customer, unless authorized in accordance with subsection (e);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The District shall reimburse the Contractor in order to defray the costs incurred in subsection (b); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>If a unique situation arises in which the two hundred fifty dollars ($250.00) is not enough to cover the work related expense, the Contractor shall contact the Contracting Officer&amp;#8217;s Technical Representative (COTR) for approval to spend
        above this limit.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5813.5.</num>
    <text>A participant&amp;#8217;s engagement in the mandatory program shall equal or exceed four (4) hours of activity per day or an equivalent amount per week in order for the allowance to be provided.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5813.6.</num>
    <text>The work participation allowance shall be provided in a timely manner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5813.7.</num>
    <text>A participant in a mandatory program who qualifies for the work participation allowance pursuant to subsection 5813.5 may appeal a denial of the allowance through the fair hearing process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5813.8.</num>
    <text>The Director or his or her designee may provide a TANF recipient an incentive payment if he or she obtains and retains unsubsidized employment through the Department of Human Services&amp;#8217;, Temporary Assistance for Needy Families Employment
      Program (TEP) and all of the following occur:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If he or she is a current recipient of TANF at the time that he or she commences employment in a job for which he or she is seeking an incentive payment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The TANF recipient is paid not less than the applicable federal, District, state, county, or municipality wage rate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Has participated in TEP at some point within three (3) months of starting to work in an unsubsidized job; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Is a resident of the District of Columbia, as determined in accordance with § 503 of the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982, effective April 6, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-101; D.C. Official Code § 4-205.03).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5813.9.</num>
    <text>An individual shall not be eligible to receive a TEP incentive payment if he or she has received an incentive payment from a TEP provider any time during the immediate twelve (12) month period prior to the commencement of his or her current employment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5813.10.</num>
    <text>In order to be eligible to receive a TEP incentive payment, a TANF recipient shall be required to adhere to the following conditions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Provide verification, in a manner approved by the Department of Human Services, that he or she has entered unsubsidized employment;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Submit it to the TEP provider not later than three (3) months after commencing his or her unsubsidized employment; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Provide a copy of his or her pay stub, verifying the number of hours worked during the period for which he or she is requesting an, incentive payment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5813.11.</num>
    <text>A TANF recipient shall forfeit his or her right to receive an incentive payment if he or she fails to submit the required documents within three (3) months of the benchmark requested, which are set forth in subparagraph 58 13.12 below.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5813.12.</num>
    <text>A TANF recipient shall be entitled to receive an incentive payment for unsubsidized employment, based on the duration of his or her employment under the following conditions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Incentive Point 1: A TANF recipient shall be entitled to receive one hundred dollars ($100) if he or she works in an unsubsidized job and is expected to work the minimum number of hours set forth in Section 5804.2 of this Chapter that is applicable
        to his or her family;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Incentive Point 2: A TANF recipient shall be entitled to receive two hundred dollars ($200) if he or she works for one (1) month in an unsubsidized job for at least the average number of hours set forth in Section 5804.2 of this Chapter that is
        applicable to his or her family;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Incentive Point 3: A TANF recipient shall be entitled to receive three hundred dollars ($300) if he or she works for three (3) months in an unsubsidized job for at least the average number of hours set forth in Section 5804.2 of this Chapter that
        is applicable to his or her family; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Incentive Point 4: A TANF recipient shall be entitled to receive one hundred fifty dollars ($1 50) if he or she works for six (6) months in an unsubsidized job for at least the average number of hours set forth in Section 5804.2 of this Chapter
        that is applicable to his or her family.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5813.13.</num>
    <text>The TEP incentive payments shall be provided in a timely manner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5813.14.</num>
    <text>A TEP participant who believes that he or she qualifies for an incentive payment pursuant to subsection 5813.13 may appeal a denial of the incentive payment through the fair hearing process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 10251 (November 9, 2001); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 1583 (February 18, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 8634 (September 23, 2005).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>