<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6704</num>
  <heading>LICENSURE BY EXAMINATION (ยง 17-6704)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6704.1.</num>
    <text>An applicant for licensure as a physical therapist by examination shall initiate the application process by submitting a completed application together with the appropriate application fee and the documentation required by ยง 6702.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6704.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant for licensure by examination shall take and pass a Board approved national licensure examination in physical therapy (the national examination and a Board-approved District of Columbia jurisprudence examination (the District examination).
      The applicant shall have pre-approval from the Board before taking any licensure or jurisprudence examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6704.3.</num>
    <text>In addition to applicants identified in ยง 6704.2, the following applicants shall take and pass the District examination prior to issuance of a license if the District examination has not previously been taken:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An applicant who is seeking renewal of a license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An applicant who is seeking re-activation of an inactive license; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An applicant who is seeking reinstatement of a license.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6704.4.</num>
    <text>Following approval from the Board to take the applicable examinations, the applicant may take the national examination and the District examination in any order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6704.5.</num>
    <text>The passing score on the national examination shall be determined by the body administering the examination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6704.6.</num>
    <text>The District examination shall be a written examination, developed and administered by the Board or a body approved by the Board, on laws and rules pertaining to the practice of physical therapy in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6704.7.</num>
    <text>The District examination may consist of questions on District of Columbia laws pertaining to physical therapy including the Act, this chapter, and chapters 40 and 41 of this title. The passing score on the District examination shall be determined
      by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6704.8.</num>
    <text>An applicant for licensure who does not pass either examination on the first attempt must seek and obtain Board approval for any subsequent attempts to retake the examination. Before the Board may approve an applicant for subsequent testing beyond
      three (3) attempts, an applicant shall submit proof satisfactory to the Board of having successfully completed any remediation as determined by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6704.9.</num>
    <text>If the Board determines that an applicant has engaged in or has attempted to engage in conduct that subverts or undermines the integrity of either the national examination process or District examination process, the Board may disqualify the applicant
      from taking the examinations. Examples of such conduct may include, but are not limited to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Utilizing in any manner recalled or memorized examination questions;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Failing to comply with all test center security procedures;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Attempting to communicate with other examinees during the test; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Copying or sharing examination questions or answers or portions of questions or answers.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6704.10.</num>
    <text>All occurrences of any violations set forth in ยง 6704.9 shall be recorded in the official records of the Board. Board action may include, but is not limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Disqualifying test results of the applicant&amp;#8217;s examinations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Disqualifying the applicant, permanently or for a specified period of time, from eligibility for the examinations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Disqualifying the applicant, permanently or for a specified period of time, from eligibility for licensure;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Revocation, suspension, or imposition of probationary conditions on a license issued to the applicant.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 945, 946 (February 12, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 1061 (February 3, 1989); and by Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 2747, 2753 (May 4, 1990); as amended by Final Rulemaking published
        at 49 DCR 11780 (December 27, 2002); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 6451 (June 25, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12488 (December 12, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>