<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6710</num>
  <heading>LAWFUL PRACTICE (§ 17-6710)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6710.1.</num>
    <text>A physical therapist licensed under this act is fully authorized to practice physical therapy within the District of Columbia as defined herein.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6710.2.</num>
    <text>A physical therapist shall adhere to the recognized standards of ethics of the physical therapy profession and as further established by rule.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6710.3.</num>
    <text>A physical therapist may purchase, store and administer topical and aerosol medications as part of the practice of physical therapy as defined herein, as long as the purchasing, storage, and administration of those medications is carried out pursuant
      to all laws and regulations of the Federal Government and District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6710.4.</num>
    <text>A physical therapist shall use the letters &amp;#8220;PT&amp;#8221; in connection with the physical therapist&amp;#8217;s name or place of business to denote licensure under the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6710.5.</num>
    <text>Unless authorized to practice physical therapy, a person or business entity, its employees, agents or representatives shall not use in connection with that person&amp;#8217;s name or the name or activity of the business, the words &amp;#8220;physical
      therapy,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;physical therapist,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;physiotherapy,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;physiotherapist,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;registered physical therapist,&amp;#8221; the letters &amp;#8220;PT,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;DPT,&amp;#8221;
      &amp;#8220;LPT,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;RPT,&amp;#8221; or any other words, abbreviations or insignia indicating or implying directly or indirectly that physical therapy is provided or supplied.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6710.6.</num>
    <text>A person or business entity shall not advertise or otherwise promote another person as being a &amp;#8220;physical therapist&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;physiotherapist&amp;#8221; unless the individual so advertised or promoted is licensed as a physical
      therapist under the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6710.7.</num>
    <text>A person or business entity that offers, provides or bills any other person for services shall not characterize those services as &amp;#8220;physical therapy&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;physiotherapy&amp;#8221; unless the individual performing those
      services is a person licensed as a physical therapist under the Act.</text>
    <text>A physical therapy assistant shall use the letters “PTA” in connection with his or her name.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6710.9.</num>
    <text>A physical therapist shall be responsible for managing all aspects of the physical therapy care of each patient. A physical therapist shall provide:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The initial evaluation for each patient and all supporting documentation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Periodic reevaluation of each patient and all supporting documentation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The documented discharge of the patient, including the response to therapeutic intervention at the time of discharge.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6710.10</num>
    <text>6710.10 A physical therapist shall assure the qualifications of all physical therapy students, physical therapy assistants, physical therapy aides, and first-time applicants practicing pursuant to § 6711, under his or her direction and supervision.</text>
    <text>A physical therapist may not have more than a total of three (3) physical therapy students or physical therapy aides or physical therapy assistants or first-time applicants for a physical therapy license practicing pursuant to § 6711, under his or
      her direct supervision at any one time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6710.12.</num>
    <text>A physical therapist shall review and co-sign any documentation written by a physical therapy student, physical therapy assistant, physical therapy aide, or first-time applicant for a physical therapy license practicing pursuant to § 6711.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6710.13.</num>
    <text>If a physical therapy patient fails to respond to treatment within thirty (30) days after being seen by a physical therapist for the first time, the physical therapist shall refer the patient to an appropriate health care provider for assessment,
      medical diagnosis, intervention, or referral.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6710.14</num>
    <text>6710.14 A licensed physical therapist shall perform the final evaluation for a patient who has been treated throughout the patient’s history by a physical therapy assistant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6710.15</num>
    <text>6710.15 A physical therapist shall ensure the qualifications of all physical therapy</text>
    <text>assistants under his or her supervision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6710.16</num>
    <text>6710.16 Before a patient is treated by a physical therapy assistant, a licensed physical therapist shall evaluate the patient and formulate initial and ongoing treatment goals and plans.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6710.17</num>
    <text>6710.17 Pursuant to § 6710.16, a licensed physical therapist shall reevaluate each patient being treated by a physical therapy assistant by the seventh (7th) visit and every seventh (7th) visit thereafter,</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6710.18</num>
    <text>6710.18 Support personnel shall only perform routine assigned tasks under the direct supervision of a licensed physical therapist or a licensed physical therapy assistant, who shall only assign those tasks or activities that are nondiscretionary and
      do not require the exercise of professional judgment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6710.19</num>
    <text>6710.19 A licensed physical therapist shall be fully responsible for any actions by a</text>
    <text>physical therapy assistant performing physical therapist functions while under the physical therapist’s supervision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 945, 950 (February 12, 1989); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 6451 (June 25, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 2853 (March 21, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 55 DCR 7949 (July 25, 2008); as corrected by Errata Notice published at 57 DCR 11093 (November 26, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>