<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6707</num>
  <heading>APPROVED CONTINUING EDUCATION PROGRAMS AND ACTIVITIES (§ 17-6707)
    <text>The Board may, in its discretion, approve continuing education programs and activities that contribute to the growth of an applicant in professional competence in the practice of physical therapy and which meet the other requirements of this section.</text>
    <text>The Board may approve the following types of continuing education programs, if the program meets the requirements of § 6707.3:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An undergraduate or graduate course given at an accredited college or university;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A seminar or workshop;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>An education program given at a conference;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>In-service training;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Home study courses;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Real-time, interactive remote media courses; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Online courses, video courses, telecourses, videoconferences, and teleconferences offered by colleges or universities accredited by an agency</text>
    </level>
    <text>recognized for that purpose by the United States Department of Education, or which is approved by the Board, in accordance with § 504(j) of the Act (D.C. Official Code § 3-1205.04(j)(2007 Repl.)), or pre-approved by the American Physical Therapy Association
      (APTA) or the Board for two (2) or more credit hours.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <num>6707.3.</num>
    <text>Not more than one-half (1/2) of the total required number of Continuing Education Units (CEUs) may be accepted in any renewal period, or for</text>
    <text>reinstatement or reactivation of a license, for approved online courses, video courses, telecourses, videoconferences, and teleconference activities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6707.4</num>
    <text>6707.4 The limitation set forth in § 6707.3 shall not apply to the Federation of State Boards of Physical Therapy’s Practice Review Tool or to Board- approved courses which grant more than twenty (20) credit hours for a single course.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6707.5</num>
    <text>6707.5 To qualify for approval by the Board, a continuing education program shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be current in its subject matter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Be developed and taught by qualified individuals; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Meet one (1) of the following requirements:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be administered or approved by a recognized national, state, or</text>
    </level>
    <text>local physical therapy organization, a health care organization, and</text>
    <text>accredited health care facility, or an accredited college or</text>
    <text>university; or</text>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Be submitted by the program sponsor or the applicant to the Board</text>
    </level>
    <text>for review no less than sixty (60) days before the date of the</text>
    <text>presentation and be approved by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6707.6</num>
    <text>6707.6 The Board has pre-approved for acceptance all physical therapy continuing education seminars, workshops, or programs administered or approved by:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The American Physical Therapy Association (APTA);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Federation of State Boards of Physical Therapy (FSBPT);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The American Occupational Therapy Association, Inc.;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A health care facility accredited by the Joint Commission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A college or university approved by an accrediting body recognized by the</text>
    </level>
    <text>Council on Postsecondary Accreditation or the Secretary of the United States Department of Education; or</text>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Any of the following organizations if the training is substantially</text>
    </level>
    <text>related to physical therapy services:</text>
    <text>The American Medical Association under Physician Category I; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The American Nurses Association.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6707.7.</num>
    <text>The Board may issue and update a list of approved continuing education</text>
    <text>programs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6707.8.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall have the burden of verifying whether a program is approved by the Board pursuant to this section prior to attending the program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6707.9.</num>
    <text>The Board may approve the following continuing education activities by an applicant:</text>
    <text>Serving as an instructor or speaker at a conference, seminar, or workshop;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>In-service training;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Publication of an article in a professional journal, publication of a book</text>
    </level>
    <text>or a chapter in a book, or publication of a book review in a professional journal or bulletin; and</text>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Participating in research as a principal investigator or research assistant.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 945, 949 (February 12, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 6451 (June 25, 2004); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 5462, 5465 (July 1, 2011).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>