<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-6708</num>
  <heading>CONTINUING EDUCATION CREDITS (§ 17-6708)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6708.1.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant continuing education credit for whole hours only, with a minimum of fifty (50) minutes constituting one (1) credit hour.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6708.2.</num>
    <text>For approved undergraduate or graduate courses, each semester hour of credit shall constitute fifteen (15) hours of continuing education credit, and each quarter hour of credit constitutes ten (10) hours of continuing education credit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6708.3.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant a maximum of ten (10) continuing education credits per year to an applicant who attends in-service education programs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6708.4.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant to an applicant who serves as an instructor or speaker at an acceptable program for both preparation and presentation time, subject to the restrictions in §§ 6708.5 through 6708.8.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6708.5.</num>
    <text>The maximum amount of credit that may be granted for preparation time is twice the amount of the associated presentation time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6708.6.</num>
    <text>The maximum amount of credit that may be granted pursuant to § 6708.4 is fifty percent (50%) of an applicant&amp;#8217;s continuing education requirement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6708.7.</num>
    <text>If an applicant has previously received credit in connection with a particular presentation, the Board shall not grant credit for a subsequent presentation unless it involves either a different subject or substantial additional research concerning
      the same subject.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6708.8.</num>
    <text>The presentation shall have been completed during the period for which credit is claimed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6708.9.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant an applicant who is an author or editor of a published book four (4) units or forty (40) hours of continuing education credit, if the book has been published or accepted for publication during the period for which credit is claimed
      and the applicant submits proof of this fact in the application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6708.10.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant an applicant who is the sole author or co-author of a published original paper, journal article or poster presentation, two (2) continuing education units or twenty (20) hours of continuing education credit, subject to the same
      restrictions set forth for books in § 6708.9.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6708.11.</num>
    <text>The Board may grant an applicant who is the sole author of a published book review, review paper, or abstract, one (1) unit or ten (10) hours of continuing education credit, subject to the same restrictions set forth for books in § 6708.9.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 945, 950 (February 12, 1988); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 6451 (June 25, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>