<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-404</num>
  <heading>LICENSE REQUIREMENTS (§ 17-404)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>404.1.</num>
    <text>To qualify for a license under this chapter, the applicant shall be required to meet the qualifications set forth in this section for each class of license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>404.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a Class 1 &amp;#8211; Steam Engineer license shall have the following qualifications:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The experience and knowledge to take charge of and operate any plant; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Two (2) years of experience in addition to the experience required for the Class 3 license (§404.4), one of which shall be as an engineer in a 2nd class plant, or as a Class 2 Steam Engineer and assistant engineer in a 1st Class plant while holding
        a 2nd Class License.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>404.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a Class 2 &amp;#8211; Steam Engineer license shall have the following qualifications:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The experience and knowledge to take charge of and operate a high pressure steam plant where total horsepower of the boilers and engines or refrigeration machinery is not in excess of seven hundred fifty (750) horsepower; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>In addition to the experience required for examination for the Class 3 Steam Engineer license, one (1) year of experience as an assistant engineer in charge of a 3rd Class plant.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>404.4.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a Class 3 &amp;#8211; Steam and Hot Water Heating Boiler Engineer license shall have the following qualifications:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The experience and knowledge to take charge of and operate any of the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A plant having high pressure steam boilers not to exceed four hundred (400) horsepower or a combination of high pressure boilers and heating boilers or refrigeration equipment, not to exceed a total of four hundred (400) horsepower;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A heating plant having low pressure steam boilers with a pump return and refrigeration equipment, with no limitation on total capacity; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A heating plant having hot water boilers and refrigeration equipment, with no limitation on total capacity.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>At least two (2) years of experience in a high pressure steam plant of more than seventy-five (75) boiler horsepower as an assistant engineer, fireman, or oiler; or four (4) years of experience in a plant of not less than fifty horsepower (50) [Seven
        thousand square feet (7,000 ft.2) of steam radiation or eleven thousand two hundred square feet (11,200 ft.2) of water radiation at one hundred fifty degrees Fahrenheit (150° F.)].One year of experience will be waived for a graduate mechanical
        engineer from a duly recognized school of technology or a graduate of an approved engineer apprentice training program.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>404.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a Class 4 &amp;#8211; Steam Engineer license shall have the following qualifications:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The experience and knowledge to take charge of and operate high pressure stationary steam boilers not in excess of seventy-five (75) horsepower and steam pressure not in excess of one hundred twenty-five pounds per square inch (125 lbs./in.2); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>At least six (6) months of experience in the care and operation of steam boilers.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>404.6.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a Class 5a &amp;#8211; Steam Engineer license shall have the following qualifications:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The experience and knowledge to take charge of and operate high pressure stationary steam boilers not in excess of twenty-five (25) horsepower and steam pressure not in excess of one hundred twenty-five pounds per square inch (125 lbs./in.2); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>At least six (6) months of experience in the care and operation of steam boilers.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>404.7.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a Class 5b &amp;#8211; Miniature Boiler Engineer license shall have the following qualifications:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The experience and knowledge to take charge of and operate a boiler which does not exceed the following limits: sixteen inch (16&amp;#8243;) diameter of shell, forty-two inches (42&amp;#8243;) of shell, twenty square feet (20 ft.2) of heating surface,
        and one hundred pounds per square inch (100 lbs./in.2) allowable working pressure; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>At least six (6) months of experience in the care and operation of steam boilers.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>404.8.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a Class 6 &amp;#8211; Steam and Hot Water Heating Boiler Engineer license shall have the following qualifications:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The experience and knowledge to take charge of and operate steam and hot water heating boilers, where the steam pressure does not exceed fifteen pounds per square inch (15 lbs./in.2 and the steam or hot water heating boilers do not exceed two hundred
        (200) horsepower (twenty eight thousand square feet (28,000 sq. ft.2)) of steam radiation or forty-four thousand eight hundred square feet (44,800 sq. ft.2) of water radiation at one hundred fifty degrees (150°F.); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>At least one (1) year of experience as a fireman or operator of a boiler other than a miniature boiler.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>404.9.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a Class 7 &amp;#8211; Portable and Construction Equipment Operator license shall have the following qualifications:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The experience and knowledge to take charge of and operate portable and construction equipment and machinery where the prime mover is in excess of twenty-five (25) horsepower, or as otherwise designated in the following classifications:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Air compressors having a pressure capacity in excess of one hundred ten cubic feet per minute (110 ft.3 /min.) at one hundred pounds per square inch (100 lbs./in.2), hoists, and similar related equipment: at least six (6) months of experience in
        the care and operation of the class of equipment for which the license is to be applied;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Bulldozers, scrapers, rollers, graders, front-end loaders, trenching machines, and similar and related equipment: at least one (1) year of experience in the care and operation of the class of equipment for which the license is to be applied;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Cranes, shovels, derricks, draglines, clam shells, pile drivers, and similar and related equipment: at least two (2) years of experience in the care and operation of the class of equipment for which the license is to be applied.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>404.10.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a Class 8a &amp;#8211; Operating Engineer &amp;#8211; Refrigeration license shall have the following qualifications:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The experience and knowledge to take charge of and operate refrigeration systems where the total connected load is not in excess of two hundred (200) compressor horsepower, or two hundred (200) tons for an absorption system, and where there is no
        other equipment requiring a licensed steam or other operating engineer; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>At least one (1) year of experience in the care and operation of refrigeration equipment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>404.11.</num>
    <text>An applicant for a Class 8b &amp;#8211; Operating Engineer &amp;#8211; Stationary Internal Combustion license shall have the following qualifications:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The experience and knowledge to take charge of and operate stationary internal combustion engines where there is no other equipment requiring a licensed steam and other operating engineer; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>At least one (1) year of experience in the care and operation of internal combustion engines.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§§3.1 through 3.10 of Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order No. 301, 945, 5M DCRR §§3.1 through 3.10.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>