<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-6406</num>
  <heading>RECOVERABLE COSTS (ยง 20-6406)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6406.1.</num>
    <text>Whenever District of Columbia UST Trust Fund monies or Federal LUST Trust Monies are expended, for undertaking corrective or enforcement action with respect to the release of a regulated substance from an underground storage tank, the responsible
      party or parties shall be jointly and severally liable to the District government for the costs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6406.2.</num>
    <text>Recoverable costs shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>All costs related to identification and notification of owners, operators and other responsible parties, and enforcement actions against a responsible party;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>All costs related to investigation, assessment, cleanup, and monitoring of sites;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Indirect costs incurred by the District based upon the formula negotiated annually with the appropriate federal agency;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>All expenditures reasonably related to inducing a recalcitrant responsible party to comply and to recovering cleanup expenditures including salaries and other expenses associated with case development, negotiations and litigation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Expenditures related to oversight of responsible party cleanups;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Legal costs associated with protracted negotiations, issuance of cleanup orders and litigation to compel reluctant responsible parties to clean up or pay clean-up costs; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Interest at the rate of six percent (6%) per annum.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 7835 (November 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7699 (October 1, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>