<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-1600</num>
  <heading>PREMISES (§ 30-1600)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1600.1.</num>
    <text>The premises where any licensed Monte Carlo night party is conducted or where it is scheduled to be conducted shall be open or available at reasonable times for inspection by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.2.</num>
    <text>A licensed organization shall only lease a premise for any Monte Carlo night party by means of a fixed rental payment; Provided, that the fixed rental payment is not based on a percentage of gross receipts or net proceeds from a Monte Carlo night
      party and reflects a fair rental value.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.3.</num>
    <text>Any lease entered into in accordance with §1600.2 shall be in writing and filed with the application for a license and reviewed by the Board to determine compliance with this subsection and §1600.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.4.</num>
    <text>Each licensed organization shall hold the Monte Carlo night party only at the premises listed on the face of the license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.5.</num>
    <text>A licensed organization shall not hold a Monte Carlo night party in a building which does not have an occupancy permit as required by the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.6.</num>
    <text>Licensed organizations shall provide at least one (1) security person, either a District police officer or a person licensed by the District as a security guard.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.7.</num>
    <text>A licensed organization shall not lend money to, or borrow money from a lessor or a person who is connected with the lessor either directly or indirectly.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.8.</num>
    <text>The rental or purchase of Monte Carlo night party equipment shall not be included in the rental of premises.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.9.</num>
    <text>Neither a lessor nor a person donating premises for the conduct of a Monte Carlo Night party shall have any pecuniary interest in any supplier&amp;#8217;s business either directly or indirectly.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.10.</num>
    <text>Neither a lessor nor a person donating premises for the conduct of a Monte Carlo Night party shall exert any influence upon a licensed organization&amp;#8217;s choice of supplier.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.11.</num>
    <text>Each licensed organization shall post the license at the entrance where the Monte Carlo night party is held.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is §4 of the Law to Legalize Lotteries, Daily Numbers Games, and Bingo and Raffles for Charitable Purposes in the District of Columbia, D.C. Law 3-172, D.C. Official Code §3-1301 et seq.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3788, 3814 (May 20. 1988).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL NOTE</heading>
      <text>Prior to May 20, 1988, the D.C. Lottery and Charitable Games Control Board published Final Rulemaking at 29 DCR 5016, 5039 (November 12, 1982).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>