<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-1401</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION (ยง 18-1401)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1401.1.</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise exempted, this chapter shall be applicable to all self-propelled or towed vehicles operating on the streets and highways of the District of Columbia, if the following occurs:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The gross vehicle weight rating (GVWR) or gross combination weight rating (GCWR) of the vehicle exceeds ten thousand (10,000) pounds;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The vehicle is designed to transport more than fifteen passengers, including the driver; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The vehicle is used in the transportation of hazardous materials in a quantity requiring placarding under title 49 of the Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1401.2.</num>
    <text>This chapter shall apply to all motor carriers of property and passengers, including common carriers by motor vehicle, contract carriers by motor vehicle, private carriers by motor vehicle, and any agent, officer, representative or employee who is
      responsible for the hiring, supervision, training, assignment, or dispatching of drivers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1401.3.</num>
    <text>All motor carriers engaged in intrastate commerce within the District of Columbia shall conduct their operations in accordance with the regulations established under this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1401.4.</num>
    <text>With respect to any intrastate motor carriers covered by this chapter, any notices or requests which the carriers are permitted or required to make to the U.S. Department of Transportation or designated officials, shall instead be made to the Metropolitan
      Police Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1401.5.</num>
    <text>Each motor carrier and shipper shall be instructed in, familiar with, and comply with the applicable rules in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1401.6.</num>
    <text>All regulations and parts of regulations in effect in the District of Columbia which are inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter are superseded with respect to matters covered by this chapter, unless specifically stated otherwise.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>