<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-6200</num>
  <heading>OBLIGATIONS OF RESPONSIBLE PARTIES (§ 20-6200)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>6200.1.</num>
    <text>Any responsible party, as defined in the District of Columbia Underground Storage Tank Management Act of 1990, as amended, D.C. Law 8-242; D.C. Code § 6-995 et seq. (1995 Repl.) (&amp;#8220;the Act&amp;#8221;) and Chapter 70 of this Subtitle, shall
      be subject to the requirements of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6200.2.</num>
    <text>If the actions required pursuant to this chapter are not taken, the Director may undertake the corrective action, and the responsible party or parties shall be jointly and severally liable to the District government for costs as set forth in § 6406.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6200.3.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this chapter shall not be construed to alter the private rights at law or equity and liabilities between the neighboring property owner and the UST system owner or operator, or to relieve an UST system owner or operator of any liability
      he or she may have under statutory or common law for causing the release of the regulated substance which migrated onto a neighboring property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>6200.4.</num>
    <text>The provisions of 40 CFR Sections 280.200 through 280.230 (Subpart I Lender Liability) are incorporated by reference herein and shall apply to all existing and future security interests, including holders of security interests as defined in 40 CFR
      § 280.200(d).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is §13 of the District of Columbia Underground Storage Tank Management Act of 1990, as amended, D.C. Law 8-242, D.C. Code §6-995.1 et seq. (1995 Repl. Vol.), Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 91-160 dated
        October 9, 1991; and the District of Columbia Water Pollution Control Act of 1984, D.C. Law 5-188, D.C. Code 6-921 (1995 Repl. Vol.), Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 85-152 dated September 12, 1985).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 7835, 7882 (November 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7699 (October 1, 1999).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>