<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-600</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION AND SCOPE (§ 31-600)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>600.1.</num>
    <text>This chapter shall be applicable to and governs parts and equipment of taxicabs licensed in the District of Columbia (District).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.2.</num>
    <text>No motor vehicle shall be operated as a taxicab in the District without the prior approval of the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.3.</num>
    <text>Each motor vehicle licensed as a public vehicle for hire in the District shall comply with the regulations governing the equipment requirements, inspection of passenger vehicles for hire and standards established by the Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.4.</num>
    <text>Hack Inspectors, police officers, and other duly appointed law enforcement personnel may make traffic stops in order to enforce the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission Establishment Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-97; D.C. Official
      Code §§ 50-301, et seq. (2009 Repl.)) and its implementing regulations. Traffic stops may include, but are not limited to, stops to verify compliance with license and insurance requirements; stops to inspect vehicles for compliance with safety standards;
      and stops made in response to observed conduct which may constitute safety and service violations. Such traffic stops shall be conducted in accordance with Commission rules and regulations and General Orders.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.5.</num>
    <text>The enforcement of this chapter shall be governed by the procedures set forth in Chapter 7 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>600.6.</num>
    <text>If, at the time of a violation, the procedures in Chapter 7 do not extend in their terms to a person regulated by this chapter, violations of this chapter shall be enforced as if such person were a taxicab owner or operator.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 3595, 3603 (June 1, 1990); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8564, 8565 (July 20, 2012); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 1173 (February 1, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 60 DCR 10994 (July 26, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>