<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-602</num>
  <heading>TAXIMETERS (§ 31-602)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>602.1</num>
    <text>602.1 All licensed taxicabs shall be equipped with a functioning taximeter that meets the following requirements and the requirements for a modern taximeter system (MTS) pursuant to § 603:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The taximeter shall provide for calculation of the following rates and charges, as may be amended by the Commission from time to time:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Flag drop rate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Distance rate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Luggage charge;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Radio dispatch charge;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Fuel surcharge;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Snow emergency; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Wait time charges.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The taximeter shall provide the following data and reports:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A printed customer receipt;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Shift statistics, including but not limited to paid miles, unpaid miles, and number of trips; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>End-of-year statistics, including but not limited to paid miles, unpaid miles, and number of trips.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The taximeter shall meet the following requirements:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be fully electronic;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Have all access points sealed by a taximeter business licensed by the Commission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Have casings made of hard impenetrable plastic or metal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Be capable of operating within a temperature range of negative twenty degrees Fahrenheit (-20° F) and positive one hundred twenty degrees Fahrenheit (+120° F);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Be capable of automatically producing a printed receipt for passengers or Commission personnel, as described in Subsection 803.1;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Be capable of producing a printed receipt within ten (10) seconds;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Be capable of producing a printed report for Commission personnel which shows total mileage, total paid mileage, total trips, total units, and total extras. All such printed reports must show a minimum of six (6) digits exclusive of decimals, for
        example 009,999. This function shall be operated by a separate button or switch;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Have the name and license number of the licensed taximeter shop on the sealed surface of all seals. If an adjustment can be made to any component affecting the performance of the printer, then provision shall be made for by applying a seal in a
        manner which requires the seal to be broken before an adjustment can be made;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Have an auxiliary power source contained in the unit which operates independently of the vehicle’s electrical system and operates the memory at its full capacity for a minimum of two (2) years;</text>
    </level>
    <text>(10) Have a memory which shall be non-erasable;</text>
    <text>(11) Upon reaching the limits of any display, the unit shall be capable of turning over;</text>
    <text>(12) Have a fully programmable fare structure with low-cost rate change capability;</text>
    <text>(13) For two (2)-piece units, have a printer capable of interfacing with and recording information from a fully approved electronic taximeter;</text>
    <text>(14) For two (2)-piece units, have all connections between the display unit and the memory/printer unit permanently sealed and tamper-proof by use of approved tubing or electrical conduits. The display unit must be unable to function if disconnected
      from the memory/printer unit;</text>
    <text>(15) Be capable of automatically making meter displays inoperable if printer paper is not available in the taximeter;</text>
    <text>(16) Have model and serial numbers appearing on the face of the unit. For two (2)-piece units, model and serial numbers must appear on the display unit and the memory/printer unit;</text>
    <text>(17) Have all operating buttons and/or switches related to passenger functions appearing on the face of the unit, properly labeled, and indicating each function;</text>
    <text>(18) Have all extra charges appear separately on the display as well as the receipt for passengers and have the extra charge indicator illuminated when in operation;</text>
    <text>(19) Have the fare displayed for a total of fifteen (15) seconds from the time the printer begins to print the customer receipt at the completion of the ride;</text>
    <text>(20) Have a clearly visible fare display;</text>
    <text>(21) Have a receipt dispenser unit which is visible to the passenger;</text>
    <text>(22) Have sufficient candlepower so that all illuminated indicators are visible to the passenger;</text>
    <text>(23) Be permanently affixed to the vehicle in a location approved by the Commission;</text>
    <text>(24) Have a cruising light that is controlled by engaging the meter; provided, however, that the cruising light may be disengaged by a separate toggle switch if a taxicab is “Off Duty” and not for hire or is “On Call” and responding to a dispatched
      call or previously arranged engagement, acting in compliance with Subsections 605.6, 605.7, 605.8, and 820.3.</text>
    <text>(25) Calculate and display the authorized metered rate of fare required by Section 801 in Chapter 8 of this title;</text>
    <text>(26) Use switches, wiring, and wire caps in all connections to the taximeter harness, cruiser light wires, and pulse wires that meet the specifications of the Society of Automotive Engineers, where such specifications are applicable. All of the ports
      and peripheral connections shall be physically secure from tampering that could disrupt the functionality or compromise the integrity of the taximeter; and</text>
    <text>(27) Meet the specifications and tolerances published in the National Bureau of Standards Handbook 44.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Whenever the Office issues an Office Order requiring taxicab owners to gather or report information, each taxicab company, association or fleet shall be responsible for the gathering or reporting of such information from each taxicab operator associated
        with such company, association or fleet. The company, association, or fleet shall be a conduit of that information to the Commission without liability for the transmission of such information to the Commission.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.2.</num>
    <text>[REPEALED]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.3.</num>
    <text>[REPEALED]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.4.</num>
    <text>Taximeters shall only be installed by taximeter businesses licensed by the Commission which meet the requirements in Chapter 13 of these Regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.5.</num>
    <text>No taxicab shall be equipped with more than one taximeter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.6.</num>
    <text>Each taximeter shall be sealed to avoid tampering and only a licensed taximeter business shall perform the sealing:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Lead seals shall use a numbered seal press with an official inscription issued by the Commission;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The taximeter business shall place a certification sticker, issued by the Commission on each taximeter that states the following:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The taximeter&amp;#8217;s serial number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The date it was sealed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The name of the authorized sealer;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The sealer&amp;#8217;s signature;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The revolutions (constant &amp;#8220;K&amp;#8221;) of the taximeter; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The wheel and tire size at the time of inspection and the recommended tire pressure.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.7.</num>
    <text>Each taximeter shall be tested once per year by a taximeter business licensed by the Commission. The annual inspection shall not be conducted by a taximeter business on taxicabs owned or affiliated with the taximeter business conducting the inspection.
      The annual inspection shall be identical to the inspection process identified in Section 1324.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.8.</num>
    <text>Each new taximeter unit submitted for approval to the Commission by the manufacturer, its licensed representative, or the taximeter business shall be subject to a testing period.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.9.</num>
    <text>Drivers shall comply with the following requirements as to the condition of the taximeter and cruiser lights:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A driver shall not drive a taxicab unless all taximeter seals and cable housing seals are in good condition and pressed by the Commission or its authorized designee. The serial number of the taximeter must be the same as that shown on the rate card
        assigned to the taxicab;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A driver shall not pick up or transport a passenger unless the taxicab has a properly functioning taximeter, which shall be equipped with paper for the printing of receipts; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>While on duty a driver shall have the cruiser light illuminated when the taximeter is not in use, indicating that the taxicab is available for hire, except as authorized by Subsection 602.1(c)(24). When a driver has a passenger and the meter is
        engaged, the cruiser light shall not be illuminated, indicating the taxicab is not available for hire.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.10.</num>
    <text>A driver shall not operate a taxicab with a non-functioning taximeter, including a taximeter in which the taximeter or the seals affixed to the taximeter by a licensed taximeter repair shop have been tampered with, broken, or altered in any manner.
      The operation of a taxicab with a non-functioning taximeter or with a broken taximeter seal shall give rise to a rebuttable presumption that the driver knew of the non-functioning taximeter, tampering, or alteration and operated the taxicab with
      such knowledge. The specifications of a functioning taximeter are found primarily in Subsection 602.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.11.</num>
    <text>A driver shall not tamper with, repair or attempt to repair, or connect any unauthorized device to the taximeter or the taximeter technology system, including any seal, cable connection, or electrical wiring of the taximeter or taximeter technology
      system, or make any change in the vehicle&amp;#8217;s mechanism or its tires which would affect the operation of the taximeter or the taximeter technology system.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.12.</num>
    <text>Except as authorized by Subsection 602.1(c)(24), a driver shall not tamper with the cruiser light or any of the interior lights or connections of the taxicab except to replace a defective bulb or fuse. The cruiser light of a taxicab shall be automatically
      controlled by the movement of the taximeter button or ignition switch so that it is lighted only when the taximeter is in an off or &amp;#8220;Vacant&amp;#8221; position and unlighted when the taximeter is in a recording or &amp;#8220;Hired&amp;#8221;
      position. The operation of a taxicab with an unauthorized installation or device controlling interior or cruiser lighting shall give rise to a rebuttable presumption that the driver knew of the unauthorized installation or device and operated the
      taxicab with such knowledge.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>602.13.</num>
    <text>A driver shall not place tires or wheels of a different size, or &amp;#8220;off-size&amp;#8221; tires, on the taxicab without reinspection and recalibration of the taximeter. The driver shall not operate a taxicab with tires inflated outside the manufacturer&amp;#8217;s
      recommended level, whether under-inflated or over-inflated. The driver shall not operate a taxicab carrying passengers while the vehicle is equipped with a temporary tire, also known as a “donut,” as this is operation of an “unsafe vehicle” in violation
      of Section 608.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 3595, 3604 (June 1, 1990); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 3831 (April 11, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 8564, 8565 (July 20, 2012); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 60 DCR 7007 (May 17, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 12387 (August 30, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>