<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>31-701</num>
  <heading>COMPLAINTS (§ 31-701)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>701.1.</num>
    <text>There shall be displayed in a suitable frame on the back of the front seat of each taxicab, in a position as to be clearly visible to passengers, notice of the procedure to be followed by persons wishing to file a complaint.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>701.2.</num>
    <text>Each taxicab operating in the District shall prominently display the passenger rights form that shows the address and telephone number of the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>701.3.</num>
    <text>Complaints shall be filed within thirty (30) days after the event giving rise to the complaint.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>701.4.</num>
    <text>Complaints shall be in writing, signed by the complainant, and contain the complainant&amp;#8217;s address and telephone number.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>701.5.</num>
    <text>Written complaints shall be delivered or mailed to the Office of Taxicabs, District of Columbia Taxicab Commission, 2041 Martin Luther King Jr., Avenue, S.E., Washington, D.C. 20020.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>701.6.</num>
    <text>Within ten (10) days of receipt of a complaint the Office of Taxicabs (Office) shall notify the taxicab operator or owner, by certified mail, return receipt requested, of the nature of the complaint.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>701.7.</num>
    <text>The notification shall direct the operator or owner to file an answer with the Office within ten (10) days of receipt.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>701.8.</num>
    <text>When the answer shows a violation of the Commission&amp;#8217;s Rules and Regulations, the Office, within ten (10) days, shall notify the taxicab owner or operator of the violation and the proposed sanction. The Office shall also inform the complainant
      of the proposed sanction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>701.9.</num>
    <text>When the answer does not show a violation of the Commission&amp;#8217;s rules, the Office shall notify the complainant of the answer and provide an explanation of why there is no violation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>701.10.</num>
    <text>When the Office does not determine whether action under §§ 701.8 and 701.9 should be taken, the Office shall attempt to resolve the complaint.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>701.11.</num>
    <text>If the Office does not resolve the complaint, the matter shall be referred to the Panel on Adjudication (Panel) for disposition.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>701.12.</num>
    <text>If the statements alleged in a complaint are clearly not in violation of the Commission&amp;#8217;s Rules and Regulations, the Chief of the Office shall dismiss the matter and notify the complainant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 37 DCR 3595, 3608 (June 1, 1990).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>