<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-1504</num>
  <heading>APPLICATIONS FROM FOREIGN APPLICANTS AND PERSONS WITH DEGREES FROM FOREIGNCHOOLS (ยง 17-1504)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1504.1.</num>
    <text>All foreign language documentation submitted with the completed application shall be accompanied by certified translations of each individual document. The translator shall send the translation report directly to the Board for review.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1504.2.</num>
    <text>An applicant shall be able to speak and write in English. The Board may require the applicant prove his or her English proficiency by providing a certified copy of his or her score on the Test of English as a Foreign Language (TOEFL) examination showing
      a score of 500 or greater.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1504.3.</num>
    <text>An applicant who, for political or other reasons deemed valid by the Board, is unable to obtain his or her college transcript shall be required to complete a supplementary application form approved by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1504.4.</num>
    <text>NCEES standards and recommendations on foreign engineering curricula shall serve as the Board&amp;#8217;s guide for evaluation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1504.5.</num>
    <text>An applicant possessing a current Professional Engineer license or Professional Land Surveyor license issued by an appropriate licensing authority in a state, province, or territory of Canada or Mexico may be permitted to obtain a license in the District
      of Columbia if the applicant proves to the satisfaction of the Board that he or she otherwise qualifies for licensure under this chapter, has passed an examination acceptable to the Board, and has completed education and training requirements for
      licensure in the foreign jurisdiction that were substantially equivalent, at the time they were received by the applicant, to the Board&amp;#8217;s current education and experience requirements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 8783 (September 7, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>