<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-1502</num>
  <heading>ORGANIZATION OF THE BOARD (§ 17-1502)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1502.1.</num>
    <text>Pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 47-2853.06(e), the Board shall consist of seven (7) members. Four (4) members shall be Professional Engineers licensed in various disciplines, two (2) members shall be Professional Land Surveyors, and one (1) member
      shall be a public member.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.2.</num>
    <text>The Mayor appoints the members of the Board, with the consent of the Council of the District of Columbia, to three-year terms. Members may serve on the Board for no more than three (3) consecutive three-year terms as long as the requirements set forth
      in D.C. Official Code § 47-2853.07 are met.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.3.</num>
    <text>At the first regularly scheduled meeting of each calendar year, the Board shall elect a chairperson. The Board may also choose to elect a vice chair and a treasurer. The vice chair shall preside at meetings or portions thereof when the chairperson
      is absent. The treasurer shall be responsible for budgeting, tracking, and controlling all Board expenditures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.4.</num>
    <text>The Board shall hold at least four (4) meetings each year at times and places determined by the Board by resolution. The Board shall publish notice of all regular meetings at least one (1) week in advance in the D.C. Register. All meetings are open
      to the public, except meetings or portions of meetings which the Board closes for executive session.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.5.</num>
    <text>The Board may meet in committees smaller than the full Board, but of not less than three (3) members, for carrying out specific functions of the Board, provided that the full Board votes to approve any actions of such smaller committees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.6.</num>
    <text>A quorum of the Board shall equal a majority of the number of legislated positions on the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.7.</num>
    <text>After a quorum is established, a majority vote of those Board members present and voting is necessary for the Board to take any official action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.8.</num>
    <text>The current edition of Roberts Rules of Order shall govern the normal proceedings of the Board. Exceptions include hearings that may be disciplinary in nature.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.9.</num>
    <text>Pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 47-2853.09(b), each member of the Board shall be entitled to receive compensation in accordance with D.C. Official Code § 1-611.08, and in addition shall be reimbursed for reasonable travel and other expenses incurred
      in the performance of their duties, subject to appropriations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.10.</num>
    <text>All applications and requests for which the Board has prescribed a form shall be presented to the Board on the forms.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.11.</num>
    <text>Pursuant to the procedures and limitations set forth within Title 2, Chapter 5, subchapter II (Freedom of Information), of the D.C. Official Code, the public may request and receive copies of public records generated by the Board. The public shall
      direct all requests for copies of the Board&amp;#8217;s public records, as defined in D.C. Official Code § 2-502, to the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs&amp;#8217; Freedom of Information Officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 8783 (September 7, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>