<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-1519</num>
  <heading>COMPLIANCE (ยง 17-1519)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1519.1.</num>
    <text>A person must be licensed pursuant to this chapter and the Act to practice or offer to practice engineering or land surveying in the District of Columbia, except as exempted by D.C. Official Code ยง47-2886.10.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1519.2.</num>
    <text>No person shall use the words &amp;#8220;engineer,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;engineering,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;land surveyor,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;land surveying&amp;#8221; or any modification or derivative thereof in any form indicating or tending
      to indicate that he or she is licensed by the Board unless he or she possesses a valid license as a Professional Engineer or Land Surveyor issued by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1519.3.</num>
    <text>Any person presenting or attempting to use the certificate of licensure or the seal of another, or any person who shall give any false or forged evidence of any kind to the Board or any member thereof in obtaining or attempting to obtain a certificate
      of licensure, or any person who shall falsely impersonate any other licensee of like or different name, or any person who shall attempt to use an expired or revoked or non-existent certificate of licensure, or who shall practice or offer to practice
      when not qualified, or any person who falsely claims that he/she is licensed under these Rules, or any person who shall violate any of the provisions of these Rules shall be in violation of these Rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1519.4.</num>
    <text>Any individual licensed with this Board to perform land surveying services shall comply with the minimum standards codified for land surveys in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 8783 (September 7, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>