<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-1508</num>
  <heading>EDUCATION REQUIREMENTS (ยง 17-1508)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1508.1.</num>
    <text>Applicants for a Professional Engineer license must have obtained a four-year baccalaureate engineering degree from an engineering program approved by the Board. The Board will approve baccalaureate degree programs that meet the following standards:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The baccalaureate engineering degree program held accreditation from the Engineering Accreditation Commission of the Accreditation Board for Engineering Technology (EAC/ABET) at the time the applicant received the degree;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The baccalaureate engineering degree program received accreditation from EAC/ABET within three years after the date that the applicant received the degree; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The baccalaureate engineering degree program was not accredited by EAC/ABET but, within two years of the date that the applicant received the degree from the unaccredited institution, the Board has determined, in accordance with EAC/ABET standards,
        that the program is substantially equivalent to programs that are accredited by EAC/ABET.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1508.2.</num>
    <text>Applicants for a Professional Land Surveyor license using a four-year baccalaureate land surveying degree to satisfy the Board&amp;#8217;s education requirements must have obtained their degree from a land surveying program approved by the Board.
      The Board shall approve land surveying programs that meet the following standards:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The college or university awarding the degree must be accredited by the accrediting agency or state approval agency recognized by the U.S. Secretary of Education as a &amp;#8220;reliable authority as to the quality of postsecondary education&amp;#8221;
        within the meaning of the Higher Education Act of 1965, as amended (HEA), located in the state or territory where the main campus of the college or university is located;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The land surveying program was accredited by EAC/ABET, the Applied Science Accreditation Commission of ABET (ASAC/ABET), the Technology Accreditation Commission of ABET (TAC/ABET);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The land surveying program was evaluated and approved by the Board as being substantially equivalent to those curricula that are accredited by ABET prior to the date that the applicant received the degree; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The land surveying program received accreditation from one of the ABET Commissions within three years after the date that the applicant received the degree.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1508.3.</num>
    <text>A non-degreed applicant for a Professional Land Surveyor license by examination must demonstrate the attainment of a minimum of 12 years of education and experience, having taken at least one course of land surveying at an institution accredited,
      at the time the course was taken, by an accrediting agency or state approval agency recognized by the U.S. Secretary of Education as a &amp;#8220;reliable authority as to the quality of postsecondary education&amp;#8221; within the meaning of the
      Higher Education Act of 1965, as amended (HEA). Acceptable courses are those courses in the various kinds and facets of land surveying that have been evaluated and approved by this Board as being substantially equivalent to those curricula that
      are accredited by ABET. Acceptable experience must meet the requirements of section 1509 of this Chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1508.4.</num>
    <text>A non-degreed applicant for a Land Surveyor Intern license by examination must demonstrate the attainment of a minimum of 8 years of education and experience, having taken at least one course of surveying at an institution accredited, at the time
      the course was taken, by an accrediting agency or state approval agency recognized by the U.S. Secretary of Education as a &amp;#8220;reliable authority as to the quality of postsecondary education&amp;#8221; within the meaning of the Higher Education
      Act of 1965, as amended (HEA). Acceptable courses are those courses in the various kinds and facets of land surveying that have been evaluated and approved by this Board as being substantially equivalent to those curricula that are accredited by
      ABET. Acceptable experience must meet the requirements of section 1509 of this Chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1508.5.</num>
    <text>Applicants are responsible for verifying the approval status of degree programs used to satisfy the Board&amp;#8217;s education requirements and may do so by contacting the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 8783 (September 7, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>