<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-2219</num>
  <heading>SEVERE WEATHER TRAFFIC CONTROLS[COLON] SNOW EMERGENCY ROUTE (§ 18-2219)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2219.1.</num>
    <text>Between October 15th and April 15th of each year, whenever snow, sleet, or freezing rain is falling within the District or whenever there is a covering or coating of snow, sleet, or ice on any street in the District marked as a Snow Emergency Route,
      no person in charge of a motor vehicle operated on any such street shall allow the vehicle to become stalled on that street due to the fact that the driving wheels of the vehicle are not equipped with tire chains or effective snow tires.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2219.2.</num>
    <text>Whenever the Director has announced, pursuant to § 2414, that parking is prohibited on Snow Emergency Routes, and such parking prohibition is in effect with respect to a particular street which has been designated as a Snow Emergency Route, no person
      in charge of a motor vehicle operated on such street shall allow the vehicle to become stalled on that street due to the fact that the motor fuel supply of the vehicle has been allowed to become exhausted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2219.3.</num>
    <text>Whenever the Director has announced, pursuant to § 2414, that parking is prohibited on Snow Emergency Routes, and such parking prohibition is in effect, the person in charge of a motor vehicle which becomes stalled on any such route, for whatever
      reason, including, without limitation, a flat tire, shall without delay take action to have the vehicle towed or pushed off the roadway of the Snow Emergency Route; Provided, that nothing in this subsection shall permit the violation of any other
      law or regulation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2219.4.</num>
    <text>No person shall abandon or leave a motor vehicle in the roadway of a Snow Emergency Route at any time when the parking of motor vehicles on that route has been prohibited pursuant to § 2414; Provided, that a vehicle standing in the roadway of a Snow
      Emergency Route shall not be considered abandoned or left within the meaning of this subsection in the following circumstances:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If the operator leaves the vehicle only for the purpose of securing assistance and for a time actually necessary to secure such assistance, either to make a telephone call from a nearby public telephone or to go to a nearby garage, gasoline station,
        or other place of assistance, and if thereafter the operator, without delay, returns to and remains with the stalled vehicle until its removal; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The operator has, prior to leaving the vehicle, placed on the windshield a note stating the approximate time of his or her departure in search of assistance and the location to which he or she has gone for such assistance.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2219.5.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provisions of this title, any unattended vehicle found on any Snow Emergency Route when the parking prohibition is in effect pursuant to § 2417 of this title, may be removed from the route in accordance with § 2421 of this
      title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2219.6.</num>
    <text>Whenever by reason of the declaration of a weather emergency, Federal and District government employees are dismissed from duty one (1) or more hours in advance of their normal quitting time, those traffic regulations that normally go into effect
      at 4:00 p.m. shall go into effect the same number of hours in advance of 4:00 p.m. that the Federal and District government employees are dismissed in advance of their normal quitting time (for example, and not by way of limitation, “No Standing,”
      “No Parking,” One-Way Streets, Unbalanced Lanes, and “No Left Turn”).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2219.7.</num>
    <text>The traffic regulations advanced in their hours of operation under the provisions of this section shall remain in force until their normal termination at 6:30 p.m., or as may be otherwise indicated at specific locations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2219.8.</num>
    <text>At least one (1) hour’s notice of the advanced operation of traffic regulations, as provided in this section, shall be given the public in the manner required by § 2414.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Commissioners’ Order 274, 310/949 effective September 1, 1949, 17 DCRR §§ 116.5, 116.7 (October19, 1970); as amended by Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order 61-2030 effective November 22, 1970; and by Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 7633 (November
        27, 1987).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>