<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-2224</num>
  <heading>ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES IN MOTOR VEHICLES (§ 18-2224)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2224.1.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in §§ 2224.2 and 2224.3, no person shall operate or ride in a vehicle when any opened alcoholic beverage is in or on the vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2224.2</num>
    <text>2224.2 An open container shall not be considered to be in or on a vehicle if the open container is located:</text>
    <text>In a trunk, cargo area, or storage compartment that is inaccessible from the passenger area of the vehicle;</text>
    <text>In a locked compartment within the passenger area of the vehicle; or</text>
    <text>With respect to a vehicle without a trunk, behind the last row of seats within the passenger area of the vehicle such that the open container is inaccessible by the driver or passengers while in their seats.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2224.3.</num>
    <text>[REPEALED]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2224.4.</num>
    <text>A person operating a vehicle in violation of this section shall be subject to a fine of one hundred dollars ($100).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2224.5</num>
    <text>2224.5 For purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <text>“Alcoholic beverage” means an alcoholic beverage as defined in D.C. Official Code § 25-101(5)).</text>
    <text>“Opened alcoholic beverage container” means an alcoholic beverage in a bottle, can, or other container from which:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The top, cap, cork, seal, or tab seal has at some time been removed or broken; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Some of the alcohol beverage has been removed.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 6(c) of the Comprehensive Anti-Driving Amendment Act of 1991, effective May 5, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-96; 38 DCR 7274, 7279 (December 6, 1991)); as amended by the Department of Motor Vehicles Reform Amendment Act of 2004, effective April 8, 2005
        (D.C. Law 15-307; 52 DCR 1700 (February 25, 2005)); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 52 DCR 5759 (June 17, 2005); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 129134 (September 13, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>