<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-2204</num>
  <heading>TURNING REQUIREMENTS AND RESTRICTIONS (§ 18-2204)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2204.1.</num>
    <text>No vehicle shall be turned so as to proceed in the opposite direction upon any curve, or upon the approach to or near the crest of a grade, where such vehicle cannot be seen by the driver of any other vehicle approaching from either direction within
      five hundred feet (500 ft.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2204.2.</num>
    <text>No person shall turn a vehicle to enter a private road or driveway or otherwise turn a vehicle from a direct course or move right or left upon a roadway unless and until such movement can be made with reasonable safety.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2204.3.</num>
    <text>No person shall turn any vehicle to enter a private road or driveway, or otherwise turn a vehicle from a direct course or move right or left upon a roadway without giving an appropriate signal in the manner provided in this chapter if any other traffic
      may be affected by the movement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2204.4.</num>
    <text>A signal of intention to turn right or left when required shall be given continuously during not less than the last one hundred feet (100 ft.) traveled by the vehicle before turning.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2204.5.</num>
    <text>When authorized markers, buttons, or other indications are placed within or between intersections indicating the course to be traveled by vehicles, no driver of a vehicle shall disobey the directions of the indications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2204.6.</num>
    <text>Whenever authorized signs are erected indicating that “NO RIGHT TURN” or “NO LEFT TURN” or “NO U-TURN” is permitted, no driver of a vehicle shall disobey the directions of any such sign.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2204.7.</num>
    <text>No vehicle shall make a U-turn so as to proceed in the opposite direction at any intersection controlled by traffic lights or police officer, or on a crosswalk adjacent to such an intersection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2204.8.</num>
    <text>The driver of any vehicle shall not turn a vehicle so as to proceed in the opposite direction unless such movement can be made in safety and without interfering with other traffic.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2204.9.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section shall not apply to streetcars.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2204.10</num>
    <text>2204.10 No vehicle shall make a U-turn so as to proceed in the opposite direction across a bicycle lane.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order 274, 310/949 effective September 1, 1949, 17 DCRR § 39(a), (b) 42 &amp;#8211; 45 (October 19, 1970); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 5629 (April 12, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>