<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-709</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION FOR PERMIT FOR A NON-FIRST AMENDMENT RELATED PARADE, MARCH, RACE,ALK-A-THON OR OTHER SIMILAR ACTIVITY[COLON] ISSUANCE OF PERMIT (ยง 24-709)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>709.1.</num>
    <text>Final action shall be taken on an application for a non-First Amendment activity permit within a reasonably prompt period of time after receipt of the completed application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>709.2.</num>
    <text>Final action on an application shall consist of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Issuance of a permit in accordance with the terms of the application;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Issuance of a permit in accordance with terms other than those set forth in the application; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Denial of the application by the Chief of Police or his or her designee.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>709.3.</num>
    <text>If a timely-filed application is denied or modified, the applicant shall be served with a written notice of denial or modification at least ten (10) days prior to the proposed date of the proposed activity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>709.4.</num>
    <text>The notice of denial or modification shall include specific reasons for the denial or modification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>709.5.</num>
    <text>Service of the notice of denial or modification shall be made personally or by certified mail.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>709.6.</num>
    <text>If the late filing of an application or ongoing negotiations concerning the terms of a permit make it impractical to issue a written notice of denial or modification at least ten (10) days prior to the proposed date of the activity, every effort shall
      be made to promptly notify the organizers of the activity once a decision to deny or modify the application has been made; and a written notice of denial or modification shall be served as soon as reasonably possible.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 1079 (February 1, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>