<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-4711</num>
  <heading>APPEAL OF ADJUSTMENTS TO THE PAYMENT RATE (ยง 24-4711)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4711.1.</num>
    <text>After completion of an audit of CFSA&amp;#8217;s reported costs, MAA shall provide CFSA with a written notice of its determination of any adjustment to the payment rate. The notice shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A description of the rate adjustment, including the original payment rate and the revised payment rate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The effective date of the change in the payment rate:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The amount of money due to or from MAA attributable to the change in the payment rate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A summary of all audit adjustments made to CFSA&amp;#8217;s reported costs, including an explanation, by appropriate reference to law, rules, or the program manual, of the reason in support of the adjustment; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A statement informing CFSA of the right to request an administrative review within sixty (60) days of the date of the determination.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4711.2.</num>
    <text>CFSA shall have sixty days from the date of the determination issued pursuant to subsection 4711.1 to submit a written request for administrative review if it disagrees with any audit adjustment or payment rate calculation. The request for administrative
      review shall be submitted to the Financial Manager, Audit and Finance Office, Medical Assistance Administration, Department of Health.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4711.3.</num>
    <text>The written request for administrative review shall include a specific description of the audit adjustment or payment rate calculation to be reviewed, the reason for the review, the relief requested, and any documentation in support of the relief
      requested.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4711.4.</num>
    <text>MAA shall mail a written determination relative to the administrative review not later than one hundred and twenty (120) days from the date of the written request for administrative review under 4711.1.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4711.5.</num>
    <text>Within forty five (45) days of receipt of the MAA&amp;#8217;s written determination, CFSA may appeal the written determination by filing a written notice of appeal with the Board of Appeals and Review, 441 4th Street, N.W., Suite 540, Washington,
      DC 20001.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4711.6.</num>
    <text>Filing an appeal shall not stay any action to recover any overpayment.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>