<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-5503</num>
  <heading>PARTIAL APPLICABILITY OF UST REGULATIONS TO HEATING OIL TANKS FOR CONSUMPTIVESE ON THE PREMISES STORED (§ 20-5503)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5503.1.</num>
    <text>Heating oil UST systems having a capacity less than one-thousand-one-hundred (1,100) gallons shall be exempt from the requirements of this Subtitle with the following exceptions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>In the event of a suspected or confirmed release from the UST system, a responsible or remediating party shall comply with all of the provisions of Chapter 56 except §§ 5600.7(d) and 5601;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Chapter 62 except that the Director may waive or modify any requirements of Chapter 62 that are inappropriate or unduly burdensome upon consideration of the nature of the release and the degree of contamination.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5503.2.</num>
    <text>Owners or operators of heating oil tanks having a capacity of one-thousand-one-hundred (1,100) gallons or more shall comply only with the following:</text>
    <text>The provisions of Chapter 56 except the requirement of §5600.7(d);</text>
    <text>Sections 5700.6 and 5703;</text>
    <text>For new heating oil tanks installed after November 12, 1993, §§ 5700.7, 5700.9 through 5700.10, 5704 through 5706;</text>
    <text>Chapter 59; and</text>
    <text>Tanks that are fifteen (15) years old or older, shall use one of the release detection methods set forth below, as applicable:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Statistical Inventory Control (SIR) pursuant to §6005;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Tank Tightness Testing, once every three (3) years, pursuant to §6007;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Automatic Tank Gauging pursuant to §6008;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Monthly Ground-water Monitoring pursuant to §6010;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Continuous Interstitial Monitoring pursuant to §6011; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Section 6012 (Other Methods);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The provisions of Chapter 61 pertaining to closure of heating oil tanks; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Chapter 62, except that the Director may waive or modify any requirements of Chapter 62 that are inappropriate or unduly burdensome upon consideration of the nature of the release and the degree of contamination.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5503.3.</num>
    <text>Owners or operators of heating oil tanks having a capacity of one-thousand-one-hundred (1,100) gallons or more shall comply with the release detection requirements set forth in § 5503.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 DCR 7835, 7841 (November 12, 1993); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 46 DCR 7699 (October 1, 1999); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 6678 (August 21, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>