<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>9-2001</num>
  <heading>MEETINGS AND QUORUM (§ 9-2001)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2001.1.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall meet at least four (4) times annually for administrative matters.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.2.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall also meet:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>As necessary to conduct its business.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>As necessary after any special assessment that shall be generally applicable to a class of real property.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>In accordance with law to hear appeals regarding supplemental assessments made pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 47-829 (2012 Supp.).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.3.</num>
    <text>The Commission may be convened at any other time by the call of the Chairperson; provided, the Chairperson shall provide at least three (3) days’ notice to the Commissioners unless emergency circumstances necessitate a shorter notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.4.</num>
    <text>Meetings of the Commission shall be held at times agreed upon by its members or as directed by the Chairperson.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.5.</num>
    <text>The Commission shall publish notices of its meetings in the District of Columbia Register and on the Commission’s website as early as possible before the meeting is scheduled to be held.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.6.</num>
    <text>A majority of the Commission shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of all Commission business.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.7.</num>
    <text>The Chairperson shall preside over each Commission meeting; provided, the Vice Chairperson shall, in the absence of or recusal of the Chairperson, preside over the Commission meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.8.</num>
    <text>All meetings of the Commission shall be open to the public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.9.</num>
    <text>Minutes shall be kept of each Commission meeting. The minutes shall record each action taken by the Commission, the names of those present and voting, and any other matter that the Chairperson may determine to be appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2001.10.</num>
    <text>Within a reasonable time after each Commission meeting, the minutes shall be posted on the website of the Commission and shall be made available to the public at the office of the Commission during normal business hours.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 24, 26 (January 2, 1998); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 9888 (July 5, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>