<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-8901</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION FORM (ยง 17-8901)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>8901.1.</num>
    <text>Each applicant must state on the form for trade name registration:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The trade name under which the business is to be conducted.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The true and real name of each person conducting or intending to conduct the business, or who has an interest in that business:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A sole proprietorship shall state the true and real name or names of each person comprising the sole proprietorship.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A general partnership shall state the true and real name or names of each person comprising the general partnership and state the name of the general partnership.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A foreign or domestic limited partnership or foreign or domestic limited liability partnership shall state the true and real name of the partnership and the name of the general partner as filed with the Corporations Division of the Department.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A foreign or domestic limited liability company shall state the true and real name of the limited liability company and the name of the manager or member as filed with the Corporations Division of the Department.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A foreign or domestic corporation shall state the true and real name of the corporation and the name of an officer or director as filed with the Corporations Division of the Department.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The District of Columbia street address, not a post office box number</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>of the business location, or,</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If there is no fixed business location within the District of Columbia, then the District of Columbia street address of the resident agent if person owning the business is a sole proprietor, otherwise the street address of the registered agent.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The business phone number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The business activities associated with the trade name shall be listed using the business codes identified in the Office of Tax and Revenue application for Combined Business Tax Registration; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Any other information as the Director may require.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8901.2.</num>
    <text>Each person shall certify that the business entity is in compliance with payment of all fees, taxes, penalties, and fines owed to the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8901.3.</num>
    <text>If registered with the Corporations Division of the Department, each person shall certify that such entity is in good standing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>8901.4.</num>
    <text>The application along with instructions shall be available on the Internet, at the Business License Center of the Department, and other designated locations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by final rulemaking published at 49 DCR 10075 (November 8, 2002).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>