<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-5403</num>
  <heading>SERVICE DELIVERY AND QUALITY ASSURANCE REQUIREMENTS (§ 29-5403)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5403.1.</num>
    <text>Each fee-for-service primary care provider shall provide each enrollee with high quality health care at locations that ensure reasonable availability and accessibility to enrollees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5403.2.</num>
    <text>Each fee-for-service primary care provider shall provide either directly or by referral, each service in the Medicaid managed care benefits package, including patient management and referrals and approvals.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5403.3.</num>
    <text>Each fee-for-service primary care provider shall ensure that urgent and emergency medical care are available to AFDC and AFDC-related Medicaid enrollees on a twenty-four (24) hour basis, seven (7) days a week, either through the fee-for-service provider
      or through other appropriate facilities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5403.4.</num>
    <text>Each AFDC and AFDC-related Medicaid recipient shall receive the same services in the same facilities as the fee-for-service primary care provider’s non-AFDC and AFDC-related Medicaid enrollees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5403.5.</num>
    <text>Each AFDC and AFDC-related Medicaid enrollee shall be fully integrated into the fee-for-service primary care provider’s practice and shall not be treated in a manner different from non-AFDC or AFDC-related patients.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5403.6.</num>
    <text>Each fee-for-service primary care provider shall provide health education programs for its enrollees in languages understood by the population being served. The education programs shall include, at a minimum, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Information regarding the importance and availability of preventive care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Information regarding the importance and availability of childhood immunizations;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Information regarding the importance of and right to, and procedure for scheduling the Early Periodic Screening, Diagnosis and Treatment (EPSDT) screens for children covered by Medicaid;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Information on birth control and on the importance and availability of prenatal and well baby care;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Information regarding proper nutrition for pregnant women and children; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Information regarding preventive and treatment measures for drug abuse and alcoholism.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5403.7.</num>
    <text>The fee-for-service primary care provider shall have a system of follow-up of patient care for enrollees with chronic and acute illnesses, including an appointment follow-up system for persons who do not appear for appointments.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5403.8.</num>
    <text>Waiting times for appointments for AFDC and AFDC-related Medicaid enrollees shall not exceed the waiting times for non-AFDC or AFDC-related patients of the fee-for-service primary care provider.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5403.9.</num>
    <text>Each fee-for-service primary care provider shall maintain a current, unified medical record on each enrollee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 42 DCR 1566, 1590 (March 31, 1995).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>