<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-521</num>
  <heading>ADMINISTRATIVE SEGREGATION AND PROTECTIVE CUSTODY (ยง 28-521)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>521.1.</num>
    <text>Administrative segregation shall be defined as confinement to a control cell with limited recreation and privileges, as set forth in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>521.2.</num>
    <text>Administrative segregation may be used for the following purposes:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>To hold a resident prior to a housing hearing or adjustment hearing; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>To hold a resident in voluntary or involuntary protective custody.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>521.3.</num>
    <text>Administrative segregation shall also include restrictive confinement of a prisoner in any cell of the maximum security facility, or in a control cell of the central facility, or in a control cell at Youth Center II, or in the protective custody unit
      of Youth Center I, or in the adjustment unit of Youth Center I.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>521.4.</num>
    <text>Before a resident is placed in any cell of the maximum security facility, or in a control cell of the central facility, or a control center at Youth Center II, there shall be a finding made that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>There is a clear and present threat to the safety of the resident;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The resident poses a clear and present threat to the safety of others; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The resident poses a definite escape risk.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>521.5.</num>
    <text>In order to place a resident in the adjustment unit of Youth Center I, there shall be a finding that the resident poses a clear and present danger to the safety of others or is a definite escape risk.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>521.6.</num>
    <text>A resident found to be in need of placement for protective custody in Youth Center I may be housed temporarily in the adjustment unit of Youth Center I when space is unavailable in the protective custody unit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>521.7.</num>
    <text>No resident shall be held in administrative segregation for more than three (3) days without a hearing, except as specifically provided in this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>521.8.</num>
    <text>A resident shall be provided with at least two (2) hours per week out-of-cell recreation while placed in administrative segregation; provided, that recreation may be restricted because of extraordinary safety and security risks.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>521.9.</num>
    <text>The following privileges shall be afforded to residents placed in administrative segregation:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Uncensored correspondence;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Visitation of one (1) hour per day, five (5) days per week;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The right to have items purchased for them from the canteen;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Smoking privileges in the cell; provided that this right may be restricted for safety reasons;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Reading matter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Radios; provided, that this right may be restricted for extraordinary safety and security reasons;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Work assignments, if available, and if the assignments would not pose extraordinary safety or security risks;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Education and training programs with the following exceptions:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Residents held in pre-hearing administrative segregation; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any other resident where participation in education and training programs would pose an extraordinary safety or security risk.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>521.10.</num>
    <text>Involuntary protective custody shall be defined as confinement of a resident in administrative segregation against the resident&amp;#8217;s will.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>521.11.</num>
    <text>Voluntary protective custody shall be defined as the placement of a resident in administrative segregation at the request of the resident.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>521.12.</num>
    <text>If a resident in voluntary protective custody provides the Department with a written statement that the resident no longer wishes to remain in protective custody, the resident shall be released at once from protective custody; provided, that a resident
      who requests release may be placed in involuntary protective custody under the provisions of this chapter for involuntary placement in protective custody.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 865, 890-92 (February 27, 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>