<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-1201</num>
  <heading>LAY-BYS[COLON] GENERAL PROVISIONS (ยง 24-1201)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1201.1.</num>
    <text>The District Department of Transportation (DDOT) shall approve a public space permit for a lay-by only when there is no parking lane and other options to safely pick up and drop off passengers are shown to be infeasible or impractical.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.2.</num>
    <text>In addition, a lay-by shall be approved only if:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The property to be served by the lay-by is a commercial property, such as a hotel or hospital having a high demand for passenger pick-up and drop-off space at the building entrance; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An unobstructed, continuous pedestrian pathway of no less than ten feet (10 ft.) wide can be maintained on the public sidewalk adjacent to the proposed lay-by.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.3.</num>
    <text>No person shall construct a lay-by in public space:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Without first obtaining a public space permit from the Director;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>For the purpose of parking motor vehicles; provided, motor vehicles may park temporarily in an approved lay-by in order to drop off or pick up passengers; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>For the purpose of creating a commercial loading zone.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.4.</num>
    <text>A person shall apply for a public space permit for a lay-by by completing an application as provided by the Director. The following documentation shall accompany the application:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A site plan showing the proposed lay-by that is drawn to scale per the latest site plan drawing requirements provided by the Director;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A description of the existing or projected passenger pick-up and drop-off demand at the property and the specific right-of-way conditions on the street that warrant the construction of a permanent lay-by and why other options to safely pick-up and
        drop-off passengers, including private space or a curbside location in an adjacent parking lane, are infeasible or impractical; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Additional documentation as may be requested by the Director, such as a traffic impact study and photographs or illustrations showing the area intended for the proposed lay-by.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.5.</num>
    <text>When a lay-by is located adjacent to a travel lane intended for the movement of motor vehicle traffic, the lay-by shall be no more than ten feet (10 ft.) wide.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.6.</num>
    <text>When a lay-by is located adjacent to a travel lane intended for the movement of motor vehicle traffic, the combined width of the lay-by lane and the adjacent travel lane shall be no less than nineteen feet (19 ft.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.7.</num>
    <text>When a lay-by must be located adjacent to a parking lane to accommodate wider vehicles or to allow additional pedestrian maneuvering space on the traffic side of the vehicle, the lay-by shall be no more than three feet (3 ft.) wide.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.8.</num>
    <text>When there is a privately funded streetscape project following the construction of a new building or the substantial rehabilitation of an existing building, the public space permit for any existing lay-by adjacent to the property shall expire. If
      the property owner desires a new lay-by, a request for a lay-by must be included as part of the public space permit application to perform the privately funded streetscape restoration project.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.9.</num>
    <text>If a person constructs a lay-by in public space without a permit, the person, at his or her own expense, shall remove the lay-by and restore the public space in accordance with the current DDOT Standard Specifications for Highways and Structures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.10.</num>
    <text>When the Director determines that a lay-by should be removed to allow the public space to be used for another purpose which benefits the District, such as for a bus stop, the Director shall revoke the permit for a lay-by in public space and the person
      who constructed the lay-by shall remove the lay-by and restore the public space in accordance with the current DDOT Standard Specifications for Highways and Structures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.11.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding ยง 1201.10, if the lay-by is to be removed as part of a DDOT street reconstruction project, the Department may itself remove the lay-by and restore the public space instead of requiring the person who constructed the lay-by to remove
      the lay-by and restore the public space in accordance with the current DDOT Standard Specifications for Highways and Structures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1201.12.</num>
    <text>If a lay-by that existed prior to the final publication of these rules was constructed without a public space permit, the person who constructed the lay-by shall apply for a public space permit under this section by October 1, 2014. If the permit
      is not approved, the person who constructed the lay-by shall remove the lay-by and restore the public space in accordance with the current DDOT Standard Specifications for Highways and Structures.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 16852 (December 13, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>