<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>15-4006</num>
  <heading>LEVEL 3 INTERCONNECTION REVIEWS (ยง 15-4006)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4006.1.</num>
    <text>The EDC shall use Level 3 review procedures for evaluating interconnection requests to area networks and radial distribution circuits where power shall not be exported based on the criteria in this section; however, interconnection to spot networks
      is not permitted under the Level 3 review process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4006.2.</num>
    <text>For interconnection requests to the load side of an area network the following criteria shall be satisfied to qualify for a Level 3 expedited review:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The nameplate capacity of the small generator facility is less than or equal to 50 kW; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The proposed small generator facility utilizes a certified inverter-based equipment package.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4006.3.</num>
    <text>For Level 3A Adverse Impact Screens, the EDC shall evaluate the potential for adverse system impacts using the following screens which must be satisfied:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>If the small generator facility utilizes reverse power relays and/or other protection functions that prevent power flow to the area network, the proposed small generator facility cannot cause network protector cycling; cause inadvertent network
        protector opening; or impact any other customer under any conditions (including under fault conditions);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The aggregated other generation on the area network may not exceed the smaller of five (5) percent of an area network&amp;#8217;s maximum load or 50 kW; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>No construction of facilities by the EDC shall be required to accommodate the small generator facility.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4006.4.</num>
    <text>For Level 3A, the EDC shall use the additional review procedures listed in Section 4006.8 and the following review procedures:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The EDC shall evaluate the interconnection request under Level 2 interconnection review procedures as set forth in Level 3A Procedures except that the EDC may have twenty-five (25) business days to conduct an area network impact study at its own
        expense to determine any potential adverse system impacts of interconnecting to the EDC&amp;#8217;s area network.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>In the event the area network impact study identifies potential adverse system impacts, the EDC may determine at its sole discretion that it is inappropriate for the small generator facility to interconnect to the area network in which case the
        interconnection request shall be denied; however, the interconnection customer may elect to submit a new interconnection request for consideration under Level 4 procedures in which case the queue position assigned to the Level 3 interconnection
        request shall be retained provided the request is made within fifteen (15) business days of notification that the current application is denied.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>In the event the EDC denies the interconnection request, the EDC shall provide the interconnection customer with a copy of its area network impact study and written justification for denying the interconnection request.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4006.5.</num>
    <text>For interconnection requests to a radial distribution circuit, the following criteria shall be satisfied to qualify for a Level 3 review:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The small generator facility has a nameplate capacity of 10 MW or less;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The aggregated total of the nameplate capacity of all of the generators on the circuit, including the proposed small generator facility, is 10 MW or less;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The small generator shall use reverse power relays or other protection functions that prevent power flow onto the electric distribution system;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The small generator is not served by a shared transformer; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>No construction of facilities by the electric distribution company on its own system shall be required to accommodate the small generator facility.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4006.6.</num>
    <text>Level 3.B Adverse Impact Screens are the same as the Level 2 adverse impact screens.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4006.7.</num>
    <text>Level 3.B review procedures are the same as Level 2 review procedures, except that Section 4006.8 contains additional procedures for all Level 3 requests.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4006.8.</num>
    <text>The following additional procedures shall apply to all Level 3 interconnection requests:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Once the interconnection request is deemed complete by the EDC, the EDC shall assign a queue position based upon the date and time the interconnection request is determined to be complete. The queue position of each interconnection request shall
        be used to determine the potential adverse system impact of the small generator facility based on the relevant screening criteria. The interconnection customer shall proceed under the timeframes of this section. The EDC shall notify the interconnection
        customer about other higher-queued interconnection customers on the same radial line or area network to which the interconnection customer is seeking to interconnect.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The interconnection customer shall have thirty (30) business days after submission of the small generator interconnection agreement to sign and return the small generator interconnection agreement. If the interconnection customer does not sign the
        small generator interconnection agreement within thirty (30) business days, the request shall be deemed withdrawn unless the parties mutually agree in writing to extend the time period for executing the small generator interconnection agreement
        prior to the expiration of the thirty (30) business day period. After the small generator interconnection agreement is signed by the parties, interconnection of the small generator facility shall proceed according to all milestones agreed to by
        the parties in the small generator interconnection agreement.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The interconnection agreement shall not be final until:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>All milestones agreed to in the small generator interconnection agreement are satisfied;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The small generator facility is approved by electric code officials with jurisdiction over the interconnection;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The interconnection customer provides a certificate of completion to the EDC; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>There is a successful completion of the witness test per the terms and conditions found in the Standard Agreement for Interconnection of Small Generator Facilities unless waived.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>If the small generator facility is not approved under a Level 3 review, the interconnection customer may submit a new interconnection request for consideration under the Level 4 procedures without sacrificing the original queue position, provided
        the revised interconnection request is submitted within fifteen (15) business days of notice that the current request has not been approved.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>As amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 1415, 1418 (February 13, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>