<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-2936</num>
  <heading>RENTAL HOUSING CASES &amp;#8211; APPEALS BEFORE A FINAL ORDER (§ 1-2936)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2936.1</num>
    <text>2936.1 An Administrative Law Judge’s rulings in a proceeding ordinarily mayot be appealed to the Commission until a final order is issued. Before a finalrder is issued, a party may appeal an order of the Administrative Law Judgenly if the Administrative
      Law Judge certifies the ruling for appeal to theommission.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2936.2</num>
    <text>2936.2 A party may move the Administrative Law Judge to certify to theommission an appeal of any ruling other than a final order. Such an appeal isn “interlocutory appeal.”</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2936.3</num>
    <text>2936.3 The Administrative Law Judge shall certify a ruling for interlocutoryppeal only if he or she determines that the issue presented is of suchmportance to the proceeding that it requires the immediate attention of theommission, and only if the
      following are shown:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The ruling involves an important question of law or policy requiringnterpretation of the Rental Housing Act, and about which there is substantialasis for difference of opinion; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Either of the following applies:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An immediate ruling will materially advance the completion of theroceeding; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Denial of an immediate ruling will cause undue harm to the parties or theublic.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2936.4</num>
    <text>2936.4 A party seeking review by interlocutory appeal shall file a motion forertification within five (5) calendar days of service of a ruling by thedministrative Law Judge. The opposing party shall have five (5) calendar daysn which to respond. Unless
      extended by a written order, the Administrative Lawudge shall rule on the motion within ten (10) calendar days following theiling of any response.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2936.5</num>
    <text>2936.5 If the Administrative Law Judge declines to certify a ruling, theommission may review that ruling on appeal from a final order.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2936.6</num>
    <text>2936.6 The Administrative Law Judge may stay the proceeding while annterlocutory appeal is pending.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 5674, 5680 (July 14, 2006); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 9553, 9554 (December 25, 2009);s amended by Notice of Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 12541,2581 (December 31, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>