<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-2999</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 1-2999)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2999.1.</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise provided, the definitions in Chapter 28 apply to this Chapter</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2999.2</num>
    <text>2999.2 For purposes of this Chapter, the term:</text>
    <text>Commission means the Rental Housing Commission.</text>
    <text>Contested residency case means a case in which an adult student or a minor student’s parent or guardian has filed, pursuant to 5 DCMR E§ 2009.3, a request for review of a decision by DCPS that a student is not entitled to tuition-free education because
      the student is not a resident of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text>DCPS means District of Columbia Public Schools.</text>
    <text>Disciplinary file means any and all tangible evidence, in DCPS’s possession, which forms the basis for the school’s decision to propose the specific disciplinary action, including, but not limited to, student, staff and other witness statements, incident
      reports, photographs, police reports, and security camera footage. Nothing in these rules prohibits DCPS from redacting any information it deems confidential or protected.</text>
    <text>RAD means the Rental Accommodations Division of the Department of Housing and Community Development.</text>
    <text>Rent Administrator means the Rent Administrator of the RAD.</text>
    <text>Rental Housing Act means the Rental Housing Act of 1985, D.C. Law 6-10, effective July 17, 1985, D.C. Official Code §§ 42-3501.01, et seq.</text>
    <text>Rental housing cases means cases initiated pursuant to the Rental Housing Act, but does not include petitions for declaratory orders pursuant to the Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980.</text>
    <text>School day means a day that school is open, whether or not students are attending, but does not include any day that OAH is closed.</text>
    <text>Service Provider means a person or entity that furnishes assistance to members of the public through a contract with or grant from the Government.</text>
    <text>Student discipline case means a case in which DCPS seeks to expel a student or to suspend a student for at least eleven (11) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 6433, 6444 (June 25, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 5674, 5682 (July 14, 2006); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 12541, 12593 (December 31, 2010); as amended
        by Notice of Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 58 DCR 11122 (December 23, 2011)[EXPIRED]; as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 3128, 3131 (April 20, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>