<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-2934</num>
  <heading>RENTAL HOUSING CASES &amp;#8211; SUBPOENAS (§ 1-2934)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2934.1.</num>
    <text>In rental housing cases, the Clerk shall issue no more than three (3) subpoenas to the tenant side and no more than three (3) subpoenas to the housing provider side under Subsection 2824.5 to compel:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The appearance at a hearing of any witnesses, including housing inspectors, with knowledge of conditions, repairs, or maintenance in a party’s rental unit or any common areas for the three (3) year period immediately before the filing of the petition
        with the Rent Administrator;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The production at or before a hearing of all records not created by a government agency, relating to conditions, repairs, or maintenance to a party’s rental unit or any common areas for the three (3) year period immediately before the filing of
        the petition with the Rent Administrator;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The production at or before a hearing of housing violation notices in the possession of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs relating to a party’s rental unit or any common areas for the three (3) year period immediately before the
        filing of the petition with the Rent Administrator.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The production at or before a hearing of all records in a housing provider’s possession relating to any rent increases demanded or implemented for a party’s rental unit for the three (3) year period immediately before the filing of the petition
        with the Rent Administrator.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2934.2.</num>
    <text>Section 2824 applies to all other subpoenas for witnesses and documents at hearings in rental housing cases. Section 2825 applies to discovery.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 5674, 5679 (July 14, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5242 (July 3, 2009); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 12541, 12580 (December 31, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>