<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>1-2972</num>
  <heading>PUBLIC BENEFITS CASES &amp;#8211; REPRESENTATIVES (ยง 1-2972)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2972.1.</num>
    <text>An applicant for, or recipient of, public benefits may be represented by an attorney, a relative, a friend, or any other representative who is not employed by the District of Columbia government.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2972.2</num>
    <text>2972.2 Any person who is not a lawyer who requests a hearing on behalf of someone else must file a statement, signed by the person, authorizing that non-lawyer to be a representative. A hearing request is subject to dismissal unless that statement
      is filed. Before dismissing a case under this Subsection, an Administrative Law Judge shall notify the representative of this requirement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2972.3.</num>
    <text>As required by the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act, D.C. Official Code ยง 4-210.10, if the person who requested the hearing is not represented by a lawyer, a Government agency or service provider may not be represented by a lawyer at any
      hearing involving the following public benefit programs:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Medicaid, Healthcare Alliance or other healthcare programs administered by the District of Columbia;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>SNAP (formerly Food Stamps);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Interim Disability Assistance;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>General Assistance for Children; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Program on Work Employment and Responsibility (POWER).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2972.4.</num>
    <text>A Government agency or service provider may be represented by a lawyer at a hearing involving any other public benefit program regardless of whether the person who requested a hearing is represented by a lawyer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2972.5.</num>
    <text>The practice of lawyers or other party representatives is governed by Sections 2833 and 2835.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 2009, 2012 (March 17, 2006); as amended by Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 12541, 12586 (December 31, 2010).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>