<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-502</num>
  <heading>APPLICATION FOR DEALER REGISTRATION (§ 18-502)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>502.1.</num>
    <text>Application for registration as a new or used car dealer or dealer in motor vehicle equipment or services shall be made upon a form to be furnished by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>502.2.</num>
    <text>The application form shall contain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name of the applicant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The trade name, if any, of under which the applicant operates or will operate;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The location of the applicant’s principal place of business and of all other places used by the applicant in the conduct of that business;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A statement showing whether the applicant is an individual, partnership, or corporation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>A copy of the dealer’s business license; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>A copy of the salesperson’s license for each salesperson.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>502.3.</num>
    <text>If the applicant is a partnership, the application shall contain the names and addresses of the partners. If the application is for a corporation, then it shall contain the place of incorporation and the names and addresses of the corporate officers
      and directors.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>502.4.</num>
    <text>Each application for registration as a new car dealer shall also contain the trade names of the vehicles for which the applicant is the holder of a valid sales franchise.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>502.5.</num>
    <text>If any change in any of the information set forth in the application occurs prior to the execution of a new application, a written statement setting forth the change shall be sent to the Director within five (5) business days after the change occurs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>502.6.</num>
    <text>The Director, when satisfied that the person named in the application is entitled to be registered as a new or used car dealer or a dealer in motor vehicle equipment or services, shall register the dealer and maintain records of compliance with this
      chapter applicable to the dealer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>502.7.</num>
    <text>Dealer registrations shall expire on October 31 of each year.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>502.8.</num>
    <text>If, upon expiration, renewal is desired, an application for renewal must be executed and delivered to the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>502.9.</num>
    <text>The yearly dealer registration application fee shall be one hundred dollars ($ 100), which may be increased by the Mayor to cover administrative costs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 11340 (December 10, 2004); as amended by D.C. Act 16-636 published at 54 DCR 921 (February 2, 2007); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 9084 (August 22, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>