<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-501</num>
  <heading>REGISTRATION OF DEALERS (§ 18-501)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>501.1.</num>
    <text>A manufacturer or a branch officer of a manufacturer engaged in selling new vehicles only may apply to the Director to be registered as a new car dealer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.2.</num>
    <text>A person having an established place of business located within the District who is the holder of a franchise for the sale of new vehicles and who has a motor vehicle dealer&amp;#8217;s license may apply to the Director to be registered as a new car
      dealer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.3.</num>
    <text>A person may apply to the Director for registration as a car dealer provided, in addition to all other applicable requirements of this Title, that person:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Has a valid motor vehicle dealer’s business license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Has a valid federal tax identification number;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Has a valid certificate of occupancy in the dealer’s name;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Is actively engaged in buying, selling, and exchanging vehicles; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Has an established place of business that is located on a street or avenue.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.4.</num>
    <text>The requirement that any used car dealer have an established place of business located on a street or avenue shall not be applicable to any dealer who, on November 1, 1968, was conducting business in a place of business for which a valid certificate
      of occupancy to conduct the business had been issued.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.5.</num>
    <text>When trailers, fire-fighting equipment, construction equipment, ambulances, or funeral vehicles, including motor vehicles adapted thereof, are the only vehicles offered for sale or resale, such manufacturer, branch officer of such manufacturer, or
      person need not hold a valid motor vehicle dealer&amp;#8217;s license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>501.6.</num>
    <text>A person located in the District of Columbia dealing in motor vehicle equipment or services, including but not limited to auto paint shops, auto upholstery shops, motor or transmission rebuilders, auto body builders, and auto finance companies, may
      apply to the Director to be registered as a dealer in motor vehicle equipment or services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 11340 (December 10, 2004); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 9084 (August 22, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>