<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-9704</num>
  <heading>REMOVAL OF VEHICLES FROM DCHA PROPERTY (ยง 14-9704)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>9704.1.</num>
    <text>If DCHA determines that a vehicle is a Nuisance Vehicle located on DCHA Property, DCHA may immediately remove the vehicle from DCHA Property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9704.2.</num>
    <text>If DCHA determines a vehicle is an Abandoned or Junk Vehicle located on DCHA Property for more than 72 hours, a Notice of Infraction may be issued and a Warning Notice to Remove the Vehicle affixed to the vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9704.3.</num>
    <text>The Notice of Infraction may be issued and Warning Notice may be affixed by DCHA&amp;#8217;s Office of Public Safety, Metropolitan Police Department or other authorized appropriate District of Columbia officials.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9704.4.</num>
    <text>The owner of the Abandoned or Junk Vehicle will have seventy-two (72) hours to remove the vehicle from DCHA Property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>9704.5.</num>
    <text>Prior to proceeding under ยง 9705, DCHA will attempt to identify and contact the owner of the vehicle via telephone. In the event DCHA is able to contact the vehicle owner, DCHA will advise the owner of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The owner&amp;#8217;s vehicle is parked on DCHA Property and inquire as to the owner&amp;#8217;s intention concerning the removal of the vehicle;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The owner&amp;#8217;s timely removal of the vehicle is necessary to avoid the vehicle being towed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The vehicle was issued a Notice of Infraction for being parked on DCHA&amp;#8217;s Property; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The process for recovering the vehicle if towed from DCHA Property.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 51 DCR 2112, 21 13-21 14 (February 27, 2004).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>