<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-301</num>
  <heading>BYLAWS OF THE UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION BOARD (ยง 7-301)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>301.1.</num>
    <text>The Chair shall be the chief executive officer of the Board and shall supervise its affairs, preside at its meetings and exercise such other powers and duties as may from time to time be assigned by the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.2.</num>
    <text>In the absence of the Chair, his or her designee shall function as the Chair and also perform such other duties as shall be prescribed by the Chair or the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.3.</num>
    <text>The Chair of the Board may when he or she deems it appropriate, and shall, upon the written request of any two (2) or more members, call a special meeting of the Board for the purposes of transacting any business designated in the call.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.4.</num>
    <text>The call for a special meeting may be hand delivered to each member at least two (2) days in advance of the meeting or may be mailed to the business or home address of each member at least five (5) days in advance of the meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.5.</num>
    <text>At any special meeting, no business shall be considered other than that specified in the call.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.6.</num>
    <text>For the purpose of transacting business and conducting the affairs of the Board, a majority of the members shall constitute a quorum; Provided, that one (1) employee representative and one (1) employer representative is present at the meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.7.</num>
    <text>All meetings except Executive sessions of the Board shall be open to the public. All actions or decisions of the Board shall be formally taken at a public meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.8.</num>
    <text>Non-members shall be seated as spectators as far as the limitations of space and safety permit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.9.</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, at least ten (10) days advance notice shall be given for all meetings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.10.</num>
    <text>Non-members of the Board, at the discretion of the Chair, shall be permitted to present propositions to the Board for consideration. Non-members shall not have the right to vote.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.11.</num>
    <text>The voting on all matters by the Board shall be by voice vote or by a show of hands, and the number of yeas and nays shall be entered in the minutes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.12.</num>
    <text>Any member may request a roll call vote at which time the vote cast by each member shall be recorded and entered into the minutes.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.13.</num>
    <text>At the regular meetings of the Board, the following shall be the order of business:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Roll Call;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Reading and Approval of Minutes of Previous Meetings;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Communications;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Report of Chair;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Report of Staff;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Unfinished Business;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>New Business; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Adjournment.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.14.</num>
    <text>Each member of the Board and staff shall sit in a designated place so that they are clearly distinguished from others attending meetings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.15.</num>
    <text>The Chair will normally invite public participants to make brief comments or ask questions during and before adjournment of each meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.16.</num>
    <text>In all proceedings of the Board, Robert&amp;#8217;s Rules of Order, Newly Revised, shall apply in all matters not expressly covered by this section or by contrary rule duly adopted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.17.</num>
    <text>This section, constituting the bylaws of the Board, shall be amended only by a vote of at least two-thirds (2/3) of its members at a regular meeting or a special meeting of which at least seven (7) days written notice has been given to all of the
      members.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>301.18.</num>
    <text>Any individual who wishes to present proposed additions, amendments, or repealers to the Board for consideration may do so by submitting a written copy of the proposal to the Chair. The proposals shall be submitted by the Chair to the Board at its
      next regular meeting or at an earlier time if deemed appropriate by the Chair.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>