<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-300</num>
  <heading>UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION BOARD (§ 7-300)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>300.1.</num>
    <text>The provisions of this chapter are promulgated to implement the District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act, as amended, 49 Stat. 946 (1935); §46-301 et seq., D.C. Code, 1981 ed. (hereinafter referred to as &amp;#8220;the Act&amp;#8221;).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>300.2.</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Board (hereinafter referred to as &amp;#8220;the Board&amp;#8221;) is authorized by §13(b) of the Act to prescribe all reasonable rules which may be necessary to implement the Act, subject to review
      by the Council of the District of Columbia for thirty (30) calendar days from the date of transmittal by the Chairman of the Board to the Chairman of the Council.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>300.3.</num>
    <text>In accordance with §15(a) of the Act, the Board is composed of the Mayor or his or her designee as member ex-officio, two (2) representatives of employers and two (2) representatives of employees.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>300.4.</num>
    <text>The Chairman of the Board shall vote only to break a tie.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>300.5.</num>
    <text>Regular meetings of the Board shall be open to the public and are scheduled for the first Thursday of each quarter at 9:00. a.m. at 500 C Street, N.W.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>300.6.</num>
    <text>When the necessity for special or emergency meetings arises, adequate and timely notice shall be provided to the public.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>300.7.</num>
    <text>In accordance with §13(a) of the Act, Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1978 and Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1980, the Director is authorized and directed to administer the provisions of the Act pursuant to rules adopted by the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>