<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-305</num>
  <heading>DETERMINATION OF CLAIMS (ยง 7-305)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>305.1.</num>
    <text>In accordance with ยง11(b) of the Act, the Director shall make an initial determination of eligibility promptly.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.2.</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, &amp;#8220;predetermination fact-finding interview&amp;#8221; is an informal hearing at which evidence is received. This evidence shall be used to determine whether an otherwise eligible claimant is subject to disqualification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.3.</num>
    <text>The Director shall notify the claimant and his or her most recent employer of the time and place of the predetermination fact-finding interview.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.4.</num>
    <text>The claimant&amp;#8217;s most recent employer shall be responsible for presenting data at the predetermination fact-finding interview to make clear his or her objections to the claim. The employer&amp;#8217;s minimum obligation shall be to inform
      the Director and the claimant of any and all disqualifying factors.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.5.</num>
    <text>The Director&amp;#8217;s initial determination of eligibility shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Whether or not benefits may be payable;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The week when payments will commence if claimant is otherwise eligible;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The maximum duration of the individual&amp;#8217;s eligibility for benefits; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The weekly benefit amount.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>305.6.</num>
    <text>When the Director has made a determination of an individual&amp;#8217;s right to benefits, he or she shall promptly notify the claimant and interested parties of the determination and the reasons for the determination.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>