<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-316</num>
  <heading>REGISTRATION FOR WORK (ยง 7-316)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>316.1.</num>
    <text>In accordance with ยง9(d) of the Act, the frequency and manner requirements for claimants to register and inquire for work at a public employment office in the District of Columbia are set forth in this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>316.2.</num>
    <text>Each claimant shall register and inquire for work as specifically instructed by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>316.3.</num>
    <text>Upon a finding that good cause exists, the Director may permit a claimant to register and inquire for work at any other public employment office or may excuse failure to comply with the registration requirements.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>316.4.</num>
    <text>Justifiable reasons which the Director may consider as constituting good cause for failure of a claimant to register and inquire for work as instructed include, but are not limited to the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Acts of God which prevented the claimant from safely reaching a public employment office;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Working;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Seeking work where there is a reasonable indication that work is available;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Reasonably relying on a promise of work which did not materialize;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Failure by the Director to provide services when scheduled, including closing of Department of Employment Services office.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Personal physical incapacity;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The physical incapacity or death of a relative or ward of either the claimant or claimant&amp;#8217;s spouse;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The death of any person living in claimant&amp;#8217;s household;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Attendance at a funeral; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Jury duty.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>316.5.</num>
    <text>A claimant who fails to register and inquire for work as instructed by the Director may be held ineligible for each week in which the registration requirement is not met.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>