<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>7-322</num>
  <heading>CONTRIBUTION RATE REVIEW (ยง 7-322)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>322.1.</num>
    <text>In accordance with ยง3(c) (10) of the Act, the Director shall appoint a Contribution Rate Review Committee to hear and decide appeals by employers from contribution rate determinations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>322.2.</num>
    <text>Requests for review and redetermination of contribution rate determinations shall be filed within thirty (30) days after the mailing of notice of rate determinations to an employer&amp;#8217;s last known address or within thirty (30) days after delivery
      of the notice in the absence of mailing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>322.3.</num>
    <text>The Director may voluntarily adjust the contribution rate determination upon receipt of a request for review.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>322.4.</num>
    <text>If it is not apparent from the employer&amp;#8217;s account that an adjustment is appropriate, the Director shall grant an opportunity for hearing before the Contribution Rate Review Committee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>322.5.</num>
    <text>The Contribution Rate Review Committee shall consist of three (3) employees of the Director. The composition of the Committee shall be as follows:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>One (1) member shall have knowledge of the employer accounting process;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>One (1) member shall have knowledge of the overall financial accounting system; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>One (1) member shall have knowledge of the legal aspects of the employer contribution process.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>322.6.</num>
    <text>The decision of the Contribution Rate Committee shall be in writing and shall be supported by substantial evidence in the record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>322.7.</num>
    <text>The decision of the Contribution Rate Committee shall be the final agency action, shall be written, and shall be supported by substantial evidence in the record.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>322.8.</num>
    <text>Judicial review of the decision of the Contribution Rate Review Committee may be sought by filing an application for review with the District of Columbia Court of Appeals within fifteen (15) days after the mailing or receipt of notice of the decision.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>