<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-1502</num>
  <heading>RAFFLE TICKET REQUIREMENTS (ยง 30-1502)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1502.1.</num>
    <text>Tickets printed for raffles shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Name of the licensed organization listed on the license;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Date, time, place, and exact address of the drawing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Prizes to be awarded;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Aggregate value of the prizes;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Cost of the raffle ticket;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Purpose for which net proceeds will be used;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Statement that the winner need not be present at the drawing to win;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Appropriate odds of winning, assuming all raffle tickets printed are sold; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The phrase &amp;#8220;Licensed by the D.C. Lottery and Charitable Games Control Board.&amp;#8221;</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.2.</num>
    <text>Tickets shall have pre-printed consecutive numbers and a stub held by the licensed organization listing the name, address, and phone number of the person purchasing each ticket. This stub shall be used in the raffle draw.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.3.</num>
    <text>The price to the public of all tickets for any one raffle draw shall be in one fixed amount.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.4.</num>
    <text>Only United States currency or coin shall be accepted by a licensed organization as payment for any raffle ticket.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.5.</num>
    <text>Prior to the license being issued, but subsequent to Board approval of the application, the applicant shall provide a statement from the printer on a form provided by the Board stating the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The total number of tickets to be printed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The first numbered ticket to be printed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The last numbered ticket to be printed; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>That the tickets were numbered consecutively and that there were no duplications.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1502.6.</num>
    <text>Prior to the license being issued, but subsequent to Board approval of the application, the applicant shall provide to the Board the printer&amp;#8217;s proof of the tickets.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3788, 3811 (May 20, 1988).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL NOTE</heading>
      <text>Prior to May 20, 1988, the D.C. Lottery and Charitable Games Control Board published Final Rulemaking at 29 DCR 5016, 5036 (November 12, 1982).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>