<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-109</num>
  <heading>CONDUCT OF MEETINGS (ยง 30-109)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>109.1.</num>
    <text>All meetings of the Board shall be held at the Office of the Board unless specifically changed by majority vote of the Board. Notwithstanding any other provisions of this subsection, all meetings shall be held within the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>109.2.</num>
    <text>Board meetings shall be held in open session unless closed to the public for executive session.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>109.3.</num>
    <text>The applicable provisions of Robert&amp;#8217;s Rule of Order, Revised, shall govern the conduct of meetings of the Board, except as provided by this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>109.4.</num>
    <text>The order of items on the agenda of a meeting may be changed by consent of a majority of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>109.5.</num>
    <text>Board members shall not vote by proxy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>109.6.</num>
    <text>If there is a vacancy on the Board and one (1) Board member is absent for a meeting but is accessible by telephone, the absent Board member may vote by telephone if the vote is solely for the purpose of licensing and the Board complies with the requirements
      of ยง 109.7.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>109.7.</num>
    <text>When the Board polls an absent member pursuant to ยง109.6, it shall use equipment which will allow all members and other persons who are present at the meeting to hear what is said to or by the absent member.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>109.8.</num>
    <text>If the Board is unable to complete a meeting, the Board may recess the meeting for a time not to exceed five (5) business days and the Chairperson must state time, place and date for the reconvened meeting before recess.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>109.9.</num>
    <text>The Board may recess a meeting by majority vote.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>109.10.</num>
    <text>It shall not be necessary to give notice of the reconvened meeting or of the business to be transacted other than by an announcement at the meeting at which the recess is taken.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>109.11.</num>
    <text>A person who attends a meeting of the Board may file a statement with the Board before or after a meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>109.12.</num>
    <text>At the conclusion of the meeting, and after recognition by the Chairperson, a person who attends a meeting of the Board may make a statement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>109.13.</num>
    <text>No person from the public may create distractions or interfere with the conduct and disposition of the Board&amp;#8217;s meeting. At the discretion of the Chairperson, a person violating the provisions of this subsection may be removed from the meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 3704, 3710 (June 20, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>