<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-105</num>
  <heading>COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE MEETINGS (ยง 30-105)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>105.1.</num>
    <text>The Committee of the Whole shall be composed of all members of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.2.</num>
    <text>Committee of the Whole Meetings shall be held monthly.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.3.</num>
    <text>The Committee of the Whole meeting shall be held two (2) weeks before the regular Board meeting at 6:30 p.m.; Provided, that the time and date of the Committee of the Whole meeting may be changed by the Chairperson after concurrence by a majority
      of the Board members.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.4.</num>
    <text>Public notice shall be posted for each Committee of the Whole meeting in a public access area at the office of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.5.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director shall inform the press and the media of all Committee of the Whole meetings as soon as possible after the Board has determined that a meeting will be held.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.6.</num>
    <text>Prior to any Committee of the Whole meeting, the Executive Director shall prepare an agenda for the meeting after consulting with the Chairperson.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.7.</num>
    <text>The agenda of the Committee of the Whole meeting shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A report by the Chairperson;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A report of the Executive Director, which may include, but shall not be limited to, items for the information of the Board and items requiring the Committee of the Whole&amp;#8217;s recommendations to be made to the Board for Board vote, especially
        licensing, as required by D.C. Official Code ยง3-1302;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Comments by any Board member; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Comments from the public.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.8.</num>
    <text>Three (3) Board members shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.9.</num>
    <text>The affirmative vote of three (3) Board members shall constitute the final action of the Committee of the Whole.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>105.10.</num>
    <text>The Committee of the Whole may meet and consider matters in the absence of a quorum, but no action shall be taken in the absence of a quorum.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 3704, 3707 (June 20, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>