<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>30-107</num>
  <heading>SPECIAL MEETINGS (§ 30-107)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>107.1.</num>
    <text>Special meetings of the Board may be called to conduct official business of the Board between regular Board meetings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.2.</num>
    <text>The Chairperson of the Board may call a special meeting of the Board by informing the other Board members of the purpose of the special meeting not less than forty-eight (48) hours before the meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.3.</num>
    <text>Any three (3) members of the Board may call a special meeting of the Board by informing the Chairperson and the Executive Director of the purpose of the special meeting time and place not less than forty-eight (48) hours before the meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.4.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of the notice for a special meeting, the Executive Director shall inform the members of the Board of the time, place and purposes of the special meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.5.</num>
    <text>Notice to the public of special meetings of the Board shall be posted in a public access area at the Office of the Board.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.6.</num>
    <text>The Executive Director shall inform the press and the media of all special meetings as soon as possible after the Board has determined that a meeting will be held.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.7.</num>
    <text>The agenda of the special meeting shall include only those items set forth in the notice of the meeting.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.8.</num>
    <text>The Board shall take action only on the items set forth in the agenda.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>107.9.</num>
    <text>The quorum and voting requirements set forth in §§104.8, 104.9, and 104.10 shall apply to special meetings.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 3704, 3709 (June 20, 1986).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>