<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-315</num>
  <heading>PROVISIONAL AND RESTRICTED LICENSES (ยง 29-315)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>315.1.</num>
    <text>As an alternative to denial, suspension or revocation of a license, when a Facility has one or more deficiencies that jeopardize the health, safety or welfare of children, staff or the general public, the Director may:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Issue a provisional license if the Facility is taking appropriate ameliorative action in accordance with a timetable established by the Director; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Issue a restricted license that prohibits the Facility from accepting new children or from delivering certain specified services that it would otherwise be authorized to deliver.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>315.2.</num>
    <text>A provisional license may be issued to a new Facility in order to afford the Director sufficient time and evidence to evaluate whether a new Facility is capable of complying with the provisions of the Act, this Chapter, or any other applicable federal
      or District of Columbia law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>315.3.</num>
    <text>A provisional license may be granted for a period not to exceed ninety (90) days, and may be renewed no more than once.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>315.4.</num>
    <text>The issuance of provisional and restricted licenses may be:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Summary actions implemented in accordance with procedures set out in section 314 of this Chapter; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Non-summary enforcement actions implemented in accordance with procedures set out in sections 317 and 318 of this Chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 003793 (April 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>