<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-364</num>
  <heading>PETS AND ANIMALS (ยง 29-364)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>364.1.</num>
    <text>In the event that a Child Development Facility permits animals on the premises, it shall comply with the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Facility shall adhere to all local ordinances governing the keeping and maintenance of animals;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Facility shall advise the parent(s) or guardian(s) of the enrolled children of the presence of animals;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Facility shall ensure that all pets or animals permitted on the premises are in good health, show no evidence of carrying disease, are friendly toward children, and do not present a threat to the health, safety and well-being of children;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Facility shall maintain all animals or pets in a visibly clean manner;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The Facility shall isolate any pet or animal showing evidence of disease, e.g., diarrhea, skin infection, severe loss of appetite, weight loss, lethargy or any unusual behavior or symptoms. The Facility shall ensure that any animal suspected of
        being ill is promptly examined by a licensed veterinarian;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The Facility shall maintain, on the Facility premises, proof of current compliance with all applicable vaccination requirements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The Facility shall prohibit the presence of any animal or pet whose species is a common carrier of rabies, without specific proof that the animal has been vaccinated against that disease;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>All pet reptiles shall be kept inaccessible to children;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The Facility shall ensure that no animal, animal litter box, animal pen or cage is permitted in any area where food is stored, prepared or served; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>In the event that an animal bites a child and the child&amp;#8217;s skin is broken, the Facility shall immediately notify the child&amp;#8217;s parent(s) or guardian(s) and the Department of Health, and shall report it as an unusual incident pursuant
        to section 322 of this Chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 003793 (April 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>