<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-329</num>
  <heading>POLICIES AND PROCEDURES ON DISCIPLINE (ยง 29-329)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>329.1.</num>
    <text>The Facility shall have a written policy describing the philosophy of discipline and the specific methods of discipline that the Facility uses. Discipline shall be constructive and developmentally appropriate, and shall include child guidance and
      management techniques using redirection, separation from the problem situation, talking with the child about the situation, and praise for appropriate behavior.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>329.2.</num>
    <text>The methods of discipline described in the policies and procedures shall be utilized by all Facility staff, including employees and volunteers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>329.3.</num>
    <text>The following methods of discipline shall not be employed:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Physical harm, including punching, pinching, shaking, spanking, biting, yanking and poking;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Fear and/or humiliation;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Derogatory remarks and/or profane language;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Confinement in a locked room or enclosed area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Forced feeding, or withholding of food, rest, toilet use or outdoor activities or play; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Physical and/or chemical restraints.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>329.4.</num>
    <text>Separation, when used as discipline, shall be brief in duration and shall be appropriate to the child&amp;#8217;s age and developmental level and to the circumstances necessitating the discipline. Any child separated shall be placed in a safe, lighted,
      well-ventilated room, within the sight and hearing of an adult at all times.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>329.5.</num>
    <text>Authority to discipline shall never be delegated to another child.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>329.6.</num>
    <text>The parent or guardian of each child enrolled in the Facility shall receive a copy of the Facility&amp;#8217;s discipline policy.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 003793 (April 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>