<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-368</num>
  <heading>SWIMMING AND WATER SAFETY (ยง 29-368)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>368.1.</num>
    <text>Before an enrolled child may be permitted to swim or otherwise participate in any activity taking place in water two (2) or more feet in depth, the Child Development Facility shall obtain written permission from the child&amp;#8217;s parent(s) or
      guardian(s). The written permission shall be signed and dated, and shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The child&amp;#8217;s name;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A statement indicating whether the child is a swimmer or a non-swimmer; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A statement indicating that the parent(s) or guardian(s) grants permission for the child to participate in water activities.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>368.2.</num>
    <text>If a Facility premises contains a swimming pool or other body of water two (2) or more feet in depth, the Facility shall enclose the pool or body of water behind a secure fence of at least four (4) feet in height, and shall ensure that the area containing
      the pool or body of water is inaccessible to children at all times unless qualified adults are present and supervising the children.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>368.3.</num>
    <text>If a Facility chooses to utilize one or more wading pools, the Facility shall ensure that such pools are filtered, emptied, and drained daily, and that such pools are stored in a location that is inaccessible to the enrolled children.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>368.4.</num>
    <text>If a Facility chooses to engage in a field trip to a swimming site, such as a public or private swimming pool, lake, or river, Facility staff shall accompany and supervise the children at all times, even when a lifeguard is present.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>368.5.</num>
    <text>The Facility shall ensure that any swimming site utilized by the Facility that is at a location other than within the Facility premises is approved and supervised by the appropriate local authorities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>368.6.</num>
    <text>At least one adult certified in Emergency Water Safety and First Aid and CPR for children shall be in attendance at all times when children are swimming.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>368.7.</num>
    <text>The Facility shall ensure that all activities of children taking place in water two (2) or more feet in depth are supervised by at least one adult currently certified as a lifeguard or water safety instructor by the American Red Cross or by an equivalent
      water safety instruction and testing program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>368.8.</num>
    <text>In addition to the requirements contained in this section, the Facility shall comply with the adult/child ratios and requirements for supervision of children contained in section 343 of this Chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 003793 (April 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>