<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-354</num>
  <heading>CHILD DEVELOPMENT HOME GENERAL DAILY PROGRAM ACTIVITIES (ยง 29-354)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>354.1.</num>
    <text>Each Child Development Home Caregiver shall establish a planned program of activities for the Facility, based on the stage of development of each enrolled child. The Facility must ensure that its daily program shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Motivate and stimulate each child&amp;#8217;s cognitive, physical, social, emotional and creative development;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Contain sufficient continuity and flexibility to meet the needs of each individual child as well as the needs of the group;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Provide a balance of active and quiet learning through play;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Provide both structured and unstructured times, and both Caregiver-directed and child-initiated experiences;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Provide periods of rest, appropriate to the age and developmental needs of each child, including specific designated times for rest each day; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Provide a balance of indoor and outdoor activities, including a minimum of two (2) hours of outdoor play or outdoor activity each day for each infant, toddler, and preschool-age child in a full-day program.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>354.2.</num>
    <text>If a Child Development Home provides out-of-school-time care to school-age children, the Facility shall develop a program of supervised activities that is designed for school-age children, and that includes, for each child:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Free choice of play;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Opportunities to run, jump and climb;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Opportunities for concentration, alone or in a group;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Time to read or to do homework;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Opportunities for creative activities; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Opportunities for developing supportive relationships with the Caregiver and with peers.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 003793 (April 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>