<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-366</num>
  <heading>ROOFTOP PLAY SPACE (ยง 29-366)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>366.1.</num>
    <text>If a Child Development Facility chooses to utilize a rooftop play space, the Facility shall enclose the rooftop play space with a sturdy fence at least six (6) feet high and designed to discourage climbing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>366.2.</num>
    <text>The Facility shall provide a fire escape, which leads from the rooftop play space to an open space at the ground level of the Facility premises, and for which the Facility has received written approval from the Department of Consumer and Regulatory
      Affairs or the Department of Fire and Emergency Medical Services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>366.3.</num>
    <text>Before a Facility may utilize a rooftop play space, the Facility shall obtain written certification from a licensed structural engineer that the additional load presented by the children, staff, and play equipment on the roof is within the load capacity
      of the building structure.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>366.4.</num>
    <text>Before a Facility may utilize a rooftop play space, the Facility shall obtain written certification from a licensed industrial or civil engineer of the safety of the fence, and shall submit this certification to the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>366.5.</num>
    <text>Each Facility utilizing a rooftop play space shall, at least annually: (1) obtain an annual inspection of the fence around the play space by a licensed industrial or civil engineer; (2) obtain a written certification from the inspecting engineer of
      the safety of the fence; and (3) submit this certification to the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>366.6.</num>
    <text>Each Facility utilizing a rooftop play space shall undergo and pass an annual safety inspection of the space by the Department of Fire and Emergency Medical Services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>366.7.</num>
    <text>Each Facility utilizing a rooftop play space shall post a copy of each current certification and/or safety report next to the Facility&amp;#8217;s license, in a conspicuous location on the Facility premises.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 003793 (April 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>