<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-333</num>
  <heading>DUTIES AND RESPONSIBILITIES OF CENTER DIRECTORS (ยง 29-333)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>333.1.</num>
    <text>The Center Director shall be physically present in the Facility at least one-half (1/2) of the time during the Center&amp;#8217;s hours of operation. No less than one-half (1/2) of that time shall be during peak hours of operation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>333.2.</num>
    <text>The Center Director shall be responsible for the supervision, program planning and administration of the Child Development Center and its staff, consistent with the written operational policies and philosophy, and shall assume the following responsibilities:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Ensuring compliance with the requirements of this Chapter, and with all applicable federal and District of Columbia laws;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Selecting and supervising qualified staff;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Providing orientation and training to each staff member as required;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Designating a teacher or group leader to assume responsibility for the Facility&amp;#8217;s operation in the absence of the Center Director;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Ensuring that adult/child ratios are maintained in compliance with section 343 of this Chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Ensuring parent involvement in the program and in the activities of the Center;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Reporting unusual incidents as defined in section 399 and in accordance with section 322 of this Chapter;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>Ensuring that at least one (1) staff member with a current CPR and First Aid certification for children is present on the Facility premises at all times;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Attending in-service training programs and completing continuing education requirements as specified; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>Reporting evidence of child abuse and neglect that comes to the Facility staff&amp;#8217;s attention, in accordance with section 322 of this Chapter.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 003793(April 27, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>