<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-312</num>
  <heading>COMPLAINT INVESTIGATIONS (ยง 29-312)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>312.1.</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of a complaint alleging violation(s) of the provisions of the Act or this Chapter, the Director may conduct an on-site investigation, announced or unannounced, to determine the validity of the complaint.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>312.2.</num>
    <text>The Director shall investigate an allegation of activity that is life-threatening or imminently dangerous within (24) twenty-four hours of receipt of the complaint.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>312.3.</num>
    <text>The Director shall investigate complaints that do not allege life-threatening or imminently dangerous activity no later than thirty (30) days after receipt of the complaint.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>312.4.</num>
    <text>Upon completion of a complaint investigation, the Director shall provide a written statement to the Facility no later than ten (10) business days after the conclusion of the investigation. The statement shall include the specific provision(s) of law
      or regulation alleged in the complaint to have been violated, as well as whether the Facility was found to be in compliance. If the Facility is found not to be in compliance with one or more provisions, the Director shall provide the Facility with
      a written statement of deficiencies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>312.5.</num>
    <text>If a Facility is provided with a statement of deficiencies as a result of a complaint investigation, the Director shall include in the statement of deficiencies a recommended plan of correction, including the designation of a time within which each
      cited deficiency must be corrected.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>312.6.</num>
    <text>If a Facility is provided with a statement of deficiencies as a result of a complaint investigation, the Director may conduct one or more additional on-site inspections, as needed, to verify compliance With respect to each cited deficiency, the on-site
      inspection shall take place after the completion of the recommended compliance period contained in the statement of deficiencies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 003793(April 27, 2007)</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>