<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-1605</num>
  <heading>STANDARD VALET PARKING OPERATIONS (ยง 24-1605)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1605.1.</num>
    <text>The Permittee shall prominently display the Standard Valet Parking permit at all approved times when Valet Parking services are offered by the Permittee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1605.2.</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding 24 DCMR ยง 108, the Permittee may utilize either a valet stand or a freestanding valet sign, but in no case shall the Permittee utilize both a valet stand and a freestanding valet sign.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1605.3.</num>
    <text>A valet stand located in the public space shall:</text>
    <text>Not occupy more than three feet by three feet (3 ft. x 3 ft.) nor at any time reduce the pedestrian walkway to a clear unobstructed width of less than eight feet (8 ft.) in the Central Business District and six feet (6 ft.) in all other areas of the
      District;</text>
    <text>Not be permanently affixed to the public space in any manner;</text>
    <text>Be easily moveable by one person;</text>
    <text>Not be placed in public space except during the hours approved for valet parking operations;</text>
    <text>Indicate any fees for Valet Parking;</text>
    <text>Include an approved sign attached to the stand not larger than three feet high by three feet wide (3 ft. x 3 ft.) with an area no smaller than 12 inches by 18 inches (12 in. x 18 in.) indicating the name of the Permittee, name of the Valet Parking
      Operator, the Standard Valet Parking Permit number, and the fee, if any, for Valet Parking;</text>
    <text>Be secured and locked when left unattended;</text>
    <text>Identify the Permittee and the permit number;</text>
    <text>Be readily visible at the point where motor vehicles are accepted for Valet Parking; and</text>
    <text>Comply with all applicable laws and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1605.4.</num>
    <text>A freestanding valet sign located in public space shall:</text>
    <text>Not occupy more than three feet by three feet (3 ft. x 3 ft.) nor at any time reduce the pedestrian walkway to a clear unobstructed width of less than eight feet (8 ft.) in the Central Business District and six feet (6 ft.) in all other areas of the
      District;</text>
    <text>Not be permanently affixed to the public space in any manner;</text>
    <text>Be easily moveable by one person;</text>
    <text>Not be placed in public space except during the hours approved for valet parking operations;</text>
    <text>Indicate any fees for Valet Parking;</text>
    <text>Be readily visible at the point where motor vehicles are accepted for Valet Parking; and</text>
    <text>Comply with all applicable laws and regulations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1605.5.</num>
    <text>Valet Parking services shall be offered only during the hours specified in the Valet Parking permit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1605.6.</num>
    <text>Valet Parking Operators shall comply with all applicable traffic laws and parking regulations when providing Valet Parking services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5019, 5024 (June 28, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>