<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-1603</num>
  <heading>STANDARD VALET PARKING PERMIT APPLICATION REVIEW (§ 24-1603)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1603.1.</num>
    <text>The Public Space Committee is responsible for reviewing Standard Valet Parking permit applications.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1603.2.</num>
    <text>The Public Space Committee shall consider the following factors in its review of Standard Valet Parking permit applications:</text>
    <text>Whether the Valet Parking operation will disrupt vehicular or pedestrian traffic;</text>
    <text>Whether the Valet Parking operation will pose a threat to public safety or welfare;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The existence of any legally binding conditions on or requirements of the Applicant’s Valet Parking operations approved or imposed by public entities such as but not limited to: the Board of Zoning Adjustment; the Alcoholic Beverage Control Board;
        or other legally binding valet parking agreements;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The size and characteristics of the public space required for the Valet Staging Zone;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The anticipated traffic conditions at the time of Valet Parking operations; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>In the case of permit renewals, previous violations of the Standard Valet Parking permit conditions, or any provision of this chapter, or any other law or regulation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1603.3.</num>
    <text>If the Standard Valet Parking application is approved by the Public Space Committee, the Applicant shall be informed in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1603.4.</num>
    <text>If the Standard Valet Parking application is denied, the Applicant shall be informed of the reason for the denial in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5019, 5023 (June 28, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>