<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-1699</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 24-1699)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1699.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the following terms shall have the meaning ascribed below:</text>
    <text>Applicant – a person who applies for a permit to offer valet parking services. Two or more persons applying jointly for a valet parking permit may be treated as a single applicant.</text>
    <text>DCRA – the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
    <text>Department – the District Department of Transportation.</text>
    <text>Event – an occasional gathering such as a party, festival, reception, or other such activity that people attend for a common purpose.</text>
    <text>Event Venue – a person holding a certificate of occupancy that owns or operates an establishment providing the location for occasional parties, festivals, receptions, or other such event at which persons gather for such activities.</text>
    <text>Immediate –a period of time not to exceed ten minutes and shall represent the maximum time a vehicle is allowed to remain within a Valet Staging Zone.</text>
    <text>Motor Vehicle – any vehicle propelled by internal-combustion engine, electricity, or steam, including any non-operational vehicle that is being restored or repaired. The term &amp;#8220;motor vehicle&amp;#8221; shall not include road rollers, farm
      tractors, vehicles propelled only upon stationary rails or tracks, electric personal assistive mobility devices, and battery-operated wheelchairs when operated by a handicapped person at speeds not exceeding ten miles per hour (10 miles/hr).</text>
    <text>Permittee – a person who is issued a Valet Parking permit by the Department.</text>
    <text>Person – a natural person or a corporation, company, firm, agency, association, partnership, organization, individually-owned business, or commercial entity.</text>
    <text>Occasional or Occasional Use – less than four (4) times per week.</text>
    <text>On-going basis – four (4) or more times per week.</text>
    <text>Standard Valet Parking &amp;#8211; valet parking provided on an on-going basis, as a service to customers of an establishment with a DCRA-issued Certificate of Occupancy.</text>
    <text>Unauthorized Staging – the picking up or dropping off of motor vehicles outside of the approved valet staging zone.</text>
    <text>Valet Parking – the act of removing a motor vehicle from the public right-of-way for the benefit of the motor vehicle’s operator, regardless of whether a fee is charged for the act. Attendant parking at an off-street parking facility shall not constitute
      valet parking. A person providing Valet Parking services for a non-recurring, one-time event at a private residence shall be exempt from the provisions of this chapter.</text>
    <text>Valet Parking Operator – a person, who through its agents, authorized designees, employees, or representatives, provides the service of valet parking.</text>
    <text>Valet Parking Plan – a plan submitted by an applicant that details the location of the valet parking service, the location where motor vehicles will be parked during valet parking hours, and the hours of operation for valet parking.</text>
    <text>Valet Sign – a sign, no larger than three feet by three feet (3 ft. x3 ft.) and no taller that four feet (4 ft.), which is not permanently affixed to the public space that indicates the name of the Permittee, Valet Parking Operator, permit number,
      and any fees to be charged customers for valet parking services.</text>
    <text>Valet Staging Zone – the public space adjacent to a curb reserved for valet parking.</text>
    <text>Valet Stand – a cabinet or stand with or without an umbrella affixed thereto with a placard affixed in front and a customer key repository and valet ticket compartment that is not permanently affixed to the public space, which indicates the name of
      the Permittee, Valet Parking Operator, permit number and any fees to be charged to customers for valet parking services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5019, 5033 (June 28, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>