<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-1612</num>
  <heading>EVENT VENUE VALET PARKING DUTIES (§ 24-1612)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1612.1.</num>
    <text>Written notice of each event shall be made to the Department by the Permittee at least three (3) business days prior to the event for which Valet Parking services in the Valet Staging Zone will be provided. The method for providing notification will
      be established by the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1612.2</num>
    <text>1612.2 The Department shall issue Emergency No Parking signs after a showing by the Applicant that:</text>
    <text>The Event Venue possesses sufficient liability insurance;</text>
    <text>The Event Venue agrees to comply with all applicable laws and regulations; and</text>
    <text>The Event Venue has satisfied all financial obligations under § 1607 of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1612.3.</num>
    <text>The Permittee shall apply to the Department for any of the following changes to an approved Event Venue Valet Parking permit. These changes may be approved by the Department without review by the Public Space Committee.</text>
    <text>These proposed changes may take effect once the Permittee has filed an application with the Department for these changes. Within two (2) weeks of filing an application for any of the following changes, the Department shall issue a revised Event Venue
      Valet Parking permit.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A proposed reduction in the size of any approved Valet Staging Zone;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A change in the name, address, or telephone number of the Permittee; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A proposed change to the Permittee’s business license as issued by DCRA.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1612.4.</num>
    <text>The Permittee shall inform the Department in writing of any of the following changes to the approved Event Venue Valet Parking permit. These changes must be approved by the Public Space Committee. The Department shall prepare a revised Event Venue
      Valet Parking permit to reflect any changes approved by the Public Space Committee.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A proposed expansion of or change in the location of any Valet Staging Zone; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A proposed change in the location of the Permittee’s business.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5019, 5031 (June 28, 2009).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>