<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-1600</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 24-1600)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1600.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall conduct, operate, maintain, or provide Valet Parking services utilizing public space within the District of Columbia without a permit from the Department. A person providing Valet Parking services for a non-recurring, one-time event
      at a private residence shall be exempt from the provisions of this chapter. A person providing Valet Parking services from the section of a circular driveway between the property line and the closest edge of the sidewalk shall be exempt from the
      provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.2.</num>
    <text>A person that has been issued a Certificate of Occupancy and that provides Valet Parking services in public space on an ongoing basis shall obtain either a Standard Valet Parking permit or an Event Venue Valet Parking permit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.3.</num>
    <text>A Standard Valet Parking permit authorizes a Permittee to utilize a Valet Staging Zone on an on-going basis for Valet Parking services. An Event Venue Valet Parking Permit authorizes a Permittee to utilize a Valet Staging Zone for occasional use for
      Valet Parking services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.4.</num>
    <text>A Permittee shall use a DCRA-licensed Valet Parking Operator to provide Valet Parking services, if such a license is required.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.5.</num>
    <text>Upon approval by the Director, full payment of the public space rental fees, and the application review fee specified in this chapter, the Department shall issue a Valet Parking permit for the rental of public space for Valet Parking services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1600.6.</num>
    <text>Each Permittee shall hold harmless and indemnify the District, and its officers, agents, and employees from all suits, claims, charges, and judgments to which the District, its officers, agents, and employees may be subject on account of the issuance
      of a Valet Parking permit, the operation of Valet Parking services, or injury to any person or damage to any property, including the property of the District of Columbia arising in connection with the Permittee’s Valet Parking Operator’s actions
      or operations.</text>
    <text>Emergency and Proposed Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 5059 (June 11, 2010)[EXPIRED]; as amended</text>
    <text>by Final Rulemaking published at 57 DCR 8024, 8027 (September 3, 2010).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 5019, 5020 (June 28, 2009); as amended by Notice of</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>