<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3804</num>
  <heading>NOTICE OF PROPOSED ACTION AND APPEAL RIGHTS (ยง 17-3804)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3804.1.</num>
    <text>If the Department proposes to deny, suspend or revoke a license, a written notice shall be provided to the applicant or licensee, which states the proposed action and the basis for the proposed action.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3804.2.</num>
    <text>The notice required under ยง 3804.1 shall advise the applicant or licensee of the right to request a hearing within ten (10) business days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays) from the date of the service of the notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3804.3.</num>
    <text>The notice shall advise that the action proposed or recommended will be taken at the expiration of ten (10) calendar days after service of the notice unless an appeal is taken.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3804.4.</num>
    <text>The notice shall be:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Served personally upon the applicant or licensee, or the applicant or licensee&amp;#8217;s agent; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Sent by first class mail to the home or business address of the applicant or licensee, or the applicant or licensee&amp;#8217;s agent, appearing on the application or license.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3804.5.</num>
    <text>A notice that is returned by the post office for reason of refusal of the addressee to accept delivery, or incorrect address, is deemed to have been properly served on the addressee by mail.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3804.6.</num>
    <text>An applicant or licensee may not file a separate application for licensure under this chapter during the appeal process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12137 (November 28, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>