<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-1204</num>
  <heading>BICYCLE SAFETY EQUIPMENT (§ 18-1204)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1204.1.</num>
    <text>Each bicycle shall be equipped with a brake which enables the operator to cause the braked wheels to skid on dry, level, clean pavement; provided, that a fixed gear bicycle is not required to have a separate brake, but an operator of a fixed gear
      bicycle shall be able to stop the bicycle using the pedals.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1204.2.</num>
    <text>Each bicycle, when in use at night, shall be equipped with a lamp on the front which shall emit a steady or flashing white light visible from a distance of at least five hundred feet (500 ft.) to the front and with a red reflector on the rear which
      shall be visible from all distances from fifty feet (50 ft.) to three hundred feet (300 ft.) to the rear when directly in front of upper beams of head lamps on a motor vehicle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1204.3.</num>
    <text>A lamp emitting a steady or flashing red light visible from a distance of five hundred feet (500 ft.) to the rear may be used in lieu of the red reflector.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1204.4.</num>
    <text>In place of the requirements of § 1204.2, a lamp may be worn on the body of an operator; provided, that it may be readily seen from the distances set forth in that subsection.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1204.5.</num>
    <text>Each bicycle shall be equipped with a bell or other device capable of giving a signal audible for a distance of at least one hundred feet (100 ft.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1204.6.</num>
    <text>A bicycle shall not be equipped with, nor shall any bicycle rider use, a siren of any kind.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1204.7.</num>
    <text>A bicycle rider shall not use the device for giving an audible signal when operating the bicycle within the quiet zone established by the provisions of D.C. Law 2-53 within one hundred (100) yards of any school, college, or university while classes
      are in session, or within one hundred (100) yards of any hospital or institution for the treatment of sick persons, except where such use is reasonably necessary for the safety of the rider or pedestrians.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 72-13 effective June 30, 1972, 32 DCRR §§ 11.601 (c) – (d) Special Edition; as amended by Regulation No. 74-5 effective April 21, 1974; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 6100 ( July 28, 2006 ).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>