<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-1207</num>
  <heading>SALE AND RENTAL OF BICYCLES (ยง 18-1207)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1207.1.</num>
    <text>Every person engaged in the business of buying or selling bicycles shall inform a purchaser of the purpose and procedure for registration of bicycles.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1207.2.</num>
    <text>[REPEALED]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1207.3.</num>
    <text>[REPEALED]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1207.4.</num>
    <text>Every person who sells or transfers a new bicycle to any other person within the District shall, within four (4) business days after the sale or transfer, deliver to the transferee a certificate of sale properly describing and identifying the bicycle.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1207.5.</num>
    <text>[REPEALED]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1207.6.</num>
    <text>[REPEALED]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1207.7.</num>
    <text>[REPEALED]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1207.8.</num>
    <text>Every person engaged in the business of renting bicycles shall issue to each person who rents a bicycle a statement of rental bearing the names and addresses of the lessor and lessee, the rate at which the bicycle is rented, and the time for which
      it is rented.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1207.9.</num>
    <text>It shall be the duty of the owner, proprietor, or person in charge of any store or shop where bicycles, motor bicycles, tricycles, or similar vehicles are left for repair, to keep a written record of the number and make of each vehicle so left, together
      with the name and residence of the owner of the vehicle and the name and residence of the person leaving the vehicle at the store or shop.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Regulation No. 72-13 effective June 30, 1972, 32 DCRR ยง 11.3401(a), 11.402(a), (b), Special Edition; as amended by Regulation 74-5 effective April 21, 1974; as amended by D.C. Act published at 55 DCR 1272 (February 8, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>