<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-2303</num>
  <heading>PARKING LOTS (§ 11-2303)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2303.1.</num>
    <text>A parking lot in any district shall conform to the following provisions:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>All areas devoted to driveways, access lanes, and parking areas shall be surfaced and maintained with an all-weather surface. In addition to traditional impervious surfaces, allowable all weather surfaces include porous (or pervious) concrete, porous
        asphalt, and/or mechanically-reinforced grass, excluding grass or gravel;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The parking lot shall be designed so that no vehicle or any part of a vehicle projects over any lot line or building line;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>No other use shall be conducted from or upon the premises, and no structure other than an attendant&amp;#8217;s shelter shall be erected or used upon the premises unless the use or structure is otherwise permitted in the district in which the parking
        lot is located;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>No vehicular entrance or exit shall be within forty feet (40 ft.) of a street intersection as measured from the intersection of the curb lines extended;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Any lighting used to illuminate a parking lot or its accessory buildings shall be arranged so that all direct rays of the lighting are confined to the surface of the parking lot; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The parking lot shall be kept free of refuse and debris and shall be landscaped. Landscaping shall be maintained in a healthy growing condition and in a neat and orderly appearance. Landscaping with trees and shrubs shall cover a minimum of five
        percent (5%) of the total area of the parking lot, or an area as determined by the Board of Zoning Adjustment for a parking lot otherwise requiring Board approval.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.2.</num>
    <text>In addition to the requirements of § 2303.1, a parking lot located in an R-1, R-2, R-3, R-4 or R-5-A District, and a parking lot located in any other district where such parking lot is contiguous to an R-1, R-2, R-3, R-4, or R-5-A District, shall
      be screened from all contiguous residential property located in the R-1, R-2, R-3, R-4, or R-5-A District by a solid brick or stone wall at least twelve inches (12 in.) thick and forty-two inches (42 in.) high or by evergreen hedges or evergreen
      trees that are thickly planted and maintained and at least forty-two inches (42 in.) in height when planted.</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The parking lot shall be screened from all contiguous residential property located in an R-1, R-2, or R-3 District by a solid masonry wall at least twelve inches (12 in.) thick and forty-two inches (42 in.) high; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>All parts of the lot not devoted to parking areas, driveways, access lanes, attendant&amp;#8217;s shelter, or required screening walls shall be kept free of refuse and debris and shall be paved or landscaped. Landscaping shall be maintained in a
        healthy growing condition and in a neat and orderly appearance.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.3.</num>
    <text>If approved by the Board of Zoning Adjustment as a special exception under § 3104, the conditions in § 2303.2 may be waived or modified.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.4.</num>
    <text>Before authorizing a waiver or modification, the Board shall consider:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The adequacy of protective and screening walls located on adjacent residential property;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Topographic and traffic conditions; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Any adverse effect the requested waiver or modification of standards may have on adjacent residential property.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2303.5.</num>
    <text>The Board may require any special treatment of the premises that it deems necessary to protect the value of adjacent property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>§§ 7404.1, 7404.2, 7404.3, and 7404.4 of the Zoning Regulations, effective May 12, 1958; as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 31 DCR 6585, 6626 (December 28, 1984); and Final Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 9741-43 (December 8, 2000), incorporating
        by reference the text of Proposed Rulemaking published at 47 DCR 8335, 8511-12 (October 20, 2000); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 53 DCR 859 (February 10,2006).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>