<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-2711</num>
  <heading>EMERGENCY PROCEDURES (§ 20-2711)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2711.1.</num>
    <text>If the Mayor finds that any person is acting in a manner that constitutes a violation of the Act, the Mayor may order the person to cease and desist.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2711.2.</num>
    <text>Failure to comply with the order shall be a violation of the Act; Provided, that failure to comply with a cease and desist order shall not be an independent violation if a court of competent jurisdiction finds that no violation of the Act had occurred.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2711.3.</num>
    <text>Any person aggrieved by an emergency order of the Mayor may, within forty-eight (48) hours of the order, request a hearing by the Mayor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2711.4.</num>
    <text>Upon receiving a request for a hearing from any person aggrieved by an emergency order, the Mayor shall hold the hearing as soon as is reasonably practical.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2711.5.</num>
    <text>The hearing regarding an emergency order shall be conducted in accordance with the contested case provisions of the D.C. Administrative Procedure Act (D.C. Code § 1-1509 (1991 Repl. Vol.)).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2711.6.</num>
    <text>A request for a hearing on an emergency order shall not be grounds for noncompliance with any order issued pursuant to this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2711.7.</num>
    <text>After the conclusion of the hearing held pursuant to §§ 2711.4 and 2711.5, the person shall be notified by the Mayor of the Mayor&amp;#8217;s decision. This action shall be final; Provided, that an appeal from the action shall not be grounds for noncompliance
      with any order issued pursuant to this section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2711.8.</num>
    <text>Nothing contained in this section shall preclude the Mayor from initiating appropriate action for the recovery of a penalty as is provided in Chapters 27 and 28 of this subtitle, nor shall it preclude the Mayor from seeking any other relief or remedy
      as is provided by law.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 11 of the District of Columbia Noise Control Act of 1977, D.C. Law 2-53, 24 DCR 5293, 5328 (December 30, 1977); as amended by § 2 of the Noise Control Amendment Act of 1996, D.C. Law 11-161, 43 DCR 3727, 3730 (July 19, 1996).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>