<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-2707</num>
  <heading>TEMPORARY EXEMPTION PROCEDURES (ยง 20-2707)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2707.1.</num>
    <text>A person may apply to the Mayor for a temporary exemption from the maximum permissible noise levels or the time limits established by the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2707.2.</num>
    <text>If the applicant is required to obtain a building permit from the District government, he or she may include the request for a temporary exemption with the application for that permit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2707.3.</num>
    <text>The decision of the Mayor shall be in writing and shall include a statement of the reasons for the action taken.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2707.4.</num>
    <text>If a temporary exemption is granted, the decision shall include the following information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name of the applicant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The noise level to be permitted;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The period of time during which the exemption shall be in effect; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Any other conditions or qualifications necessary for the protection of the public under the standards applicable to the granting of a temporary exemption.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2707.5.</num>
    <text>A temporary exemption shall be granted for as long as is necessary, but shall not exceed forty-five (45) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2707.6.</num>
    <text>A notice of the issuance of a temporary exemption shall be published in the D.C. Register and shall be posted by the applicant in a conspicuous sport at the location involved for a period of our (4) consecutive days following the date of issuance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2707.7.</num>
    <text>Any person adversely affected by the issuance or denial of a temporary exemption may, within ten (10 days of the decision, request a hearing on the matter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2707.8.</num>
    <text>If the Mayor finds that a sufficient bona fide controversy exists regarding the issuance or denial of a temporary exemption, the Mayor may, in his or her discretion, hold a hearing on the matter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2707.9.</num>
    <text>The hearing shall be held as soon as practicable.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2707.10.</num>
    <text>A decision by the Mayor after a hearing shall be final, subject to a de novo review by a court of competent jurisdiction.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2707.11.</num>
    <text>Unless the Mayor orders otherwise, the filing of a request for a hearing shall not affect the issuance of a temporary exemption.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 2 of the Noise Control Amendment Act of 1996, D.C. Law 11-161, 43 DCR 3727, 3730 (July 19, 1996).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>