<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-2713</num>
  <heading>ENFORCEMENT[COLON] PENALTIES (ยง 20-2713)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2713.1.</num>
    <text>Any person who is aggrieved by a violation of any provision of the Act may complain to the Metropolitan Police Department which shall enforce the provisions of this Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2713.2.</num>
    <text>Prior to issuing a citation or notice of infraction, the Metropolitan Police Officer or other District government official may give a verbal warning to the violator and allow the violator a reasonable time to cease violating the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2713.3.</num>
    <text>Any person who violates any provision of the Act shall be punished by a fine not to exceed one thousand dollars ($1000) or imprisonment not to exceed ten (10) days, or both. In the event of any violation of or failure to comply with the Act or any
      section of the Act, each and every day of such violation or failure shall constitute a separate offense, and the penalties described in the Act shall be applicable to each such separate offense.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2713.4.</num>
    <text>Officers of the Metropolitan Police Department are authorized to enforce the provisions of the Act by issuing a notice of civil infraction for a violation of the Act that constitutes a noise distrurbance, or a noise-producing activity, during days
      or hours when prohibited, or beyond it authorized duration pursuant to the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985, effective October 5, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-42, D.C. Code ยง6-2701 et seq.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2713.5.</num>
    <text>Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of Chapter 27 or 28, pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985. Adjudication
      of any infraction of Chapter 27 or 28 shall be pursuant to titles I-III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Section 485 of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985 Technical and Clarifying Amendments Act of 1990, D.C. Law 8-237, 38 DCR 314,318 (January 11, 1991); Section 2 of the Noise Control Amendment Act of 1996,
        D.C. Law 11-161, 43 DCR 3727, 3731 (July 19, 1996).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>