<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4225</num>
  <heading>SPECIFIC PROVIDER REQUIREMENTS[COLON] PERSONAL EMERGENCY RESPONSE SERVICESPERS) (ยง 29-4225)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4225.1.</num>
    <text>Each PERS provider shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Provide in-home installation of all equipment necessary to make the service fully operational (including batteries);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Conduct recipient and representative instruction on usage, maintenance, and emergency protocol of the PERS;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Provide equipment maintenance (both in-home and response center);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Provide twenty-four (24) hours per day, seven (7) days per week response center monitoring and support;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Conduct equipment testing, monitoring, and maintenance (both in-home and response center equipment);</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Conduct monthly service checks;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Provide documentation of all services provided, recipient contacts, equipment and system checks, and equipment servicing;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Make available emergency equipment repair to the recipient on a twenty-four (24) hours per day, seven (7) days per week basis; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Allow the recipient to designate respondent(s) who will respond to emergency calls. Respondents may be relatives, friends, neighbors, or medical personnel.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4225.2.</num>
    <text>A PERS will not be provided to waiver recipients who:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Are unable to understand and demonstrate proper use of the system; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Live with a person who assumes responsibility for providing care (to the recipient) and the waiver recipient is not left alone for significant periods of time.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4225.3.</num>
    <text>Each provider of PERS services shall ensure that contractors are properly supervised and that the service provided is consistent with the recipient&amp;#8217;s ISP.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4225.4.</num>
    <text>A provider of PERS service shall be exempt from the requirement to comply with an annual tuberculosis (TB) test; and</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4225.5.</num>
    <text>A provider of PERS service shall be licensed to do business in the state in which it is incorporated.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 9025 (October 24, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>