<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-4228</num>
  <heading>PROGRAM SERVICES[COLON] RESPITE SERVICES (ยง 29-4228)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4228.3.</num>
    <text>Respite services may cover the range of activities associated with the Personal Care Aide role or the Homemaker role.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4228.4.</num>
    <text>Respite services shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Basic personal care such as bathing, grooming, and assistance with toileting or bedpan use;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Assistance with prescribed, self-administered medication;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Meal preparation and assistance with eating;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Household tasks related to keeping the recipient&amp;#8217;s living areas in a condition that promotes the recipient&amp;#8217;s health, comfort, and safety; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Accompanying the recipient to medically related appointments;</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4228.5.</num>
    <text>Respite services shall not include services that require the skills of a licensed professional, including catheter insertion, procedures requiring sterile techniques, and medication administration.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4228.6.</num>
    <text>Respite services shall not include tasks usually performed by chore workers, including cleaning of areas not occupied by the recipient, cleaning laundry for family members of the recipient, and shopping for items not used by the recipient.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4228.7.</num>
    <text>A unit of service for respite care shall be one (1) to twenty-four (24) hours spent performing allowable tasks.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4228.8.</num>
    <text>The supervisory nurse shall develop the ISP for respite services, and the case manager shall approve the ISP for respite services prior to the provision of the services. The supervisory RN must conduct the supervision of the respite aide.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4228.9.</num>
    <text>Respite services are limited to a maximum of four hundred and eighty (480) hours per year. Requirements for respite services in excess of the established limits must be approved by the MAA prior to the provision of the services.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4228.10.</num>
    <text>No waiver recipient shall receive Personal Care Aide services other than those provided by the in-home respite caregiver during the period of time which respite care is provided.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4228.11.</num>
    <text>Respite services shall not be provided to recipients who have no primary caregiver that is responsible for the provision of the recipient&amp;#8217;s care on an ongoing basis.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4228.12.</num>
    <text>A waiver recipient may choose an individual or family member other than a spouse, or parent of a minor recipient or other legally responsible relative to provide respite services</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 50 DCR 9025 (October 24, 2003).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>