<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-413</num>
  <heading>LETTERS OF INTENT (ยง 29-413)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>413.1.</num>
    <text>Prior to submission of a formal application for a proposed use of federal funds, the applicant shall submit to the SHPDA a letter of intent to apply for federal assistance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>413.2.</num>
    <text>A letter of intent shall include at least the following basic information:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A brief description of the project;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The location of the project;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The target population to be served;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The estimated total cost of the project and the amount of federal funds proposed to be requested;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The federal funding agency and legislative authority for the grant;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The applicant&amp;#8217;s contact person; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The projected implementation date and project duration.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>413.3.</num>
    <text>The letter of intent shall be submitted to the SHPDA at least sixty (60) days prior to the intended date of the submission of the application for review.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>413.4.</num>
    <text>If the nature of a special project, a short-term notification of available funds from the funding agency, or related circumstances preclude an applicant from adhering to the sixty (60) day time frame established for submission of letters of intent
      under ยง413.3, the SHPDA may waive the letter of intent requirement.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>413.5.</num>
    <text>In situations where an applicant does not have sufficient opportunity to inform SHPDA of its intent to apply for federal assistance because of circumstances beyond its control, the applicant shall advise SHPDA as soon as possible after the first oral
      or written notification of the availability of funds, but in no case more than seven (7) calendar days after written notification from the funding agency regarding the availability of funds. The applicant shall immediately ask the funding agency
      whether the review is required under the Proposed Uses of Federal Funds review authority.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 1086 (March 13, 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>