<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-422</num>
  <heading>OTHER REVIEWS (§ 29-422)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>422.1.</num>
    <text>SHPDA review procedures shall not preclude the need for review of applications under OMB Circular A-95 by the appropriate agencies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>422.2.</num>
    <text>The applicant shall notify the appropriate A-95 clearinghouse (state or local, as required) of its intent to apply for federal assistance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>422.3.</num>
    <text>All state plans and applications for federal support initiated by entities of the District government shall contain evidence that the proposals have been reviewed and approved by the Office of Budget and Resource Development prior to submission to
      the SHPDA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>422.4.</num>
    <text>A separate application for Certificate of Need shall be filed with the D.C. SHPDA if a new service will be delivered or if a capital expenditure of one hundred fifty thousand dollars ($150,000) or more or in certain other cases, as specified in the
      D.C. Certificate of need Act of 1980. Both the application for the grant award and Certificate of Need shall be deemed equally important and involve a separate review process.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>422.5.</num>
    <text>To the extent to which it is legally and otherwise possible to do so, the SHPDA and the appropriate SHCC committee(s) shall conduct a joint review of any proposal which is subject to both the Certificate of Need and proposed use of federal funds review.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 1086 (March 13, 1981).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR’S NOTE</heading>
      <text>The District of Columbia Certificate of Need Act of 1980, D.C. Code, 2001 Ed. § 44-1801 to 44-1817, was repealed by D.C. Law 9-197 § 22, 39 DCR 9195 (December 11, 1992). Current provisions regarding Certificates of Need may be found at D.C. Code,
        2001 Ed. §§ 44-401 to 44-421.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>