<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>29-414</num>
  <heading>SUBMISSION OF APPLICATIONS FOR REVIEW (§ 29-414)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>414.1.</num>
    <text>Application forms and instructions or guidelines respecting the preparation of a grant application, contract, and related matters shall be available through the appropriate federal or state funding agency. It shall be the responsibility of prospective
      applicants to obtain an application kit from the appropriate funding agency or grant program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>414.2.</num>
    <text>Each application kit shall include the necessary forms and instructions for completing the grant application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>414.3.</num>
    <text>In the case of direct federal grants, contracts, loans, and loan guarantees, an application for a grant, loan, or loan guarantee or proposal for a contract subject to review by SHPDA or SHCC shall be submitted simultaneously to the SHPDA and the federal
      funding agency.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>414.4.</num>
    <text>In the case of funds made available by the District government under an allotment program subject to review, the state program agency may establish the submission date.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>414.5.</num>
    <text>In accordance with 42 CFR 122.408(b), the Secretary of DHHS may, for certain federal funding programs or types of applications, require that applications meet the following requirements:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Be submitted first to the SHPDA and then (following approval, disapproval, or the expiration of the review period, whichever comes first) to the Federal funding agency; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Directly to the federal funding agency, which shall, before approving the application or proposal and at a time it considers appropriate, submit it or a summary to the SHPDA.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>414.6.</num>
    <text>In the situations described in §414.5, the SHPDA shall accept the application for review at the time specified by the Secretary of DHHS. Other provisions of the regular review process, including the letter of intent requirement, shall not be modified
      by the change in application submission date in these situations.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>414.7.</num>
    <text>All applicants shall submit five (5) copies of completed applications and any additional supportive materials to the SHPDA. An applicant shall be responsible for verifying the receipt of the application by the SHPDA.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>414.8.</num>
    <text>Persons proposing projects for which a certificate of need is required shall submit a letter of intent to the SHPDA at least sixty (60) days prior to submission of their application for review.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>414.9.</num>
    <text>Consistent with provisions of the D.C. Certificate of Need Act of 1980 and applicable rules, the letter required by §414.8 shall contain, in sufficient detail, information that adequately informs the SHPDA of the scope and nature of the project.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 28 DCR 1086 (March 13, 1981).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR’S NOTE</heading>
      <text>The District of Columbia Certificate of Need Act of 1980, D.C. Code, 2001 Ed. § 44-1801 to 44-1817, was repealed by D.C. Law 9-197 § 22, 39 DCR 9195 (December 11, 1992). Current provisions regarding Certificates of Need may be found at D.C. Code,
        2001 Ed. §§ 44-401 to 44-421.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>