<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-4103</num>
  <heading>FILING AND RECORDKEEPING REQUIREMENTS (ยง 3-4103)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4103.1.</num>
    <text>The treasurer of each exploratory committee must file Reports of Receipts and Expenditures (R&amp;#038;E Reports) on forms prescribed by the Director on the following dates:</text>
    <text>The 10th day of March, June, August, October, and December in the 7 months preceding the date on which an election is held for the office sought, and on the 8th day next preceding the date on which said election is held, and also by the 31st day of
      January of each year thereafter. In addition, the reports shall be filed on the 31st day of July of each year in which there is no election.</text>
    <text>The reports shall be complete as of the date prescribed by the Director, which shall not be more than 5 days before the date of filing, except that any contribution of $200 or more received after the closing date prescribed by the Director for the
      last report required to be filed before the election shall be reported within 24 hours after its receipt.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4103.2.</num>
    <text>R&amp;#038;E reports required by this section must be filed in accordance with ยง 3017 of Chapter 30 of this title.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4103.3.</num>
    <text>R&amp;#038;E Reports must disclose:</text>
    <text>The amount of cash on hand at the beginning of the reporting period;</text>
    <text>The full name and mailing address, including occupation and principal place of business, if any, of each person who has made one or more contributions to or for the exploratory committee, including the purchase of tickets for events such as dinners,
      luncheons, rallies, and similar fundraising events, within the calendar year in an aggregate amount or value in excess of fifty dollars ($50) or more, together with the amount and date of the contributions;</text>
    <text>The total sum of individual contributions made to or for the exploratory committee during the reporting period;</text>
    <text>Each loan to or from any person within the calendar year in an aggregate amount or value of fifty dollars ($50) or more, together with the full names and mailing addresses (including the occupation and the principal place of business, if any) of the
      lender and endorsers, if any, and the date and amount of the loans;</text>
    <text>The net amount of proceeds from:</text>
    <text>The sale of tickets to each dinner, luncheon, rally, and other fundraising events organized by the exploratory committee;</text>
    <text>Collections made at events; and</text>
    <text>Sales by an exploratory committee of items such as political campaign pins, buttons, badges, flags, emblems, hats, banners, literature, and similar materials;</text>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Each contribution, rebate, refund, or other receipt of fifty dollars ($50) or more not otherwise listed under Paragraphs (b) through (e) of this subsection;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>The total sum of all receipts by or for the exploratory committee during the reporting period;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The full name and mailing address, including the occupation and the principal place of business, if any, of each person to whom expenditures have been made by or on behalf of the exploratory committee within the calendar year in an aggregate amount
        or value of ten dollars ($10) or more;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The amount, date, and purpose of each expenditure;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>The total sum of expenditures made by the exploratory committee during the calendar year;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>The amount and nature of debts and obligations owed by or to the exploratory committee, listed in such form as the Director of Campaign Finance may prescribe; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(l)</num>
      <text>Other information as may be required by the Director of Campaign Finance.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4103.4.</num>
    <text>R&amp;#038;E Reports must be complete within five (5) days before the prescribed filing deadline.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 1402 (February 8, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11864 (August 16, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>