<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-3903</num>
  <heading>PETTY CASH FUNDS (§ 3-3903)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3903.1.</num>
    <text>An inaugural committee may maintain a Petty Cash Fund that shall not exceed three hundred dollars ($300) at any time.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3903.2.</num>
    <text>All records and transactions shall be recorded in a petty cash journal maintained and authorized by either:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The chairperson;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The treasurer; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Their designated agents, as listed on the Statement of Organization filed under § 3901.2.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3903.3.</num>
    <text>Petty cash funds shall be administered in the following manner:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Cash shall only be received by check drawn on the account of the inaugural committee;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Cash expenditures shall not exceed fifty dollars ($50) to any person in connection with a single purchase or transaction; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>All transactions shall be recorded in the petty cash journal.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3903.4.</num>
    <text>For each deposit to the petty cash fund, the amount and date shall be recorded in the petty cash journal.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3903.5.</num>
    <text>For each disbursement, the petty cash journal shall include:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name and address of each recipient;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The date of the disbursement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The amount of the disbursement;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The purpose of the disbursement; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The candidate’s name and the office sought, or the name of the inaugural committee for which the disbursement is made.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3903.6.</num>
    <text>All receipts, vouchers, petty cash journals, and other documentation shall be retained by the inaugural committee for a period of three (3) years from the date of the filing of the final R&amp;#038;E Report by the inaugural committee.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 1402 (February 8, 2013); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 11864 (August 16, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>