<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-3599</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (§ 20-3599)
    <text>Aggregated utility data – total whole-building energy or water data for apecified period as provided by the utility company or a third party for theuilding for a given utility type.</text>
    <text>Building – any structure used or intended for supporting or sheltering any user occupancy.</text>
    <text>Building owner – an individual, partnership, corporation, trust, association,irm, joint stock company, organization, commission, or other private entityither possessing title or designated to govern a privately-owned building, orn agent authorized
      to act on behalf of the private entity.</text>
    <text>Director – the Director of the District Department of the Environment (DDOE),r the Director’s representative, agent, designee, or successor.</text>
    <text>District Benchmark Results and Compliance Report – the Portfolio Managereport that includes benchmark results, identifies reporting methodology, andonfirms completion of a building’s benchmarking to the District.</text>
    <text>District Benchmark Reporting Template – the template developed by DDOE inartnership with the United States Environmental Protection Agency (U.S. EPA),hat exports from Portfolio Manager the building information required foruilding owners to fulfill
      District benchmarking requirements.</text>
    <text>District Data Collection Worksheet – the list of data fields required toulfill District benchmarking requirements.</text>
    <text>ENERGY STAR® Portfolio Manager benchmarking tool, or Portfolio Manager – theystem developed by the U.S. EPA that rates the energy and water performance of building.</text>
    <text>Non-Residential Tenant Information Form – the District form a building owneray use to collect information required for benchmarking from a non-residentialenant.</text>
    <text>Non-Residential Tenant Notification Letter – the District form letter auilding owner may use to inform a non-residential tenant that the tenant isequired to provide the information required for benchmarking.</text>
    <text>Space use attributes – information such as the conditioned floor area, weeklyperating hours, number of occupied units, and number of computers in use asefined by the Portfolio Manager, according to a building type.</text>
    <text>Tenant – a person or entity entitled to the possession, occupancy, or theenefits of any rental unit owned by another person or entity.</text>
    <text>Utility company – an entity distributing, supplying, or transmittinglectricity, natural gas, or other fuel for heating, cooling, or powereneration, or water to a building.</text>
    <text>Utility data – energy or water consumption data from one or more meters for apecified period.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 11318 (October 31, 2008); asmended by Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 367 (January 18, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>