<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>3-1800</num>
  <heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS (ยง 3-1800)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1800.1.</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Board of Elections and Ethics is vested with the authority to administer generally the provisions of the &amp;#8220;Charter Amending Procedures Act&amp;#8221; ["Title III, District Charter Preamble, Legislative Power and Charter
      Amending Procedure," ยง 303, District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act (hereinafter referred to as the "D.C. Self-Government Act"), P.L. 93-198, 87 Stat. 774, December 24, 1973.]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1800.2.</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Board of Elections and Ethics shall be responsible for the conduct of elections to amend &amp;#8220;Title IV, The District Charter&amp;#8221; (hereinafter referred to as the &amp;#8220;Charter&amp;#8221;), of the D.C. Self-Government
      Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1800.3.</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Board of Elections and Ethics shall be authorized to promulgate rules and regulations for the implementation of the &amp;#8220;Charter Amending Procedures Act&amp;#8221; of the D.C. Self-Government Act, pursuant to D.C. Code
      ยง 1-1001.05(a)(14) (2006 Repl.).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1800.4.</num>
    <text>In accordance with the provisions of the D.C. Self-Government Act, the Charter may be amended by an act passed by the Council of the District of Columbia and ratified by a majority of the registered qualified electors of the District voting in the
      election held for ratification.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1800.5.</num>
    <text>Any political committee organized in support of, or in opposition to, a proposed Charter amendment shall file a verified statement of contributions with the Office of Campaign Finance.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is section 303(c) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L.93-198, D.C. Code ยง 1-1001.05(a)(14) (2006 Repl.).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 40 D.C. Reg. 7083 (October 8, 1993).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>HISTORICAL NOTE</heading>
      <text>Prior to October 8, 1993, the Board of Elections and Ethics published a Final Rulemaking notice at 35 D.C. Reg. 5454, 5458-59 (July 15, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>