<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-2402</num>
  <heading>LOADING ZONES (§ 18-2402)
    <text>The Director of the District Department of Transportation (DDOT) shall installnd maintain signs designating the location for each commercial motor vehicleoading zone (“loading zone”). Each sign shall state the hours during whichhe loading zone restrictions
      apply.</text>
    <text>A commercial motor vehicle may park within a loading zone, if it meets one (1)f the following conditions:</text>
    <text>The commercial motor vehicle displays a loading zone annual pass, as describedn § 2428;</text>
    <text>The commercial motor vehicle displays a loading zone day pass, as described in 2429; or</text>
    <text>The commercial motor vehicle has one (1) of the following proofs of payment:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An unexpired single space meter; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An alternative proof of payment, as determined by the DDOT Director.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Notwithstanding § 2402.2:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A commercial motor vehicle shall not park in a loading zone pursuant to §402.2 for a purpose other than loading or unloading;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A commercial motor vehicle shall not be parked in a loading zone during anyeriod of time when parking and standing is prohibited on the block on which theoading zone is located, such as during rush hour parking restriction periods;nd</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A commercial motor vehicle shall not park in a loading zone for longer thanhe time indicated on the signs or parking meters in that zone; provided, thathere no signs are present, the maximum amount of time a commercial motorehicle may park in a
        loading zone is two (2) hours.</text>
    </level>
    <text>No other vehicle shall park or stop in a loading zone during the hourspplicable to the zone, except that the operator of a passenger vehicle carryingifteen (15) passengers or fewer may park in a loading zone during such hours ifhe operator is stopping
      momentarily within the loading zone to pick up aassenger or passengers and if such stopping does not interfere with aommercial motor vehicle that is within the loading zone or is waiting to enterhe loading zone.</text>
    <text>When parking in a loading zone, the operator of a commercial motor vehicle thatoes not have a valid loading zone annual permit or day pass shall, immediatelyfter parking, pay for the amount of time desired.</text>
    <text>A commercial motor vehicle may not park at a non-loading zone parking meterpace at the times specified in those zones; provided, that if no time ispecified, the loading zone shall be in effect between 7:00 a.m. and 6:30 p.m.;rovided further, that
      a commercial motor vehicle may park at a non-loading zonearking meter space between the hours of 10:00 a.m. and 2:00 p.m.</text>
    <text>The fee to park a commercial motor vehicle within a loading zone shall bestablished by the DDOT Director and posted in the loading zone; provided, thathe Director shall not establish a fee greater than five dollars ($5.00) perour.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 131 (January 5, 2007); as amendedy Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 16844 (December 13, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>