<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-2414</num>
  <heading>VISITOR OR TEMPORARY PERMITS (§ 18-2414)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>2414.1.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in § 2424, the Director or the Chief of Police may issue visitor permits valid for periods up to fifteen (15) days to visitors at an address on a residential permit parking block.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2414.2.</num>
    <text>Visitors permits shall be valid on commercial vehicles only while the operator of the vehicle is actually involved in the performance of construction, maintenance, repair, or reconstruction work at an address on a residential permit parking street.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2414.3.</num>
    <text>The Director may issue temporary permits, valid for periods up to sixty (60) days, for temporary use warranted by a resident’s medical necessity.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2414.4.</num>
    <text>A visitor’s permit or a temporary permit may be issued for a zone even though the motor vehicle displays a residential permit parking sticker for another zone.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2414.5.</num>
    <text>The forgery, counterfeiting, or unauthorized use or replication of a visitor permit or temporary permit shall be punishable by a fine of $ 300.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2414.6.</num>
    <text>The Director shall implement a one (1) year visitor parking pilot program within the Advisory Neighborhood Commission boundaries of the Residential Parking Permit areas of Ward 4 in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2414.7.</num>
    <text>The Director shall implement a one (1) year visitor parking pilot program within the Residential Parking Permit areas of Advisory Neighborhood Commission 1D in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2414.8.</num>
    <text>The Director shall implement a one (1) year visitor parking pilot program within the Residential Parking Permit areas of Ward 3 in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2414.9.</num>
    <text>Subject to the availability of funds, the Director shall implement a visitor parking pilot program within all residential parking permit areas in the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2414.10.</num>
    <text>The Director may phase in the District-wide visitor parking pilot program referenced in section 2414.9, beginning with those areas that are participating in a current visitor parking pilot program or have participated in a previous visitor parking
      pilot program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>2414.11.</num>
    <text>The visitor parking pilot program listed in subsection 2414.9 shall expire September 30, 2013. Any visitor parking pilot permits issued prior to September 30, 2013 shall expire on September 30, 2013.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>D.C. Act 16-464 published at 53 DCR 6719, 6720 (August 18, 2006); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 10066 (October 19, 2007); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 003972 (April 11, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking
        published at 55 DCR 7993 (July 25, 2008); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12906 (December 26, 2008); and as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 56 DCR 1812 (February 27, 2009); as amended by Final Rulemaking published at
        59 DCR 13365 (November 23, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>