<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-2429</num>
  <heading>COMMERCIAL PERMIT PARKING; DAY PASS (ยง 18-2429)
    <text>There is established a CPP day pass to provide commercial motor vehicle ownershe option to purchase a daily parking pass for a commercial motor vehicle toark in loading zones or at curbside parking spaces instead of paying forarking at the meter in
      those zones.</text>
    <text>A commercial motor vehicle owner or company shall complete an application, to berovided by DDOT, including identifying information on each vehicle to beegistered in the CPP day pass program.</text>
    <text>The CPP day pass shall be valid at loading zones and curbside parking spaces onhe date shown on the day-pass.</text>
    <text>The CPP day pass shall allow parking for up to two (2) hours at designatedoading zones during times specified in those zones; provided, that if no times specified, the loading zone shall be in effect between 7:00 a.m. to 6:30.m., or in a metered curbside
      zone during off-peak hours of 10:00 a.m. to 2:00.m. and when meter enforcement is not in effect, as posted on the signs andeters in the parking zone; provided further, that such parking is otherwiseonsistent with the provisions of ยง 2402.</text>
    <text>A CPP day pass shall be obtained by the company for each commercial deliveryehicle that will be operating in the District on a given day and will be using day pass. A CPP day pass may not be shared between two (2) or more vehicles.</text>
    <text>The commercial motor vehicle operator shall place the day pass facing out on thenside of the passenger side window of the vehicle so that it is clearly visiblehrough the passenger side window of the vehicle.</text>
    <text>The expiration date displayed on the commercial permit parking day pass shallpecify the date on which the day pass is effective.</text>
    <text>Notwithstanding ยง 2404.5, a commercial motor vehicle may park outside a loadingone between the hours of 10:00 a.m. and 2:00 p.m. with a valid day pass if itccupies no more than two (2) metered spaces or no more than forty feet (40 ft.)ithin a parking
      zone serviced by a multi-space meter.</text>
  </heading>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 60 DCR 16844 (December 13, 2013).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>