<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-3501</num>
  <heading>SECURITY ALARM COLLATERALS (ยง 17-3501)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3501.1.</num>
    <text>Pursuant to ยง13(f) of the Security Alarm Systems Regulations Act of 1980, D.C. Law 3-107, D.C. Code ยง6-3101 et seq. (1988 Supp.), as amended, a notice of violation of any provision of this Act, including the amount of collateral, shall be issued n
      a Violation Citation form prepared by the Metropolitan Police Department or the District of Columbia Fire Department, as appropriate.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3501.2.</num>
    <text>The following collateral amounts shall be established for the violations as listed:</text>
    <text>Failure of:</text>
    <text>Alarm agent to carry or display valid identification card $50</text>
    <text>Dealer to give proper instructions to users on care and use</text>
    <text>of alarm $50</text>
    <text>Dealer to have alarm agent properly respond when requested $50</text>
    <text>Dealer to employ master electrician $50</text>
    <text>User to have person properly respond to scene when</text>
    <text>requested $50</text>
    <text>User to maintain alarm in good working order $50</text>
    <text>User to post names of responsible persons at scene $50</text>
    <text>Failure to:</text>
    <text>Adequately train or instruct employees $50</text>
    <text>Comply with other sections of the Act $50</text>
    <text>Post sign indicating alarm dealer $50</text>
    <text>Maintain alarm user records as required by law $50</text>
    <text>Surrender license identification card as required by law $50</text>
    <text>False alarm $50</text>
    <text>Installation or maintenance by:</text>
    <text>Any person of system which creates improper sound $50</text>
    <text>Any person of system without delay mechanism $50</text>
    <text>Operating as an alarm dealer or agent:</text>
    <text>Without a license $150</text>
    <text>With suspended license $150</text>
    <text>Use by any person of pre-recorded message to report alarm $50</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 34 DCR 7708 (December 4, 1987), as amended by Final Rulemaking published at 36 DCR 6527 (September 15, 1989).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>