<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-700</num>
  <heading>OPERATION OF RECREATION UNITS (§ 19-700)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>700.1.</num>
    <text>The recreation units operated by the Department of Recreation (also referred to in this chapter as the “Department”) shall include those designated by the National Capital Planning Commission, in accordance with a comprehensive plan as suitable and
      desirable for the District recreation system.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>700.2.</num>
    <text>All activities in recreation centers or at recreation units shall be under the control of a director designated by the Director of the Department of Parks and Recreation, or his or her representative.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>700.3.</num>
    <text>The schedule of operation of each recreation unit and the assignment of personnel to each unit and activity shall be determined by the Director of the Department of Parks and Recreation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>700.4.</num>
    <text>The director in charge of each unit is required to be at the unit at least fifteen (15) minutes before the scheduled time of opening.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>700.5.</num>
    <text>The director of each unit shall not leave the unit at any time during his or her period of duty, without authority to do so from a superior officer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>700.6.</num>
    <text>It shall be the responsibility of the divisional directors to inform the recreation staff of all policies and agreements reached and of all administrative directives issued in connection with the use by the Department of facilities of other agencies.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>700.7.</num>
    <text>Attendance records shall be kept daily at each recreation unit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>700.8.</num>
    <text>A monthly report of attendance shall be made to the central office on prescribed forms.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is An Act To create a Recreation Board for the District of Columbia, to define its duties, and for other purposes, approved April 29, 1942, 56 Stat. 261, codified at D.C.Code §§ 8-137.1, -1808.01;
        Mayor&amp;#8217;s Order 2007-53</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>15 DCRR § 1.1-1.3 (August 10, 1970 and December 23, 1970).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR’S NOTE</heading>
      <text>The Department of Recreation was renamed the Department of Recreation and Parks pursuant to D.C. Law 10-226 and later renamed the Department of Parks and Recreation pursuant to Mayor’s Order 2000-20, dated February 4, 2000. All references in this
        chapter to the “Director of Recreation” shall mean the “Director of the Department of Parks and Recreation.”</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>