<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-725</num>
  <heading>PERMITS FOR RECREATION FACILITIES (§ 19-725)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>725.1.</num>
    <text>Permits for community and recreational use of school, park, and playground facilities by organizations or by the general public shall be issued by the permit and special services section.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>725.2.</num>
    <text>The Director of the Department of Parks and Recreation, in his or her discretion, is authorized to issue permits for public use of all facilities under the Department’s control.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>725.3.</num>
    <text>The permit and special services section shall ascertain the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>That the organization, group, or individual applying for the permit falls within the regulations of the Department;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>That the proposed use of the facilities falls within the regulations of the Department; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>That the proposed use of the facilities falls within the agreements entered into with the agency having jurisdictional control of the facility.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>725.4.</num>
    <text>Where a division of the Department has applied for and has received a permit for the recreational operation of a school, playground, or park facility, that division through its responsible employees may issue sub-permits where these are necessary
      to carry out the regular division program.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>725.5.</num>
    <text>The permit and special services section shall be responsible for keeping records and compiling reports in connection with the permits that are issued.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>15 DCRR § 6.1 (August 10, 1970 and December 23, 1970).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>