<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-731</num>
  <heading>DOG PARKS[COLON] GENERAL PROVISIONS (ยง 19-731)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>731.1.</num>
    <text>The Director may establish and maintain areas on District-owned parkland designated for use as dog parks.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>731.2.</num>
    <text>No person shall establish a dog park or charge a fee for use of a dog park on District-owned property without prior approval from the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>731.3.</num>
    <text>No person shall use a dog park for any commercial purpose, however this provision does not apply to dog walkers handling 3 or less registered dogs.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>731.4.</num>
    <text>A dog park shall be open seven (7) days per week during the posted hours for any Department park, except as provided by section 731.5.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>731.5.</num>
    <text>A dog park with lighting shall not remain open later than 10 p.m.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>731.6.</num>
    <text>The Director shall post a notice of a planned dog park closing at each entrance not less than seven (7) days before the period of closure, stating the reasons for the closure. In the case of an emergency, the Director shall post a notice as soon as
      practicable, and the notice shall state that closure is for emergency reasons.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>731.7.</num>
    <text>All dog parks shall be enclosed by appropriate fencing that is at least five (5) feet in height and includes a double-gated entryway area.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>731.8.</num>
    <text>All handlers use dog parks at their own risk. Neither the District of Columbia or its agencies nor the sponsoring dog park group shall be liable for any injury or damage caused in the dog park.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 11714 (December 7, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>