<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-732</num>
  <heading>DOG PARKS[COLON] APPLICATION PROCESS (ยง 19-732)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>732.1.</num>
    <text>Each dog park shall be sponsored by a dog park group, which shall share responsibilities with the Department for the maintenance, management and enforcement of the site. The dog park group must designate one bona fide District resident to act as primary
      contact with the Department.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>732.2.</num>
    <text>A dog park group shall contact the Department regarding a proposed location for a dog park, and the Department shall conduct a preliminary review to determine ownership of the proposed site.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>732.3.</num>
    <text>After the Department determines that the proposed dog park is available District-owned parkland, the sponsoring group must submit a formal proposal to the Department stating the reasons for establishing a dog park in the neighborhood. The application
      shall include letters and/or petitions of support from adjoining Advisory Neighborhood Commissions (ANCs) or other individuals and entities.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>732.4.</num>
    <text>All applications for dog parks shall be noticed in the D.C. Register for a 30 day public comment period and reviewed by a standing committee appointed by the Director, the Dog Park Application Review Committee (DPARC), comprised of the following:
      (1) the Director or his or her designee from the Department; (2) a representative from the Department of the Environment; (3) a representative from the Department of Health/Animal Control Division; (4) a veterinarian active in canine health in the
      District of Columbia or a recognized canine behaviorist; (5) a representative from a recognized animal shelter or animal welfare organization located within the District of Columbia; and (6) four representatives from the community, two of whom shall
      be from sponsoring dog park groups of existing or potential dog parks. Non-agency members of DPARC are appointed by the Director with input from sponsoring dog park groups. DPARC members are not paid and shall serve for two years, but may be reappointed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>732.5.</num>
    <text>The DPARC shall review and evaluate all applications and make recommendations in writing to the Director within thirty (30) days of the submission of the application. The Director shall consider the application, DPARC recommendation and comments received
      during the 30 day comment period and respond in writing to the applicant and appropriate ANC within thirty (30) days of receiving the recommendation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>732.6.</num>
    <text>The Department has three courses of action concerning the review and evaluation of applications It may:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Accept the application as submitted;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Accept the application provisionally based on modifications to be made; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Reject the proposal with a detailed explanation.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>732.7.</num>
    <text>If an application is rejected, the dog park group may re-apply to mitigate any defects in the application. If the application is rejected again, the Department may provide assistance in finding suitable alternatives.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>732.8.</num>
    <text>If an application is accepted, the Department and the dog park group shall enter into a Memorandum of Agreement (MOA) regarding financing, roles and responsibilities with respect to the dog park. The Department shall have primary financial responsibility
      for constructing and maintaining the park, and the dog park group shall have primary responsibility for daily management of the park.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 54 DCR 11714 (December 7, 2007).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>