<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-706</num>
  <heading>RECREATION TRUST FUND (§ 19-706)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>706.1.</num>
    <text>The trust fund created by the Recreation Board under authority of Public Law 534, 77th Congress, shall be deposited with the D.C. Treasurer, and shall become part of the Department appropriation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>706.2.</num>
    <text>The Director of the Department of Parks and Recreation shall designate an employee of the Department who shall function as the treasurer of the trust fund, and who shall be charged with the maintenance of records for deposits into and disbursements
      from the trust fund.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>706.3.</num>
    <text>Fees and receipts from deposit and disbursement activities, which the Department may deem advisable to conduct on a fee or charge basis, shall be collected by employees of the Department only on authorization of the Director of the Department of Parks
      and Recreation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>706.4.</num>
    <text>All fees and receipts from activities conducted on an admission or fee basis shall be deposited with the Department treasurer within forty-eight (48) hours from the date of the activity, Sundays and holidays excepted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>706.5.</num>
    <text>The trust fund treasurer shall issue a prenumbered receipt in duplicate for the full amount received.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>706.6.</num>
    <text>All monies received by the fund treasurer shall be deposited with the D.C. Treasurer as a part of the trust fund.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>706.7.</num>
    <text>Obligations shall not be incurred against the trust fund for any purpose whatsoever by any employee of the Department without prior approval of the Superintendent of Recreation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>706.8.</num>
    <text>Expenditures from the trust fund for personal services shall be made on the basis of payrolls properly certified by the Director of the Department of Parks and Recreation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>706.9.</num>
    <text>Expenditures for personal services not handled in the manner required by § 706.8 shall be made only by special arrangement with the prescribed office of the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>706.10.</num>
    <text>The quarterly audit of the trust fund shall be submitted to the Director of the Department of Parks and Recreation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>15 DCRR §§ 2.1, 2.2, 2.3, 2.5, 2.6 and 2.7 (August 10, 1970 and December 23, 1970).</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>EDITOR’S NOTE</heading>
      <text>The functions of the Superintendent of Recreation under section 706.7 were transferred to the Commissioner pursuant to the Reorganization Plan 3 of 1968, effective June 30, 1968.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>