<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-3003</num>
  <heading>GENERAL DIVING PRECAUTIONS (§ 24-3003)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3003.1.</num>
    <text>A diver experienced in the type of diving being performed shall be in complete charge of the operation as it relates to diving. This person shall be known as the &amp;#8220;diving master.&amp;#8221;</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3003.2.</num>
    <text>Duties of the diving master shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Planning the dive;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Briefing the crew;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Making certain all necessary equipment is available; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Taking all necessary precautions against foreseeable situations, and being responsible for the safety of the person he or she supervises.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3003.3.</num>
    <text>Divers shall not be required or permitted to dive when the diver or diving master has reason to believe a hazard exists that would immediately jeopardize the diver&amp;#8217;s health or safety.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3003.4.</num>
    <text>Each diver shall wear an identification tag bearing the following information for a minimum of twelve (12) hours after completion of a dive:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Diver&amp;#8217;s name;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The words, &amp;#8220;I am a diver&amp;#8221;; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The telephone number of a hospital or nearest recompression chamber, or of a doctor familiar with &amp;#8220;decompression sickness.&amp;#8221;</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3003.5.</num>
    <text>For all scuba diving operations, the buddy system shall be used. The buddy system of diving is a pair of divers working as a unit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3003.6.</num>
    <text>Divers using the buddy system shall keep in visual or physical contact with each other so either may render immediate assistance to the other when required.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3003.7.</num>
    <text>Buddy lines shall be used when visibility is poor.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3003.8.</num>
    <text>For all diving operations, and in addition to the requirements of §3003.1, a standby diver shall remain on the surface during normal diving operations and shall enter the water only in cases of emergency to aid the working diver(s).</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3003.9.</num>
    <text>Dependable two-way communications between the diver and the surface shall be provided and used during all deep sea (hard-hat) dives.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3003.10.</num>
    <text>The communications system provided shall meet the requirements of the U.S. Navy Diving Manual.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Sections 11-29009, 11-29010, and 11-29013 of Regulation No. 70-18, approved May 28, 1970; 11B DCRR, §§901.1, 901.2, 901.5, 901.6, 901.7, and 901.9 (April 1, 1971), Special Edition.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>