<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-5403</num>
  <heading>IDENTIFICATION OF CROSS CONNECTIONS AND PRACTICABILITY DETERMINATION (§1-5403)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5403.1.</num>
    <text>The General Manager may utilize all reasonable means to identify properties with cross connections and may determine whether installation of backflow prevention devices is practicable and necessary in order to prevent the introduction of pollutants
      or contaminants to the Potable Water System.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5403.2.</num>
    <text>In the event the General Manager determines that it is practicable and necessary to install backflow preventers, the General Manager shall give the Owner of the property identified written notification that the following will be required:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Installation of the number and type of backflow preventers determined to be necessary by the General Manager, at no cost to WASA, within sixty (60) days of the date of the notice;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Test and inspect the backflow preventers as directed by WASA, at no cost to WASA;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Report the test results to WASA as directed by WASA; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Permit inspection or inspections as required by WASA.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5403.3.</num>
    <text>An Owner identified in a notice issued pursuant to § 5403.2 may petition the General Manager, in writing, for additional time to install the number and type of backflow preventers required by a notice issued pursuant to § 5403.2. This petition must
      be delivered to WASA no later than fifteen (15) days after the date of notice issued pursuant to § 5403.2. The General Manger may grant the request only upon a finding of good cause shown and shall advise the petitioning Owner of his or her decision
      in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5403.4.</num>
    <text>An Owner identified in a notice issued pursuant to § 5403.2 may also submit an alternative proposal to eliminate existing or potential cross connections. The Owner&amp;#8217;s proposal shall be in writing, certified by a professional engineer, registered
      with the District of Columbia, and must be delivered to WASA no later than fifteen (15) days after the date of the notice issued pursuant to § 5403.2.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5403.5.</num>
    <text>The General Manager shall review the Owner&amp;#8217;s proposal made pursuant to § 5403.4, and after consideration of generally accepted engineering practices, in his or her sole discretion, either approve or deny, in whole or in part, the Owner&amp;#8217;s
      proposal in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5403.6.</num>
    <text>If the Owner&amp;#8217;s proposal made pursuant to § 5403.4 is approved in whole or in part, the General Manager shall notify the Owner to:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Install the number and type of backflow preventers approved, at no cost to WASA, within thirty (30) days of the date of the approval or such other period of time determined reasonable by the General Manager, within his or her sole discretion;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Take any other action determined necessary by the General Manager as a result of the approval of the Owner&amp;#8217;s proposal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Test and inspect the alternative backflow preventers as directed by WASA, at no cost to WASA;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Report the test results to WASA as directed by WASA; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Permit inspection or inspections as required by WASA.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5403.7.</num>
    <text>If the Owner&amp;#8217;s proposal made pursuant to § 5403.4 is denied, in whole or in part, the Owner shall install the devices required in the § 5403.2 notice within thirty (30) days from the date of the General Manager&amp;#8217;s denial.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5403.8.</num>
    <text>An Owner, whose proposal made pursuant to § 5403.4 is denied in whole or in part, may also petition the General Manager for additional time to install the required devices. This petition must be delivered to WASA no later than fifteen (15) days after
      the date of the General Manager&amp;#8217;s notice of denial. The General Manger may grant or deny the Owner&amp;#8217;s request within the General Manager&amp;#8217;s sole discretion and shall advise the petitioning Owner of his or her decision
      in writing.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 1743 (February 23, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>