<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-215</num>
  <heading>VAULTS[COLON] GENERAL PROVISIONS (§ 24-215)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>215.1.</num>
    <text>No excavation or structural work of any kind, including abandonment, shall be done on a vault without a permit; nor shall any vault remain in public space unless authorized by a valid permit issued to the owner.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>215.2.</num>
    <text>Vaults constructed on or after July 1, 1969, are subject to the provisions of the Act, and shall be subject to all applicable portions of all regulations of the District.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>215.3.</num>
    <text>When, in accordance with § 306 of the Act, the Director of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs serves a notice upon an owner informing him or her that the vault is unsafe, the owner shall immediately, upon obtaining the proper permit, make repairs or
      abandonment in accordance with the specifications of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. Repairs or abandonment shall be completed within the time stated in the Director&amp;#8217;s notice.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>215.4.</num>
    <text>Vaults shall not be used for any purpose prohibited by the Building Code (12 DCMR). Vaults may be used for storage of readily movable personal property, as sales or office space; for the storage of fuel; or for the parking of motor vehicles. Other
      uses not specifically forbidden by law or regulation may be approved by the Director if the Director finds it is in the public interest to do so.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>215.5.</num>
    <text>Any person who violates any provision of §§ 215 through 219 of this chapter shall be punished by a fine not exceeding three hundred dollars ($300), or by imprisonment for not more than ten (10) days for each and every day the violation continues.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Article 43, §§ 4(a), (c)(1), (f), (i), &amp;#038; (5) of the Police Regulations (May 1981).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>