<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-3301</num>
  <heading>OCCUPATION OF PUBLIC SIDEWALKS WITH PERSONALIZED PAVERS. (§ 24-3301)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3301.1.</num>
    <text>The Director of the Department of Public Works may issue a Public Rights-of-Way Occupancy Permit to property owners seeking to occupy portions of the abutting public sidewalk with personalized pavers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3301.2.</num>
    <text>Any person seeking to install personalized pavers to the public sidewalk shall submit an application for a Public Rights-of-Way Occupancy Permit together with a non-refundable $ 100.00 application fee paid by certified check or money order made payable
      to the D.C. Treasurer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3301.3.</num>
    <text>The application shall be in the form prescribed by the Director, and shall indicate:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The number and proposed location of the personalized pavers to be installed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The size, color, pattern, joint, and base of the pavers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A depiction of the design to be inscribed on the pavers;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The gross revenues received from the sale of the personalized pavers; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Such other information as the Director may require.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3301.4.</num>
    <text>At the time of permit issuance, the permittee shall pay the Director a non-refundable fee, paid by certified check or money order made payable to the D.C. Treasurer, equal to ten percent (10%) of the gross revenues received by the permittee from the
      sale of the personalized pavers identified by the permit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3301.5.</num>
    <text>Once affixed to the sidewalk, a personalized paver may not be removed or altered, except for maintenance and repair, without the written consent of the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3301.6.</num>
    <text>All terms and conditions set forth in § 3304 of this Chapter shall apply to Public Rights-of-Way Occupancy Permits issued for personalized pavers, with the exception of 3304.9; 3304.11(,) 3304.12, and 3304.16.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>AUTHORITY</heading>
      <text>Unless otherwise noted, the authority for this chapter is Sections IV(A) and V of Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1983, 30 DCR 6428 (December 16, 1983), effective March 2, 1984 and the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Emergency Act of 1996, D.C. Act
        11-429, effective October 18, 1996; D.C. Code §§ 1-337; 7-1071; 10-1141.01 et seq.; 50-921.02 to -921.06; Mayor&amp;#8217;s Orders 96-8, 96-175, 2002-102, 2006-22, 2008-116.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Regulations published at 45 DCR 1644 (March 20, 1998 ), incorporating the text of Proposed Regulations published at 44 DDCR 7186 ( November 21, 1997 ).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>