<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-3312</num>
  <heading>MOBILE STORAGE CONTAINERS (§ 24-3312)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3312.1.</num>
    <text>No person shall place in the public right-of-way a mobile storage container without a public space permit issued by the Director of the District of Columbia Department of Transportation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3312.2.</num>
    <text>A mobile storage container provider shall submit to the Director of the District of Columbia Department of Transportation an application for an annual permit to use public space together with a one hundred dollars ($100) fee. With the application,
      the mobile storage container provider shall also provide proof of insurance as outlined in subsections 3312.3 and 3312.4 and a copy of its current, valid business license.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3312.3.</num>
    <text>A permitted mobile storage container provider shall maintain throughout the term of the permit an insurance policy or policies covering all operations of the permittee’s mobile storage container business. Failure to maintain the required insurance
      shall be a violation of the terms of the permit.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3312.4.</num>
    <text>Each permitted mobile storage container provider shall obtain a public liability insurance policy made out in the name of, and for the sole benefit of the District of Columbia, a municipal corporation, and its officers and employees, covering all
      use of public space. The insurance policy shall contain coverage in the following amounts:</text>
    <text>$500,000.00</text>
    <text>Each individual</text>
    <text>$1,000,000.00</text>
    <text>Each accident</text>
    <text>$500,000.00</text>
    <text>Property damage</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3312.5.</num>
    <text>A mobile storage container provider who has obtained a permit shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Post on the outside of the mobile storage container a copy of the public space permit issued to the mobile storage container provider or clearly display the name of the mobile storage container provider on the outside of the mobile storage container;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Place the mobile storage container in the parking lane of the roadway parallel with the edge of the roadway in front of the property owned or leased by the person renting the mobile storage container, or the nearest adjacent location;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Mark the exterior, traffic facing side of the mobile storage container with reflective material;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Keep the mobile storage container completely covered and sealed during transport; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Keep the exterior of the mobile storage container clean and free of graffiti.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3312.6.</num>
    <text>No mobile storage container provider shall place a mobile storage container in the following manner:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Beyond, atop, or partially resting upon the curb of the roadway;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>In the tree box area;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>On the sidewalk or across the sidewalk;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>In violation of rush hour, street sweeping, building entrance or any other parking restrictions, except the residential permit parking restrictions; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>At a parking meter, unless the person renting the mobile storage container has provided proof of meter fee payment tendered to the Director of the Department of Transportation pursuant to subsection 3312.13 and a copy of the public space permit
        for the address specific location issued by the Director of the District of Columbia Department of Transportation pursuant to subsection 3312.9.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3312.7.</num>
    <text>The Director of the District of Columbia Department of Transportation may revoke an annual public space permit issued to a mobile storage container provider for the following reasons:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The mobile storage container provider violates a provision of subsections 3312.2 through 3312.6 or the public space permit issued to the provider;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The mobile storage container provider fails to pay the applicable fees; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Public safety and welfare.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3312.8.</num>
    <text>No person shall rent for the placement or otherwise cause to be placed on the public right-of-way a mobile storage container without a public space permit that is address specific to the location and issued by the Director of the District of Columbia
      Department of Transportation.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3312.9.</num>
    <text>At least 72 hours prior to the placement of mobile storage containers on the public right-of-way, the person renting such containers shall submit to the Director of the District of Columbia Department of Transportation an application for each address
      specific location to be occupied by the mobile storage containers.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3312.10.</num>
    <text>The person who rents the mobile storage container shall pay a public space permit fee of fifty dollars ($50) to rent space at a location in front of or adjacent to the address specific location. The total public space area occupied by mobile storage
      containers for any location shall not exceed the following dimensions, unless the fee provided in subsection 3312.12 is paid:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Width of eight feet;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Length of twelve feet; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Height of eight feet</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3312.11.</num>
    <text>For each additional six (6) feet of length of public right-of-way or portion thereof occupied by the mobile storage containers an additional permit fee of twenty-five dollars ($25) shall be paid.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3312.12.</num>
    <text>An additional fee shall be charged to compensate the District of Columbia Department of Transportation for the revenue lost due to the occupancy of the public right-of-way by mobile storage containers placed at a parking meter.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3312.13.</num>
    <text>No person shall leave any mobile storage container in the public right-of-way for longer than five (5) days.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3312.14.</num>
    <text>A mobile storage container renter who has obtained a permit to occupy public space shall do the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Post Emergency No Parking signs at the address specific location designated for the mobile storage containers at least 72 hours prior to the placement of the mobile storage containers at the location; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Post on the outside of the mobile storage container a copy of the public space permit for the address specific location.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3312.15.</num>
    <text>The Director of the District of Columbia Department of Transportation may revoke a public space permit issued for an address specific location for the following reasons:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The permittee violates a provision of subsections 3312.10 through 3312.15 or the public space permit for the address specific location;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The permittee fails to pay the applicable fees; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Public safety and welfare.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 55 DCR 12279 (December 5, 2008).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>