<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-3303</num>
  <heading>OCCUPANCY OF PUBLIC RIGHTS-OF-WAY FOR THE PURPOSE OF ACCESSING MANHOLES (ยง4-3303)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>3303.1.</num>
    <text>It shall be unlawful for any person to occupy the public rights-of-way in the roadway for the purpose of accessing a manhole without obtaining a permit issued by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3303.2.</num>
    <text>A permit may be issued for a term of one (1) day or one (1) year, at the option of the applicant.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3303.3.</num>
    <text>Any person seeking a permit under this section shall submit to the Department an application together with a non-refundable $ 85 application fee. The application may be used to obtain multiple single day permits or renewals of annual permits. The
      Applicant or Permittee is under a continuous duty to update the application as necessary.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3303.4.</num>
    <text>A person with an approved application on file with the Department may receive a single day permit upon payment of the rental fee and the submittal of a notice of the intent to occupy the public space. The notice shall include the purpose of the work,
      location of the manhole(s), location of the building or residence to be serviced (if applicable), date work will be performed and a contact name and number for the project. Except as provided in 3303.11, the notice must be filed at least one (1)
      working day prior to the date upon which the occupation is to be permitted.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3303.5.</num>
    <text>No permit issued pursuant to this section establishes legal rights to access a manhole that the Permittee may not otherwise legally access.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3303.6.</num>
    <text>The rental fee for a single day permit shall be $ 200.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3303.7.</num>
    <text>The rental fee for an annual permit shall be $ 2,500.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3303.8.</num>
    <text>The rental fees for annual permits shall be paid on the date the permit is issued, and 30 days in advance of the annual permit&amp;#8217;s expiration date if the permit is to be renewed.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3303.9.</num>
    <text>Any fees paid pursuant to this section may be paid by cash, check or credit card. Checks shall be made payable to the D.C. Treasurer.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3303.10.</num>
    <text>Except as provided in 3303.11, a person holding an annual permit shall notify the Department, by facsimile, at least one (1) day prior to occupation. The notice shall include the purpose of the work, location of the manhole(s), location of the building
      or residence to be serviced (if applicable), date work will be performed and a contact name and number for the project.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3303.11.</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the restoration of existing service in emergency circumstances where notice is not feasible; provided, that the person obtains a permit, or, if the person holds a valid annual permit, provides
      notice in accordance with 3303.10, within one (1) working day after occupation of the public rights-of-way.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3303.12.</num>
    <text>After a Permittee gives notice in accordance with 3303.4, the Permittee may proceed with occupation unless otherwise directed by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3303.13.</num>
    <text>No Permittee shall occupy a roadway so as to render the roadway impassable for motor vehicles, unless otherwise stated in writing by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3303.14.</num>
    <text>Permittees shall adhere to the applicable Traffic Control Plan attached to the permit and all other permit conditions.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>3303.15.</num>
    <text>Occupation of the roadway for the purposes of accessing a manhole in High Traffic Volume Routes identified by the Director as an attachment to the permit is allowed only between 6:30 p.m. and 7:00 a.m. and between 9:30 a.m. and 3:30 p.m., weekdays,
      and all day Saturday and Sunday, unless otherwise stated in writing by the Director.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 48 DCR 5375 (June 8, 2001).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>