<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-1301</num>
  <heading>PRELIMINARY GRANT PROPOSAL AND APPLICATION PROCEDURES FOR THE DEPARTMENT OFONSUMER AND REGULATORY AFFAIRS (ยง 21-1301)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>1301.1.</num>
    <text>Any university or institution wishing to perform the solicited work shall submit a preliminary proposal for a grant. The preliminary proposal shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The name of the university or institution submitting the preliminary proposal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The name and resume of the principal investigator;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The name and a description of the main components of the project; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The estimated total funding requested.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1301.2.</num>
    <text>The Director of DCRA shall review the preliminary proposal, and make an initial selection of those to be considered for funding, and request the submission of an application.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1301.3.</num>
    <text>An application for a grant shall consist of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A request for a grant for the proposed work, signed by the principal investigator and the head of the institution or his or her representative;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A complete proposal for which the grant is sought;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Proof of the institution&amp;#8217;s non-profit status, if requested by the Director of DCRA; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Equal Employment Opportunity (EEO) certification by the institution, if requested by the Director of DCRA.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>1301.4.</num>
    <text>The complete proposal for the grant shall include the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The names and resumes of all investigators to be involved in the project;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A detailed work plan;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A quality assurance plan if sampling and analysis are to be performed;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A work schedule;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>Details of the involvement of subcontractors;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>Detailed budget estimate including personnel, equipment, supplies, travel, contractual and indirect costs;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>A payment schedule;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>A signed concurrence from the university;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>The name and address to which payments shall be made;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>The type of technical or personnel assistance that the grantee will require from DCRA; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>The period for which the proposal is valid.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 35 DCR 3528, 3529 (May 13, 1988).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>