<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-399</num>
  <heading>DEFINITIONS (ยง 17-399)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>399.1.</num>
    <text>When used in this chapter, the words and phrases set forth in this section shall have the meanings ascribed.</text>
    <text>Air Conditioning &amp;#8211; the simultaneous control of all, or at least the first three (3), of those factors affecting both the physical and chemical conditions of the atmosphere within any structure. These factors include temperature, humidity,
      motion, distribution, dust, bacteria, odors, and toxic gases.</text>
    <text>Approved drain &amp;#8211; a receptacle intended to receive and discharge water, liquid, or water-carried wastes into a drainage system with which it is connected, the material, workmanship and type of construction of which is approved by the Director
      of the D.C. Department of Environmental Services.</text>
    <text>Board &amp;#8211; the Refrigeration and Air Conditioning Licensing Board established by Organization Order No. 115, approved October 18, 1955.</text>
    <text>Contractor &amp;#8211; a person, firm, or corporation holding himself, herself, or itself out to the public as being able to engage in the business of installing, maintaining, repairing, and replacing refrigeration and air conditioning equipment.
      A contractor may be an individual holding a license as a Master Refrigeration and Air Conditioning Mechanic or a license as a Master Refrigeration and Air Conditioning Mechanic Limited; or a contractor may be a partnership or corporation, one of
      whose officers holds one of the master licenses, or which employs an individual holding one of the master licenses.</text>
    <text>Director &amp;#8211; the Director of the D.C. Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs, or the Director&amp;#8217;s agent, representative, or designee.</text>
    <text>Disconnecting means &amp;#8211; a device, group of devices, or other means by which the conductors of an electrical circuit can be disconnected from the source of supply.</text>
    <text>Installation or installing &amp;#8211; the placement of equipment in position and the making ready of that equipment for operation.</text>
    <text>License &amp;#8211; a certificate issued by the government of the District of Columbia enabling its holder to engage in the business of Refrigeration and Air Conditioning Contractor, or to engage in the occupation of Master Refrigeration and Air Conditioning
      Mechanic, or Master Refrigeration and Air Conditioning Mechanic Limited.</text>
    <text>Person &amp;#8211; a natural person, or a firm, partnership, association, or corporation.</text>
    <text>Refrigeration &amp;#8211; the process of extracting heat by mechanical means through one of the following:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The compression and evaporation of a gas;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The evaporation of a liquid; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The absorption or adsorption of a liquid or vapor.</text>
    </level>
    <text>Self-contained unit system &amp;#8211; a complete factory-made and factory-tested refrigeration or air conditioning system which is fabricated and assembled in a suitable frame or enclosure, including all components necessary for the proper operation
      of the system, and in which no refrigerant &amp;#8211; containing parts are connected in the field.</text>
    <text>Shut-off valve &amp;#8211; a cut-off to stop the flow of water from the public water supply.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Commissioners&amp;#8217; Order No. 55-2029, ยง1, 5U DCRR, ยง1.1.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>