<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-4217</num>
  <heading>ENFORCEMENT AND PENALTIES (§ 14-4217)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>4217.1.</num>
    <text>Where it has been determined that a housing provider knowingly demanded or received rent above the rent ceiling for a particular rental unit, or has substantially reduced or eliminated services previously provided, the Rent Administrator or the Commission
      shall invoke any or all of the following types of relief:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A rent refund; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Treble the amount of the rent refund ordered paid; or</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A rent rollback for a specific period or until specific conditions are complied with.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4217.2.</num>
    <text>Rent refunds under § 4217.1 shall be trebled only where detailed findings of fact are made that the housing provider acted in bad faith.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4217.3.</num>
    <text>When the Rent Administrator imposes a rent refund or treble that amount under § 901 of the Act, interest shall be calculated on the rent refund or treble amount accordance with § 3826 of these rules.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4217.4.</num>
    <text>Where it has been determined that any person has willfully committed any act specified in § 901(b) and (e) of the Act, both the Rent Administrator and the Commission are authorized to refer the matter to the Corporation Counsel of the District of
      Columbia for criminal prosecution.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4217.5.</num>
    <text>Where a party has failed to comply with an order in a final decision of the Rent Administrator or the Commission, the Rent Administrator, the Commission, or any adversely affected tenant or housing provider are authorized to refer the matter to the
      Superior Court of the District of Columbia for civil enforcement under § 218 of the Act.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4217.6.</num>
    <text>[RESERVED]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4217.7.</num>
    <text>[RESERVED]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4217.8.</num>
    <text>[RESERVED]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4217.9.</num>
    <text>[RESERVED]</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>4217.10.</num>
    <text>Appeals of fines imposed in accordance with § 901(f) of the Act and § 4217.9 shall be reviewed in accordance with § 301 of the DCRA Civil Infractions Act of 1985 and §§ 202(a)(2) and section 219 of the Rental Housing Act of 1985.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 1336, 1417 (March 7, 1986); as amended by:</heading>
      <text>Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 33 DCR 2656, 2669 (May 2, 1986); and Notice of Final Rulemaking published at 45 DCR 684, 694 (February 6, 1998).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>