<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-800</num>
  <heading>CONTROL OF ASBESTOS (§ 20-800)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>800.1.</num>
    <text>The requirements of 40 CFR 61.141, 61.145, 61.146, 61.150, 61.152, and 61.154 (July 1, 1994 Edition), are hereby adopted by reference, with the terms used and defined, except that:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The word &amp;#8220;Administrator&amp;#8221; as used in the CFR sections shall be taken to mean &amp;#8220;Director of the District Department of the Environment&amp;#8221;;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Planned renovation operations subject to § 800 shall not be started prior to receipt of written approval therefor from the Administrator; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Demolition operations subject to § 800, except for those subject to 40 CFR § 61.145(a)(3), shall not be started prior to receipt of written approval therefor from the Administrator.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>800.2.</num>
    <text>For the convenience of persons subject to the requirements of § 800.1, Appendix No. 4 to this Subtitle contains pertinent parts of 40 CFR 61, Subpart M (July 1, 1994 Edition) which includes the sections cited in § 800.1. Appendix No. 4 was published
      in the D.C. Register on June 21, 1996 at 43 DCR 3305.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>800.3.</num>
    <text>To qualify for an asbestos abatement permit or license, a business entity or person shall:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Comply with the requirements of the Asbestos Licensing and Control Act of 1990, effective May 1, 1990 (D.C. Law 8-116; D.C. Code § 6-991 et seq.), as amended by the Asbestos Licensing and Control Act of 1990 Amendment Act of 1993, effective October
        15, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-37; D.C. Code § 6-991 et seq.) and the requirements set forth in these rules; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Show evidence of having completed a course of instruction on asbestos abatement accredited by EPA under the Asbestos Hazard and Emergency Response Act, or at least as stringent as the requirements of 40 CFR 763, Subpart E, Appendix C (July 1, 1994
        Edition); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Be considered to be qualified for a license by endorsement if the business entity or person is licensed in a state whose requirements are judged by the Administrator to be at least as stringent as those of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>800.4.</num>
    <text>The following exemptions apply:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>An asbestos abatement permit or license is not required for the removal of nonfriable asbestos containing material; and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>An asbestos abatement permit, business entity or asbestos worker licenses and recordkeeping requirements of the Act and its amendments are not required for the removal of, or other activity involving, resilient floor covering materials, including
        sheet vinyl, resilient tile, and associated adhesives, provided that the business entity persons performing the removal:</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>follow the resilient floor covering manufacturers&amp;#8217; recommended work practices for removal;</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>are not required to obtain asbestos accreditation under applicable federal asbestos requirements and regulations promulgated by the United States Environmental Protection Agency (EPA); and</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>for removals involving more than 18 square feet of resilient floor covering material, notify the Mayor in writing at least 10 days prior to the removal of the time, place and entity performing the removal and certify that asbestos accreditation
        is not required under subparagraph (2) of this paragraph.</text>
    </level>
    <level>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The requirements of Section 800 apply to removals and other activity involving resilient floor covering materials only to the extent they are required under applicable federal asbestos requirements, including the Occupational Safety and Health Act
        (OSHA) asbestos standards and the EPA asbestos National Emission Standards for Hazardous Air Pollutants (NESHAP).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>800.5.</num>
    <text>To apply for or to renew a permit or license, a business entity or person shall submit a completed application and pay the fee listed below, by certified check made payable to the D.C. Treasurer:</text>
    <level>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>License Fee Schedule</text>
    </level>
    <text>TYPE OF LICENSE</text>
    <text>FEE</text>
    <text>Asbestos Worker</text>
    <text>$ 60/2 years</text>
    <text>Business Entity</text>
    <text>$ 600/2 years</text>
    <level>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Permit Fee Schedule</text>
    </level>
    <text>AMOUNT OF RACM REMOVED</text>
    <text>FEE</text>
    <text>261 &amp;#8211; 2,600 linear feet or</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
  </level>
</level>