<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>14-5216</num>
  <heading>OWNER LEASE APPROVAL (§ 14-5216)</heading>
  <level>
    <num>5216.1.</num>
    <text>DCHA shall not review the owner’s lease for compliance with state/local law. It is the owner’s responsibility to comply with state/local law when leasing units on the owner’s property.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5216.2.</num>
    <text>The assisted dwelling lease shall contain all of the required information as listed below:</text>
    <text>The names of the owner and the tenant:</text>
    <text>The unit rented (address, apartment number, and any other information needed to identify the contract unit);</text>
    <text>The term of the lease (initial term and any provisions for renewal);</text>
    <text>The amount of the monthly rent to owner; and</text>
    <text>A specification of what utilities and appliances are to be supplied by the owner, and what utilities and appliances are to be supplied by the Family.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5216.3.</num>
    <text>The initial term of the assisted dwelling lease shall be for at least one (1) year. DCHA may approve a shorter initial lease term as a reasonable accommodation to the Family.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5216.4.</num>
    <text>This written lease is a contract between the tenant Family and the owner; DCHA is not a party to this contract.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <num>5216.5.</num>
    <text>All provisions in the HUD-required Tenancy Addendum shall also be added word-for-word to the owner&amp;#8217;s standard lease form, for use with the assisted Family. As a part of the lease, the tenant shall have the right to enforce the Tenancy Addendum
      against the owner and the terms of the Tenancy Addendum shall prevail over any other provisions of the lease.</text>
  </level>
  <level>
    <type>annotations</type>
    <level>
      <heading>SOURCE</heading>
      <text>Final Rulemaking published at 59 DCR 7875, 7888 (June 29, 2012).</text>
    </level>
  </level>
</level>